<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:s="http://www.zdnet.com/search" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
    <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
    <description>Latest Blog for ZDNet</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>ZDNet</copyright>
    <managingEditor>customerservice@zdnet.com (ZDNet Customer Services)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>uk-engineering@cbsinteractive.com (ZDNet Webmaster)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 15:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 15:29:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>2</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://i.zdnet.com/images/spry/zdnet_300x300.jpg</url>
      <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
      <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
      <width>143</width>
      <height>39</height>
    </image>
    <s:counts>
      <start>0</start>
      <return>20</return>
      <found>41622</found>
    </s:counts>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013308</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/diplomat-services-orchestrator-a-cio-job-description-five-years-from-now-7000013308/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Diplomat, services orchestrator: a CIO job description five years from now ]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Predictions about the changing roles of chief information officers: less technology management, more business management. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Mar 2013 15:11:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Joe McKendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chief information officers -- as well as other IT leaders -- will be less hands-on tech specialists, and more high-level consultants to their businesses. They won't be competely controlling technology budgets, but still will be responsible for the security, scalability and reliability of any technology the business uses.&nbsp;</strong></p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Marketing Staff-US Bureau of Labor Statistics" alt="Marketing Staff-US Bureau of Labor Statistics" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013308/marketing-staff-us-bureau-of-labor-statistics-200x143.jpg?hash=BJH5ZzEyMQ&upscale=1" height="143" width="200"><figcaption>Photo credit: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Occupational Outlook Handbook</figcaption></figure>
<p>In recent posts here at this site, we've discussed the possibilities of CIOs sharing technology initiatives with the likes of "chief digital officers" and chief marketing officers. Also, cloud computing positions IT leaders less as technology shop managers and more as high-level consultants responsible for identifying and procuring both extrenal and internal technology resources.</p>
<p>What's the future job description of the chief information officer going to look like a couple of years from now? Antonio Piraino, CTO of ScienceLogic <a href="http://www.idgconnect.com/blog-abstract/749/antonio-piraino-global-the-developing-role-cio-why-it-changing-way-we-do-business" target="_blank">provides</a> this glimpse of rising skills in a post at <em>IDG Connect:</em></p>
<p><strong>Less technology-exertion, more people-insertion:</strong> "The customer is the focus of the CIO strategy, not the product/infrastructure," says Piraino.</p>
<p><strong>Less power broker - more services orchestrator:</strong> Here we see the shift from technology guru to business guru, Piraino says. "The CIO will be more responsible for financials, legalities, security, and extensibility of services, and less responsible for technical robustness, integration, and infrastructure operations (including governance policies)."</p>
<p><strong>Less concession, more compliance:</strong> Given the global nature of business, there will need to be greater attention paid to various government regulations and mandates. Local cloud computing laws are a prime example. Piraino elevates this discussion way above merely filling out forms and delivering reports: "As cloud computing use grows, governments will become more involved in regulation, creating a worldwide opportunity for CIOs to chance their job role to that of an international power broker, ambassador, and even diplomat."</p>
<p><strong>Less security, more protection:</strong> Again, global business demands global leadership. "CIOs need to become experts in cyber-security and the nuances amongst different countries."</p>
<p><strong>Less cost, more work:</strong> IT systems are getting more complex, and sprawl is on the rise. "Centralizing control of data and applications through centralized management systems, as well as the use of virtual desktop, are areas that CIOs are becoming far more engaged in."</p>
<p><strong>Less reaction, more vision:</strong>&nbsp; CIOs are moving to "the role of proactive defender of proprietary business concerns, and also that of creator of new business productivity tools and information that help us get ahead of the market we're after."&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013304</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-introduces-thinkcentre-edge-62z-all-in-one-desktop-is-its-18-5-inch-screen-too-small-7000013304/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Lenovo introduces ThinkCentre Edge 62z all-in-one desktop: Is its 18.5-inch screen too small?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The $549 starting price tag is small enough, but is the workstation's LCD too tiny?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 23:20:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Sean Portnoy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="lenovo-thinkcentre-edge-62z-all-in-one-desktop-pc" alt="lenovo-thinkcentre-edge-62z-all-in-one-desktop-pc" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013304/lenovo-thinkcentre-edge-62z-all-in-one-desktop-pc-620x600.jpg?hash=ZmSyLmNkLw&upscale=1" height="600" width="620"></figure>
<p>All-in-one enterprise desktop PCs make a lot of sense to save valuable space for packed-in employees. But everyone also agrees that bigger screen sizes make for better worker productivity. Those two trends are in conflict in the new <a >Lenovo ThinkCentre Edge 62z</a>, its latest all-in-one that bucks the trend for bigger desktop monitors.</p>
<p>That's because the 62z (a follow-up to <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-thinkcentre-edge-92z-an-aio-for-smes-7000005119" target="_self">its larger 92z sibling</a>) squeezes in an 18.5-inch LCD, which Lenovo says yields a 65-percent savings in space over a 20-inch monitor. And in its defense, the company isn't marketing the PC as a traditional corporate machine, pitching it instead to schools and space-starved work areas like nurse's stations.</p>
<p>Still, a sub-19-inch desktop screen in 2013 might be hard for some workers to deal with -- unless they are so unlucky to have even smaller legacy screens. What no one can object to is the pricing, as the 62z starts at just $549. Notably, it offers Windows 7 Professional instead of Windows 8.&nbsp;You can get up to an Intel Core i3 Ivy Bridge processor, 8GB of RAM, and 1TB of hard drive, and you even get a DVD drive thrown in for good measure.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Speaking of measure, is the 62z the right size for Lenovo's customers? We'll find out when it becomes available in May.</p>
<p>[Via <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/28/lenovo-thinkcentre-edge-62z-stuffs-an-all-in-one-into-a-tiny-space/" target="_blank">Engadget</a>]&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013303</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/dells-directors-forecast-a-grim-future-for-the-pc-industry-7000013303/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Dell's directors forecast a grim future for the PC industry]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A lengthy proxy statement submitted to the SEC by Dell's board of directors makes a forceful case for taking the company private. A Special Committee sees a gloomy future for the PC industry and even worse prospects if Dell tries to compete with more agile rivals.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 22:36:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ed Bott]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apple/">Apple</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-byod-and-the-consumerization-of-it/">BYOD and the Consumerization of IT</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dell Inc. filed a <a href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=101133&amp;p=IROL-secToc&amp;TOC=aHR0cDovL2FwaS50ZW5rd2l6YXJkLmNvbS9vdXRsaW5lLnhtbD9yZXBvPXRlbmsmaXBhZ2U9ODgzMDY0NCZzdWJzaWQ9NTc%3d&amp;ListAll=1">special proxy statement</a> with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission today, laying out its plans to take the company private.</p>
<p>ZDNet’s Rachel King has details on what the proposed transaction <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dells-latest-sec-filing-paints-picture-of-ceos-future-employment-7000013301/">will mean for the company’s founder and CEO, Michael Dell</a>.</p>
<p>My eye&nbsp;was drawn to a lengthy bulleted list that begins on page 47, laying out the reasons why anyone holding Dell stock might want to sell. The section, under the heading “Reasons for the Merger,” was prepared by a Special Committee made up of “four independent and disinterested directors of the Company.” (The Wall Street Journal [subscribers only] has <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/deals/2013/03/29/dells-special-committee-includes-ex-goldman-analyst-reagan-adviser/">a list of the four directors</a>, with bios.)</p>
<p>The Special Committee argues that the proposed all-cash buyout represents a premium of between 25% and 37% of the Dell share price before the offer became public. If you’re a shareholder, they say, you should jump at the buyout to avoid being exposed to the “various risks and uncertainties related to continued ownership of Common Stock.” What follows is a remarkably downbeat portrait of Dell’s bleak position in a PC industry&nbsp;whose future&nbsp;is uncertain at best.</p>
<p>Year over year, PC shipments have begun to show steep declines after slowing for the past five years, as data from Gartner Research confirms:</p>
<figure><img title="pc-industry-2007-2012" alt="pc-industry-2007-2012" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013303/pc-industry-2007-2012-620x355.png?hash=BGt4AGyyLw&upscale=1" height="355" width="620"></figure>
<p>The picture in 2009-2010 was slightly distorted by the worldwide recession, with shipments down sharply in 2009 as the economy struggled to come back from the 2008 banking crisis, with a bounceback in 2010 that consisted in no small part of deferred sales. If you assume that half of the shipments in 2010 were deferred from 2009, then the percentage increase in shipments over the past six years is 13, 11, 9, 7, 4, -3.</p>
<p>Even without adjusting for those unusual factors, the trend line is unmistakably down, and with the current economic malaise in Europe there’s&nbsp;every indication&nbsp;that the negative trend will continue.</p>
<p>That’s the starting point for the Dell Special Committee’s list of negatives, which&nbsp;opens&nbsp;by citing&nbsp;“decreasing revenues in the market for desktop and notebook PCs and the significant uncertainties as to whether, or when, this decrease will end…” The Special Committee blames the slowdown on a variety of factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>continued macroeconomic pressures</li>
<li>lengthening replacement cycles</li>
<li>the uncertain adoption of the Windows 8 operating system</li>
<li>unexpected slowdowns in enterprise Windows 7 upgrades, and</li>
<li>increasing substitution of smartphones and tablets for PCs.</li>
</ul>
<p>The industry as a whole is also under pressure thanks to “the increasing usage of alternative PC operating systems to Microsoft Windows.” Presumably that’s a reference to both Apple’s OS X, which is applying pressure at the high end of the market, and Google’s Chrome OS, which has scored some recent gains with extremely low-priced models from Samsung and Acer.</p>
<p>The Special Committee also notes “the increasing importance of the smartphone and tablet markets.”&nbsp;That&nbsp;trend is especially&nbsp;unfortunate for Dell, which “currently has vey little presence” in that market.</p>
<p>Dell’s historic strength in high-volume sales to large corporations is also at&nbsp;risk, the Special Committee says, citing&nbsp;“increasing adoption of ‘bring your own device’ policies by businesses, which allow employees to make their own decisions regarding which computers and/or other electronic devices.” That’s followed by a dry bit of understatement about unnamed competitors “whose products presently have greater appeal to consumers than the Company’s current products.” Ouch.</p>
<p>Even if the PC industry can keep the volume of PC shipments up, revenues are still a big problem across the board, thanks to “ongoing downward pricing pressure and trend towards commoditization in the desktop and notebook personal computer market.”</p>
<p>Several of Dell’s competitors, most notably Lenovo and ASUS, have scored gains in this down market. The secret of their success? At least in part, they’ve grown by concentrating on the low end of the market. That’s a problem for Dell, the report says. Dell’s strength has been in “higher-margin premium PC products,” the Special Committee says. The current PC market, especially in developing economies, has seen a “shift in demand … to lower-margin value products, a segment in which the Company has historically been much less competitive.”</p>
<p>Michael Dell, who would presumably remain as&nbsp;CEO&nbsp;of&nbsp;the&nbsp;post-buyout company that bears his name, clearly wants to get out of the increasingly cutthroat PC business, where margins are slim and getting slimmer.</p>
<p><strong>More recent coverage about Dell and the PC industry's troubles on <em>ZDNet</em></strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/whats-behind-the-slump-in-pc-sales-can-the-industry-turn-around-7000009231/">What's behind the slump in PC sales? Can the industry turn around?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dells-latest-sec-filing-paints-picture-of-ceos-future-employment-7000013301/">Dell's latest SEC filing paints picture of CEO's future employment</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-will-the-new-dell-look-like-7000013193/">What will the new Dell look like?</a></li>
<li><a >Dell: As Blackstone, Icahn circle, is there 'significant upside' left?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/why-icahns-dell-plan-could-be-a-fud-nightmare-7000012268/">Why Icahn's Dell plan could be a FUD nightmare</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackstone-considering-last-minute-bid-for-dell-7000012808/">Blackstone considering last minute bid for Dell</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013301</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/dells-latest-sec-filing-paints-picture-of-ceos-future-employment-7000013301/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Dell's latest SEC filing paints picture of CEO's future employment]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Dell has filed a whopping 274-page outline and case for its shift to operating as a private company.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:56:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-dell/">Dell</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-us/">Government US</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-legal/">Legal</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="michaek-dell" alt="michaek-dell" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/michaek-dell-620x202.jpg?hash=ZGD5MzZ2MT&upscale=1" height="202" width="620"></figure>
<p>The neverending saga about the future of <strong>Dell</strong> continues as the PC maker has filed a whopping 274-page proxy statement outlining its case to go private.</p>
<p>The Round Rock, Texas-based company filed a Form PREM14A with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission on Friday, explaining to shareholders in legalese about some of the rationales for going private and what Dell could look like after all is said and done.</p>
<p>Wedged in between numerous recommendations from the board and scheduling meetings for votes, there's also a snippet about the role of the company's founder and CEO, Michael Dell.</p>
<p>Dell's <a href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=101133&amp;p=irol-SECText&amp;TEXT=aHR0cDovL2FwaS50ZW5rd2l6YXJkLmNvbS9maWxpbmcueG1sP2lwYWdlPTg4MzA2NDQmRFNFUT0xJlNFUT0xMTgmU1FERVNDPVNFQ1RJT05fUEFHRSZleHA9JnN1YnNpZD01Nw%3d%3d">legacy and future with his own business</a> has been called into serious question in the last few weeks.</p>
<p>Amid reports of a potential buyout by&nbsp;private equity investment firm Blackstone, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/report-blackstone-asked-hurd-about-leading-dell-after-buyout-7000012916/">it was even rumored</a> that Dell would be replaced (either forcibly or due to his own resignation) by Oracle president and former HP chief Mark Hurd.</p>
<p>While everything involving the future of Dell (including who will sit at the top) is up in the air at this point, the SEC filing <a href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=101133&amp;p=irol-SECText&amp;TEXT=aHR0cDovL2FwaS50ZW5rd2l6YXJkLmNvbS9maWxpbmcueG1sP2lwYWdlPTg4MzA2NDQmRFNFUT0xJlNFUT0xMTgmU1FERVNDPVNFQ1RJT05fUEFHRSZleHA9JnN1YnNpZD01Nw%3d%3d">does highlight a few things</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Term</em>. The term of Mr. Dell’s employment is indefinite and may only be terminated (i) by Mr. Dell; or (ii) by Parent’s board of directors (a) for cause at any time or (b) following a change in control of Parent or an initial public offering, whichever occurs earlier.</p>
<p><em>Base Salary</em>. Mr. Dell will be entitled to receive an initial annual base salary of $950,000. The base salary will be subject to annual review by Parent’s board of directors and may be increased, but not decreased.</p>
<p><em>Annual Bonus</em>. Mr. Dell will be eligible to earn an annual bonus pursuant to the bonus plan applicable to senior executive officers of the Company, with a target equal to 200% of base salary.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But it looks like there are a few catches too.</p>
<p>Along with a few notes about golden parachutes and stock options, Michael Dell is also going to be tied to a confidentiality agreement about all "sensitive" info related to the Dell corporation and its subsidiaries as well as all "intellectual property created by him during and within the scope of his employment."</p>
<p>The <a href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=101133&amp;p=IROL-secToc&amp;TOC=aHR0cDovL2FwaS50ZW5rd2l6YXJkLmNvbS9vdXRsaW5lLnhtbD9yZXBvPXRlbmsmaXBhZ2U9ODgzMDY0NCZzdWJzaWQ9NTc%3d&amp;ListAll=1">full 274-page filing</a> is available online now.</p>
<p><strong>More recent coverage about the bids for Dell on <em>ZDNet</em></strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-will-the-new-dell-look-like-7000013193/">What will the new Dell look like?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dell-software-chief-swainson-talks-scale-perception-growth-7000013018/">Dell Software chief Swainson talks scale, perception, growth</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dell-as-blackstone-icahn-circle-is-there-significant-upside-left-7000013078/">Dell: As Blackstone, Icahn circle, is there 'significant upside' left?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/why-icahns-dell-plan-could-be-a-fud-nightmare-7000012268/">Why Icahn's Dell plan could be a FUD nightmare</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackstone-considering-last-minute-bid-for-dell-7000012808/">Blackstone considering last minute bid for Dell</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013298</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/reports-debate-how-much-amazon-paid-for-goodreads-7000013298/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Reports debate how much Amazon paid for Goodreads]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The estimates for how much Amazon paid for Goodreads range from a modest $150 million to a whopping $1 billion.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 18:57:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-amazon/">Amazon</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following the news that <strong>Amazon</strong> is acquiring <strong>Goodreads</strong>, now everyone wants to know (or at least speculate) about the price tag.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/amazon-acquires-goodreads-aims-to-meld-kindle-with-social-7000013272/">Amazon acquires Goodreads, aims to meld Kindle with social</a></p>
<p>For starters, Amazon hasn't revealed how much it paid for the literary social network -- and it likely won't. All that has been confirmed is that the deal is expected to close <a href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=1801563&amp;highlight=">during the second quarter</a>.</p>
<p>Thus, plenty of analysts and media outlets are taking it upon themselves to estimate how much the Seattle-headquarted corporation forked over.</p>
<p>That debate is actually getting a bit heated.</p>
<p>Earlier on Friday, <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-03-29/amazon-likely-paid-1-billion-for-goodreads"><em>Bloomberg BusinessWeek</em> published</a> its possibly educated guess of $1 billion. The news service backed that up with a lengthy worksheet based on the number of Goodreads users and lined that up with how much users are worth at other social networks, such as Facebook and LinkedIn.</p>
<p>Interestingly, <a href="http://allthingsd.com/20130329/actually-amazon-paid-about-150-million-for-goodreads/">Kara Swisher at <em>AllThingsD</em></a> quickly shot that hefty figure down, positing that the Kindle Fire maker paid something closer to $150 million.</p>
<p>While she admitted that she is "still trying to determine how much of the deal was cash and how much was stock," Swisher described the <em>BusinessWeek</em> report as "a we-are-just-guessing story," adding (unnamed) sources told her "that number is simply wrong."</p>
<p>Regardless, whatever Amazon paid is likely going to pay off in the long run as it integrates Goodreads's popular social platform (and user base of more than 16 million) onto the Kindle brand of e-readers and tablet.</p>
<p>(Also, whatever Amazon paid, it can probably afford it without blinking.)</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000012718</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/9-best-ipad-keyboards-hands-on-march-2013-7000012718/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[9 best iPad keyboards (hands on): March 2013]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The question I get asked most frequently is, "what keyboard do you like for the iPad"? This collection is bound to have an iPad keyboard for everyone. I have even covered two keyboards for the iPad mini.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 18:31:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Gallery]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apple/">Apple</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ipad/">iPad</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>9 good keyboards for the iPad (March 2013) including bonus iPad mini model</h3>
<p>It seems there is a keyboard released for the iPad every few weeks, and figuring out which one might work best is almost as hard as finding a good app in the App Store.</p>
<p>This collection of iPad keyboards is unique in that with the exception of one they all have been used by me. I own all of them, except two that were supplied for evaluation by the manufacturer. I have used all but one of these keyboards extensively in my work, and I have a good feel for which ones are best for me.</p>
<p>All of the keyboards in this collection are shown closed for thinness and open for business. With the one excepton mentioned, all of the keyboards charge via microUSB and will last for months on a charge. A microUSB to USB charging cable is included with these keyboards. They all connect to the iPad via Bluetooth.</p>
<p>In addition to the eight good iPad keyboards, there is a bonus for iPad mini owners. Three keyboards for the iPad mini are also covered in this collection.</p><h3>Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case</h3>
<p>This new case from Belkin uses innovative magnetic strips to provide three different viewing angles for using the iPad with the keyboard. The Bluetooth keyboard turns on automatically when the iPad is placed in one of the strips and turns off when the magnetic connection is broken.</p>
<p><strong>Dimensions</strong>: 245 x 197 x 18.8 mm (9.6 x 7.75 x 0.74 inches); 411 gm (0.9 pounds)</p>
<p>The&nbsp;Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case for the iPad&nbsp;is available in black and in white. The white model, which is aluminum on both the top and bottom of the case, is $129. The white model should be slightly lighter than the black one.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.belkin.com/us/p/p-f5l149">$99.99 from Belkin</a></p><h3>Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case</h3>
<p>This case allows sliding the iPad forward covering the keyboard for use as a tablet. This mode works surprisingly well in spite of the extra weight of the case.</p><h3>Logitech Keyboard Folio</h3>
<p>This case has just been released and I have not used it. It is worth including in this collection given the history of Logitech with good accessories and the use of magnets for propping the iPad at convenient viewing angles, much like the Belkin model.</p>
<p>Logitech has designed the Folio with a full keyboard that works much like the others in this roundup.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 248 x 198 x 25 mm (9.76 x 7.8 x 0.98 inches); 639 gm (1.43 lbs.)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/keyboard-folio?wt.mc_id=global_news_kbfolio">$99.99 from Logitech</a></p><h3>Logitech Keyboard Folio mini</h3>
<p>Logitech also makes the Keyboard Folio case in a version to work with the iPad mini.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/keyboard-folio-mini?wt.mc_id=global_news_kbfoliomini">$89.99 from Logitech</a></p><h3>ZAGG Profolio+</h3>
<p>ZAGG has been making keyboards for the iPad as long as any company, and the Profolio+ is the latest model. It is also the best one I have used.</p>
<p>This keyboard is also a full case for the iPad, offering total protection for the tablet. It has a faux leather cover that makes it secure to hold. It is the thinnest folio from ZAGG to date and has the same good keyboard as the others.</p>
<p>The keyboard is thinner than the older models and is not only backlit but also offers seven colors of backlighting. The colors can be changed at will and each has three brightnesses to adjust to taste.</p>
<p>The Profolio+ is currently my favorite keyboard for the iPad.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 7.5 x 9.75 x 0.81 inches; 1 lb.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zagg.com/accessories/zaggkeys-ipad-profolio-plus-keyboard-case.php#profolioplus">$129.99 from ZAGG</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/profolio-from-zagg-best-keyboard-case-for-the-ipad-7000012504/">See the full review by James Kendrick on ZDNet</a></p><h3>ZAGG Profolio+</h3>
<p>Like all of the keyboards covered, the Profolio+ is almost full-sized and provides a great typing experience. Even the fastest touch typists should be able to use this keyboard without compromise.</p>
<p>The case uses magnets to turn the iPad on/off when the case is opened/closed. Magnets also hold the case closed when not in use.</p>
<p>The backlighting on the keyboard may sound like a gimmick but it comes in handy quite often in my use.</p><h3>ClamCase Pro</h3>
<p>Those who prefer a laptop form will really like the ClamCase Pro. Once the iPad is popped into the lid (an easy process) it becomes a MacBook Air-like laptop without a trackpad. Magnets in the ClamCase turn the iPad on and off when opened and closed.</p>
<p>The typing experience on the ClamCase Pro is the best of all the keyboards in this collection. It is also the most expensive of the lot.</p>
<p>The screen can be folded under the keyboard for using the iPad as a tablet without removing it. The keys are exposed to the hand holding the unit, which feels a bit weird. They are deactivated so there are no inadvertent keypresses when using the iPad this way.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 7.88 x 9.68 x 0.85 inches; 1.5 lbs.</p>
<p><a href="http://clamcase.com/">$169 from ClamCase</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/clamcase-pro-review-turn-your-ipad-into-a-versatile-laptop-7000012167/">See the full review by James Kendrick of ZDNet</a></p><h3>ClamCase Pro</h3>
<p>The iPad fits securely in the lid of the ClamCase Pro and is very much like a laptop in use. The keys have a nice tactile feedback with good key travel.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Apple doesn't support trackpads with the iPad so it's no surprise it is missing on the ClamCase Pro. The space where a laptop trackpad would normally be found instead is a good palm rest on the front of the keyboard.</p><h3>Thickness comparison</h3>
<p>ClamCase Pro (left; ZAGG Profolio+ (right)</p>
<p>0.85 inches vs. 0.81 inches</p><h3>Logitech Ultrathin Keyboard Cover</h3>
<p>Those wanting a keyboard/case for the iPad that is the thinnest and lightest possible should look no further than the Ultrathin Keyboard Cover. The iPad snaps onto the keyboard via a magnetic hinge that closes like a book when not in use.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Magnets in the Ultrathin turn the iPad on/off when opened/closed. To use the keyboard the iPad must be detached from the Ultrathin and popped into the keyboard slot. This slot also has magnets that firmly grip the iPad once it is in place. It is so secure that the whole assembly can be picked up by the iPad without detaching.</p>
<p>The Ultrathin only covers the screen of the iPad, so it offers no protection to the back.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 7.47 x 9.5 x 0.39 inches (without iPad); 0.78 lbs.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/ultrathin-keyboard-cover">$99.99 in white, black, and red from Logitech</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/hands-on-with-the-logitech-ultrathin-keyboard-cover-video/7567">Don't miss the video review by James Kendrick of ZDNet</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><h3>Logitech Ultrathin Keyboard Cover</h3>
<p>The Ultrathin keyboard offers a good typing experience for even the fastest typist. The key layout is standard and it has a row of special iPad control keys, as is standard on all of the keyboards in this collection.</p><p>Thickness comparison</p>
<p>ZAGG Profolio+ (left); Logitech Ultrathin Keyboard Cover (right)</p>
<p>0.81 inches vs. 0.39 inches (without iPad)</p><h3>Logitech Solar Keyboard Folio</h3>
<p>The Solar Keyboard Folio has several unique features not found on any of the other keyboards in this collection. This case is a real portfolio that closes like a book. It also uses two small solar panels to keep the keyboard charged so it requires no charging by the user. Last but not least, it supports two different usage modes.</p>
<p>The solar charging keeps the keyboard charged even in room lighting. The solar panels are on one side of the folio so you have to make sure these are exposed when the case is closed. Sadly, these panels are covered when being used as a keyboard so it can't charge while typing.</p>
<p>In addition to a typing position, the case supports a media viewing mode that puts the iPad at a comfortable angle for such activity. This position is also good for reading ebooks in my experience.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 16.85 x 9.9 x 0.7 inches; 1 lb. (without iPad)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.logitech.com/en-us/product/solar-keyboard-folio" target="_self">$129.99 from Logitech</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/logitech-solar-keyboard-folio-for-ipad-no-sun-required-review/7956">Don't miss the full review by James Kendrick of ZDNet</a></p><h3>Logitech Solar Keyboard Folio</h3>
<p>The rubberized keys provide a pleasant and fast typing experience. The row of iPad control keys is present.</p>
<p>The case senses when the iPad is in the typing position and activates automatically.</p><h3>Logitech Solar Keyboard Folio</h3>
<p>When the iPad is placed in the forward position as demonstrated in the photo, the keyboard enters into a media playing mode. The one row of keys exposed below the iPad become special control keys for playing media.</p>
<p>This position is perfect for watching video on crowded airplanes.</p><h3>Thickness comparison</h3>
<p>ZAGG Profolio+ (left) vs. Logitech Solar Keyboard Folio (right)</p>
<p>0.81 inches vs. 0.70 inches</p><h3>ZAGGfolio</h3>
<p>The original ZAGGfolio is not as good as the newer Profolio+ but it is still a good keyboard for the iPad. It works much the same as the newer keyboard but without the backlighting. It is also a bit thicker and heavier but is now available at a bargain price.</p>
<p>Unlike the Profolio+, the keyboard unit of the ZAGGfolio can be removed from the case and used by itself.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 7.6 x 9.75 x 0.9 inches; 1.1 lbs (without iPad)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zagg.com/accessories/zaggfolio-ipad-3-keyboard-case">$49.99 from ZAGG</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-ipad-and-zaggfolio-keyboard-case-compact-and-fast-7000010109/">Catch the full review by James Kendrick of ZDNet</a></p><h3>ZAGGfolio</h3>
<p>The keyboard of the ZAGGfolio is very similar to that of the Profolio+ with the exception of the backlighting. It offers a good touch typing experience and is a solid case for the very low price now available.</p><p>Thickness comparison</p>
<p>ZAGG Profolio+ (left) vs. ZAGGfolio (right)</p>
<p>0.71 inches vs. 0.90 inches</p><h3>ZAGGkeys Flex</h3>
<p>Those wanting a separate keyboard for the iPad will find the ZAGGkeys Flex to be an outstanding choice. The keyboard is slightly bigger than the other keyboards in this collection and is very close to the size of a standard keyboard.</p>
<p>The black carrying case of the Flex opens to become a stand for the iPad. The separate keyboard means it can be positioned wherever the user prefers for typing.</p>
<p>Since this is a separate keyboard it can also be used with the iPad mini.</p>
<p>Android tablet owners may want to give the Flex a look as it can be used with those tablets, too. There is a toggle to turn the row of special control keys into keys for Android tablets.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 9.4 x 5.0 x 0.75 inches; 11.3 ounces</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zagg.com/accessories/zaggkeys-flex-tablet-keyboard-stand">$79.99 from ZAGG</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/zaggkeys-flex-portable-keyboard-for-ios-and-android-review-7000007543/">Full review by James Kendrick of ZDNet</a></p><h3>Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case</h3>
<p>This new case from Belkin uses innovative magnetic strips to provide three different viewing angles for using the iPad with the keyboard. The Bluetooth keyboard turns on automatically when the iPad is placed in one of the strips and turns off when the magnetic connection is broken.</p>
<p><strong>Dimensions</strong>: 245 x 197 x 18.8 mm (9.6 x 7.75 x 0.74 inches); 411 gm (0.9 pounds)</p>
<p>The&nbsp;Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case for the iPad&nbsp;is available in black and in white. The white model, which is aluminum on both the top and bottom of the case, is $129. The white model should be slightly lighter than the black one.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.belkin.com/us/p/p-f5l149">$99.99 from Belkin</a></p><h3>ZAGGkeys Flex</h3>
<p>The separate keyboard and stand means the iPad can be used in portrait mode with the keyboard.</p><h3>ZAGG Mini 9</h3>
<p>The ZAGG Mini 9 may look like the Profolio+ but this one has a big difference. It is a keyboard and case for the iPad mini. It has the same size keyboard as the iPad keyboards so it provides a good typing experience. Unlike the other ZAGG keyboards, the iPad mini doesn't fit in a slot for typing. There is a stand that pops out of the back of the case for propping the tablet up for typing.</p>
<p>The iPad mini pops easily in and out of the Mini 9 and totally protects the tablet when in the case. This keyboard turns the little iPad mini into a decent production machine for writing.</p>
<p>Dimensions: 8.13 x 5.75 x 0.88 inches; 10.5 ounces (without iPad mini)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zagg.com/accessories/zaggkeys-mini-ipad-keyboard-case.php#9-black">$49.99 from ZAGG</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/zagg-mini-9-keyboard-case-for-the-ipad-mini-review-7000008258/">Don't miss the full review by James Kendrick of ZDNet</a></p><h3>ZAGG Mini 9</h3>
<p>The keyboard is outstanding and turns the iPad mini into a decent writing system. It is now only $49.99 from ZAGG, a bargain price.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013295</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-likes-can-reveal-your-sexuality-ethnicity-politics-and-your-parents-divorce-7000013295/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Facebook 'Likes' can reveal your sexuality, ethnicity, politics, and your parent's divorce]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Big data is not your friend because it can easily be used to reveal highly personal information...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:48:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Tom Foremski]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook users that click "like" on a variety of cultural subjects reveal a surprisingly large amount of information about themselves even if they've taken steps to tighten up their privacy settings.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2013/03/06/1218772110">A recently published study</a>&nbsp;by researchers at Cambridge University in the UK and Microsoft Research, used an automated analysis of 58,000 volunteers' Facebook "likes" to make highly accurate predictions about a person's private and very sensitive personal attributes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The authors of the study: "<a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2013/03/06/1218772110">Private traits and attributes are predictable from digital records of human behavior</a>"&nbsp;claim that they were able to use "easily accessible digital records of behavior, Facebook Likes,"&nbsp;to accurately predict a wide range of attributes that included:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sexual orientation, ethnicity, religious and political views, personality traits, intelligence, happiness, use of addictive substances, parental separation, age, and gender.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The researchers developed a model that could predict if a man was homosexual 88 percent&nbsp;of the time, and 75 percent&nbsp;of the time for women; ethnic origin (95 percent), gender (93&nbsp;percent), religion (82 percent), political affiliation (85 percent), if they use addictive substances (75 percent), and relationship status (67 percent).</p>
<p>Margaret Weigel, writing on&nbsp;<a href="http://journalistsresource.org/studies/society/internet/private-traits-attributes-predictable-digital-records-behavior?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+journalistsresource+%28Journalist%27s+Resource%29&amp;utm_content=Google+Feedfetcher">Journalist's Resource</a>, notes that clicking "Like" on popular subjects such as "Britney Spears" or "Desperate Housewives"&nbsp;were among signs of a homosexual orientation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The model was less accurate when attempting to predict the length of the parents' marriage (60 percent). "Individuals with parents who separated have a higher probability of liking statements preoccupied with relationships, such as 'If I'm with you then I'm with you. I don't want anyone else.'"</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Foremski's Take:</strong>&nbsp;Predictive models such as the ones used by the researchers in this study, become even more accurate as more data is collected.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Easy access to such highly sensitive information could be used by employers, landlords, government agencies, educational institutes, and private organizations, in ways that discriminate and punish individuals. And there's no way to fight it.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Big Data is growing into a massive threat to individual well being in society. There is no difference between Big Data and Big Brother when it comes to commercial interests.</p>
<p><strong>Big data is the Stasi of our online worlds</strong></p>
<p>There are many "silent listeners" in social networks that collect people's "Likes" and other online behaviors so that the information can be sold discretely to third parties.&nbsp;Facebook, Google, and all other social networks, also collect such behavioral information.&nbsp;</p>
<p>While the companies say that their behavioral Big Data is stripped of users' names, it is possible to use other databases such as electoral records, demographic information, and location data, to identify individuals by name.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It's essentially a secret dossier on more than a 1 billion social network users. &nbsp;</p>
<p>While this dossier is fragmented at the moment, sophisticated new technologies will soon make it trivial to pull together a massive amount of sensitive private data on every individual that interacts with the Internet in any way.</p>
<p>Your phone records, or information about events and parties you attend, could implicate you in the future if they show a connection with people that were later identified as drug dealers, criminals, terrorists, or maybe even paedophiles.</p>
<p>Big Data gradually accumulates a cloud of suspicion around you simply by association.</p>
<p><strong>Deleting bad links</strong></p>
<p>Google, for example, already assesses the quality of a web site by who links to it. If you have lots of what Google considers to be low-quality, spammy site back links, it will downgrade your web site's all important PageRank and bury it deep within its index.&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is why website owners are desperately sending out letters to other web sites asking them to delete their back links. [<a href="http://www.siliconvalleywatcher.com/mt/archives/2012/07/the_unravelling.php">The Fast Unravelling Web: How Google Is Killing The Hyperlink</a>.]</p>
<p>Think about how such methodology could be applied to determine the "TrustRank" of an individual in Google's world. People can't erase past links to friends and associates now considered "low quality" or possibly even criminal.</p>
<p>Welcome to the future obligations of your present life. Will people start purging their online social circles of unsavory characters? Or people they think might turn to criminal activities?&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Big data knows you better than you know you</strong></p>
<p>Big Data technologies currently under development will be able to make highly accurate predictions about nearly every important aspect of your existence: your health, your lifespan, even your sanity.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Big business loves Big Data because it helps them manage their risks -- it's what corporations do best.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I was at a recent Cisco event featuring their futurists. One of them talked about people's FICA scores, which determine their ability to get a mortgage, and developing a type of healthcare "FICA" score for each person as a way of determining their ability to get healthcare insurance.</p>
<p>I pointed out that it was a brilliant idea for cutting healthcare costs since it would likely result in mass hospital closures as companies only insured people with a low risk of needing their services.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The future benefits of Big Data are stacked firmly against the individual.&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013291</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/google-business-and-open-source-patent-protection-7000013291/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Google, business, & open-source patent protection]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Google has just pledged that it won't sue other companies over open-source patents if they don't sue Google first, but this is actually a long established policy. Now, if only it could stop the patent wars!]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 17:22:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-legal/">Legal</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-linux/">Linux</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-nokia/">Nokia</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software-development/">Software Development</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.google.com/patents/opnpledge">Google's Open Patent Non-Assertion (OPN) Pledge</a> in which <a href="http://google-opensource.blogspot.com/2013/03/taking-stand-on-open-source-and-patents.html">Google promises "not to sue any user, distributor or developer of open-source software</a> on specified patents, unless first "attacked" sounds good. Indeed, it is good. But, this is far from the first time that Google has made such a pledge. Indeed, open-source companies have long banded together to protect themselves and their patents from outside attackers.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="OIN" alt="OIN" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013291/oin-200x21.jpg?hash=LJHjAQuvZm&upscale=1" height="21" width="200"><figcaption>Before Google was sharing patents for open source, the Open Invention Network was there. </figcaption></figure>
<p>The most important protector of open-source patents is the <a href="http://www.openinventionnetwork.com/%20OIN">Open Invention Network</a> (OIN). <a href="http://practical-tech.com/operating-system/companies-join-up-to-share-patents-for-linux/2638/">The &nbsp;OIN was formed in 2005</a> by IBM, Sony, Philips, Red Hat, and Novell. <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-joins-open-source-patent-network-3039288457/">Google joined the OIN in 2007</a>.</p>
<p>The OIN freely acquires Linux-related patents and then shares them, royalty-free, to any company or organization that agrees not to assert its patents against Linux or its applications. Since then, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/linux-patent-defense-group-expands-open-source-protection/10491">the OIN has significantly expanded and updated the technologies it covers</a> with its protective network of royalty-free cross-licenses. OIN now also covers patents related to such open-source programs such as Kernel Virtual Machine (KVM), Git, OpenJDK, and WebKit.</p>
<p>The OIN is an example of what's called a patent pool or patent commons. They're popular for frenemies so they can work together &nbsp;without friction on intellectual property issues while still competing in the marketplace. In a business world where companies can waste millions of dollars in patent wars patent pool arrangements have become increasingly common.</p>
<p>Outside of patent pools, Google is also far from the only company to promise not to use a group of patents against open-source developers. In 2005,<a href="http://www.ibm.com/ibm/licensing/patents/pledgedpatents.pdf"> IBM pledged the free use of 500 of its patents for the development, distribution, and use of open-source software</a> (PDF Link). <a href="http://www.redhat.com/legal/patent_policy.html">Red Hat has made similar promises</a>. And, in 2005, <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20051229190243/http://www.nokia.com/iprstatements">Nokia promised not to use its patents against the Linux kernel</a>. Indeed, even <a href="http://www.linuxplanet.com/linuxplanet/reports/6793/1">Microsoft, when it comes to .NET anyway, has promised not to sue open-source developers</a>.</p>
<p>At the same time though patents are still being used by theoretically open-source-friendly companies to try to clobber each other. In the most recent example, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/nokia-throws-spanner-into-googles-plans-for-vp8-codec-standard-7000013067">Nokia is refusing to license 64 plus patents to Google to cover its open-source VP8 Web video codec</a>. This came after <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-and-mpeg-la-settle-long-running-vp8h-264-patent-dispute-7000012289">Google and MPEG had settled their patent disagreements</a> which had been keeping VP8 from becoming an Internet standard.</p>
<p>So, while in short I applaud Google for its patent promise and don't think for a moment that we're done with patent wars between major companies or the constant toll on the economy of patent trolls. No, our <a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9176257/First_we_kill_all_the_patent_lawyers">patent system is still utterly broken</a>. While patent pools, fair, reasonable, and non-discriminatory terms (FRAND) patent policies, and promises to use patents only in defense are all well and good, we're still a long way from having a fair and equitable patent system.</p>
<p><strong>Related Stories:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-pledges-to-only-strike-back-not-first-in-open-source-patent-cases-7000013263/">Google pledges to only strike back (not first) in open source patent cases</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/nokia-throws-spanner-into-googles-plans-for-vp8-codec-standard-7000013067/">Nokia throws spanner into Google's plans for VP8 codec standard</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-and-mpeg-la-settle-long-running-vp8h-264-patent-dispute-7000012289/">Google and MPEG LA settle long-running VP8/H.264 patent dispute</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/linux-patent-defense-group-expands-open-source-protection/10491">Linux patent defense group expands open-source protection</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-profits-from-linux-patent-fud-7000001598/">Microsoft profits from Linux patent FUD</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013292</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/entrepreneur-tech-iphone-apps-from-savvy-start-ups-7000013292/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Entrepreneur Tech: iPhone apps from savvy start-ups]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Start-ups are creating innovative mobile apps destined for success. This week 17 year old Nick D'Alosio sold his Summly app to Yahoo for about $30 million. We look at other iPhone apps created by start-ups that could also be in the same position one day. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:47:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Eileen Brown]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Gallery]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software/">Software</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Move app records all of the walking, cycling and running you do. The storyline shows where and how much you moved during the day.</p>
<p>The app automatically recognizes activities (walking, running, cycling, transportation), routes and places. The data is visualized on a map and a daily storyline that encourages the user to take small steps towards more healthy habits and lifestyles. There is no need to start and stop the app as it runs continuously on the background.</p>
<p>ProGeo raised $ 1.6 million (&euro; 1.2 million) of seed funding in 2013. Founded by Aleksi Aaltonen, Juho Pennanen, Jukka Partanen, Sampo Karjalainen, Zsolt Sz&aacute;sz and Aapo Kyr&ouml;l&auml;. </p>
<p>Credit: <a href="https://moves-app.com/">Move</a></p><p>Arro analyses ratings from stores. When you want to buy something immediately, you don&rsquo;t have time to read reviews. Arro shows your best choices and shows you whether to get the product you&rsquo;re looking at in the store.</p>
<p>You do not need to do the research yourself -- Arro simplifies the searching process. When a friend needs advice, text them a link with your suggestions.</p>
<p>Arro was founded in Palo Alto, California by Manish Vij, Sekhar Narayanaswami and Aaron Snow.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://www.arroapp.com/">Arro</a></p><p>Audiobox is a platform that lets you store, manage and stream your media library online anytime and everywhere. It provides integrations with third party services, such as Last.fm, YouTube, Dropbox, Twitter and Facebook.</p>
<p>AudioBox.fm lets the user stream an entire music library through the Cloud Web Player, an online media player working with any common web browser.</p>
<p>Audiobox was founded by Fabio Tunno, Claudio Poli and Valeria Chiodina and is based in Brooklyn, New York.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="https://audiobox.fm/">Audiobox</a></p><p>Founded by Russell Okamoto and Greg Passmore, Celly aims to creates networks where existing social networks don&rsquo;t work.</p>
<p>Celly provides a quick way to form a group that everyone can join. Participants can organize into cells of unlimited size by texting a single message.</p>
<p>In schools, students and teachers can communicate with Celly whilst keeping phone numbers private. Group messages can be moderated by one or more curators to keep conversations on-topic.</p>
<p>For city governments, businesses, and neighborhoods, each bureau, office, or block can communicate internally using private cells which can be linked together into a larger network using hashlinks.</p>
<p>&nbsp;Credit: <a href="http://cel.ly/">Celly</a></p><p>GymPact, based in San Francisco, California sets a committment for you to go to the gym -- with a financial penalty if you don't get there. If you meet your committment you get a financial reward.</p>
<p>Your penalties go towards paying other GymPact members that meet their exercise commitments. It is integrated with Runkeeper for when you excercise outside.</p>
<p>Founders Yifan Zhang and Geoff Oberhofer secured $118,000 funding in Jan 2012 with a further $850,000 in June 2012.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://gym-pact.com/">GymPact</a></p><p>Hubble is a private sharing app that gives the family one place to see messages, check-ins and shared experiences. Hubblegrams -- digital postcards can be sent to selected family members within your private Huggle network.</p>
<p>Hubble's purpose is to help you stay connected with the people you are closest to -- your family. You can stay in touch, share experiences and remember special and everyday moments of your family's life.</p>
<p>Hubble founders Robert Evans and Andre Neumann-Loreck run Hubble from San Francisco, California.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://hubblelabs.com/index.html">Hubble</a></p><p>Relay helps you discover the newest and best visual entertainment from around the web. Find GIFs, videos and images and send them (&ldquo;relay&rdquo; them) to your friends.</p>
<p>Co-founders Joe Rideout and John McGee run Relay from Toronto, Canada and have raised $700,00 in seed funding.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://tryrelay.com/">Relay</a></p><p>Hushed gives you the ability to create private, local and international disposable numbers to place voice calls and send SMS messages anonymously. Having a private number allows users to continue the conversation on a more personal level without compromising security and privacy.</p>
<p>Hushed numbers are temporary and can be disposed at any time.</p>
<p>Founded by Justin Shimoon and Timo Mika Gl&auml;&szlig;er, Hushed is located in Gatineau, QC Canada.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://hushed.com/">Hushed</a></p><p>Laveem gives consumers nutrition and allergen information for every food in the world to empower them to make better deciscions on their diets. The core technology understands food compositon and nutrition.</p>
<p>Laveem reads what allergens and ingredients food contains, what food groups it represents, what major flavorings it contains and what dishes it is similar to. The food information is organised so that queries return answers in a way relevant to your needs.</p>
<p>Founders Varun Chirravuri, Shaun Seo, Ralph Bouquet and Matthew Ng run Laveem from Cambridge, MA.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://www.laveem.com/">Laveem</a></p><p>Roximity is a location based alert system that sends targeted contextual offers, alerts and messages to potential customers that are in the vicinity of their stores. Sign up for notifications and be alerted when sales and discounts are in store.</p>
<p>Roximity was founded by Daniel Newman and Austin Gayer and is located in Denver, Colorado.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://beta.roximity.com/">Roximity</a></p><p>Co-founders Aaron Gotwait and Jesse Engle created Seesaw to enable you to make better decisions by asking your friends for feedback when you are choosing a product to purchase. You can receive an SMS message or see the options on your iPhone. You can vote and give feedback to help your friends decide.</p>
<p>Seesaw is located in San Francisco.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="https://seesaw.co/">Seesaw</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>Ubooly turns your iPhone or iPod touch into an interactive soft toy for children. Buy the toy for $29.95, download the app, insert the iPhone into the soft toy pocket and give the pet voice instructions such as 'Play a game'.</p>
<p>Ubooly is based in Colorado and was founded by Carly Gloge and Isaac Squires.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="https://www.ubooly.com/order">Ubooly</a></p><p>Sunrise is a calendar app for your iPhone. It is intended for Google Calendar users. It integrates with Eventbrite, LinkedIn and shows birthdays and events from Facebook.</p>
<p>It was founded by Pierre Valade and Jeremy Le Van and and is located in New York City.</p>
<p>Credit: <a href="http://www.sunrise.am/">Sunrise</a></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013287</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-spoiling-me-for-other-chromebooks-7000013287/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Chromebook Pixel: Spoiling me for other Chromebooks]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[My Samsung Chromebook has kept me happy for months but that's changed and it's Google's fault.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:41:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-laptops/">Laptops</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="samsung-chromebook-v1" alt="samsung-chromebook-v1" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013287/samsung-chromebook-v1-200x186.jpg?hash=MQZ1BGtkZQ&upscale=1" height="186" width="200"><figcaption>Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook</figcaption></figure>
<p>I have been using a Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook since picking it up last year. The Samsung is a great laptop that happens to run Chrome OS, something that works very well for me. I like everything about the Samsung. Then Google sent me a Chromebook Pixel and spoiled me.</p>
<p>The Series 5 550 Chromebook works very well for me. It runs Chrome OS nicely and is a super work machine that meets my needs. There is not really anything I don't like about the Samsung, but it's no longer enough.</p>
<p><strong>Related stories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a >Chromebook Pixel: Run Ubuntu alongside Chrome OS</a></li>
<li><a >Chromebook Pixel hands on (photos)</a></li>
<li><a >The Chromebook Pixel cost me a lot of money</a></li>
<li><a >MacBook Pro (Retina display) vs. Chromebook Pixel on video</a></li>
<li><a >Chromebook Pixel: 5 tips and tricks (including pinch to zoom)</a></li>
<li><a >New Samsung Chromebook and Samsung Series 5 550 head-to-head</a></li>
<li><a >New Samsung Chromebook: ARM processor and $249</a></li>
<li><a >Samsung Chromebook in 3G slips out for $330</a></li>
<li><a >Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook: All in after a week</a></li>
<li><a >11 good Chrome web apps for the Chromebook</a></li>
<li><a >Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook: Day one</a></li>
<li><a >New MacBook for me? No, a new Samsung Chromebook on the way</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The culprit is the Chromebook Pixel, the expensive laptop from Google that costs almost three times what I paid for the Samsung. The Pixel hardware is as good as that on any laptop, even better in some ways. Using the Chromebook Pixel is sheer joy and it's not often you can say that about a laptop.&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img title="Pixel side view" alt="Pixel side view" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013287/pixel-side-view-v1-600x440.jpg?hash=AwyxL2EyBJ&upscale=1" height="440" width="600"><figcaption>Chromebook Pixel</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel keyboard is great, the trackpad is outstanding, and then there's that screen. The high resolution, even higher than the famous Retina Display, is simply wonderful to use. Text displays razor sharp and graphics pop. The integrated LTE is so darn convenient when wi-fi is not available. Then there's the touch screen. This has come in handier far more than I thought it would. Chrome OS is not fully optimized for touch but what it can do with it makes the Pixel even better than without.</p>
<p>Given the high price of the Chromebook Pixel, surely I'm not thinking of getting one? As you have probably guessed that's exactly what I am considering. My Samsung Chromebook that I liked so much is just not cutting it now that I've used the best Chromebook.</p>
<p>I haven't pulled the trigger on the Pixel yet as it was not in my budget. I recently bought the MacBook Pro and another similar purchase is not in the budget. But I admit I've come very, very close to doing so.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Pixel I am using now is going back to Google shortly and the thought of going back to a regular Chromebook is not appealing at all. Stepping down on the hardware, the build quality, the integrated LTE, the gorgeous display, the touch screen...</p>
<p>You may think I'm crazy to be considering spending this much ($1449) for a Chromebook Pixel and you're not far off the mark. I don't know anyone I would recommend to do so. But the fact is I use Chrome OS, it works well for me, and I want to run it on the best hardware available to run it. It's my money, after all.</p>
<p>That in a nutshell is the narrow audience that the Chromebook Pixel is aimed at. Someone who is already convinced that Chrome OS will work fine for them. The price is too high for those not sure about Chrome OS. But for those like me who know it's good, and want to run it on the best hardware available to do so, the Pixel is it.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013289</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/nec-mulling-mobile-phone-unit-sell-off-to-lenovo-report-7000013289/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[NEC mulling mobile phone unit sell-off to Lenovo: report]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Japanese technology firm may be considering a sell-off of its mobile phone unit to Lenovo or others, reports suggest, amid declining sales targets and financial troubles. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:35:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="lenovointelphone610x407-v1-610x407" alt="lenovointelphone610x407-v1-610x407" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013289/lenovointelphone610x407-v1-610x407-610x407.jpg?hash=BQpjBGWyLm&upscale=1" height="407" width="610"><figcaption>(Credit: Corinne Schulze/CNET)</figcaption></figure>
<p>NEC may be looking to sell off its struggling mobile phone unit to PC maker Lenovo, according to sources <a >speaking to the Reuters news agency</a>.</p>
<p>While Lenovo may be in the front-running to snap up the unit, goes the report, NEC is also looking to others in a bid to raise much needed cash, after nearly two years of consistent quarterly financial losses as well as in market share.</p>
<p>NEC confirmed with a statement through the Tokyo Stock Exchange that "considering a number of ways to bolster the competitiveness of our mobile phone business" amid a rapidly changing and evolving market.</p>
<p>"But nothing has been decided," the firm was keen to stress. It does, however, confirm earlier rumors that NEC was at very least in discussions with other firms.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117062" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-still-talk-7000010434/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/010434/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-talk-220x165.png?hash=BTZ5LmR3Aw&upscale=1" alt="Lenovo, RIM: You two should probably still talk" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-still-talk-7000010434/">Lenovo, RIM: You two should probably still talk</a></p>
<p class="more">

																	<p>Sit down, have a glass of wine over dinner, and discuss the endless possibilities of a smartphone coalition--or a hardware unit takeover, should RIM finally bite the dust. </p>

																</p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-still-talk-7000010434/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>There have been prior relationships between NEC and Lenovo. But after entering financial difficulties,&nbsp;<a >NEC ditched its entire 281.1 million shares in Lenovo</a> to raise short-term cash, generating some $227.7 million at the time. Lenovo, meanwhile, shrugged it off, saying it wouldn't harm its PC or tablet coalition between the two firms.</p>
<p>Also, six months ago NEC cut its mobile phone sales target for the year ending this month down from 5 million units to 4.3 million units. As one of its more lucrative units, NEC will likely see dinged upcoming financial results.</p>
<p>Lenovo already has a smartphone business, but it's far from the global lucrative business that Apple or Samsung have. It does, however, have a Chinese equivalent stake in the mobile market, holding second-place <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-slow-pc-market-not-to-worry-we-also-have-smartphones-7000005971/">in the region with 11.5 percent of the market</a> as of last October.</p>
<p>That said, the company has no plans to ditch its PC business in favor of taking on the smartphone market. Rumors swirled when <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-may-bid-to-acquire-rim-in-smartphone-boost-report-7000009901/">Lenovo was reportedly looking at acquiring Canadian smartphone maker BlackBerry</a>, but no deal was made.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In January, Lenovo chief executive&nbsp;Yuanqing Yang said the firm was focused <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-ceo-forget-post-pc-were-in-the-pc-plus-era-7000009638/">on the "PC plus" age</a>&nbsp;rather than the "post-PC" era. This confirmed that it will continue to develop its position in the PC market&nbsp;— in which it's <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/idc-hp-is-still-top-pc-vendor-worldwide-amid-soft-q4-sales-7000009673/">coming in at a close second-place behind HP</a>, which holds the top spot by shipments&nbsp;— as well as bolstering its position in the smartphone space.</p>
<p>For NEC, it could be a helpful boost to the company's bottom line as it continues to slowly fall to pieces. It cut 10,000 jobs last year&nbsp;— one-tenth of its workforce&nbsp;— amid a poor economic climate and increasing losses.&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013290</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/windows-blue-under-the-hood-minkernel-and-basefs-7000013290/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Windows Blue under the hood: MinKernel and BaseFS]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Since rumors about Windows Blue first surfaced, there's been talk that the Windows 8 update would include more than just UI tweaks. Clues about some of these deeper level changes are emerging.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:31:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Jo Foley]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft-surface/">Microsoft Surface</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-server/">Windows Server</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the recently leaked Windows Blue build out for the past few days, those downloading it are continuing to find new details as they dissect the code.</p>
<p>While some of the early user-interface changes -- in some cases, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-alleged-windows-blue-build-shows-off-coming-interface-tweaks-7000013035/">making Windows Blue look and feel more like Windows Phone</a> -- have been a big focus, the under-the-hood changes have gotten less coverage.</p>
<figure><img title="basefsminkernel" alt="basefsminkernel" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013290/basefsminkernel-v1-620x277.png?hash=Z2DmZwuyAw&upscale=1" height="277" width="620"></figure>
<p>But over on ITWorld.com, long-time Microsoft watcher Sandro Villinger has shared a few of his findings.</p>
<p>Villinger found <a href="http://www.itworld.com/windows/350114/7-hidden-gems-windows-blue">mention of something called "BaseFS" buried in the Windows Blue code</a>. This doesn't seem to be a new name for <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsoft-goes-public-with-plans-for-its-new-windows-8-file-system/11666">ReFS, the new file system for Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012</a>. Instead, according to one of my contacts, BaseFS is more of an internal concept that has to do with shared functionality between the different file systems</p>
<p>Interesting. Even more interesting (to me, at least) is Villinger's find regarding "Minkernel." (A screen capture by Villinger showing <a href="http://www.itworld.com/windows/350114/7-hidden-gems-windows-blue">references in Windows Blue to BaseFS and Minkernel</a> is embedded above in this post.)</p>
<p>Microsoft has been working to detangle the Windows hairball since it was developing Windows Vista, and possibly before. MinWin is the Windows "core" that resulted. MinWin includes some kernel interfaces, but it isn't simply the Windows kernel. As I've described it in the past,<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsoft-confirms-minwin-is-in-windows-7-after-all/1690"> MinWin is the heart of Windows</a>, organized in a way so that none of the included parts has any dependencies on anything outside of MinWin.</p>
<p>So what is MinKernel in this context? According to one of my sources, MinKernel is a minimal set of functionality that is shared across the different Windows kernels that run on x86, ARM, Windows Phone and Xbox. MinKernel is the one base-level implementation on top of which these platforms are built, the same way that BaseFS may be the base-level file system that is common across different platforms.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: <a href="https://twitter.com/h0x0d/status/317648138804527107">WalkingCat (@h0x0d</a> on Twitter) found MinKernel references dating back to Windows 7. He pointed me to an <a href="http://www.nvlabs.in/vbootkit2.0-AttackingWindows7viaBootSectors.pdf">NVLabs security-research presentation</a> mentioning it, a slide from which is here:</p>
<figure><img title="minwinminkernel" alt="minwinminkernel" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013290/minwinminkernel-620x428.png?hash=LmMwLmEvAJ&upscale=1" height="428" width="620"></figure>
<p>Since word of Windows Blue first surfaced months ago, tipsters have said there would be <a href="/story/create/">kernel-level and driver-level changes included as part of this first operating-system update to Windows 8</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.itworld.com/windows/350114/7-hidden-gems-windows-blue">Villinger also found a few more Blue clues</a> worth noting. He discovered some references within the Blue bits to a Modern/Windows Store version of the Windows Defender antivirus app that Microsoft bundled with Windows 8 and Windows RT. (Right now, Defender is a Desktop, not a Metro-Style app.) He also found some hints that indicate that 3G/4G tethering support may be built into Blue.</p>
<p>My ZDNet colleague Ed Bott also discovered <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-windows-8-hardware-specs-hint-at-7-inch-tablets-and-a-microsoft-reader-7000013271/">a change&nbsp;in Microsoft's certification guidelines for Windows 8 hardware that clear the path for 7- and 8-inch tablets</a>.</p>
<p>Microsoft officials have been hinting for the past couple months that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-windows-8-coming-to-a-smaller-screen-size-near-you-7000010773/">smaller Windows 8 tablets were likely in the pipeline</a>. Rumors of both a <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/htc-said-to-plan-windows-tablets-to-challenge-apple-led-market.html">7-inch HTC Windows tablet</a> and an <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-report-throws-fuel-on-microsoft-xbox-surface-rumors-7000006986/">Xbox Surface media-consumption tablet</a> are out there.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013288</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/facebooks-android-play-could-be-boon-for-htc-7000013288/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Facebook's Android play could be boon for HTC]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Should HTC be Facebook's hardware partner for a social phone the smartphone maker could get a revenue boost and more scale to compete with Samsung.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:06:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-htc/">HTC</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>HTC is an underdog in the Android landscape, has to battle Samsung's scale and Apple's knack for design. It's a tall order that could be made a bit easier with the help of Facebook.</p>
<p>According to a Facebook invitation, the company will outline its new home on Android April 4.</p>
<figure><img title="fbandroid" alt="fbandroid" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013288/fbandroid-595x588.png?hash=LmSyZGyuAz&upscale=1" height="588" width="595"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Reports <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/28/facebook-android-phone/">from TechCrunch</a> and <a href="http://www.techmeme.com/130328/p63#a130328p63">a few others</a> are betting that Facebook's Android overlay would go along with HTC hardware. If these reports play out, HTC would likely see unit volume pick up and perhaps even have a hit on its hands.</p>
<p>A Facebook phone business model could look like Google's Nexus program. Facebook would embed natively social features on a device's home screen and hardware makers would line up as a partner.</p>
<p>For HTC, there's not much to lose. The company needs to make a few big bets to juice revenue growth.</p>
<p>More:</p>
<ul>
<li><a >A more aggressive HTC would be welcome</a></li>
<li><a >The HTC One is the best smartphone I have ever used (review)</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013277</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/pertino-serves-up-small-business-networks-in-the-cloud-7000013277/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Pertino serves up small-business networks, in the cloud]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Backed with new funding of $20 million, the startup aims to offer software-defined networks for SMBs that don't want to make - or can't afford - complex hardware.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Heather Clancy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Startup <a href="http://pertino.com/">Pertino</a>, which just raised an additional $20 million in Series B funding, is testing a cloud service that allows small businesses to set up virtual local area networks or wide area networks using just software. It's an idea similar to the one behind Meraki, the company that was snapped up by Cisco in November 2012 for a cool $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>Pertino's vision is that it should be as easy for small-business owners to set up secure networks for file sharing and shared collaboration scenarios as it is to invite someone to join your social network. In other words, very easy. All you need is Internet connectivity.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Right now, the technology works with Windows devices although support for the Macintosh operating system and various mobile devices is planned throughout 2013 as the company tests its services, said Craig Elliott, co-founder and CEO of Pertino, which is based in Los Gatos, Calif.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"You can have multiple networks, basically used to connect local, secure groups of people that need to share information," he said.</p>
<p>If Elliott's name sounds familiar, it's because he used to be the CEO of Packeteer, the network optimization company that was eventually bought by Blue Coast Systems.</p>
<p>There are approximately 1,000 customers trying out the early version of the system, after a beta test of the technology with the Spiceworks IT pro community. The initial devices supported include Windows 7, Windows Server 2008 R2 Systems with Windows 8, Windows Server 2012, with Mac OS &nbsp;systems to be supported soon. Mobile devices will be added in late 2013.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Small businesses can use Pertino to create networks for up to three users for free; after that, it is <a href="http://pertino.com/">priced</a> at $10 per month, per user.</p>
<p>Pertino's new $20 million in backing comes from Jafco Ventures. The infusion brings Pertino's total raised so far to $28.85 million. Its other funders include Norwest Venture Partners and Lightspeed Venture Partners.</p>
<p>"One of the things that attracted us to Pertino is the fact that they have built a cloud-based solution leveraging the most innovative and disruptive technology to hit networking in a decade -- software defined networking (SDN) -- and they're delivering it in a practical and consumable way to an underserved global market," said Jeb Miller, general partner at Jafco, explaining the rationale for the investment.</p>
<p>Here's more about Pertino's concept:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/JnMTLbWURv4" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013286</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/savvis-capitalizes-on-their-cloud-customer-relationships-7000013286/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Savvis capitalizes on their cloud customer relationships]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Savvis lays it on the line on providing reliable cloud services]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:49:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[David Chernicoff]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the issues that consumers of cloud services consider, as part of the selection process for determining which cloud service providers to use, is the reliability of the infrastructure that is hosting the desired services. Removing that concern from the purchase selection criteria can speed the adoption process for cloud services, and that&rsquo;s part of what <a href="http://www.savvis.com/">Savvis </a>is trying to do with their Client Connect service.</p>
<p>After all, if you are using a colo or cloud host for yourself, you must have already gone through the vetting process for that provider, otherwise why would you be using their services. And Client Connect is designed to give Savvis customer&rsquo;s an enhanced ability to connect with other Savvis datacenter users in any of the Savvis datacenter facilities.</p>
<p>The Client Connect service, which Savvis customers need to voluntarily choose to participate in, both as buyers and sellers, Is basically a directory of service providers hosting at any of Savvis&rsquo; datacenter facilities. Each client gets a profile page where they can promote their service offering and where they need to provide contact information for potential customers. &nbsp;Offering your company&rsquo;s erices in this fashion also includes the requirement for rapid deployment;&nbsp; Savvis is attempting to guarantee &nbsp;rapid client-to-client cross-connect provisioning, with a deployment completion target of within 48 hours when the service is ordered via the SavvisStation portal</p>
<p>This is one of those perfectly obvious things that every large scale coclo and hosting services vendor should be providing. While a goal of using cloud services is to be able to not worry where the actual services reside, that&rsquo;s proven to be a somewhat elusive task. Weekly reports of even the largest service providers facing outages have to make customers think twice about where the service they contract for is being hosted. Especially given the degree of finger pointing that seems to occur when problems do crop up.</p>
<p>By promoting the other services running within the environment they control, Savvis would take the heat for any outages; giving their customers the proverbial &ldquo;one throat to choke&rdquo; for infrastructure issues. So making this service model available not only promotes customers of Savvis but also shows them taking a stand for the reliability of their underlying infrastructure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013285</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-the-business-impact-of-it-7000013285/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[What is the business impact of IT?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[What's the real business impact of information technology? What is the real cost when a workload slows down or fails?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:18:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Dan Kusnetzky]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Business executives increasingly wish to understand this impact, but, unfortunately, the knowledge and experience about the causes of slow downs or failures is not held by the same people who focus on business issues such as the loss of revenues, increase in costs or the loss of customers.</p>
<p>Although executives want to be able to quickly learn how a slow-down or outage impacts the company's revenues and intangibles such as customer satisfaction. Quick actionable answers aren't always easily created. Items such as the cost of the outage in terms of revenues, shipments, retail sales and the like require delving into both business and operational data. Teasing out the actual costs and value of lost opportunities often requires a team of people from different parts of the organization.</p>
<p>Today's management software technology has only recently developed the ability to sift through operational data, make decisions about what is happening in real time and then project the business impact. This type of technology is known generally as "predictive analytics for IT." It may also be discussed as using machine intelligence to address this complex problem.</p>
<p>It is clear that it has become time for IT decision-makers to embrace IT analytics and be able to easily understand the full impact their systems and solutions have on the business.</p>
<p>If you're interested in a quick analysis of this issue and potential solutions, I've recently released a paper focused on the business impact of IT. It can be found <a href="http://kusnetzky.net/publications/ImpactPapers/20130319%20Do%20You%20Know%20the%20Business%20Impact%20of%20IT%20final.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>, if you'd like a free copy.</p>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: this paper was sponsored by a Kusnetzky Group client.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013280</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/bb10-on-the-z10-is-making-me-a-blackberry-fan-again-7000013280/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[BB10 on the Z10 is making me a BlackBerry fan again]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[I have never been a die hard BlackBerry user, but a couple years ago the PlayBook and Bold 9930 combo appealed to me. It looks like the fresh UI and usefulness of BlackBerry 10 may be grabbing hold of me again.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Matthew Miller]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-blackberry/">BlackBerry</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="BB10 on the Z10 is making me a BlackBerry fan again" alt="BB10 on the Z10 is making me a BlackBerry fan again" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013280/bbz10-200x166.jpg?hash=Mwt1AwAwZJ&upscale=1" height="166" width="200"></figure>
<p>The BlackBerry Z10 is now available from AT&amp;T, T-Mobile, and Verizon here in the US. A couple years ago I <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/cell-phones/becoming-a-blackberry-fan-when-its-not-cool-to-do-so/6377">became a BlackBerry fan</a> due to the PlayBook and Bold 9930 combo. It looks like it's happening again as I just ordered another PlayBook and am thoroughly enjoying the Z10 experience. My love of the underdogs, including Windows Phone, BlackBerry, and HTC, continues.</p>
<p>I've been using a US GSM model of the Z10 for over a month and just received the <a href="http://shop.crackberry.com/blackberry-transform-hard-shell/4A123A13567.htm">red BB Transform Shell</a> case I ordered to go along with the device. I previously tested out the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-accessories-roundup-review-7000012982/">black Transform Shell case</a> and like the red one even better. My wife commented that it looks like Darth Maul's case due to the black and red color scheme. It offers decent protection, adds minimal size, and gives me a way to prop up the Z10 and enjoy video content.</p>
<p>I have a few devices to use with T-Mobile, including the Galaxy Note II and Nokia N9. The Note II is an extremely powerful device, but it is also a rather large device and it ends up on my desk and in my bag more than in my pocket. The Z10 works well with a single hand and has been in my pants pocket and with me quite a bit over the past couple of weeks.</p>
<p>However, it's not just an issue of size. The BlackBerry Z10 UI appeals to me, especially the BlackBerry Hub and peek functionality. I am finding that I prefer the simple way various forms of communications appear in the Hub rather than jumping in and out of apps or special notification areas.</p>
<p>I have many apps loaded on the Z10, there are great apps released almost daily now too, however I am finding that BlackBerry 10 has most of what I need built into the device and the powerful web browser lets me get things done when apps are not available. The apps that are available work well on the Z10 and the MeeGo-like multi-tasking screen lets me work very efficiently. Take an honest look at what apps are truly essential on a daily basis and you may just find those 10-15 apps are available on the Z10.</p>
<p>BlackBerry has a long ways to go, but they did have a rather <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-q4-better-than-expected-1m-blackberry-z10-devices-shipped-7000013220/">successful Q4</a> when the Z10 was only shipping in a few select countries. With the Z10 now available in the US and the Q10 coming in April, I look forward to hearing about more success from BlackBerry in the next financial period.</p>
<p>I plan to stick with the Z10 on T-Mobile exclusively if I can for the next month and give it a serious test. You need to spend dedicated time with devices for long periods of time to judge whether or not it can work well in your life.</p>
<p>I find the UI to be <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/nokia-meego-fans-will-appreciate-ui-elements-of-blackberry-10-7000010634/">much like MeeGo was</a>, but Nokia dropped MeeGo as soon as it was released and we can rest assured that BlackBerry is all in with the Z10 and BlackBerry 10. Actually, BlackBerry's strategy and dedication to succeed with BlackBerry 10 give me more confidence than Microsoft and its Windows Phone strategy. As a result, I think BlackBerry may just retain its current third place and increase in market share faster than Windows Phone.</p>
<p><strong>Related stories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-aims-to-show-it-can-keep-popular-apps-updated-7000013276/">BlackBerry aims to show it can keep popular apps updated</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-us-release-week-is-there-enough-in-bb10-to-attract-new-buyers-7000013123/">BlackBerry Z10 US release week: Is there enough in BB10 to attract new buyers?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-accessories-roundup-review-7000012982/">BlackBerry Z10 accessories roundup (review)</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-is-an-efficient-communications-focused-device-7000011793/">BlackBerry Z10 is an efficient communications-focused device</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-q4-lives-to-die-another-day-7000013239/">BlackBerry Q4: Lives to die another day?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-daily-driver-thanks-to-these-10-apps-and-shortcuts-screenshot-gallery-7000011780/">BlackBerry Z10: Daily driver, thanks to these 10 apps and shortcuts</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-10-and-the-z10-10-things-i-like-and-5-things-i-dont-7000010757/">BlackBerry 10 and the Z10: 10 things I like and 5 things I don't</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-10-is-the-first-blackberry-to-fully-support-byod-7000010717/">BlackBerry 10 is the first BlackBerry to fully support BYOD</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-daily-driver-thanks-to-these-10-apps-and-shortcuts-screenshot-gallery-7000011780/">BlackBerry Z10: Daily driver thanks to these 10 apps and shortcuts (screenshot gallery)</a></p>
</li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013284</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/its-about-frickin-time-u-s-gov-requires-security-review-for-chinese-tech-purchases-7000013284/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[It's about frickin' time: U.S. gov requires security review for Chinese tech purchases]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[We have been letting the fox guard the hen house for far too long, and it's high time the U.S. government did something about it.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:56:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[David Gewirtz]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government/">Government</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-china/">China</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you look out the window, you might notice that the moon is blue. If you check the Weather Channel, reports are that hell has indeed frozen over. As unlikely as it may seem, our politicians have apparently done something right.</p>
<p>In order for America's government to fund its operations, programs, and agencies, money has to be allocated for this purpose on a regular basis. In many years, that budget money is allocated through something called a "continuing resolution," that's passed in Congress and signed by the President.</p>
<p>A continuing resolution passed this year as well, except this time it had some teeth, in particular when it comes to China's ongoing acts of apparent espionage and skulduggery.</p>
<p>Put simply, the newly signed 240-page law requires law enforcement authorities to be consulted and perform a cybersecurity and sabotage risk assessment when buying IT gear.</p>
<p>Here's the hot button, the once-in-a-blue-moon, hell-freezing-over smart move by our politicians. The formal risk assessment by law enforcement must (and I'm quoting the <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/28/us-usa-cybersecurity-espionage-idUSBRE92Q18O20130328">Reuters article</a> quoting the bill): "...include any risk associated with such system being produced, manufactured or assembled by one or more entities that are owned, directed or subsidized by China."</p>
<p><strong>This. Is. Huge.</strong></p>
<p>I'm not going to go over the whole China risk thing in-depth here because we've been down this trail before. See the links at the end of the article for a good set of reads on China's apparent inability to play well with others.</p>
<p>But I will say this: China, by all indications, wants it both ways. They want to sell us gear, bring our currency into their country, and grow their economy with the help of American purchasing power. But they also seem to want to sneak into our computer systems, constantly testing, probing, and attacking our networks, and otherwise cause us harm.</p>
<p><strong>They want to make money from us at the same time they're willing to attack us.</strong></p>
<p>What's been deeply disturbing me for years (and I've been writing about this here, <a href="http://ac360.blogs.cnn.com/2009/04/10/is-china-friend-or-foe/">on CNN</a>, and even giving lectures and advisories on this to government officials) is that Chinese gear is inside everything we use today.</p>
<p>The motherboard inside the computer I'm using right now was made in China. In fact, the computer I'm using right now was made in China. Your iPhone was assembled in China.</p>
<p>In fact, many of the internal components and entire computers (Lenovo on its way to becoming the world's largest PC producer) are made in China. Telecommunications equipment is made in China. We even did a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/huawei-should-you-put-it-in-your-data-center/10107066/closing-statement/">Great Debate</a> here on ZDNet about whether it was wise to buy networking gear from Chinese Huawei, who has been involved in some dubious doings (and is becoming a major vendor of smartphones as well).</p>
<p>Think back to the cold war days when the Soviets and the Americans where banging shoes at each other and threatening total nuclear destruction. Would any of us (or our grandparents, I guess) have thought it made sense to buy security gear from the Soviets?</p>
<p>Of course not. Even the most pacifist peaceniks around would have thought that letting your enemy provide your security wasn't exactly a wise course.</p>
<p>And yet that's what we've been doing. Nearly all of us rely on gear made by China. Nearly all our personal and confidential passwords and logins travel over circuits made by China. Many of our networks and network switches, if not made by China directly, have Chinese components.</p>
<p>We have been letting the fox guard the hen house for far too long, and it's high time the U.S. government did something about it. I applaud this action by Congress and the President (did you <em>ever</em> think I'd ever say anything like that?), and encourage the government to take even more stringent action and due-diligence against foreign-supplied security equipment.</p>
<p><strong>ZDNet Government China coverage:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/questionable-loyalties-the-cybersecurity-implications-of-buying-system-software-from-foreign-companies/11276">Questionable loyalties: the cybersecurity implications of buying system software from foreign companies</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/huawei-should-you-put-it-in-your-data-center/10107066/closing-statement/">Great Debate - Huawei: Should you put it in your data center?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/it-might-be-time-to-throw-some-salt-on-china-7000011521/">It might be time to throw some SALT on China</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/state-of-the-union-cyberthreat-7000011248/">State of the Union: Cyberthreat</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/14-global-cybersecurity-challenges-for-2013-7000009352/">14 global cybersecurity challenges for 2013</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dear-china-cut-out-the-sneaky-spying-shenanigans-7000005623/">Dear China: Cut out the sneaky spying shenanigans</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/hack-in-the-box-researcher-reveals-ease-of-huawei-router-access-7000005600/">Researcher reveals ease of Huawei router access </a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/u-k-to-probe-huawei-bt-relationship-over-security-concerns-7000005616/">U.K. to probe Huawei, BT relationship</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/did-chinese-security-firm-snag-too-many-american-security-secrets-before-the-barn-door-closed/11008">Did Chinese security firm snag too many American security secrets before the barn door closed?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/in-china-many-younger-military-leaders-view-america-as-the-ultimate-enemy/9517">In China, many younger military leaders view America as the ultimate enemy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/is-china-gearing-up-to-start-world-war-iii/9368">Is China gearing up to start World War III?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/welcome-to-the-new-cold-war-china-vs-the-united-states/10289">Welcome to the new Cold War: China vs. the United States</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/dear-mrs-clinton-whether-you-believe-it-or-not-china-is-a-threat-to-america/10380">Dear Mrs. Clinton: whether you believe it or not, China is a threat to America</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/us-finally-acknowledges-chinese-and-russian-cyberthreat/10971">U.S. finally acknowledges Chinese and Russian cyberthreat</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/video-should-americans-worry-about-a-chinese-cyber-threat/10760">Video: Should Americans worry about a Chinese cyber-threat?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/pace-university-forensics-expert-on-china-and-cybercrime-exclusive-video/11187">Pace University forensics expert on China and cybercrime (exclusive video)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/technology-policy-challenges-faced-by-the-u-s-federal-government-video-seminar/11029">Technology policy challenges faced by the U.S. Federal Government (video seminar)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/deconstructing-a-nasty-chinese-world-of-warcraft-phishing-scheme/10952">Deconstructing a nasty Chinese World of Warcraft phishing scheme</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/why-the-united-states-might-pay-china-before-we-pay-our-own-soldiers/10588">Why the United States might pay China before we pay our own soldiers</a></li>
<li><strong>Also see:</strong> There are chapters covering China in my book, <em>How To Save Jobs</em> (<a href="http://howtosavejobs.org">free PDF download</a>)</li>
<li><strong>And, for balance, from ZDNet Asia:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cn/dear-america-enough-with-the-china-bashing-already-7000006044/">Dear America: Enough with the China-bashing already</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013094</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/worst-pitch-of-the-month-qpid-me-and-sharing-std-results-via-text-7000013094/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Worst pitch of the month: Qpid.me and sharing STD results via text]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[This month's roundup of terrible PR pitches include using Facebook to find out if a spouse is cheating and "the cubicle walk of shame."]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month, we started a new column here on <em>ZDNet</em> dedicated to the worst pitches we receive from PR reps.</p>
<p>At first I was a little nervous at how this featurette would be received, but turns out a lot of my PR friends spread the word via email and Twitter -- either out of entertainment or as a warning to their colleagues.</p>
<p>Either way, let's continue as there will likely never be a shortage of fodder for this topic. The 194 voicemails on my phone can attest to that.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/worst-pitch-of-the-month-plantronics-and-the-mass-employee-wedding-7000011145/">Worst pitch of the month: Plantronics and the mass employee wedding</a></p>
<p>In February, the overwhelming theme that strung most of our winners together was Valentine's Day. Honestly, I don't see how business technology and romance mix in any plausible way. Perhaps I should give more credit to PR professionals for trying -- but really they were just trying too hard.</p>
<p>With <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/sxsw-interactive-2013-trade-show-favorites-7000012578/">South by Southwest</a> earlier in March, naturally there was a deluge of pitches each day.</p>
<p>(For reference, while I typically receive many story ideas and press releases each day in my inbox, it tends to downpour at certain times of year, such as the holiday season and the few weeks leading up to CES in January.)</p>
<p>Considering SxSW attracts a wide range of interests and characters itself, there's not much room for surprise when it comes to just how ridiculous some of the story pitches were.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, one should never underestimate how outlandish (not to mention inappropriate) some of these emails can get.</p>
<p>Here's the worst (or maybe just creepiest) one, by far:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Is South by Southwest (SXSW) the new Spring Break for Emerging Tech Geeks? The must have mobile technology for SXSW isn&rsquo;t a festival guide or chat/photo feature &ndash; it&rsquo;s a new website that allows you to verify and check someone&rsquo;s STD status on your mobile phone &ndash; Qpid.me. *Qpid.me is a free website for people who wants to privately share their verified STD results with anyone via text message or online*. </em></p>
<p><em>Geeks love it! It&rsquo;s a known fact that there is a huge amount of "Sex" that happens at SXSW as creators, indie film makers, up-and-coming stars flock there to spark ideas, find investors, create together and&hellip;have sex. The panel sessions on Sex and Creativity tend to be most popular. But is the free love of the festival worth the after effects of coming home with an unwanted gift like some Spring Breakers, an STD? </em></p>
<p><em>If you would like to speak to the creator of Qpid.me &ndash; Ramin Bastani, please let us know!</em></p>
<p>[REDACTED]</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's not that such a service isn't useful. Certainly, it's a good idea to discuss things with a partner, and this potentially removes some of the embarrassment factor.</p>
<p>But besides potentially surpassing the boundaries of mobile notifications, all the spring break/SxSW/tech geek references are all just a bit much -- especially considering, once again, this doesn't relate to business and enterprise technology at all.</p>
<p>(Or at least not on the surface, but I digress...)</p>
<p>I also feel that I should include a few honorable mentions -- albeit they are not SxSW-related. However, this is more of a subcategory for the worst email subject lines.</p><p>Or perhaps I should rephrase that as the best worst subject lines because while they certainly caught my attention, the rest of the text was drab if not a complete letdown.</p>
<p>Here are two for your enjoyment and ridicule:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Subject line: <strong>Facebook, Is My Wife Cheating On Me?</strong></p>
<p><em>Facebook&rsquo;s social search via Graph has put the first nails in the coffin of multiple industries. It threatens to make marketing agencies, detectives, lawyers and more obsolete. Graph tells you the intersection of people, places, photos and interests from a billion members. The outcomes are very different than googling someone since you are getting references rather than simple look ups. </em></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Graph&rdquo; is a computer science term for traversing data structures, not just up and down but in any direction. </em></p>
<p><em>Facebook Graph users (marketers, jealous spouses, potential employers) could potentially search your past or potential whereabouts, activities, opinions and &ldquo;friends.&rdquo; When using search engines people tend to believe the results as &ldquo;fact&rdquo; or &ldquo;news.&rdquo; The now famous State Farm, &ldquo;Where&rsquo;d you hear that?&rdquo; commercial is a spoof on what happens when fact meets opinion. </em></p>
<p><em>I put Graph to the test on two highly talked about items last month. I asked who would win Grammy&rsquo;s &ldquo;Best New Artist.&rdquo; The result &ldquo;Scotty McCreery&rdquo; (posted here) is a miss because he wasn&rsquo;t nominated in 2013 though many people &ldquo;like&rdquo; him. I then asked who would win Best Picture for the Oscars (Academy Awards, I tried several variations), with oddly no results at all. Interpreting the results is too much like Fortunetelling. The system has the potential for sowing doubt without enough facts. </em></p>
<p><em>The implication is that we must give up more of our privacy to make Graph accurate or take ourselves completely &ldquo;off the grid.&rdquo; Cheating spouses and Grammy winners aside, the evolution of Social Search outlines new job opportunities just as the first Internet search engines did. </em></p>
<p><em>I am Lawrence I. Lerner (President LLBC, LLC) a recognized and published change agent. Last year I co-wrote &lsquo;Facebook for Your Business.&rsquo; In this book I predicted the release of this latest feature in the world of Social Commerce. It&rsquo;s my prediction that information privacy will be an important platform of the next presidential election. </em></p>
<p><em>Please let me know if you are interested in an interview and I will plan accordingly. </em></p>
<p><em>Sincerely, </em></p>
<p><em>Lawrence</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Subject line: <strong>The Cubicle Walk of Shame</strong></p>
<p><em>Yahoo! has stunned the nation by its decision to no longer allow employees to work from home. Is their justification really about efficiency or is it merely a way to micro-manage? Tim Houlne and Terri Maxwell, authors of The New World of Work: From the Cube to the Cloud, offer a unique perspective on this highly controversial topic. They are phenomenal speakers and make entertaining guests. </em></p>
<p><em>Please read the following press release and let me know if I may schedule an interview with either Tim or Terri that is sure to be of interest to your audience. Thank you. </em></p>
<p><em>[REDACTED]</em></p>
<p><em>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE </em></p>
<p><em>The Cubicle Walk of Shame </em></p>
<p><em>Irving, TX, March 13, 2013 - In one of the most stunning, non-progressive moves seen from a technology company, Yahoo! has banned working from home. The justification was to improve speed and quality by working side-by-side as one. This begs the question &ndash; is the issue really virtual work or the lack of good management coupled with an inability to capitalize on the virtual work environment? </em></p>
<p><em>There is a New Currency: </em></p>
<p><em>The truth is that the new currency for top tier talent is freedom. These people came to the realization long ago that gold-watch retirements are a thing of the past, and to ensure a long-term career meant taking matters into their own hands. Since the benefits offered by corporations such as insurance and paid vacations are not part of this new world of work, freedom and flexibility became the desirable traits. </em></p>
<p><em>Spend the New Currency with Better Management: </em></p>
<p><em>Progressive companies attract creative, productive talent with the way they &ldquo;manage people,&rdquo; which truthfully is not to manage people at all. Rather than buy into the &ldquo;productivity can only be seen&rdquo; mode of thinking, companies that embrace the virtualization of work product attract that always sought after motivated self-starter. </em></p>
<p><em>To capitalize on this new work currency, companies must: </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Manage the process and outcome, not the people. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Utilize more peer to peer management to encourage collaboration. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Invest in cloud technology to manage projects. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Understand virtual collaboration both from a technology and communication standpoint in order to get the best ideas. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Physical presence does not improve creativity. Creative people engaged in the idea and committed to a solid outcome do. </em></p>
<p><em>$2 Bills Seemed Like a Good Idea at the Time: </em></p>
<p><em>Forcing people to return to a cubicle breeds a level of mistrust. Obviously those who have enjoyed the freedom of virtual work environments will feel that they are not empowered to perform their job on their own. The top tier talent won&rsquo;t make the cubicle walk of shame. They will simply find another place to commit their talents. Only those who feel they do not have a choice will succumb.</em></p>
</blockquote>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013282</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/apples-new-iphone-wraparound-display-no-buttons-7000013282/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Apple's new iPhone? Wraparound display, no buttons]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A new patent filed by Apple shows us how future smartphones may look.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:48:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="apple iphone patent design flexible display" alt="apple iphone patent design flexible display" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013282/appleiphone-620x358.jpg?hash=AQtkLmRmMQ&upscale=1" height="358" width="620"></figure>
<p>Could a future iPhone feature a wraparound display?</p>
<p>According to a new patent filed by Apple, <a href="http://appft1.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;r=29&amp;p=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;d=PG01&amp;S1=%28apple.AS.+AND+20130328.PD.%29&amp;OS=an/apple+and+pd/3/28/2013&amp;RS=%28AN/apple+AND+PD/20130328%29">patent application 20130076612</a>, a potential smartphone design could include a full wraparound display and have no buttons. Enclosed within "transparent housing," a flexible display panel would be configured to display content at any portion of the gadget's frame.</p>
<p>The patent application explains:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The majority of portable electronic device manufacturers utilize a common form factor consisting generally of a flat planar form factor with a single surface dedicated mainly for use as a display surface, while the other surfaces remain largely unused, save for the occasional button or switch."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Potentially, the smartphone could contain up to two AMOLED screens. Standing for Active Matrix OLED -- these types of screen pair a traditional TFT display with an OLED display. Due to their active matrix, AMOLED screens have faster pixel switching, which means that response types are higher than OLED displays. The use of AMOLED and a conical shape for the flexible panel could offer users "an illusion of depth perception [...] mimicking a 3D experience."</p>
<p>In addition, the patent explains that facial recognition technology could be used to detect a registered end-user of the smartphone.</p>
<p>The aim of the new design is to make use of "unused space" which is typical with any current mobile device, extending functionality to both the back and the sides of a gadget. Therefore, Apple may be considering the use of curved screens and a flexible display which not only is touch-responsive, but makes use of the surface on both sides of a future iPhone.</p>
<p>The patent proposes that touch replace buttons entirely -- and a coating could be added to the display to reduce smudge marks and keep the gadget looking pretty. As an example, the application says that "Instead of the hold button a multi touch gesture along one of the sides could instead act as a method of locking and unlocking the hold function."</p>
<p>The new design relies heavily on flexible display technology, but in order to limit the possibility of damage, the patent describes the phone as being incased in glass -- bent into a conical shape, but serving as protection in case you drop your gadget. With such advances being made in the smartphone industry -- and the market already crowded with operating systems, similar phone designs and application ecosystems -- perhaps Apple's move into flexible displays could help the firm keep its dominant position.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
