<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:s="http://www.zdnet.com/search" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
    <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
    <description>Latest Blog for ZDNet</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>ZDNet</copyright>
    <managingEditor>customerservice@zdnet.com (ZDNet Customer Services)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>uk-engineering@cbsinteractive.com (ZDNet Webmaster)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:51:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>2</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://i.zdnet.com/images/spry/zdnet_300x300.jpg</url>
      <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
      <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
      <width>143</width>
      <height>39</height>
    </image>
    <s:counts>
      <start>0</start>
      <return>20</return>
      <found>42240</found>
    </s:counts>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014143</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/the-netbook-may-not-be-dead-yet-intel-talks-200-300-touch-enabled-bay-trail-laptops-7000014143/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[The netbook may not be dead yet: Intel talks $200-$300 touch-enabled Bay Trail laptops]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[During its Q1 earnings call, Intel execs discussed thin notebooks using the forthcoming Atom platform being available by the holiday season at a bargain price. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:45:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Sean Portnoy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-laptops/">Laptops</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="intel-atom-bay-trail-mobile-chip-processor-cpu_220" alt="intel-atom-bay-trail-mobile-chip-processor-cpu_220" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014143/intel-atom-bay-trail-mobile-chip-processor-cpu220-200x160.jpg?hash=A2V3MJIwZm&upscale=1" height="160" width="200"></figure>
<p>Don't bury the netbook yet. That seemed to be the message Intel delivered during <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-q1-good-enough-company-remains-upbeat-7000014097/" target="_self">its first quarter earnings call</a>, when CEO Paul Otellini and CFO Stacy Smith talked up the forthcoming Bay Trail Atom platform as the core of a series of cheap, touch-enabled laptops.</p>
<p>Bay Trail, the Atom system-on-a-chip that's due later this year, has been viewed as the <a href="http://newsroom.intel.com/community/intel_newsroom/blog/2013/02/24/intel-accelerates-mobile-computing-push" target="_blank">next-generation Intel architecture for tablet PCs</a>, but the company appears to have other designs for the SoC as well. During the earnings call (<a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/1346081-intel-s-ceo-discusses-q1-2013-results-earnings-call-transcript" target="_blank">transcribed by Seeking Alpha</a>), Smith stated the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[B]ecause of Bay Trail coming into the marketplace, you’ll see touch-enabled thin notebooks with really good performance that are hitting kind of $300 price points.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Otellini followed up with this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you look at touch-enabled Intel based notebooks that are ultrathin and light using non-core processors, those prices are going to be down to as low as $200 probably.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Given the widespread belief that the netbook -- just the type of cheap, thin, laptop Otellini is describing --<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/netbook-to-die-off-2015-says-isuppli-7000013956/" target="_self"> is on the way out</a>, this would seem to fly in the face of market trends. Then again, the system Intel is talking about may not be your father's netbook. Bay Trail is based on the 22nm manufacturing process, which means lower power consumption and improved battery life. It also will double the number of processing cores from two to four and include the Intel HD 4000 graphics in current Ivy Bridge processors to improve performance. (See more details <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/leaked-intel-atom-bay-trail-t-roadmap-details-next-gen-tablet-soc-processors-7000007597/" target="_self">here</a>.)</p>
<p>Of course, these are limited statements that tell us little about Intel's plans. Still, they are provocative, given the pricing issues that are dogging the PC industry and Intel's own Ultrabook platform. Are $200 to $300 laptops with more power than a netbook realistic for the holiday season? Let us know your thoughts in the Talkback section below.</p>
<p>[<a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/1346081-intel-s-ceo-discusses-q1-2013-results-earnings-call-transcript" target="_blank">Seeking Alpha</a> via <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/04/17/intel-bay-trail-200/" target="_blank">Engadget</a>. Image: <a href="https://ru.intel.com/business/community/?automodule=blog&amp;blogid=7605&amp;showentry=3925" target="_blank">ru.intel.com</a>]</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014089</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/gadget-boosts-mobile-phone-signals-7000014089/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Gadget boosts mobile phone signals]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The latest small-business bundle in the zBoost product line includes an upgrade device that adds 4G data coverage capabilities.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Heather Clancy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="DataBlast setup" alt="DataBlast setup" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014089/datablast-setup-200x183.png?hash=AzIwBQDmZQ&upscale=1" height="183" width="200"></figure>
<p>No matter how quickly the big wireless carriers move to upgrade their networks, there are times we could all do with a little boost.</p>
<p>That's the value proposition promised by<a href="http://zboostyourlife.wi-exblog.com/about-2/"> Wi-Ex</a>, creator of the <a href="http://www.wi-ex.com/homeOffice.aspx">zBoost mobile phones signal extender series</a>, designed to prevent dropped calls and speed up sluggish data connections. Or, frankly, to help your cell phone work better while you're inside your home or small-business office.</p>
<p>The latest addition, called zBoost SOHO, is a bundle that creates a Cell Zone for multiple users and devices that operate on the 800 and 1900 megahertz (MHz) frequency bands (exceptions include the Nextel/iDEN, 4G and 2100 MHz phones).</p>
<p>The device boosts indoor signal coverage by up to 3,000 square feet, and it can help extend the battery life of your phone (because it won't have to work so hard when the signal is stronger).</p>
<p>The bundle, which typically lists for $649, also comes with an upgrade component that covers 4G services from Verizon, AT&amp;T and T-Mobile. (You have to pair the upgrade with the base 2G/3G booster component.)</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014027</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/avaya-aims-to-boost-ip-multicast-methods-with-new-network-fabric-7000014027/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Avaya aims to boost IP multicast methods with new network fabric]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Avaya contributes to the fabric networking buzz with a new option that should support up to tens of thousands of video streams versus just hundreds previously.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-centers/">Data Centers</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-management/">Data Management</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-unified-comms/">Unified Comms</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Avaya</strong> is the latest networking player to throw its submission into the growing ring of fabric networking solutions debuting this week.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dell-intros-new-sdn-fabric-for-data-economics-architectures-7000014024/">Dell intros new SDN fabric for data economics, architectures</a> | <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/avaya-taps-emc-vmware-for-speeding-up-cloud-connections-7000013738/">Avaya taps EMC, VMware for speeding up cloud connections</a></p>
<p>Announced amid the Open Network Summit in Santa Clara, Calif. this week, Avaya reps described that <strong>VENA Fabric Connect</strong> is designed to deliver network services from datacenters to the desktop while enabling a more agile network.</p>
<p>Sounds straightforward enough, but the key is differentiating this from a pack of new network fabric technologies rolling out.</p>
<p>Many of Silicon Valley's old guard businesses have been turning toward open technologies, in particular, to handle unified communications as well as big data -- much like we've seen recently with Hadoop and open source software. <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/ibm-spills-more-about-hadoop-strategy-with-new-puredata-system-7000013293/">Just look at IBM</a>, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intel-baking-apache-hadoop-into-silicon-for-big-data-security-uses-7000011802/">Intel</a>, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/emc-launches-hadoop-distribution-takes-aim-at-cloudera-7000011701/">and EMC</a>, for starters.</p>
<p>The main theme of Avaya's new fabric release could be summed up as "out with the old, in the with the new" being that VENA is intended to enable businesses to gradually phase out legacy infrastructures in favor of a unified, end point provisioning infrastructure.</p>
<p>One of Avaya's approaches is touting one of its new releases, the VSP 4000, as the "industry&rsquo;s first" fabric-enabled multi-service and multi-tenant edge device, which is supposed connect up the dots from the VENA fabric across an entire network to remote offices, whether it be at mid-market enterprises or for hosting providers.</p>
<p>With these back-end solutions in play, that's where Avaya is inserting its core unified communications products.</p>
<p>For example, Avaya touted that with the VENA Fabric Connect, IP Multicast protocols should then be able to support up to tens of thousands of video streams versus just hundreds previously with sub-second failover times rather than seconds or minutes.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014140</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/advice-for-struggling-pc-software-vendors-7000014140/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Advice for struggling PC software vendors]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[If your business is struggling, more and more of the same ol', same ol' isn't going to suddenly give you a lift. You need to make a few changes (and fortunately, they're not all that hard or costly) or the vicious cycle will continue.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 10:45:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[David Gewirtz]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software-development/">Software Development</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Despite all the headlines where <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/mediatechnologyandtelecoms/9952658/British-teen-sells-Summly-app-for-millions.html">teenage app makers sell their barely pubescent products for millions</a>, being an independent software vendor -- especially in the old-school PC world -- is not an easy gig.</p>
<p>I'm talking especially about the makers of specialty PC software, particularly those who make what we used to call "utilities" or "power tools." In a world where <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/idc-global-pc-shipments-plunge-in-worst-drop-in-a-generation-7000013839/">PC sales drop precipitously</a>, and our operating system makers seem to be dumbing everything down to an Angry Birds least common denominator, makers of deep, rich, power tools are having some dog days.</p>
<p>These are the makers of the incredibly feature-rich text editor, developers of the screen capture program with 400 features, authors of the thumbnail viewer that's really a full digital asset manager, creators of the file copy program that has more features buried in its graphical UI than the Linux shell has in all its arcane commands, coders of the development environment that can do the craziest sorts of cross-platform live debugging.</p>
<p>Many of these vendors have been in business for a decade or more. They've been making money on one main piece of software and have continued to refine it, improve it, add customer-requested features, and chugged along, providing a unique value to a select set of customers with unique needs.</p>
<h3>You get the idea. Power tool software for power users.</h3>
<p>These companies don't sell their products to everyone. Here's an analogy. Most homeowners own a power drill. It might not get used much, but once in a while you might break it out. But few of us homeowners own a full drill press. After all, that's more like something you'd see in a shop rather than the typical home.</p>
<p>But some homeowners have home shops, and use drill presses, milling machines, and all sorts of customized tools. There's a market for these power tools. It's not just the same market that sells Hello Kitty powered screwdrivers.</p>
<p>Over the past month or so, I've been working on a big image workflow project, and so I've been looking at and discarding an entire array of power tool software. I go through these phases when I put on my power user hat, and try to optimize a solution for some sort of unique work problem or process.</p>
<p>During these phases, I often sift through a couple of dozen tools, looking at the problem from a wide variety of angles, and get to see some very slick, deep, special-purpose software.</p>
<p>The PC software industry also goes through its phases. It's had its ups and downs for decades now. There are times when there seems to be no end of opportunity and times (like now) when things seem particularly bleak and sales are down.</p>
<p>When the market is down, being a software company owner can be a rough, rough gig. There are often not quite enough new customers to support the workload, so something has to give. Often, it's the support staff that's the first to go, followed by good nights' sleep, and perspective.</p>
<p>If you're an owner/developer, you're struggling with trying to balance development time with support time with the time you devote to any other forms of income that are being used to prop up the business and pay bills.</p>
<p>If you're an owner, but reliant on a developer either as a partner or a contractor, things get even more worrisome, because somehow you have to keep the developer in pizza and caffeine, and keep him or her happy enough (and paid enough) so you can continue to keep your product evolving and on the market.</p>
<p>I know. I've been there.<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/apples-lost-decade-hypercard-and-what-might-not-have-been-if-apple-then-was-like-apple-is-today/10185"> I ran a company</a> that made and sold specialty software (in my case, plugins and embedded database technology) for over a decade, before I finally sold off my flagship product. I then wrote <em>The Flexible Enterprise</em> (<a href="http://usspi.org/download">free PDF download</a>), about how to transform a business model and create an agile business.</p>
<p>Before then, I was Symantec's director of product marketing. I've been on the board of the Software Entrepreneur's Forum (now SDForum), and in my subsequent decade as a publisher of online technology magazines, worked with hundreds of other software vendors. I even wrote 40 <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/true-confessions-of-a-former-iphone-developer-7000002761/">rather silly iPhone apps</a> and made a few bucks off that experience.</p>
<p>In other words: been there, done that. I think I'm reasonably qualified to give advice to the struggling PC software vendors out there. Now, I'm fully aware your situation is different, you have a plan, you know what you're doing, you don't have time, you know you should, but... look, I've given all those excuses. Like I said, been there, done that.</p>
<p>But the bottom line is simple. If your business is struggling, more and more of the same ol', same ol' isn't going to suddenly give you lift. You need to make a few changes -- and, fortunately, they're not all that hard or costly -- or the vicious cycle will continue.</p>
<p><strong>Roll up your sleeves. Let's get started...</strong></p><h3>Update and modernize your web site</h3>
<p>If there's one universal thing I've noticed in this power tool search, it's the really sorry state of web sites run by PC software vendors. Oh. My. Gosh.</p>
<p>These sites often look like they haven't been updated since 2002 or 2003, like they made a big push to get a product out for XP, but haven't really done much since then. It's clear products have been updated, because the release notes constantly show improvements and point releases every few months, but often the last "news" item in the news section is from 2008.</p>
<p>Often, the online documentation doesn't match the latest version number. The manual says it's for version 11 of the product, but the release notes indicate that version 15 is now out.</p>
<p>If there are video tutorials, they were often created pre-YouTube and are downloadable, low-res files, rather than embedded YouTube videos.</p>
<p>It's terrible. Despite all the work you put in each day holding things together, and the quiet desperation you live with in the dark of the night, it looks to all the world like you don't care about your products and your business. New customers who visit your site will click away almost instantly, because your site looks like one of those old, untouched, ghost town sites that live all over the Internet.</p>
<p>So here's my advice: if you're going to sell software in the Internet-age, you must (must, must, must -- more than anything else -- must) modernize your Web site.</p>
<p>This isn't hard to do. There are thousands of quite fine WordPress templates, hosting providers who can do complete Web site installs for a click of a button, plans that won't cost you more than ten bucks a month, and so forth. If you don't have the graphics design skill, use one of the pre-made templates.</p>
<p>In fact, I'll help you here as well. Here are some of the vendors I've used:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://ithemes.com/">iThemes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.elegantthemes.com/">Elegant Themes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://premium.wpmudev.org/">WPMUDev</a></li>
<li><a href="http://themeforest.net/">ThemeForest</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.pagelines.com/">PageLines</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I know this process could take a week or so you don't have, but trust me on this: if you don't do this soon, you'll have all the free weeks you want.</p>
<h3>Deal with your forums</h3>
<p>You know there's a problem when forums are populated with "Hello, is anyone here?" messages. It's particularly bad when the main web pages point customers to the forums for support, and the forums are populated with complaints that the company doesn't answer or brutal complaints about products, product strategy, updates, etc.</p>
<p>Here's a hint: if you can click into your forums and before you even scroll down, you can see a pile of "this company sucks" messages, you need to deal with your forums.</p>
<p>My advice (and this is my software company owner hat, not my transparency journalism hat) is to shut down those forums. Just kill them. I know there's a lot of knowledge trapped in there, but there's also a lot of bile you just don't want new customers to see.</p>
<p>Besides, your forum software probably also looks like it came from the days when Bill Clinton was President. It, too, probably needs a big face lift.</p>
<p>Many of the theme vendors I've suggested above also offer forum software, and there's also a ton of free downloads. Heck, <a href="https://www.phpbb.com/">phpBB</a>&nbsp;might be annoying, but it's free and looks at least like it came from a year with a "2" in it.</p>
<p>My other forum tip is this: check over your forums at least once a week. If you can't scan your forums, find someone (even your kid, your mom, that annoying but very loyal customer ... someone) who can look over the site and let you know when strongly negative posts need to be dealt with.</p>
<p>If you can, solve the problem or make good, don't just sweep those problems under the carpet. But no matter what, if you want to keep selling software, you can't have that sort of activity on your forums. It's the kiss of death.</p>
<h3>Scan for old dates</h3>
<p>While we're talking about the kiss of death, another sure-fire way to scare away new, prospective customers before you even know they came-and-went is to have lots of old dates on your site.</p>
<p>Seriously, if most dates on your site show 2009 or earlier, you're in trouble. It's okay to have release notes that end in 2013 and start back in 1999, but other than that, you really should make sure no date on your site is older than 2012 -- especially if its your software product.</p>
<p>I found one product in my search for a good media asset manager that listed its last update as 2005. Given the importance (to me, anyway) of my project, I couldn't take a chance on something that hadn't been updated since before Vista.</p>
<p><strong>Keep reading. Tough love is good for you...</strong></p><h3>Update your installers</h3>
<p>Another easy thing to do is update your installers. Even if the software you're installing is pretty much the same as you've been selling and updating for years, that installer that is sized for eight-character file names and likes to stick things in the root C:\ directory is going to seem completely anachronistic.</p>
<p>There are some great, free installers out there. I know it's another weekend's worth of work, but you do want to keep your company, don't you?</p>
<h3>Update your system requirements specs</h3>
<p>If the last OS listed in your system requirements is Vista, you have a problem. If you list NT in your system requirements, you have a bigger problem.</p>
<p>Test your product against Windows 7 and Windows 8, and then update your system requirements to explicitly call out that the product works on Windows 8. Don't worry about the idiotic "Metro" interface, but if you say you support the Windows 8 desktop (and you do), then your prospective customers won't think you've been in suspended animation since the Bush administration.</p>
<h3>Post a frickin' phone number</h3>
<p>Yeah, I know we're moving to a world where all interaction is online. But customers who want to buy stuff sometimes want to call and get an answer to a question right now.</p>
<p>I also know that posting a phone number is an invitation to your current customers to call, bitch you out, and ask you questions you can't answer, but that dialog is good, too. It'll reinforce to your customers that you're still there. Plus, you never know. That really loyal (if cranky customer) might just have a way to save your bacon -- simply because he needs your product as much as you do.</p>
<h3>Acquire some other products</h3>
<p>Most of the software tools vendors I've seen are one-trick ponies. They have their one product, and that's it. That means if you make a sale to a customer, you're done. There's no more money to be mined from that hole until you release a major update.</p>
<p>One great way to augment your income (and help maximize utilization of the business infrastructure you already have) is to acquire publishing rights for other programs. This isn't quite as easily done now as the days when distribution meant brick-and-mortar and manufacturing meant paying for packaging, but there are still a lot of talented programmers out there who don't want to do the administrivia.</p>
<p>Don't contract out to have something built. Instead, scour the Internet for great programs with poor descriptions, support, or web sites. Offer to publish those products, update the manual, sell them, and provide a royalty back of 15-30 percent after your cost.</p>
<p>You'll probably need a contract to do this, but don't go running to a lawyer. First, most lawyers don't know squat about the software business, and you'll wind up paying more for the contract than you'll make selling software. Instead, find another software vendor who isn't a direct competitor and ask them if they've got a publishing contract they don't mind you using.</p>
<p>Make friends with other software vendors. These sorts of mutual-support contacts are very helpful.</p>
<p>I know you may not think you can afford to acquire a product, but trust me, it can be done. In fact, I wrote two chapters on this phenomenon in two of my books. Read the first chapter in <em>The Flexible Enterprise</em> and read "Luck is a skill" in <em>How To Save Jobs</em>. Both are <a href="http://usspi.org/download">free downloads</a>, so there's no excuse not to.</p>
<p>An even easier approach (although a little less profitable) is to resell other existing products on your web store and in mailings to your existing customers. Find complementary (or even competing products) that would appeal to your class of customer, do a deal with the software vendor to resell it (you'll usually get 40 to 60 percent of the selling price).</p>
<p>Do yourself a favor and start this process now. An extra five or ten SKUs will do wonders for your incremental income.</p>
<h3>Know when to hold 'em, know when to fold 'em</h3>
<p>Finally, we're at the tough love stage of our discussion. Sometimes, it's just time.</p>
<p>Look, if your product really hasn't been updated since 2005, if you can only run on 32-bit XP, and you crash constantly on 64-bit systems or anything running Windows 7 or later, it may be time to throw in the towel. This dog won't hunt anymore.</p>
<p>There are lots of ways to get out of this hole, but all of them involve a change in business strategy. Again, I'll point you to some great reading. Read the third section of <a href="http://HowToSaveJobs.org">How To Save Jobs</a>. It will show you how to evaluate your assets and reinvent your business from the inside out.</p>
<h3>Live long and prosper</h3>
<p>I sometimes get the urge to go out and build another software product. I love to code and I actually love the entire chain of activity that is product marketing. But after more than two decades of running my own software and then publishing company, I also needed to get a life.</p>
<p>I was fortunate in that I was able to sell off my software assets back in the day, and have managed to transform my career so that I get to talk to you here on ZDNet, lecture, advise, and teach. I'm having more fun in my work life than I've ever had before, I get to spend time with my wife, enjoy my car, lift weights, and sometimes work on my house and hobbies.</p>
<p>The point is that there is life after software. While my advice here is intended to keep you in business, if that time comes, you should know that there <em>is</em> life after software entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>Good luck. Live long. And prosper.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014095</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/more-experiments-with-linux-only-uefi-secure-boot-installation-7000014095/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[More experiments with Linux-only UEFI Secure Boot installation]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[UEFI BIOS and Secure Boot work perfectly well with only Linux installed according to the experiments I have conducted on my own PC.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 09:00:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[J.A. Watson]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-open-source/">Open Source</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-operating-systems/">Operating Systems</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My recent series of posts concerning <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/how-i-installed-fedora-18-with-uefi-secure-boot-7000013464/" target="_self">UEFI and Secure Boot technology</a> has drawn several comments and questions about the possibility of installing only Linux on such a system.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I have just had to completely reload my HP Pavilion dm1-4310 system (don't ask), so before reloading Windows 8, I decided to take the opportunity to do a bit of testing.&nbsp; The results have been quite interesting and encouraging.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10118231" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>How I installed Fedora 18 with UEFI Secure Boot</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/how-i-installed-fedora-18-with-uefi-secure-boot-7000013464/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013464/fedora0-220x165.png?hash=MTR3LwSxMG&upscale=1" alt="How I installed Fedora 18 with UEFI Secure Boot" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/how-i-installed-fedora-18-with-uefi-secure-boot-7000013464/">How I installed Fedora 18 with UEFI Secure Boot</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/how-i-installed-fedora-18-with-uefi-secure-boot-7000013464/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>Before performing these installations, in order to ensure that there would be no "relics" left on the disk, I deleted all of the existing partitions. I also ensured that UEFI Boot and Secure Boot were enabled, and Legacy Support was disabled.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I made the installations from the standard openSuSE 12.3 and Fedora 18 ISO images, both of which are compatible with UEFI Secure Boot. I decided to do the testing in four steps - first, I installed only Fedora to the empty disk; then I wiped the disk again, and installed only openSuSE to the empy disk; then I reduced the size of the openSuSE partition to free up some space, and installed Fedora alongside openSuSE; finally, I wiped the disk again and reinstalled Windows 8 using the HP Recovery USB stick.</p>
<h3>Step One: Fedora 18 installation</h3>
<p>I specifically tried to let <em>anaconda</em> make a "default" installation, the only significant change that I made was to select "Standard Partitions" rather than LVM disk management.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Fedora was installed with five paritions; one was a FAT partition for EFI Boot, and the others were ext4 partitions for swap, root, home and boot. When I rebooted after the installation was complete, it booted Fedora with absolutely no problem, with UEFI Secure Boot still enabled. When I checked the UEFI boot configuration with <em>efibootmgr</em>, I found that it had cleared out all the old entries and made a single entry to boot Fedora via the shim EFI binary.</p>
<h3>Step Two: openSuSE 12.3 installation</h3>
<p>Once I was convinced that the Fedora 18 installation was working properly, I once again deleted all of the existing disk partitions, and installed openSuSE to the empty disk.&nbsp; The only change that I made this time was to correct the bootloader installation, from "grub2" to "grub2-efi" (the necessity for this is described in my prevoius post about <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/opensuse-uefi-secure-boot-installation-how-i-did-it-7000013311/"> Installing openSuSE 12.3 with UEFI</a>).&nbsp; This time the installer created four partitions (openSuSE does not create a separate /boot partition by default).</p>
<p>Once again the EFI boot configuration had been cleared but this time it had created two new entries, one for Secure Boot which pointed to the<strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong>shim EFI binary, and the other pointed to a grub EFI binary, which could be used when Secure Boot is disabled.&nbsp; When I rebooted after installation, with Secure Boot still enabled, openSuSE came up with no problem.</p>
<h3>Step Three: Adding Fedora to the existing openSuSE installation</h3>
<p>I reduced the size of the openSuSE home partition to make room for Fedora, then went through the normal Fedora installation.&nbsp; I once again let <em>anaconda</em> make a default installation, chaning only to Standard Partitions. Interestingly, <em>anaconda</em> created new partitions for both EFI boot and swap, even though there were existing partitions for both of those. If I had been doing a "normal" installation, I would have directed it to use the existing partitions for both of those.&nbsp;</p>
<p>When I checked the EFI Boot configuration, I saw that the installer had created an entry for Fedora, but the number was higher than the existing openSuSE entries. Sure enough, when I rebooted it came up with openSuSE so it was obviously booting the lowest numbered entry.&nbsp; I then deleted the openSuSE boot entries, using <em>efibootmgr</em>, and when I rebooted it came up with Fedora.</p>
<p>At this point I decided to do some experimenting with UEFI boot configuration - prevoiusly, with the standard HP Windows 8 configuration, any changes I made to the UEFI boot configuration were very unpredicable - some worked, some didn't, and some appeared to work for a while but then would suddenly be removed and it would return to the default configuration.&nbsp;</p>
<p>As a first small step, with the configuration containing only the Fedora boot information, I added a line for openSuSE with identification number 0000, so it became the first in the list.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Then I rebooted, and openSuSE came up.&nbsp; So far so good.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Then I removed both of the boot entries, and created them again, this time with Fedora first at number 0001, and openSuSE at number 0002.<em>&nbsp; </em>This also worked as I expected, when I rebooted it once again came up with Fedora.&nbsp; Finally, I rebooted and pressed F9 (Boot Select), and I could then select to boot either openSuSE or Fedora.</p>
<p>This is all very good news, it means that the erratic behavior I had previously seen, with EFI Boot configuration changes getting lost is indeed a result of some sort of special handling set up either by HP or Microsoft.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If I spent a lot more time experimenting and observing this I might be able to figure out specifically which one did it (or both), but I don't really care enough to fight with it any more. Suffice it to say, for those who want to know if Linux-only installation with UEFI boot is possible, the answer is yes.</p>
<h3>Step Four: Restore the original Windows 8 from the HP recovery media&nbsp;</h3>
<p>I removed the existing disk partitions again, so it was starting with an empty disk, and then booted the USB stick that HP support had sent me. The difference in time required here was really astounding.&nbsp; Installing either Fedora or openSuSE from scratch required less than 30 minutes, but the Windows 8 "recovery" has been running for over two hours now, and it is still not done.&nbsp; It just finally asked me for the user name and password, so at least it is getting close.&nbsp; Wow.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10118230" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignLeft"><h3>OpenSuSE 12.3: In-depth and hands-on</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/opensuse-12-3-in-depth-and-hands-on-7000012698/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/012698/opensuse-12-3-released-220x165.png?hash=MwxmLmt1BQ&upscale=1" alt="OpenSuSE 12.3: In-depth and hands-on" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/opensuse-12-3-in-depth-and-hands-on-7000012698/">OpenSuSE 12.3: In-depth and hands-on</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/opensuse-12-3-in-depth-and-hands-on-7000012698/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>Finally, I got a bit more evidence that someone is "fiddling with the knobs in the back" when Windows is installed. After the Windows installation finally finished, I reduced the size of the C: partition and installed openSuSE into the free space.&nbsp;</p>
<p>When that had finished, but before rebooting, I checked the EFI boot configuration again and as expected, I saw that it had added its usual two entries, one for Secure Boot and one for normal boot.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Unexpectedly, though, the Windows installation had created the entry for its Boot Loader with number 0002 (no idea why it did this, there was nothing else in the list at that time), and now openSuSE had created the non-secure entry with number 0001 and the Secure Boot entry with number 0003.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hmmm.&nbsp; If this works as I would expect it to, the system should now boot openSuSE.&nbsp;</p>
<p>But of course it didn't, when I rebooted it came up with Windows 8.&nbsp; I have no idea why - it certainly isn't because of the sequence of the numbers, and it isn't because of the BootOrder configuration, so there must be some kind of hidden priority for the Windows Boot Loader.&nbsp; Sigh.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014108</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/traveling-with-mobile-gear-follow-up-7000014108/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Traveling with mobile gear: Follow-up]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[I recently shared the small mobile kit I planned on using on a short trip. The trip is almost over and it's worth following up with thoughts on how well it worked, or didn't work, in different areas.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 09:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-4g/">4G</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ipad/">iPad</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-laptops/">Laptops</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-samsung/">Samsung</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="20130416_184526" alt="20130416_184526" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014108/20130416184526-200x113.jpg?hash=ZGD0Awp3AG&upscale=1" height="113" width="200"></figure>
<p>My trip to San Francisco is winding down, and I will be heading back to Houston by the time you see this. The gear in my bag was as small and light as any I've used on a trip, and for the most part it performed admirably.</p>
<p>I recently <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/got-my-traveling-shoes-on-and-unique-gear-in-the-bag-7000013633/">shared the kit I planned on taking</a> on the trip along with my reasoning for the choices. At the last minute I made one change, choosing to leave the iPad mini at home and bringing the bigger iPad with keyboard/case instead.</p>
<blockquote class="alignLeft">
<p><strong>It was interesting to note that of the roughly 20 attendees at this conference, seven of them were using iPads with keyboards in place of a laptop.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The collection of gadgets that accompanied me to San Francisco consisted of the Chromebook Pixel, iPad, and the Galaxy Note 2. That's all I brought and I used it all heavily.</p>
<p>The iPad in the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/profolio-from-zagg-best-keyboard-case-for-the-ipad-7000012504/">ZAGG Profolio+ keyboard case</a> was used each day at the conference I was attending. The days were long but the iPad's battery easily handled it. I only plugged the iPad into the wall in the hotel room at the end of the day.</p>
<p>Bringing the iPad instead of the iPad mini was a good substitution as it easily handled everything I needed in the meeting room each day. I kept up with all my online communications, writing duties, and everything else on the iPad.</p>
<p>The Chromebook Pixel was my main work system at night in the hotel room and worked fine. I did heavy work on the Pixel at night, as I was too busy at the conference during the day. I could have done the night work on the iPad, but the Chromebook Pixel was easier to use so I'm glad I brought it.</p>
<p>Both the iPad and Chromebook Pixel have integrated 4G LTE on the Verizon network. I had full signal strength on this network so it was lightning fast in San Francisco. It was so much faster than the hotel wi-fi at the conference that I used both devices on LTE the entire stay.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The only device I experienced problems with was the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/samsung-galaxy-note-2-big-enough-to-be-worth-the-trouble-7000010723/">Galaxy Note 2 </a>on the Sprint network. The primary problem was all Sprint's, as there was no 4G LTE network anywhere I went in San Francisco. This caused the phone to stay on the much slower 3G network, but even that didn't work well. I found the phone constantly dropping the 3G network, leaving me waiting to reconnect and continue. It was extremely aggravating.</p>
<p>The other problem I had I believe was due to a bug with the Note 2. Even though the phone immediately connected to the Sprint network when I arrived in San Francisco, it didn't make the location switch for geolocation. Anything I did with geolocation in San Franscisco, eg Foursquare, thought I was still in Houston.</p>
<p>I initially blamed Sprint for this failure to update my location but I now think it is a problem with the Note 2. After checking Sprint Note 2 user forums, I found it is a common problem with that phone on that network.</p>
<p>I ended up rebooting the Note 2 which triggered a location change, so it finally recognized I was in San Francisco when it came back up. I suspect I'll have to reboot it when I get back to Houston so it will figure out I'm no longer in San Francisco.</p>
<p>Overall I am happy with the gear I brought on the trip and how well it performed. I do wish the Sprint LTE network was active in San Franscisco. The 3G network was awfully slow at times, and the frequent network drops were annoying.</p>
<p>I could have gotten by with just the iPad but I'm glad I also had the Pixel with me. It made some things easier to do and didn't add much weight to the backpack. It was interesting to note that of the roughly 20 attendees at this conference, seven of them were using iPads with keyboards in place of a laptop.</p>
<p>The entire trip was successful and I accomplished everything I intended to do on the trip. I can attest that the Hotel Vitale in San Francisco is a nice hotel, although it doesn't have coffee in the rooms. That's a big negative for me personally so next trip I'll probably stay somewhere else.</p>
<p><strong>Related stories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-hands-on-photos-7000011694/">Chromebook Pixel hands on (photos)</a>&nbsp;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/the-chromebook-pixel-cost-me-a-lot-of-money-7000011711/">The Chromebook Pixel cost me a lot of money</a>&nbsp;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/macbook-pro-retina-display-vs-chromebook-pixel-on-video-7000011739/">MacBook Pro (Retina display) vs. Chromebook Pixel on video</a>&nbsp;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-spoiling-me-for-other-chromebooks-7000013287/">Chromebook Pixel: Spoiling me for other Chromebooks</a></p>
</li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014132</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/dells-new-latitude-3330-making-common-core-assessments-a-reality-7000014132/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Dell's new Latitude 3330 - Making Common Core assessments a reality]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Dell's new laptop for schools is slick. But what's much more interesting is how they envision it being used to support the latest generation of student assessments.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 07:47:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Christopher Dawson]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-dell/">Dell</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As many readers have pointed out, I haven't been posting as frequently as I used to. In fact, this is going to be one of my last stories on ZDNet Education as my career shifts and takes me in some new directions. It's appropriate then, that this story, related to <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dell-introduces-latitude-3330-laptop-for-students-and-small-businesses-7000014041/">Sean Portnoy's news</a> yesterday about Dell's new Latitude 3330 ultrabook for schools and small businesses, represents many aspects of what I've been advocating for over the last several years in this blog:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reasonable, standards-aligned assessments</li>
<li>Choice in technology, allowing schools to design hardware and software solutions that best meet their particular needs</li>
<li>Requirements first, then platform, then (and only then) hardware</li>
<li>Technology that solves problems for schools and enhances teaching and learning, rather than technology for the sake of technology.</li>
</ul>
<p>I've been a fan of Dell hardware for many years and have deployed more than my share of Dell machines. My current primary tablet is a Latitude 10 Essentials (their Windows 8 tablet targeted at schools). My geek heart is filled with gadget lust for their new XPS 18 super-tablet. I'm no fanboi, though. I'm typing this on an HP mobile workstation that rocks out loud and is my main computer. Various members of my family use everything from a Lenovo desktop to an Acer laptop to Chromebooks to Macbook Pros and I've had good luck with all of them (and more) in education settings. What really continues to impress me about Dell is how educational pain points are driving their products, services, and solutions, rather than simply shoehorning their existing enterprise stack into schools.</p>
<p>The Latitide 3330 is a great example. The aforementioned Latitude 10 is already a solid tool for schools and works well for 1:1, younger students, and teachers. However, the upcoming Common Core-aligned assessments being rolled out in many states in 2014, all of which are administered electronically, needs an easily-managed testing environment, especially in schools that can't afford 1:1 or extensive, elaborate labs. So Dell did a couple of things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Put together a team of former teachers and school CIOs that developed a framework for assessing district readiness for these exams</li>
<li>Made sure that schools could leverage existing hardware, tablets (including the Latitude 10) if it suited their situation, or low-cost, highly manageable laptops like the 3330</li>
<li>Outlined a use case with their new Mobile Computing Cart to support the new assessments with a turnkey mobile testing environment; schools where space, funds, or other resources are an issue can roll a set of the 3330's into a classroom or testing site, fully charged and centrally configured, potentially using Dell's simple KACE management tools to save time for IT and instructors.</li>
<li>Added cost-saving, performance-improving hardware like hybrid hard drives so students can get to work quickly and on hardware that schools can afford.</li>
</ul>
<p>If it sounds like I'm raving about Dell here, I am. Other OEMs should be following their lead in taking very realistic, hands-on, problem-driven approaches to student computing. For their part, schools shouldn't be rushing to make 1:1 happen at all costs (although I think most of us agree that 1:1 is both the ideal and the goal). I've seen schools lay off good teachers to fund technology implementations. However, when OEMs respect the real-world budget, time, and resource constraints facing most schools, then it becomes much easier for schools to find solutions for providing technology to students without sacrificing art, music, sports, or even entire teacher positions for the sake of technology that may end up underutilized anyway without the right training, use cases, and learning platforms.</p>
<p>Bottom line, the 3330 is great, but what's greater is that schools can make tablets available where appropriate, laptops can be available where physical keyboards are still necessary or 1:1 becomes cost-prohibitive, or desktops/thin clients can be deployed where lab space is easier to come by than money. Computers are just a tool, albeit valuable tools that are also now required for a growing number of assessments. As always, it's the students and teachers who need to come first, supported by the best tech for the job (and not just the tech to many people think students automatically need without fully assessing &nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014130</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/the-chromebook-isnt-selling-so-what-7000014130/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[The Chromebook isn't selling -- so what?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Apparently people aren't buying Chromebooks. Or they're buying them but not using them. But does that actually matter?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 07:14:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Matt Baxter-Reynolds]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Artist's impression of what Chromebook sales might look like." alt="Artist's impression of what Chromebook sales might look like." src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014130/chromebook-slaes-200x137.png?hash=ZTLjAQqzBQ&upscale=1" height="137" width="200"><figcaption>Artist's impression of what Chromebook sales might look like.</figcaption></figure>
<p>My ZDNet colleague Ed Bott broke the story last night that despite the fact that&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-spoiling-me-for-other-chromebooks-7000013287/?s_cid=e539">people seem to love the Chromebook</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/first-real-world-usage-figures-suggest-chromebooks-are-struggling-7000014102/">no one seems to be using them</a>.</p>
<p>Despite the fact the Chromebook was introduced in June 2011 and thus is much more market exposure than Windows RT, in the real world Chromebooks and Windows RT devices appear to have the same usage according to analysis of website statistics. Specifically, around 0.023 percent.</p>
<p>Which isn't very much.</p>
<p>If you were in my office now, you may notice a shelf. On it sits a Chromebook. To its right, sits a Surface RT. Neither of them I've used in -- it's either weeks or months -- I honestly can't remember.</p>
<h4 id="peas">Peas</h4>
<p>My reaction last night was to jump on Twitter and start justifying the low sales of Chromebook -- i.e. I badly wanted to be a "Chromebook apologist".</p>
<p>Being an apologist is always a good sign that you like something. And&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/the-chromebook-its-like-an-ipad-but-with-a-keyboard-7000009905/">I do really,&nbsp;<em>really</em>&nbsp;like the Chromebook</a>. So why's mine sitting on a shelf doing nothing waiting for me to get around to chucking it on eBay.</p>
<p>Because I can't do very much with it compared to the other tools I have at my disposal. Well, other "tool"&nbsp;<em>singular</em>&nbsp;-- my Mac is more useful. (And this doesn't have to be a Mac, it can be a PC. I happen to use a Mac. "Go, me".)</p>
<p>For example, today I have to write this piece, then do a bunch of ASP.NET development, then a bunch of book editing, then some other bits, and spend some time on Twitter. I can use the Chromebook to do some of that, but not all. There's no point physically switching the Mac and Chromebook around just to be task specific -- I might as well use my Mac.</p>
<p>When it comes to Windows RT and Chromebook, they are two peas in a pod. They are so similar in so many ways it's actually a bit spooky.</p>
<p>First similarity is that I don't use either of them day-to-day because they don't have enough utility to cover the specialised work that I do day-to-day.</p>
<p>Second similarity is that what they're both good at and bad at is roughly the same. I can't use either of them for specialised development work. I could use Surface RT for doing the book editing as it's rather good for doing <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/surface-is-it-microsofts-ipad-or-something-else-7000007020/">heavy work in Office</a><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong>and the Chromebook is abundantly not. (Although for light work, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/giving-up-the-file-system-with-google-docs-or-office-web-apps-7000011769/">Google Docs is ace</a>.)</p>
<p>Third similarity is that they're both bold experiments in how to reframe the PC away from being a device focused on corporate efficiency and one that's more about fitting into lifestyle of normal people away outside of their lives at work.</p>
<p>Wait though -- there's another way to look at that first similarity of applicability for day-to-day use which is the "what's it for?" test.</p>
<h4 id="actually">Actually...?</h4>
<p>This is classic technology adoption curve stuff. Early adopters (usually technologists) look at something new, and find a way to use the tool for their own purposes, and <em>voila</em> they like it. And then that group and the vendor's marketing department has to explain it to normal people who promptly turn round and say "Uh?"</p>
<p>In both the case of the Chromebook and Windows RT the same point has to be explained -- "No, you can't run your normal software on it."</p>
<p>And then you have this conversation: "So shouldn't I just buy a normal PC?"</p>
<p>"Yes."</p>
<p>And a normal PC gets bought. Which is fine. Or a normal PC doesn't get bought because the potential customer that we're talking about already has one and that happens to be working OK. Which is also fine if you consider the big picture that puts the customer and the environment first, but not fine if you're an OEM or Microsoft.</p>
<p>(Personally, I don't care about the OEMs or system vendors. I'm all about the customer and environment on this one. If you've got an decade old XP machine that does you fine, great. Don't waste resources demanding a new one -- just check you've got your backups working well.)</p>
<p>One of the big advantages that Google has with the Chromebook compared to Microsoft with Windows RT and also Windows generally is that Google probably doesn't care that much if Chromebooks sell because their business is currently mostly agnostic with regards to the device on which their services are consumed.</p>
<p>Microsoft is in a much weaker position in this regard because much as management there wants to pivot their business to be devices and services based, as opposed to utterly dependent on Windows and Office sales, that hasn't happened yet.</p>
<p>Google is facing the enemy here -- Microsoft is still trying to work out who's shooting at it.</p>
<p>The fact that sales and/or real world usage of both of these experiments is so low tells you that the experiments have failed. Or is failing. Either way.</p>
<p>But failing experiments are fine. Which, peculiarly, is something that all engineers fundamentally understand so why engineers would complain about failures is beyond me. Perhaps it's not them complaining vociferously.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Young man, why would I feel like a failure? And why would I ever give up? I now know definitively over 9,000 ways that an electric light bulb will not work. Success is almost in my grasp."</p>
<p>Thomas Edison. Well, probably. You know what the internet is like. Sounds valid enough though.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The important thing to remember here is that the customer is well served by these experiments. Much as I love the PC as a general purpose compute device that adapts beautifully to specific, commercial problem domains, it's a boneheaded lump of a thing chock full of malware and abuse vectors that is fundamentally unsuited to a general population of non-technologists looking to use compute devices to augment their lives.</p>
<p>The sooner the PC dies, frankly, the better.</p>
<p>So does it matter that the Chromebook isn't selling? Or that Windows RT isn't selling? As I mentioned earlier -- they're basically the same principle just done differently.</p>
<p>No. I don't think it does. The important thing is that smart engineers are out there trying to build great devices and services that serve a general population of normal human beings better than the old school PC.</p>
<p>Whether Google, Apple, or Microsoft do that -- who cares, really? At least having 0.023 percent market share drives the story on.</p>
<p>Sitting back and doing nothing does nothing for anyone.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014115</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/nokia-q1-preview-make-or-break-quarter-on-windows-phone-sales-7000014115/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Nokia Q1 preview: 'Make or break quarter' on Windows Phone sales]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The ailing phone maker is expected to report yet another loss for its first-quarter results. Lumia sales will be one thing, but the company's decreasing cash pile is a whole other worry.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 06:19:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nokia announces its third-quarter earnings on Thursday. With so many lemons, why is it not making any lemonade?</p>
<figure><img title="Nokia_Lumia_900" alt="Nokia_Lumia_900" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014115/nokialumia900-610x368.jpg?hash=LGNkMQAvZ2&upscale=1" height="368" width="610"><figcaption>(Image: CNET)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Analysts are pegging the upcoming earnings results as the "make or break quarter" for Nokia, which has struggled in the past couple of years with poor Windows Phone 8 device sales. </p>
<p>Nokia is expected to lose &euro;0.04 ($0.05 cents) per share on revenue of €6.63 billion ($8.73bn). According to analysts, cash is expected to settle at €3.7 billion ($4.87bn) compared to €4.4 billion ($5.79bn) at the fourth-quarter count.</p>
<p>It's not a great picture, but Nokia can stay afloat a little longer. The trouble is that Nokia's Windows Phone strategy remains unclear and has, at this point, little direction, except for an attempt to flood the market.</p>
<p>There are two things to look out for when the earnings break on Thursday:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>The (continued) burn rate of how much Nokia is churning through its cash reserves, as a result of declining revenue and overall profits</p></li>
<li><p>Lumia performance, and whether Windows Phone 8 is helping boost sales.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>The range of Lumia devices that the Finnish phone maker has on the market has been widely considered as the last gasp of air the company will breathe, with a string of quarterly losses and a declining cash pile.</p>
<p>Of all things to look out for, it's Lumia sales. Supply was generally problematic during the first quarter, although a growth in the number of regions selling the Windows Phone-powered Lumia may have boosted numbers.</p>
<p>Analysts are expecting between 4.8 and 5.8 million Lumia devices sold during the three-month period ending March 31. </p>
<p>With the majority of devices being sold expected to run the latest Windows Phone 8 software — compared to the fourth quarter, which was largely driven by the discounted Windows Phone 7.5-powered Lumia 800 — it's hoped that Nokia's continued Windows Phone 8 strategy may be enough to carry it on in subsequent quarters.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10116453" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-nokia-recovering-or-collapsing-by-the-numbers-7000010520/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/010520/blackberry-nokia-still-heading-towards-collapse-by-the-numbers-220x165.jpg?hash=LmVkZJD3AQ&upscale=1" alt="BlackBerry, Nokia: Recovering or collapsing? By the numbers" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-nokia-recovering-or-collapsing-by-the-numbers-7000010520/">BlackBerry, Nokia: Recovering or collapsing? By the numbers</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-nokia-recovering-or-collapsing-by-the-numbers-7000010520/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>What's preventing Nokia from sinking further is an emerging market grasp on the Asha and Symbian-based devices that still remain popular in certain parts of the world.</p>
<p>The latest comScore figures show that Symbian's market share remains flat. While Nokia had been hoping that Symbian figures continued to decline in favor of the higher-profit devices, Symbian's market share remains flat month on month.</p>
<p>Nokia is still expected to sell around 72 million devices in total during the first quarter, down around 20 percent year on year, with Lumia devices taking just 7 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts are expecting the gross margins of Nokia's Smart Device unit — which includes the Lumia range of devices — to increase sequentially, due largely to a lower mix of low or negative margin Symbian devices compared to the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The bottom line: Nokia has all the lemons, but will likely make little lemonade. Windows Phone is a strong platform, and reviewers have fawned over the Lumia hardware. But by failing to keep ahead of the curve, Nokia has fallen behind out of sight, and can only be heard by its faint whispers at a distance. </p>
<p>Nokia's recovery — if there will be one — will start now, or never. There are only so many times we can keep cheering on the guy at the back of the race.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014119</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/sg/post-bis-blackberry-z10-offers-superior-e-mail-functionality-7000014119/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Post-BIS BlackBerry Z10 offers superior e-mail functionality]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[After almost a month of use, Paul Mah is of the opinion the BlackBerry Z10--even without BlackBerry Internet Services--offers great push mail capabilities and is a step ahead of rival mobile platforms.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 05:41:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Paul Mah]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-blackberry/">BlackBerry</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The pace and complexity of technological changes can sometimes make new developments daunting to understand. This is especially the case for those without formal IT training, or in situations where a commenter does not have the opportunity to use a particular technology.</p>
<p>A report titled "No push e-mail, no thanks to new BlackBerry" published a few weeks ago on Singapore broadsheet, The Straits Times, underscored the point. Based on interviews with a couple of users on older BlackBerry devices and an unnamed market watcher, the report sought to cast the new BlackBerry Z10 smartphone as an inferior platform for push e-mail.</p>
<p>Let me explain why the opposite is true.</p>
<h3>Z10 <em>is</em> capable of push e-mail</h3>
<p>The entire issue originates from the BlackBerry Z10's extensive onboard support for a wide array of e-mail protocols. This ranges from POP and IMAP, as well as popular Web-based e-mail services such as Gmail, Hotmail and Yahoo Mail. In addition, the BlackBerry 10 operating system (OS) that powers the Z10 also supports the Exchange ActiveSync (EAS). EAS was created by Microsoft and has evolved to become a de facto standard that is heavily used by large organizations and small businesses alike.</p>
<p>Previously, users have to subscribe to either BIS (BlackBerry Internet Services) or BES (BlackBerry Enterprise Services) before they can tap into the push mail capabilities of BlackBerry smartphones. The former was designed for end-users or small businesses, while the latter came with features that enterprises and government agencies will need. The downside of BIS and BES is an often hefty monthly fee payable to mobile operators; the latter also necessitates an in-house server and separate licensing fee for the backend software.</p>
<p>In the new paradigm, BES continues to be available for large businesses as usual. Smaller firms and end-users can simply rely on the Z10's direct e-mail support without having to subscribe to a BIS data plan. Moreover, businesses that want to separate between business (BES) and personal data can do so with the use of BlackBerry Balance.</p>
<h3>Living without BIS</h3>
<p>One concern expressed by veteran BlackBerry users is the apparent loss of BIS capability on BlackBerry 10 OS. Though this fuss may seem bizarre to non-BlackBerry users, the advantages offered by BIS are real. BlackBerry users are accustomed to how BIS makes it possible to receive e-mails and BBM (BlackBerry Messenger) messages even in areas with very poor or intermittent mobile reception. </p>
<p>Charles Dufourcq, country director for Singapore at BlackBerry, previously said <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/sg/blackberry-z10-launch-marks-10-years-in-singapore-7000011551/">during the launch in February</a> that since BlackBerry 10 OS is architected just like other mobile players, consumers here will not need to subscribe to BIS when getting the Z10 device.&nbsp;</p>
<p>On a practical note, how does the loss of BIS reflect on the Z10's performance? As a user of various iPhone and BlackBerry smartphone models for the last three years, I made a switch to the BlackBerry Z10 three weeks ago. My experience showed the push mail experience with EAS isn't worse compared to that of BIS.</p>
<p>I did notice the occasional influx of WhatsApp messages coming in at the same time, but that's par for course since it happens on the iPhone too. Furthermore, frequent travelers currently on an unlimited BackBerry data plan but who are not hooked up to BES will feel the pinch now that BBM messages and e-mails are charged at the usual exorbitant rates set by operators.</p>
<p>On the plus side, I gained full push e-mail capabilities on two separate Exchange mail accounts &ndash; something not possible on previous generations of BlackBerry devices on BIS. The BlackBerry 10 OS does not place any limit on the number of Exchange accounts that are added.</p>
<p>In conclusion, BlackBerry has now joined the ranks of modern smartphone platforms such as the iOS, Android and Windows Phone with the Z10's comprehensive on-board support for e-mail. Indeed, its continued ability to work with BES gives the Z10 the same security and manageability which has made it so popular with businesses, effectively <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/samsungs-knox-rides-asia-byod-wave-to-draw-enterprises-7000013716/">putting it one step ahead of other mobile platforms</a>.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013928</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/uk/whats-your-mobile-game-plan-7000013928/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[What’s Your Mobile Game Plan?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Mobile is one of these ‘evolve or get left behind’ things. Not having a mobile strategy today is like not having an Internet strategy in the late ‘90s.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 04:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Diarmuid Mallon]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sixty-one percent of CIOs plan to enhance their mobile capability during the next three years, according to a Gartner survey. Forty-eight percent believe they will become leaders in their industries by fully adopting innovative mobility solutions.</p>
<p>So, everyone&rsquo;s doing it.</p>
<p>Now, I&rsquo;m not one to recommend that everyone just follow the trends, but I do think that mobile is one of these &lsquo;evolve or get left behind&rsquo; things. Since I work in the industry, you could say that I&rsquo;m slightly biased, but I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;m the only one saying that not having a mobile strategy today is like not having an Internet strategy in the late &lsquo;90s.</p>
<p>Mobile has the potential to transform your enterprise, even more so than the Web did. We all know that giving employees access to company data and email when they&rsquo;re on the go boosts productivity. Beyond that, mobile can improve internal processes, help sales teams close faster, speed decision-making and improve customer service. It can help you connect directly with customers, learn about what they like, and market to them more effectively for less money.</p>
<p>To help you understand the opportunities (and risks), IDG and SAP have created an informative, three-part Mobile Playbook series filled with data, insights, best practices, resources, and a checklist for developing a winning mobile strategy. I&rsquo;ll be talking about each of the playbooks in turn over the next couple of weeks.</p>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t want to wait to hear more about each one, you can go ahead and download the entire series for free, right <a href="http://www54.sap.com/solutions/tech/mobile/featured/offers/mobile-game-plan.html">here</a>.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014112</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/repeat-after-me-i-will-back-up-my-mac-today-7000014112/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Repeat after me: I will back up my Mac today]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[It's a familiar refrain, but not enough people back up regularly. Here's a story of my close call and how to prevent a data loss catastrophe.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 02:24:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Jason D. O'Grady]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software/">Software</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everyone's got a story about losing data; most end with a pact to never let it happen again and a blood oath to backup more regularly. I've avoided data loss over the years due to a rigorous backup schedule and a hardware upgrade cycle that's shorter than most.</p>
<figure><img title="Repeat after me: I will back up my Mac today - Jason O'Grady" alt="Repeat after me: I will back up my Mac today - Jason O'Grady" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014112/owc-ssd-620-620x429.jpg?hash=BTMvAGqyAw&upscale=1" height="429" width="620"><figcaption>(Image: Jason D O'Grady/ZDNet)</figcaption></figure>
<p>But I got lazy a couple weeks ago and paid the price as a result.</p>
<p>I got a new 2013&nbsp;Retina MacBook Pro 13-inch to replace my late 2012 model, and decided that it would be quicker to move the SSD from the old to the new Mac rather than migrate&nbsp;the data from a Time Machine backup.</p>
<p>Simple enough, right? No. Bad idea.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For starters, migrating from a backup is <em>always</em> better, because it forces you to make a backup that you can restore from. I hadn't made a backup in around six weeks because I got lazy and neglected to plug in the USB drive sitting on my desk.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Take a close look at the photo above. The SSD in question, a blazing fast 6G model from OWC, just<em> barely</em> fits inside the carrier bezel under the trackpad in the rMBP13. When I moved it to the new Mac, I guess that I didn't seat it firmly enough in the socket and, as you can see in the photo above, the corners of the SSD are just barely resting on top of the curved corners of the carrier bezel.&nbsp;</p>
<p>When I tightened the screw that holds the SSD in place (gently, mind you), it flexed the board enough to crack a component on the board. Sure enough, it wouldn't boot and I was greeted by the dreaded blinking grey folder of death.&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img title="Mac OS X grey folder of death - Jason O'Grady" alt="Mac OS X grey folder of death - Jason O'Grady" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014112/grey-folder-of-death-183x163.jpg?hash=MGOwZmyvMQ&upscale=1" height="163" width="183"><figcaption>(Image: Jason D O'Grady/ZDNet)</figcaption></figure>
<p>And that was the end of my SSD.</p>
<p>Thoughts began racing through my mind of everything I had worked on (and not backed up) in the past six weeks, including my book manuscript and photos from my daughter's birthday party. Luckily, I had shared the photos with my wife via PhotoStream and a bunch of documents that I was working on were located on <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTY2NzI5Mzk?src=global9" target="_blank">Dropbox</a>. In other words, thank goodness for the cloud.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Unfortunately, I had a lot of documents that weren't on the cloud that got obliterated with my quarter turn of a screwdriver. But my bad fortune (stupidity?) should be a lesson to you. It's relatively inexpensive to back up your data, and today's tools make it completely automatic and transparent.&nbsp;</p>
<p>After my data loss issue, I took two steps to ensure that it never happens again:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I replaced my Airport Extreme with a 2GB <a href="http://www.apple.com/timecapsule/" target="_blank">Time Capsule</a>. It's essentially an Airport base station with an internal hard drive. I configured it to back up my hard drive via Time Machine any time I'm on my network.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I subscribed to an online backup service. I chose <a href="http://www.crashplan.com/consumer/crashplan-plus.html" target="_blank">CrashPlan+ Unlimited</a> ($60/year) because: a) It includes unlimited online storage; b) It doesn't have a single file size limit (I use a large Windows VM); c) It offers 448-bit user encryption; d) It <a href="http://www.crashplan.com/consumer/details.html" target="_blank">keeps deleted files</a>; e) It offers a <a href="http://support.crashplan.com/doku.php/feature/seed_service" target="_blank">Seed Service</a> to speed your initial upload; and f) It's priced fairly.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>With tools like Time Machine included in OS X and Time Capsules starting at $299, there's simply no reason not to backup your data automatically. I added an online backup service for protection against a local catastrophe and recommend that you do the same. Immediately.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Ask yourself two simple questions: If your hard drive/SSD were to fail (or was lost/stolen) today, do you have a full backup at your fingertips? How long would it take you to get back up and running?</p>
<p>Now go purchase a Time Capsule and subscribe to an online backup service.&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014113</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/under-cispa-google-facebook-twitter-microsoft-others-cant-promise-to-protect-your-privacy-7000014113/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Under CISPA, Google, Facebook, Twitter, Microsoft, others can't promise to protect your privacy]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[An amendment to CISPA failed to pass. This now means major tech and Web companies will be disallowed under law to promise to protect your privacy.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 17 Apr 2013 02:04:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-us/">Government US</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Major technology and Web companies&nbsp;— not limited to Google, Facebook, Twitter and Microsoft&nbsp;— will not be allowed to promise to protect users' privacy should CISPA pass Congress.</p>
<figure><img title="capdometwi7610x430-620x366" alt="capdometwi7610x430-620x366" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014113/capdometwi7610x430-620x366-620x366.jpg?hash=MwyzLGxlLm&upscale=1" height="366" width="620"><figcaption>CISPA will soon be voted on in the coming few weeks. (Image: CNET)</figcaption></figure>
<p>For those out of the loop, CISPA will allow private sector firms to search personal and sensitive user data of ordinary U.S. residents to identify this so-called "threat information", and to then share that information with each other and the US government — without the need for a court-ordered warrant.</p>
<p>Under a new amendment <a href="http://www.rules.house.gov/amendments/AMASH_008_xml416130939483948.pdf">voted on earlier today in the U.S. House</a>&nbsp;[PDF], U.S. companies would have been able to keep their privacy policies intact and their promises valid, including terms of service, legally enforceable in the future.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10118203" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-7000013965/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013965/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-220x165.jpg?hash=ZwZkBTExZT&upscale=1" alt="What is CISPA, and what does it mean for you? FAQ" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-7000013965/">What is CISPA, and what does it mean for you? FAQ</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-7000013965/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>But the Republicans narrowly failed to get it through by a 5-8 vote to reject the amendment.</p>
<p><a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-57579958-38/cispa-vote-means-companies-cant-promise-to-protect-privacy/">According to CNET's Declan McCullagh</a>, Rep. Pete Sessions (R-TX), who chairs the House Rules Committee, urged his colleagues to reject the amendment. And they did. All Republican members of the committee voted against, despite a unanimous&nbsp;show of support from the Democratic membership.</p>
<p>It would have allowed companies to make promises to their customers not to voluntarily share their data with other private firms or the U.S. government under the law, which would have been legally valid and enforceable in court.</p>
<p>It means that those who signed up to services under the explicit terms that data would not be shared&nbsp;— with perhaps the exception of the U.S. government if a valid court order or subpoena is served — would no longer have such rights going forward.</p>
<p>The amendment would have weakened CISPA's position. Now it gives these private firms watertight legal immunity under CISPA to share their customer and user data with other firms and the U.S. government, by being "completely exonerated from any risk of liability," according to Rep. Jared Polis (D-CO) speaking to <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-57579958-38/cispa-vote-means-companies-cant-promise-to-protect-privacy/">our sister site CNET</a>.</p>
<p>This gives private sector firms the right to hand over private user data, while&nbsp;<a >circumventing existing privacy laws</a>, such&nbsp;as emails, text messages, and cloud-stored documents and files, with the U.S. government and its law enforcement and intelligence agencies.</p>
<p>Today, the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/white-house-threatens-to-veto-new-cispa-bill-ahead-of-vote-7000014099/">White House throwed its weight behind a threat</a>&nbsp;that would see CISPA, known as its full title as the&nbsp;Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act, vetoed by President Obama should it pass his desk.</p>
<p>A vote on CISPA will go ahead on the House floor either on April 17 or April 18.</p>
<p>(<a ><em>Via</em> CNET</a>)</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014101</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/the-shrinking-gap-between-cloud-service-providers-and-consumers-7000014101/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[The shrinking gap between cloud service providers and consumers ]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[An insurance services provider crosses the line: 'If you talked to me four years ago, I suspect I would not have envisioned myself sitting on stage today saying I'm a cloud service provider.']]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 21:02:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Joe McKendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the rise of cloud services, many non-IT companies are finding themselves in the cloud business. They may not even call it that, but they are providing cloud services to customers and partners. </p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Clouds and Sun 2-photo by Joe McKendrick" alt="Clouds and Sun 2-photo by Joe McKendrick" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014101/clouds-and-sun-2-photo-by-joe-mckendrick-200x150.jpg?hash=BGMvAJD2MG&upscale=1" height="150" width="200"><figcaption>(Image: Joe McKendrick/ZDNet)</figcaption></figure>
<p>InfoWorld's Eric Knorr just <a href="http://www.infoworld.com/t/cloud-computing/how-become-accidental-cloud-service-provider-216465" target="_blank">uncovered</a> another example of a non-IT company morphing into a cloud provider, part of the increasingly blurry lines between service providers and consumers.</p>
<p>Milliman, a large independent actuarial and consulting firm, is now a cloud provider, and calls it for what it is:</p>
<p>"If you talked to me four years ago, I suspect I would not have envisioned myself sitting on stage today, saying I'm a cloud service provider," Van Beach, product manager at Millman, told Eric. "But that's really what we are, and I think we're doing pretty well at it."</p>
<p>Milliman initially moved a risk management application to Microsoft's Windows Azure public cloud in 2010 to handle spikes in its workload. The project took on a life of its own as the company moved more functionality, such as workflow, into the cloud &mdash; functionality that it extends to its client base.</p>
<p>"What began as public cloud approach to address a problem of variable workloads quickly morphed into an opportunity to take multiple activities related to the actuarial process &mdash; previously scattered across client desktops &mdash; and centralize and secure them in the public cloud. As a result, Beach said, Milliman can now offer a solution that exists nowhere else in the industry today."</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014104</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/yahoo-ceo-marissa-mayer-morale-is-on-the-rise-7000014104/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Yahoo CEO Marissa Mayer: Morale is on the rise]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[With job applicants increasing and attrition slumping, things are looking up at Yahoo, the company's chief executive said today.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:53:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cxo/">CXO</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-project-management/">Project Management</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="marissa-mayer-headshot-google-offset-crop-620x348-620x348" alt="marissa-mayer-headshot-google-offset-crop-620x348-620x348" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014104/marissa-mayer-headshot-google-offset-crop-620x348-620x348-620x348.jpg?hash=ZzMwMQZjLG&upscale=1" height="348" width="620"></figure>
<p>On Yahoo's first quarter 2013 earnings conference call this afternoon, chief executive Marissa Mayer said that morale is already improving at the beleaguered technology company.</p>
<p>She said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The commitment we've made to make Yahoo the absolute best place to work is already leading to better employee collaboration, innovation and execution. As of today, we've implemented more than 567 employee-focused initiatives across the company, including a new program that encourages all employees to test and improve our latest products, which is yielding excellent, exciting new thinking.</p>
<p>As a result of these initiatives, the data is undeniable.&nbsp;Today, more people are applying to work at Yahoo and more employees are staying. In Q1, the number of resumes we received more than tripled over the course of the quarter. And reflecting on this period last year, the number of candidates applying Yahoo! s has nearly doubled. Our attrition rate for top talent is essentially half of what it was just a year ago.</p>
<p>And with the renewed excitement around Yahoo, we're seeing a steady increase in what we call "boomerangs." They have rejoined. In fact, 14 percent of the hires we made in the first quarter were boomerangs, one in every seven.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Mayer said building positive company culture among its 11,300 employees was the first part of her strategy -- "getting people to believe in Yahoo, making Yahoo a really terrific place to work and contribute and getting the organization fit," she said -- and the second phase will follow with "building beautiful products and executing well against our business strategy."</p>
<p>"As I said before, companies with the best talent win," she said, "and it's clear we're now back in the game."</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014094</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/intel-predicts-rebounds-for-pc-datacenter-units-later-this-year-7000014094/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Intel predicts rebounds for PC, datacenter units later this year]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[While the PC market looks like it's on a downward spiral, Intel executives are still predicting a comeback.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:45:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-intel/">Intel</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-processors/">Processors</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="intelceo" alt="intelceo" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/us-carousel/companies/intelceo-620x202.jpg?hash=LmZ4ZTZ3Lw&upscale=1" height="202" width="620"></figure>
<p>With the PC market looking like it is in shambles,<strong> Intel</strong> is still predicting rebounds for both its PC and datacenter units -- at least by the end of 2013. For PCs, executives stressed lower prices matched with touch as key growth drivers this year.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-q1-pcs-mobile-data-center-wild-cards-abound-7000014018/">Intel's Q1: PCs, mobile, data center wild cards abound</a> | <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-q1-good-enough-company-remains-upbeat-7000014097/">Intel's Q1 good enough, company remains upbeat </a>| <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/outgoing-intel-ceo-otellini-materials-manufacturing-our-foundation-7000014103/">Outgoing Intel CEO Otellini: Materials, manufacturing our foundation</a></p>

<p>During the earnings call on Tuesday, Intel chief financial officer Stacy Smith responded to analyst skepticism as why investors shouldn't expect a repeat of last year's second half.</p>
<p>Here's Smith's answer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I think that as the OEMs start looking at new form factors that they can design around our new chips (Haswell in particular and maybe Baytrail) and Windows 8 enabling touch, the explosion and form factors and competitiveness of that platform is going to be substantially different at price points down into the [$300] or $400 range enabling touch. We didn't have that last year. So you go into the prime selling season with new products, new technologies, new form factors, and new capabilities that up to now [had] unapproachable price points.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Smith also outlined the chip maker’s forecasts for "double-digit" revenue growth for the datacenter group followed by growth for the PC group in the "low single digits."</p>
<p>To recall, first quarter revenue for Intel's PC Client Group was $8.0 billion, down 6.6 percent quarterly and down 6.0 percent annually (<a href="http://newsroom.intel.com/community/intel_newsroom/blog/2013/04/16/intel-reports-first-quarter-revenue-of-126-billion">statement</a>). The Data Center Group saw Q1 revenue of $2.6 billion, down 6.9 percent sequentially but up 7.5 percent year-over-year.</p>
<p>Intel's view on the PC market comes across as either patient and optimistic or foolhardy and in denial.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/idc-global-pc-shipments-plunge-in-worst-drop-in-a-generation-7000013839/">Just last week</a>, IDC reported that global PC shipments plunged by 14 percent during the first quarter of 2013, which is the worst drop for the market in a generation.</p>
<p>Gartner's take on the PC market was a little less steep with a 11.2 percent decline.</p>
<p>It is important to note that the market intelligence firm defines PCs as "Desktops, Portables, Mini Notebooks and Workstations." That definition includes netbooks, but it excludes tablets with detachable keyboards.</p>
<p>Garnter's definition consists of "desk-based PCs and mobile PCs, including mini-notebooks but not media tablets such as the iPad."</p>
<p>Intel's definition appears to be all of the above.</p>
<p>Intel chief executive officer Paul Otellini asserted during the call that it is "no longer necessary to choose between a PC and a tablet."</p>
<p>Smith followed up later, stressing that Otellini's point was that the lines between traditional notebooks, convertibles, and tablets have blurred, giving way to a "market of computing."</p>
<p>He continued that analysts and investors should expect an improving economic environment to help out, describing that as "a reasonable assumption" and in line with "normal historical growth."</p>
<p>Smith added that the difference for the PC segment is that now it just consists of "a wider range of devices than previously supported," hinting that analysts should change their own ideas about what the PC market comprises.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014102</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/first-real-world-usage-figures-suggest-chromebooks-are-struggling-7000014102/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[First real-world usage figures suggest Chromebooks are struggling]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[When the initial batch of Chromebooks hit the market nearly two years ago, some thought these low-cost devices running Google's cloud-centric Chrome OS could be a Windows killer. NetMarketShare just started measuring Chromebook usage this month, and the first reported numbers are startlingly low.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:43:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ed Bott]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Uh-oh. It looks like Google’s Chromebook has fallen victim to the same malaise that’s affected Windows PCs and Macs. These low-cost devices were supposed to be perfect for an always-on, post-PC world. But just-released usage&nbsp;statistics suggest&nbsp;that the category&nbsp;has so far been&nbsp;unsuccessful.</p>
<p>In its first week of monitoring worldwide usage of Google's Chrome OS,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.netmarketshare.com/">NetMarketShare</a>&nbsp;reported that the percentage of web traffic from Chromebooks was roughly 2/100 of 1 percent, a figure too small to earn a place on its reports.</p>
<figure><img title="samsung-chromebook" alt="samsung-chromebook" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014102/samsung-chromebook-588x373.jpg?hash=MGR5ZGt1ZJ&upscale=1" height="373" width="588"></figure>
<p>The first Chromebooks went on sale in June 2011, nearly two years ago. In the run-up to the launch, ZDNet’s own Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols called the Chromebook a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/five-reasons-why-googles-linux-chromebook-is-a-windows-killer/8887">“Windows killer,”</a> predicting that “Microsoft is facing real trouble”&nbsp;in the market for desktop PCs.</p>
<p>Those first Chromebooks&nbsp;didn’t make an immediate dent in the market, with <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/computers/poor-sales-of-chromebooks-wont-stop-google-from-promoting-chrome-os/7014">Acer reportedly selling fewer than 5000 units</a> in the first six months and Samsung selling even fewer. But the new OS and its ultra-low-cost hardware have&nbsp;attracted their fair share of coverage from enthusiasts who like Google’s all-cloud-all-the-time vision of computing.</p>
<p>The two biggest names&nbsp;in the list&nbsp;of&nbsp;PC OEMs, Lenovo and HP, have <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/chrome-os-gains-on-windows-8s-pains-7000010439/">jumped into the market as well</a>, adding low-cost Chromebooks to their lineup. Last fall Samsung introduced a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-samsung-chromebook-arm-processor-and-249-7000006006/">$249 ARM-powered Chromebook</a>&nbsp;in a form factor reminiscent of the MacBook Air.&nbsp;And Google raised a few eyebrows when it introduced its own model, the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-from-google-pushing-the-cloud-to-the-limit-7000011635/">spectacularly pricey Chromebook Pixel</a>, with a high-resolution touchscreen.</p>
<p>With all those choices, you’d think the category would be successful. Indeed, that Samsung model topped Amazon’s list of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/amazons-top-selling-laptop-doesnt-run-windows-or-mac-os-it-runs-linux-7000009433/">best-selling laptops this winter</a>.</p>
<p>But so far, Chromebooks haven’t appeared at all on the list of operating systems monitored by Net Applications, which publishes its figures at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.netmarketshare.com/">NetMarketShare.com</a>. And that’s an important metric, according to my opponent in last week's ZDNet Great Debate&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/windows-8-can-this-os-be-saved/10117509/">on the future of Windows 8</a>, who&nbsp;cited disappointing usage reports as evidence that Windows 8 has flopped:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Windows 8's market numbers are <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/five-%20reasons-why-windows-8-has-failed-7000012104/">even lower than Vista's pathetic ranking</a> at a similar point in their sales cycle. Even if you&nbsp;buy the most optimistic reading of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/latest-os-share-%20data-shows-windows-still-dominating-in-pcs-7000013351/">NetMarketShare's numbers</a>, Windows 8, after being in the market for six months, has just 3.31% of the desktop marketplace—that's just over what Vista had with 3.02% in three months.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Well, it was only five months, not six, and NetMarketShare also changed the way it calculated usage in 2008, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Browser_share#Net_Applications_.282004_Q4_to_present.29">rendering those comparisons invalid</a>. But let's not quibble over details. When I looked at the same numbers last month, I <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/latest-os-share-data-shows-windows-still-dominating-in-pcs-7000013351/">found a slightly different story</a>. I also noticed a curious omission:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One widely discussed operating system isn’t visible in the&nbsp;NetMarketShare numbers. There’s no entry for Chrome OS at all. A spokesperson for the company tells me those numbers will be included in an update to their tracking stats, coming soon.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The first numbers were due to show up in the subscriber-only reports for the week ending April 14. This morning I asked a company spokesperson for a sneak peek and got this report:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>For the week of 4/8 - 4/14, ChromeBook has 0.023 percent&nbsp;weighted worldwide usage. Because it rounds to less than 0.1 percent&nbsp;it’s not showing up in our reports.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To put things in perspective, as of April 2013&nbsp;all Chromebooks combined have managed to achieve 7/10 of 1 percent of the usage of Windows 8 PCs worldwide.</p>
<p>Put another way,&nbsp;that figure suggests that in nearly two years on the market, all of those Chromebooks have&nbsp;achieved&nbsp;a smaller percentage of usage&nbsp;than Windows RT earned as of January 2013, after only three months on the market. Windows RT has been widely considered a disappointment, with OEMs <a >cutting prices for RT-powered devices</a>.</p>
<p>In both categories, those tiny results suggest&nbsp;a fair amount of pain for the OEMs that jumped in early. Google’s gone all-in for its cloud-based OS, and Microsoft is similarly gung-ho about the future of its Windows RT operating system. But it might be another couple of years before the general buying public is really ready for either one.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014103</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/outgoing-intel-ceo-otellini-materials-manufacturing-our-foundation-7000014103/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Outgoing Intel CEO Otellini: Materials, manufacturing our foundation]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA["Never in the history of our company has our ability to participate across the spectrum of computing been greater," says Intel CEO Paul Otellini.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:29:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-centers/">Data Centers</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-processors/">Processors</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tech-industry/">Tech Industry</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Intel CEO Paul Otellini, who has a month on the job before he steps aside, said the company is in good hands, has a new generation of leadership coming and added "material science and manufacturing technology is the foundation on which our future success will be based."</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="otellini" alt="otellini" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014103/otellini-200x241.png?hash=ZJL3MzIvLz&upscale=1" height="241" width="200"></figure>
<p>The comments, which were delivered during a rare Otellini appearance on <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-q1-good-enough-company-remains-upbeat-7000014097/">an earnings conference call</a>, highlight the big debate about Intel's future.</p>
<p>Some analysts are questioning <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intel-post-otellini-the-big-challenges-ahead-7000007605/">Intel's focus on manufacturing and driving Moore's Law</a>. The argument against Intel's view is that technology is entering a good enough era where the chip giant's quest for specification leadership won't fly. Regarding manufacturing, analysts also question Intel's penchant for capital spending.</p>
<p>Otellini obviously disagrees with those worries. He said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Never in the history of our company has our ability to participate across the spectrum of computing been greater, from industrial machines that are increasingly connected to the Internet to the smallest battery powered devises from traditional PCs to ultrabooks and from high performance servers to micro servers, storage and networking equipment. We now compete wherever there is computing. At the same time, we've put more distance between us and the rest of the semiconductor industry than ever before. In the first quarter we shipped our 100 millionth 22-nanometer processor, using our revolutionary 3D transistor technology while the rest of the industry works to ship its first unit. That breakthrough is just one in the long history of material science firsts, following innovations like silicon and high K metal gate. This leadership and material science and manufacturing technology is the foundation on which our future success will be based, arming us with the world's lowest power and lowest cost transistors. Even as I prepare to pass the baton to a new generation of leadership I know Intel's story is nowhere near completely written. I'm excited about what lies ahead for Intel. The company has a historically broad portfolio of products, spanning the spectrum of computing and price points and as we begin to transition to 14-nanometer technology later this year our architectural and process technology investments and innovation will become increasingly apparent and valuable for our customers and to the market.</p>
<p>The company’s core architectural and manufacturing strengths have never been more valuable and the opportunity presented by the evolution and expansion of the computing industry has never been greater.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10118218" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Intel remains positive</h3><ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intel-predicts-rebounds-for-pc-datacenter-units-later-this-year-7000014094/">Intel predicts rebounds for PC, datacenter units later this year</a></li>

<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-q1-good-enough-company-remains-upbeat-7000014097/">Intel's Q1 good enough, company remains upbeat</a></li>
</ul></div>
<p>Otellini's successor will face multiple questions about whether Intel can navigate change such as mobility, cloud computing and big data and thrive. Otellini knows the drill. He said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Naturally, constant change and reinvention creates plenty of room for both opportunity and skepticism.</p>
</blockquote>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014100</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-starts-testing-visual-studio-2012-update-3-7000014100/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Microsoft starts testing Visual Studio 2012 Update 3]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Visual Studio team is continuing with its seemingly quarterly update pace, delivering the first public test build of the next update for Visual Studio 2012.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 19:44:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Jo Foley]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just like clockwork, the Visual Studio team is continuing to push ahead with what look to be quarterly updates to Visual Studio 2012.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="vs2012" alt="vs2012" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014100/vs2012-200x178.png?hash=ZJZmLJWuZJ&upscale=1" height="178" width="200"></figure>
<p>On April 15, the team made available for download <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=38426">the first Community Technology Preview (CTP) of Visual Studio 2012 Update 3</a>.</p>
<p>Microsoft released to manufacturing Visual Studio 2012 in early August 2012. In September, the team announced <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-makes-good-on-promise-of-quicker-visual-studio-releases-7000007922/">plans for more rapidly and regularly delivered "updates."</a> These VS updates, which includes new features and not just fixes, are becoming increasingly across the company, with a push to deliver versions of key Microsoft products on an accelerated time table.</p>
<p>Microsoft just made<a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/somasegar/archive/2013/04/04/visual-studio-2012-update-2-now-available.aspx"> the final release of Update 2 for Visual Studio 201</a>2 available on April 5.</p>
<p><a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2835600#newtech">CTP1 of Visual Studio 2012 Update 3 includes</a> some new Team Foundation Server functionality. It also includes fixes for various issues involving the debugger, Web tools, C++ support and more.</p>
<p>I'm curious what Microsoft will be showing off at the Build 2013 conference in late June this year on the Visual Studio front. Will developers get new features as part of Visual Studio 2012 Update 4? Or will Microsoft already be moving on to a whole new VS release (VS Blue?) that will be focused around bringing the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-working-to-unify-further-its-windows-and-windows-phone-platforms-7000011070/">Windows Phone 8.x, Windows 8.1 and possibly the next Xbox development experiences more into alignment</a>?</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014099</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/white-house-threatens-to-veto-new-cispa-bill-ahead-of-vote-7000014099/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[White House threatens to veto new CISPA Bill ahead of vote]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Obama administration has issued another stark warning to the US House currently preparing to vote on a regurgitated cybersecurity Bill. If it passes the president's desk, he's not going to sign it.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 16 Apr 2013 19:39:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ahead of a vote scheduled for either April 17 or April 18 in the US House of Representatives on the Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act (CISPA), the White House today issued a statement threatening to veto the Bill altogether.</p>
<figure><img title="congress" alt="congress" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014099/congress-620x348.jpg?hash=AmWwZTV0AQ&upscale=1" height="348" width="620"><figcaption>The US House will vote on the CISPA Bill this week. (Image: CNET)</figcaption></figure>
<p>It repeats a similar sentiment by the Obama administration last year, when CISPA reached as far as passing the House but failed in the upper Senate chamber.</p>
<p>Citing above all else the need to "carefully safeguard privacy and civil liberties", the White House doesn't believe the intelligence sharing Bill, otherwise known as H.R. 624, goes far enough to protect the ordinary rights of citizens.</p>
<p>The key takeaway from the letter states:</p>
<blockquote><p>The administration recognizes and appreciates that the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence (HPSCI) adopted several amendments to H.R. 624 in an effort to incorporate the administration's important substantive concerns.</p>
<p>However, the administration still seeks additional improvements, and if the Bill, as currently crafted, were presented to the president, his senior advisors would recommend that he veto the Bill. </p></blockquote>
<p>The controversial Bill cleared the House Intelligence Committee last week, and is expected to go before a wider vote in the coming days. While there were <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/surprise-surprise-house-committee-to-amend-cispa-in-secret-again-7000013607/">efforts made to amend the Bill</a> with features that would ultimately add safeguards and additional privacy measures, many did not garner enough votes from the committee.</p>
<p>CISPA will allow private sector firms to search personal and sensitive user data of ordinary US residents to identify this so-called "threat information", and to then share that information with each other and the US government — without the need for a court-ordered warrant.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10118203" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-7000013965/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013965/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-220x165.jpg?hash=ZwZkBTExZT&upscale=1" alt="What is CISPA, and what does it mean for you? FAQ" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-7000013965/">What is CISPA, and what does it mean for you? FAQ</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-cispa-and-what-does-it-mean-for-you-faq-7000013965/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>By citing "cybersecurity", private sector firms — including those in the web and technology industry — can  hand over private user data, while <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/02/cispa-privacy-invading-cybersecurity-spying-bill-back-congress">circumventing existing privacy laws</a>. This means CISPA can be used to permit non-governmental entities to share your data, such as emails, text messages, and cloud-stored documents and files, with the US government and its law enforcement and intelligence agencies.</p>
<p>The Bill, if passed into law, will also give these firms legal protection when handing over data.</p>
<p>In April last year, the White House said that President Obama would not sign the Bill — even though it had only just passed the lower house hurdle in Congress — as the Bill "fails to provide authorities to ensure that the nation’s core critical infrastructure is protected while repealing important provisions."</p>
<p>Obama, earlier this year in February, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/obamas-cybersecurity-executive-order-what-you-need-to-know-7000011221/">signed a cybersecurity executive order</a> in a bid to create a "framework" between agencies that preserves the privacy and civil liberties of US residents.</p>
<p>The "framework" will effectively allow intelligence to be gathered on cyberattacks and cyberthreats to privately owned critical national infrastructure — such as the private defense sector, utility networks, and the banking industry — so they can better protect themselves, as well as the general US population, the economy, and other nations that are reliant on US support.</p>
<p>The full text of the letter, issued on Tuesday, can be read below.</p>
<p><iframe id="doc_90920" class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="http://www.scribd.com/embeds/136325070/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=scroll" height="450" width="100%" data-auto-height="false" data-aspect-ratio="undefined"></iframe></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
