<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:s="http://www.zdnet.com/search" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
    <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
    <description>Latest Blog for ZDNet</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>ZDNet</copyright>
    <managingEditor>customerservice@zdnet.com (ZDNet Customer Services)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>uk-engineering@cbsinteractive.com (ZDNet Webmaster)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:16:43 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 14:16:43 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>2</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://i.zdnet.com/images/spry/zdnet_300x300.jpg</url>
      <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
      <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
      <width>143</width>
      <height>39</height>
    </image>
    <s:counts>
      <start>0</start>
      <return>20</return>
      <found>42343</found>
    </s:counts>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014270</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/google-to-buy-39m-provo-fiber-service-for-1-7000014270/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Google to buy $39m Provo fiber service for $1]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[If the deal between Provo and Google doesn't work out, the tech giant can sell the network back for a dollar. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 10:50:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-fiber/">Fiber</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-wi-fi/">Wi-Fi</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, the latest destination for Google Fiber was confirmed to be Provo, Utah, but rather than building the system from scratch, the tech giant would buy out the city's own network.</p>
<p>iProvo will be bought out by Google pending a vote by the Provo City Council on April 23, but the financial details were not disclosed at the time of the original report. However, according to <a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/google-buying-39m-fiber-service-utah-1">the Associated Press</a>, Google will buy the existing network -- which cost $39 million to build -- for only $1.</p>
<p>The Mountain View, Calif.-based firm is taking an unusual step in its roadmap by <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-fiber-speeds-up-with-new-destination-provo-utah-7000014181/">buying an existing fiber-optic network</a>, but it's not difficult to see why. Under the terms of the deal, Google will complete the network's construction and upgrade the system so it offers Provo residents gigabit connections, which are touted to be 100 times faster than current broadband speeds. The city will have to pay remaining loans resultant of the $39 million build, but if Google decides the merger isn't working out, the firm has a get-out clause -- it can sell the network back to the city for the same symbolic dollar.</p>
<p>Provo is approximately 45 miles south of Salt Lake City, and has a population of 115,000 residents. If the deal is voted in, then the city will be the third extension of Google Fiber's city roadmap. At the moment, according to the publication, Provo residents have been paying a little over $5 a month for their Internet, television and phone services. However, if residents agree to sign up to a $30 connection fee, then they will receive basic Internet services at no charge.</p>
<p>Google has five years to complete Provo's fiber network. In <a href="http://googlefiberblog.blogspot.com/2013/04/silicon-slopes.html">a blog post</a> Wednesday, Google Fiber general manager Kevin Lo explained why Provo is of interest to the firm:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Utah is already home to hundreds of tech companies and startups, and many of them are based in Provo. In fact, the Provo area ranks second in the nation in patent growth, and is consistently ranked as one of the top places to live and do business in the U.S."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The high-speed Internet service will join fiber networks expanding across the U.S. Last month, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-fiber-approved-for-expansion-7000012879/">Google announced</a> that residents in Olathe, Kansas, would join those waiting in Westwood, Westwood Hills and Mission Woods, Kan. that would have access to the network in the near future, although "a lot of planning and engineering work" is required first.</p>
<p>Google Fiber is currently available in Kansas City, KS, and Kansas City, MO, with Austin, Texas marked as the next city for the service to launch.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014265</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/10-geeky-things-to-do-in-space-7000014265/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[10 geeky things to do in space]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Ever wondered how to dissolve an antacid tablet in space? Have a look at these cool activities you could do in orbit.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 10:23:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Eileen Brown]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Gallery]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/qHrBhgwq__Q?rel=0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: ReelNASA</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/xICkLB3vAeU" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Canadian space agency</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/o8TssbmY-GM?rel=0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Canadian space agency</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CrTUpTDyGpI?rel=0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Reel NASA</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zxDUSibU3SI?rel=0" height="315" width="420"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Benwl</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/iGiQZIb34_s?rel=0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Video from space</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/qxk3VqZZBsw?rel=0" height="315" width="420"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Terry Johnson</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/cOrJqFDAKcw?rel=0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Naughty Miss Tee</p><p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/P0Ihg-77aos?rel=0" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p>Credit: Phobosuchus1</p><p>Not geeky - but something we all want to know about. </p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/opGts0hjOKM?rel=0" height="315" width="420"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;Credit: Michael Interbartolo</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014245</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/macbook-pro-with-retina-display-45-days-in-7000014245/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[MacBook Pro with Retina Display: 45 days in]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[One and a half months ago I broke down and replaced my aging MacBook with a 13-inch MacBook Pro. This laptop rocks a Retina Display and is my primary desktop system. Paired with an inexpensive gadget it is a great tool for my work.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:55:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apple/">Apple</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-laptops/">Laptops</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="MBP" alt="MBP" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014245/mbp-600x407.jpg?hash=LwV0ZQp3LG&upscale=1" height="407" width="600"></figure>
<p>The MacBook I used for years was flagging and in need of replacement. I originally <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/why-i-bought-a-macbook-air-7000011676/">ordered a MacBook Air</a> but cancelled the order since the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/the-chromebook-pixel-cost-me-a-lot-of-money-7000011711/">Chromebook Pixel spoiled me for a Retina Display</a>. The 13-inch MacBook Pro arrived 45 days ago and has become my primary desktop system. It has already served me well and I am happy with the purchase.</p>
<p>The model I ordered has a 2.6 GHz Intel Core i5 processor paired with 8 GB of memory. The 256 GB solid-state disk (SSD) has enough free space to keep me comfortable for a good while. This configuration is faster than I thought it would be and it handles all tasks with ease.</p>
<p>The 13-inch Retina Display is simply gorgeous and I am so glad I cancelled the MacBook Air for this model. It helped that Apple recently dropped the price $200 to make the switch more palatable.</p>
<p>I use the MacBook Pro as my primary desktop system. The display is so good that it's all I use. In the past I have used a laptop with a large external display at the desk but this laptop screen is all I have needed and I have no immediate plans to get a monitor to use with it.</p>
<p>I use an old Magic Mouse at the desk but mostly for gaming. The trackpad is my preferred pointer for regular work tasks.</p>
<p>I occasionally take the laptop for working remotely but most of the time it stays at the desk. It works fine when taken mobile but I have other gadgets which work well for day trips. I usually grab something smaller and lighter to throw in the bag.</p>
<p>I am very pleased with the purchase and how the MacBook Pro has handled desktop duty. It works better than I expected with no shortfalls.</p>
<p>The short list of apps I have installed get me through my work day with ease.</p>
<ul>
<li>SnagIt: Screen capture tool</li>
<li>Google Play Music Manager: Utility that automatically brings Google Play music purchases into iTunes</li>
<li>Google Drive: Finder integration for my Google Drive cloud storage</li>
<li>Evernote: My favorite cross-platform note taking app</li>
<li>iMovie: Used for video productions</li>
<li>Air Display: Connects my iPad or iPad mini via wi-fi for use as an external monitor when convenient</li>
<li>Logmein: App that lets me control the MacBook remotely from either iOS or Android</li>
</ul>
<p>One of the special purposes that drove me to purchase a new MacBook is video production for product reviews. The reviews are edited, encoded, and then uploaded to YouTube for inclusion in reviews.&nbsp;</p>
<p>By far the greatest amount of time with video reviews is spent in the encoding of the video. This is especially true for HD video, and while the MacBook Pro is pretty fast I found a little gadget that greatly reduces the time required for encoding.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Elgato Turbo" alt="Elgato Turbo" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014245/elgato-turbo-200x102.jpg?hash=MwL2ZTEzMG&upscale=1" height="102" width="200"><figcaption>Elgato Turbo.264</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Elgato-Turbo-264-Encoder-Computers-10020196/dp/B0021AEPTY/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1366336999&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=elgato+turbo.264+hd">Elgato Turbo.264</a> is a USB "stick" that plugs into the MacBook and takes over the encoding duty from the laptop processor. It is simply amazing how fast the Elgato encodes video. True HD video is encoded in near real-time in the little USB device which greatly reduces the post-production time required.</p>
<p>I bought the Elgato on Amazon for $85 and consider it a good investment. It comes with its own video software but I use it directly with iMovie for simple encoding. The Elgato is recognized when plugged in and just works.</p>
<p>I am very happy with the MacBook Pro and have no complaints at all, which is unusual for a gadget. There is nothing I wish it did differently or better, and I consider it worth the money I paid.</p>
<p><strong>See related: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a >75 days with a MacBook Pro</a> (Adrian Kingsley-Hughes)</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-hands-on-photos-7000011694/">Chromebook Pixel hands on (photos)</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a >Why I bought a MacBook Air</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a >The Chromebook Pixel cost me a lot of money</a></strong></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014267</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/toshiba-kirabook-is-latest-windows-laptop-competitor-to-take-on-apple-macbook-pro-7000014267/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Toshiba Kirabook is latest Windows laptop competitor to take on Apple MacBook Pro]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The swanky and svelte notebook starts at $1,599.99 when it becomes available in May.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:45:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Sean Portnoy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="toshiba-kirabook-laptop-notebook-ultrabook-macbook" alt="toshiba-kirabook-laptop-notebook-ultrabook-macbook" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014267/toshiba-kirabook-laptop-notebook-ultrabook-macbook-606x445.jpg?hash=MwD3LmtkMQ&upscale=1" height="445" width="606"></figure>
<p>There's lots of hand wringing about the high price of Windows 8 laptops and Ultrabooks contributing to sales declines in the PC market, but that hasn't stopped manufacturers from embracing costly Windows 8 Ultrabooks to compete against Apple's MacBook Pro lineup.</p>
<p>Following on the heels of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/samsung-boosts-series-9-premium-ultrabook-screen-to-1080p-resolution-7000013105/" target="_self">Samsung's Series 9 notebook family</a>, Toshiba's <a href="http://us.toshiba.com/kira/home" target="_blank">new Kirabook lineup</a> is a luxury bid that features premium, well, everything. From its AZ91&nbsp;pressed magnesium alloy body and&nbsp;Corning Concore Glass display for touchscreen configurations to its&nbsp;2,560x1,440 13.3-inch screen, nothing about the Kirabook screams "budget laptop." Toshiba touts the chassis material, claiming it's 100-percent stronger than aluminum alloy and unique in the Ultrabook category, as well as its&nbsp;AirFlow II fan cooling technology.</p>
<p>Like its competitors, the Kirabook is super-svelte, starting at 2.66 pounds and 0.7 inches thick and its narrowest point. It also comes with a two-year warranty, in an age when a one-year warranty is usually the norm, and&nbsp;Toshiba's Platinum Service &amp; Support.</p>
<p>None of this comes cheap, of course, no matter which of the three configurations you choose. Starting at $1,599.99, the base model includes an&nbsp;Intel Core i5-3337U processor, 8GB of RAM, 256GB solid state drive, and Windows 8 Pro. (Not surprisingly, given the form factor, no optical drive is included.) You can add touchscreen capabilities to this model for an additional $200, while the top-of-the-line flavor includes a touchscreen and bumps the CPU up to a&nbsp;&nbsp;Core i7-3537U for $1,999.99.</p>
<p>Our sister site CNET got <a href="http://www.cnet.com/laptops/toshiba-kirabook/4505-3121_7-35667194.html" target="_self">some hands-on time with the Kirabook</a> and while its Retina-like display was impressive, pricing was obviously a concern for what else you get. It's going to be difficult to sell many premium Windows Ultrabooks that cost more than some versions of the MacBook Pro, but maybe Toshiba will have better luck with the Kirabook. Do you think so? Let us know in the Talkback section below.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014233</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/my-experiments-with-installing-ubuntu-13-04-pre-release-with-uefi-boot-7000014233/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[My experiments with installing Ubuntu 13.04 (pre-release) with UEFI Boot]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Live image is Secure Boot compatible, but the installed system is not?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:30:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[J.A. Watson]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Gallery]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-open-source/">Open Source</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-operating-systems/">Operating Systems</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ubuntu/">Ubuntu</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I said last week after posting galleries for installing <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/opensuse-uefi-secure-boot-installation-how-i-did-it-7000013311/">openSuSE 12.3</a> and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/how-i-installed-fedora-18-with-uefi-secure-boot-7000013464/">Fedora 18</a> with UEFI Boot that I would do the same with Ubuntu when it got a little closer to the final release.&nbsp; It is now one week until the release, so I suppose it is time. The following installation was done using the Raring Ringtail Daily Build for 17 April 2013.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Of course it is possible that some things might still change in the week before the release, but as time gets shorter that gets increasingly unlikely &mdash; still, my point is there is no guarantee that any particular part, feature or bug discussed here will still be the same in the final release.</p>
<p>The Ubuntu Live ISO image includes UEFI Secure Boot compatibility. When you boot it, you can choose between going directly into the installer (<em>ubiquity</em>) or going to a live desktop.&nbsp; If you choose the latter, there is then an icon on the desktop to start the installer.</p>
<p>The first screen in the installer has the language select, and a whole lot of empty space. I find this a bit baffling, why not fill that space with something, even if it is only Ubuntu propoganda?&nbsp; Seems like a waste to me, but perhaps there is a reason for it.</p><p>The next screen checks and confirms the installation environment.</p>
<p>Note that it says at the top "<em>For best results</em>..." these are not strict requirements they are suggestions. If there is not sufficient disk space available, you will have the opportunity to free some more, or assign some existing partition(s) to this installation; if you are are brave enough to start the installation without power connected, that's up to you &mdash; if you don't have an internet connection, there are a couple of optional things you won't be able to select during the installation but otherwise the basic installation will work just fine.</p>
<p>If you have an internet connection, you can choose to have <em>ubiquity</em> download and install the latest updates during installation, and you can also have it install some commonly used third-party software packages along with the installation.</p><p>If your system has a WiFi network adapter, this screen gives you the opportunity to make a wireless connection.&nbsp; Well, sort of. There should be a list of available networks shown here, but I was doing this installation on my HP Pavilion dm1-4310, and Ubuntu still doesn't include the firmware for its Ralink 3290 WiFi adapter, so it only shows the name of the adapter, rather than the SSID list.</p><p>This is the first step in determining the disk partitioning.&nbsp; If your computer only has Windows installed, and you want <em>ubiquity</em> to shrink the Windows C: partition to make room to install Ubuntu, all you have to do here is leave it on the default "Install alongside them".&nbsp; But my system has a bunch of other stuff on it already, so I choose "Something else", which will take me to a partitioner where I can do exactly what I want.&nbsp; Of course, I could have also chosen to have <em>ubiquity</em> wipe the disk clean and install Ubuntu alone...</p><p>Because I chose "Something Else" in the previous screen, <em>ubiquity</em> now takes me to this disk partitioning screen.&nbsp; This shows the current partitions with their sizes, both in the table and in the colored graphic display at the top of the window.</p>
<p>Unfortunately when the partition layout is large and/or complex, the graph is not scaled so it just shows the first part and then runs off the edge of the window. That is not a problem, but it can be confusing if you haven't seen it before - I just ignore it.</p>
<p>This screen is where I think the Ubuntu installation with UEFI gets a bit confusing. It shows the EFI Boot partition, and has it correctly labeled as <em>efi</em> in the 'type' column, but it gives absolutely no indication that it is actually going to do anything with that, or for that matter it is not even obvious that it is going to make a UEFI-compatible installation at all.&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is a column labeled 'mount point', and it doesn't show that the efi partition will be mounted, but in fact when the installation in complete, that is what will happen, and I don't need to do anything here about it. It just occurred to me that the same is true of the <em>swap</em> partition, it is labeled correctly but there is no indication that it will be properly configured and used, but it will be. Oh well, I just press on and see how it turns out.</p>
<p>In fact, the only thing I need to do here is designate the root partition, which is shown in the next screen shot.</p><p>At this point I have scrolled down the partition list in the previous screen and selected the partition where I want to install Ubuntu, and clicked <em>Change</em>. Once again, I find this window to be short of information - in this case, it doesn't say what partition we have selected.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Yes, I know, I must have just selected it to get here, but would it really be that hard to be user friendly and add the partition name at the top? I can't tell you how many times I have done this, and then had to move this window so that I could see the parition list under it and be sure that I had selected the correct one.</p>
<p>Oh, and another thing I had to watch out for - <em>ubiquity</em> has a nasty habit of popping this window up with the 'Size' set to 1MB <em>more</em> than whatever the current size of the partition is. I don't know why it does this, but if I leave it like that, it will want to resize the partition - and if the disk is full, as mine is, that will fail.&nbsp; Ugh.</p>
<p>So I check this, and if it is too large, set it back to the correct (current) size.</p>
<p>You also have to select the filesystem type from the drop-down list in the 'Use as'<strong>:</strong> field, and specify the 'Mount point' and whether you want to format it (although in many cases it will automatically be formatted, regardless of what you specify here).</p><p>This screen asks for confirmation before <em>ubiquity</em> goes off and starts fiddling with disk partitions.</p>
<p>I'm a bit confused by it, to be honest, I'm not sure when or why it shows up - I know what would make sense (if I have changed the partition size or type, or specifically formatted it) but that doesn't seem to correspond with how it really acts.&nbsp; Maybe I'm just confused, or maybe it is just being over-cautious.&nbsp; Anyway, when I am happy with the input I just click 'Continue'.</p><p>Now we are back at the partitioner display, and it shows the selection for the root filesystem.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the UEFI Boot gets even more confusing here. It still doesn't show that it is going to do anything with the efi partition (you can't see it here, but trust me that part still looks exctly as it did two screens ago), and now it is still giving you a choice of the 'Device for Bootloader installation'. What the heck does that mean?&nbsp;</p>
<p>If it is going to do a UEFI Boot installation, then it will install the bootloader to the efi partition so why does it need you to select anything here? Or perhaps you are supposed to select the EFI parition?&nbsp;</p>
<p>Or is it going to make new efi partition for its own use, like Fedora does by default?&nbsp;</p>
<p>Or is it going to install the legacy boot loader to wherever you select here?&nbsp; I just don't understand what it wants.&nbsp;</p>
<p>All I can tell you is that I am paranoid enough that I don't want to risk having it install the bootloader to the MBR (or turn the entire sda device into one huge EFI boot partition? Ack!), so i always change this the partition which will contain the root filesystem.&nbsp;</p>
<p>To be honest, what I suspect is that when doing a UEFI Boot installation this input field is ignored, but I have never seen that documented anywhere, so who really knows for sure?</p>
<p>When I click on 'Install Now', <em>ubiquity</em> will do just that - it goes off in the background and starts performing the installation. At the same time, it will progress to the next screen and continue the user input.</p><p>This is where you select the timezone, by clicking on the map. As far as I can tell, <em>only</em> by clicking on the map.&nbsp; I haven't been able to get the text bar to do anything useful.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you happen to live in a relatively small country, such as Switzerland, it can be challenging to find the right place to click.</p><p>This is where you select your default keyboard layout. There is a text input box where you can type after making the selection, to be sure that you chose the right one. If you aren't sure, or you just feel like a laugh, you can go through the "Detect Keyboard Layout" procedure.</p><p>Finally, the last input screen. Here you enter the usual stuff - your full name and login name, the computer nodename, and your password.&nbsp; You can also choose automatic login on boot, if security is not a concern for you.</p><p>While you have been giving input in the last few screens, <em>ubiquity</em> has been chugging along with the installation.&nbsp; After you finish the last screen, you will join the installation in progress. The status bar at the bottom of the window will show how far along it is, and you will get a slide show of Ubuntu features while it finishes.</p><p>When the installation is complete, I am prompted to reboot (or continue working with the Live system).&nbsp;</p>
<p>On both of my UEFI systems, I got the same surprise with Ubuntu that I had already gotten with openSuSE and Fedora - reboot didn't bring up Ubuntu, it still brought up whatever was booted before I did any of this (in most cases this will be Windows 8).&nbsp;</p>
<p>Now, there may be other systems, from other manufacturers, which do in fact get UEFI boot parameters set, stored and stable properly so that they boot Ubuntu, but that hasn't been my experience.&nbsp; Oh, and there is another even bigger problem...</p>
<p>If you still have Secure Boot enabled, which was the purpose of this exercise, then when you finally do try to boot Ubuntu (probably by pressing Boot Select) you are going to be very surprised to find that it doesn't boot.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Seriously.&nbsp;</p>
<p>At least, it didn't for me, on either one of my systems. What the heck is that about?&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Live image on a USB stick worked just fine with Secure Boot enabled, but the installed system won't?&nbsp; Really? I must be wrong about this. I must be confused. I must be doing something wrong. But I can't figure out what, and I have installed Ubuntu 13.04 quite a few times now over the past six weeks or so.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I keep thinking this is some kind of pre-release problem, and they will get it sorted out before the final release, but time is running out.</p>
<p>Anyway, although I hope that they get this working, if they don't then you will have to disable Secure Boot for Ubuntu. Note that this means <em>only</em> secure boot, it works just fine with UEFI Boot then, you don't have to go all the way back to Legacy Boot.</p>
<p>Oh, and one last note for others who might have a system with the same Ralink 3290 WiFi adapter my HP has. Although it doesn't work with Ubuntu 13.04 out of the box (at this stage), it actually has the correct kernal and drivers, all that is missing is the firmware file. I was able to "cheat" and copy the file /lib/firmware/rt3290.bin from either openSuSE 12.3 or Fedora 18, and then after rebooting it works just fine. If you don't have one of those distributions, I believe that you can pick up the firmware file from the Rallink web page.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014266</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/sony-hacker-sentenced-to-a-year-in-prison-7000014266/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Sony hacker sentenced to a year in prison]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A member of the LulzSec group has been given a year behind bars after pleading guilty to breaching Sony's servers. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:26:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="lulznomore" alt="lulznomore" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014266/lulznomore-620x349.jpg?hash=AQR3MzEuBQ&upscale=1" height="349" width="620"><figcaption>Credit: C.Osborne/ZDNet</figcaption></figure>
<p>LulzSec member Cody Kretsinger will spend one year in prison for his role in breaching the defenses of Sony Pictures Entertainment servers.</p>
<p>The hacker pleaded guilty in April 2012 to one count of conspiracy and one count of unauthorized impairment of a protected computer, according <a href="/story/create/&quot;http:/www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/18/us-usa-lulzsec-hacker-idUSBRE93H10K20130418">to Reuters</a>.</p>
<p>Kretsinger -- also known as "Recursion," -- is part of LulzSec, an offshoot group from hacktivist collective Anonymous. LulzSec first came to attention in 2011, after a number of pranks including <a href="http://crave.cnet.co.uk/software/lulzsec-hacks-the-sun-claiming-rupert-murdoch-is-dead-50004459/">hacking The Sun's website</a> to proclaim that Rupert Murdoch was dead entered the spotlight, as well as the group's role in coming to the defense of whistleblower website WikiLeaks. However, these pranks later turned into Sony's worst nightmare -- as the group stole the credentials and information of over 70 million user accounts of both PlayStation Network and Sony Online members.</p>
<p>This security breach led to Sony closing down the network for a month. The Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) in the U.K. later fined the firm 250,000 for what it considered a "serious breach of the Data Protection Act" for not keeping customer data adequately protected. Prosecutors say that the network breach cost Sony over $600,000 in damages.</p>
<p>The 25 year-old has been ordered by a U.S. district judge in Los Angeles to serve 12 months before performing 1,000 hours of community service upon release. Although prosecutors refused to say whether the hacker was co-operating with authorities in return for a softer sentence, a leading member of Anonymous, "Sabu," in reality Hector Xavier Monsegur, has pleaded guilty to similar charges and offered the FBI information on other hackers.</p>
<p>Last week, three other members of LulzSec -- Ryan Ackroyd, Jake Davis, and Mustafa al-Bassam -- all pleaded guilty to a computer hacking-related charge at Southwark Crown Court in London. Between them, <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57578654-93/lulzsec-hackers-plead-guilty-to-attacks-on-sony-nintendo-more/">the hackers admitted</a> to trying to hack into various websites related to Nintendo and Sony, as well as plotting to take down law enforcement agency websites based in the U.S. and United Kingdom.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014230</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/vodafone-icici-bank-india-launch-m-pesa-mobile-wallet-7000014230/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Vodafone, ICICI Bank India launch M-Pesa mobile wallet]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Vodafone India and ICICI Bank India officially roll out the M-Pesa mobile wallet, bringing the mobile money transfer and payment service to the local market.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 09:19:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Nitin Puri]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vodafone India and ICICI Bank India have rolled out M-Pesa, bringing the mobile money transfer and payment service to the local market.</p>
<p>Initially announced in November with&nbsp;Vodafone India's subsidiary, Mobile Commerce Solutions Limited (MCSL) and ICICI Bank, the service allows users to transfer money to any mobile phone in India and also remit money to any bank account in India. Within&nbsp;India, the service is initially rolled out in Bihar, Kolkata, and West Bengal, with over 8,300 authorized agents and will soon be rolled out nationwide in phases.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a >Vodafone offers M-Pesa</a>&nbsp;globally in different regions via partnerships with mobile carriers and leading banks.</p>
<p>The service is available only to Vodafone customers, who can sign up for the service by visiting an M-Pesa agent outlet to fill in a form and providing address verification and photo identification. A minimum deposit is required to open the M-Pesa account.</p>
<p>Upon registration, Vodafone India will activate the MCSL mobile wallet for the customer, so it can be used as a closed wallet for transactions such as cash deposits, money transfers to any bank account, and to another M-Pesa customer. The service can also be used to top up credit on mobile phones and make payments, along with making payments for DTH (direct-to-home) services and utility bills.&nbsp;</p>
<p>According to the ICICI Bank's&nbsp;<a title="M-Pesa website" href="http://www.icicibank.com/mobile-banking/mpesa/m-pesa.html" target="_blank">M-Pesa&nbsp;Web site</a>, customers are required to make an&nbsp;initial&nbsp;minimum deposit of 200 rupees (US$3.71), of which 100 rupees (US$1.85) is deducted as a one-time account activation fee and the remaining balance is credited to the account balance. The maximum daily limit for funds transfer is 5,000 rupees&nbsp;(US$92.6)&nbsp;a day and the maximum daily limit for prepaid mobile credit topup is 2,500 rupees (US$46.3).</p>
<p>M-Pesa mobile wallets can have a maximum account balance of 10,000 rupees (US$185.3), while Mobile Wallet and Mobile Money accounts can have a maximum account balance of 50,000 rupees (US$926.6).</p>
<p>M-Pesa is a great service to finally introduce and implement in India as many users in <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/mobile-banking-yet-to-take-off-in-rural-india-2062202064/">rural India</a> don't have easy access to banks. They have to go to great lengths and distances for these services and to make these transactions. Furthermore, having the ability to top up your phone credit on-the-go, and for someone else, is also another great feature as not all vendors have top-up facilities for all <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/indian-banks-must-heighten-mobile-focus-2062208254/">mobile phone operators</a> in India.&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014259</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/cn/yahoo-china-ceases-email-services-7000014259/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Yahoo China to cease e-mail service]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Alibaba Group says Yahoo China's e-mail service will shut down on August 19, and advises users to start migrating their data to its alternative e-mail service called Aliyun.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 08:32:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Cyrus Lee]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-china/">China</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yahoo China will cease its e-mail service on August 19 and has advised users to register for an account with Alibaba's e-mail service, called Aliyun, to retain their data.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://migration.cn.yahoo.com/explain.php" target="_blank">In an announcement Thursday</a>, titled "Yahoo China's e-mail services start overall migration on April 18, 2013", Alibaba Group&nbsp;said Yahoo's e-mail service will only remain available for the following four months. The <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cn/alibaba-buys-backs-half-of-yahoo-stake-for-7-6b-7000004465/">Chinese Web giant owns Yahoo's operations in China</a>.</p>
<p>With an <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cn/alibabas-aliyun-os-hopes-to-be-android-of-china-7000003937/">Aliyun</a> account, Yahoo China e-mail users will be able to retain e-mail messages and continue to receive e-mail sent to their Yahoo Mail account even after it ceases operations in August. However, this e-mail redirect will only be supported until December 31, 2014.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The announcement comes as Alibaba prepares to reduce its dependence on Yahoo's global infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Zhang Jianhua, Yahoo China's&nbsp;public relations executive,&nbsp;<a >told Chinese media</a>&nbsp;the company's e-mail services were supported by the U.S. headquarters' global unified mailbox-based systems. As mutual agreements between both companies only allow Alibaba to use the system for four more years--from 2012--the company is making moves now to give users options as early as possible,&nbsp;Zhang said.</p>
<p>Chinese media, however, suggested the termination of agreement between the two companies played only a minor part of the cease of service today. They pointed to Yahoo China's diminishing market presence.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Over the past six years, the market share of e-mail service providers have altered dramatically in the country. Five local services providers including Tencent and NetEase had seized majority share, while Yahoo China slumped to sixth position, according to&nbsp;<a >Hitwise data</a>.</p>
<p>The data also showed that termination of Yahoo China's e-mail services will only affect 2 percent of e-mail users in the country. Market share of Yahoo's e-mail service in China has continued to shrink over the past 12 months to its current 1.9 percent.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alibaba in 2005&nbsp;sold 40 percent of its stock to Yahoo in a US$1 billion deal to acquire the latter's China operations. Last year, the Chinese Web giant <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cn/alibaba-buys-backs-half-of-yahoo-stake-for-7-6b-7000004465/">bought back half of the stake</a> Yahoo owns for US$7.6 billion as it <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/report-alibaba-prepping-ipo-with-help-from-credit-suisse-goldman-sachs-7000009909/">preps for its initial public offering</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014260</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/blackstone-drops-out-of-the-race-to-bid-for-dell-report-7000014260/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Blackstone drops out of the race to bid for Dell: report]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Blackstone has reportedly withdrawn its plans to counteract a buyout offer for Dell, leaving the firm's fate in the hands of a rival firm and its founder. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 08:05:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Private equity investment firm Blackstone Group has ended its plans to counteract a buyout offer from Silver Lake and Michael Dell, less than a month after the company's intentions were made public.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="dell blackstone silver lake buyout offer withdrawn " alt="dell blackstone silver lake buyout offer withdrawn " src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014260/dell-logo-320px-200x200-200x200-200x200.jpg?hash=ZGx2A2AvZm&upscale=1" height="200" width="200"></figure>
<p>Blackstone planned to buy the majority of Dell's remaining stock for $14.25 a share in order to compete with a buyout offer led by private equity firm Silver Lake and the PC maker's founder Michael Dell, according to <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/report-blackstone-drops-race-buy-031908315.html;_ylt=Ahoj6Hea16wxnRSTacut4PsCuodG;_ylu=X3oDMTQwa3I5OGw4BG1pdANUb3AgU3RvcnkgQ29sbGVjdGlvbnMEcGtnAzViYzgyZDIyLWZjZDItMzc5NS05MTUyLTA2NmE1ZWFiZjQ4OARwb3MDMTgEc2VjA3RvcF9zdG9yeQR2ZXIDZDg5YTFlODAtYThhNy0xMWUyLTlkZjYtOGNhOGQ2ZTQxMjBi;_ylg=X3oDMTMwZGVmaGc1BGludGwDdXMEbGFuZwNlbi11cwRwc3RhaWQDZTQyZDg3NWMtZDMyNi0zMzBiLWE5NTYtZTVlZmJjMmI1MjZkBHBzdGNhdAMEcHQDc2VjdGlvbnMEdGVzdANUZXN0X0FGQw--;_ylv=3">the Associated Press</a>. The latter's offer stands at $24.4 billion, at the time made on a share-price premium, but left a number of shareholders less than appeased.</p>
<p>Outside investors including Southeastern Asset Management and T. Rowe Price have vehemently opposed the deal. Shareholder Catherine Christner has taken the matter further, <a href="http://media.bloomberg.com/bb/avfile/reUNPQrR9qwM">filing a complaint</a> with Delaware Chancery Court alleging that Dell's board of directors have breached their fiduciary duties, and Silver Lake has "aided and abetted those breaches."</p>
<p>The disgruntled shareholder also claims that Michael Dell has "abused his position as CEO," and the PC maker is being bought "on the cheap."</p>
<p>Michael Dell -- who owns a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/amid-buyout-anger-dell-offers-investors-financial-data-7000012599/">15.7 percent stake</a> in the company -- wants the firm to go private. This means that not only will financial statements be denied to Wall Street, but the control of future business strategy will be stripped from investing parties.</p>
<p>If Blackstone's plans had come to fruition, then a higher proportion of the company would have remained in the hands of public shareholders, an important factor as the deal requires majority approval from shareholders excluding the PC maker's founder.</p>
<p>The private equity firm's offer of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/michael-dell-likely-to-boost-buyout-offer-report-7000013063/">$14.25 a share</a> trumps the founder and Silver Lake's $13.65 per share valuation, but if reports prove sound, the loss of a bidder will have to be disclosed in coming days by Dell management.</p>
<p>A bidding war <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dell-as-blackstone-icahn-circle-is-there-significant-upside-left-7000013078/">could still take place</a>, as investor Carl Icahn has also submitted an offer of up to $15 per share for 58 percent of Dell's stock, and Dell's CEO may in turn <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/michael-dell-likely-to-boost-buyout-offer-report-7000013063/">counter with a higher bid</a>; a situation which can only benefit shareholders who feel that if the firm goes private, they will not be able to reap the rewards of the company's awaited recovery.</p>
<p>Michael Dell believes that the PC maker could do well in the tablet and cloud computing markets. As the PC market continues to deteriorate -- worldwide shipments <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/idc-global-pc-shipments-plunge-in-worst-drop-in-a-generation-7000013839/">sliding 14 percent</a> in the first three months of 2013, according to Gartner -- the world's third largest maker of PCs will need to adjust to the times. However, the company's founder does not believe this can be achieved, considering Wall Street's fixation on short-term results, if Dell continues its 25-year stint as a publicly-trading company.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013881</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/in/how-far-should-startups-integrate-facebook-open-graph-7000013881/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[How far should startups integrate Facebook Open Graph?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Startups should consider integrating the social media function into their products and create buzz and brand awareness, but how far should they go?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 07:17:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Srinivas Kulkarni]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Certainly, this isn't something that is very new and is something that Mark Zuckerberg and his team had in mind when they released the API (application programming interface) for <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-extends-social-network-with-open-graph-3040088730/">Facebook's Open Graph</a>. Of course, there's now also <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-unveils-next-step-for-sharing-user-content-graph-search-7000009844/">Open Graph Search</a> which can change the way people search for businesses on the social Web.&nbsp;</p>
<p>One very interesting phenomenon I noticed lately and wrote about in a different blog post was the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/facebook/42-of-urls-have-facebook-open-graph-tags/13107">progress of Facebook's Open Graph</a> and how products were using and spreading the feature&nbsp;within their timelines, thus, reaching out to different users on what activities they were carrying out.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Is this something that is required? I'm going to have to say yes, but whether it is something that should be an integral part of a startup's product, I'll have to say no.&nbsp;</p>
<p>A lot of users these days are fascinated with applications that are intuitive and at the same time can allow them to quickly connect to Facebook. So one of the first things that a lot of users might prefer, as much as it would be a bad idea for them to do, is to sign up for services using <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/facebook-connect-the-masses-and-the-fishbowl/11029">Facebook Connect</a>.&nbsp;So your products should support this and should have a verification aspect to it as well.</p>
<p>Essentially whatever you do on your product, it would be a good thing to encourage people to share their real-life experience. This is&nbsp;becoming popular culture especially since a lot of us are using various applications that already include Open Graph as part of their ecosystem and are integrated tightly with Facebook.</p>
<figure class="alignLeft"><img title="Screenshot-1-Botification1-300x196" alt="Screenshot-1-Botification1-300x196" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013881/screenshot-1-botification1-300x196-200x131.png?hash=BJV2BJEzMG&upscale=1" height="131" width="200"></figure>
<p>Take a look at my activities. Something I addressed in this <a href="http://www.srinistuff.in/2013/04/business2community-facebooks-open-graph.html" target="_blank">blog</a>&nbsp;is&nbsp;how the integration of Facebook Open Graph with products is making our life very "bot-like" and very few updates involve actual human interactions. For example, my updates would look something like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>I biked 10 kms via Runkeeper</li>
<li>I read Steve Jobs on GoodRead</li>
<li>I checked in at McDonalds, Mumbai</li>
<li>I am watching The House of Cards on GetGlue</li>
<li>I pinned Paris to "Places I want to Travel to"</li>
<li>I viewed "How to Sell Better" on Slideshare</li>
</ul>
<p>However, at the same time, I would say it's a really interesting for startups to offer products that&nbsp;actually capitalize on an opportunity that's gaining&nbsp;great momentum and feed into timelines of other users, as well as create buzz and brand awareness about the startup brands.&nbsp;</p>
<p>One such product is <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/how-online-learning-with-lurnq-is-more-social-and-clutter-free-7000013593/">LurnQ</a>, which I featured here a couple of weeks ago. I'm sure there are many other startups in India that are already doing this.</p>
<p>What I'd particularly like to know is, from a user perspective, do you think it's a good idea or would you prefer to have a certain amount of control over what kind of content is shared--albeit, the products will typically give you the option, tucked away in a corner of some settings, or on Facebook to disable it. By default, usually the option is set to be shared automatically.&nbsp;</p>
<p>What's your take as a product builder or as a user&nbsp;on Facebook Open Graph?</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014256</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/wordpress-attack-highlights-30-million-targets-7000014256/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[WordPress attack highlights 30 million targets]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The recent botnet attack on websites running WordPress hasn't had much impact &mdash; yet. But with millions of vulnerable sites and a knowledge gap at the low end of the market, things could get much, much worse.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 05:47:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Stilgherrian]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-web-development/">Web development</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It'd be easy to dismiss the recent reports of a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/wordpress-hit-by-massive-botnet-worse-to-come-experts-warn-7000014019/">botnet attack</a> on sites running the WordPress content management system (CMS) as yet another cry-wolf scare story from an exaggeration-prone web hosting company eager for business. After all, <a href="http://blog.cloudflare.com/patching-the-internet-fixing-the-wordpress-br">one of the earliest posts</a> about the attack was from CloudFlare, and they've got form.</p>
<p>Less than a month ago, CloudFlare chief executive officer Matthew Prince spun the distributed denial of service (DDoS) attack against Spamhaus into <a href="http://blog.cloudflare.com/the-ddos-that-almost-broke-the-internet">"The DDoS that almost broke the internet"</a>, and he shamelessly <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/27/technology/internet/online-dispute-becomes-internet-snarling-attack.html?_r=0">told <em>The New York Times</em></a> that "These things are essentially like nuclear bombs ... It's so easy to cause so much damage."</p>
<p>An extreme cynic might even note that this botnet, claimed to be 90,000 computers strong, is conducting brute-force password-guessing against WordPress sites around the planet just days after <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/two-step-authentication/">WordPress.com announced two-factor authentication</a> for sites hosted on its own infrastructure &mdash; just the thing to mitigate against that risk. I couldn't possibly comment.</p>
<p>But despite the lack of vaporised cities and radioactive fallout, or even any serious impact so far, these WordPress attacks have the potential to get a lot worse &mdash; thanks to the very factors that make WordPress such a popular CMS.</p>
<p>WordPress' big selling point is ease of use. That means it has massive appeal right at the bottom end of the market.</p>
<p>Down at this level, even in 2013, websites are usually little more than static brochureware that gets updated rarely, if at all. With nothing to change, the sites' owners don't log into WordPress, so they don't see the software upgrade notices. Or if they do, they don't know what they mean.</p>
<p>This is where businesses are reluctant to spend even a thousand dollars on a site, so asking them to fork over more money for "maintenance" is a waste of time &mdash; what visible difference does it make?</p>
<p>Besides, they'll say, they have someone who "takes care of" their website.</p>
<p>That someone is generally a "web designer", not a developer. WordPress has been a boon for them. Its multitudinous free or cheap themes and plugins make it possible to build a decent website with plenty of functionality without having to dirty their hands with actual code. Or dirty their minds understanding it.</p>
<p>Forgive me, for I'm about to commit the sin of extrapolating from personal experience, but in nearly two decades, I have yet to encounter a "web designer" with halfway-decent security practices &mdash; by which I mean creating a different login for every human rather than a generic "admin" account, creating strong passwords, not reusing passwords, deleting unused accounts, and not blithely emailing a business' master internet hosting password to any sub-contractor who might need momentary access.</p>
<p>Indeed, many of those I've encountered have deliberately set the WordPress admin password (or its equivalent in pre-WordPress days) to be exactly the same as their client's hosting account master password, their domain registry password, the login on their PC, and everything else in sight to "make it easier" &mdash; because that gets rid of those annoying "I've lost my password" support calls.</p>
<p>WordPress is now the tool of choice for these people, and they've built millions of WordPress websites.</p>
<p>But have they maintained them? No.</p>
<p>As I write this, the <a href="http://wordpress.org/download/counter/">WordPress download counter</a> tells me that 17,594,130 people have downloaded the current WordPress version 3.5 and, erm, counting. But over at the <a href="http://wordpress.org/about/stats/">statistics page</a>, a rather alarming pie chart tells us that version 3.5 accounts for only 30.5 percent of running WordPress installations.</p>
<p>More than two-thirds of WordPress installations are running versions with known security vulnerabilities? A password-guessing botnet would be the least of our worries.</p>
<p>While CloudFlare was talking up this attack, <a href="http://blog.sucuri.net/2013/04/mass-wordpress-brute-force-attacks-myth-or-reality.html">Sucuri Security was talking it down</a>. They were seeing "only" around three times the number of password-guessing attempts they usually see.</p>
<p>Could it be just a trial, or the calm before a much bigger storm? My impression is that WordPress sites are usually hacked as part of black-hat search engine optimisation (SEO) operations, posting links to their masters' websites for the extra Googlejuice, with no attempt to compromise the hosting account or the server it runs on.</p>
<p>Yet most low-end WordPress sites run on servers with plenty of spare capacity. "Apparently, someone is building a formidable botnet of compromised WordPress accounts that is likely to be used in a much larger attack," said a <a href="http://threatpost.com/hackers-using-brute-force-attacks-harvest-wordpress-sites-041513/">relatively sober post at Threatpost</a>, though they add one proviso: "Some experts are speculating."</p>
<p>Speculating they are. And I am. But there's maybe 30 million WordPress sites there for the taking, and that's a lot of firepower.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014251</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/welcome-to-the-coalitions-nbn-argument-clinic-7000014251/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Welcome to the Coalition's NBN argument clinic]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[One of the most enduring characteristics of Tony Abbott's Liberal Party &mdash; particularly with reference to its preference for a retrograde NBN &mdash; has been its enshrinement as the ‘party of no'. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 04:53:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[David Braue]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-au/">Government AU</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-australia/">Australia</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the dust now well settled after <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/coalition-launches-alternative-nbn-policy-7000013715/">the announcement</a> of the party's long-awaited broadband policy, it's clear that the so-called <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23noalition">Noalition</a> is determined to turn the 2013 election into its own version of Monty Python's famous "Argument Clinic" sketch.</p>
<iframe width='620' height='349' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/RDjCqjzbvJY' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>Far from answering questions and addressing concerns about the fibre-to-the-node (FttN) policy that Australia's telco community had dreamed up to fill the Coalition's earlier policy vacuum, the actual policy made it clear that the real fact of the Coalition's policy is that — while <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/libs-kick-nbn-policy-own-goal-but-can-labor-convert-7000013781/">conceding</a> that broadband is actually <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/coalitions-nbn-to-cost-almost-30bn-7000013702/">going to be expensive</a> —it takes so much about the industry for granted that it is, like Inception, a dream, within a dream, within a dream.</p>
<p>Those who have tried to talk logic with Malcolm Turnbull — even an industry that is variously <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/nbn-will-change-regardless-of-government-analysts-7000013986/">interested</a> and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/many-unanswered-questions-in-coalitions-nbn-plan-macquarie-telecom-7000014058/">concerned</a> about the policy — have been greeted with a Pythonesque disregard.</p>
<p>If I may, I here offer what we can expect will be the meat of every interview Turnbull will give between now and the election.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Mr Turnbull, it's going to be extremely difficult to <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/turnbull-looks-forward-to-telstra-deal-7000013969/">renegotiate a value-for-money contract</a> with Telstra.</strong></p>
<p>No, it's not.</p>
<p><strong>Surely Telstra will have issues with basically giving you their copper network for free.</strong></p>
<p>No, they won't.</p>
<p><strong>Your use of the words "slight rearrangements" to describe the negotiations is both euphemistic and crazily optimistic.</strong></p>
<p>No, it isn't.</p>
<p><strong>You've <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/regional-councils-want-to-pay-for-broadband-turnbull-7000013908/">suggested that local councils will want to fork over money</a> to fund a national broadband network (NBN) rollout when many can't even afford to maintain their footpaths and recreational facilities. Even the Federal Department of Regional Australia, Local Government, Arts and Sport <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/news/2012-04-04/government-departments-filleted-as-budget-looms/3931294">is downsizing</a>, so expecting councils to pay for broadband infrastructure seems quite optimistic.</strong></p>
<p>No, it isn't.</p>
<p><strong>Would you care to elaborate?</strong></p>
<p>No.</p>
<p><strong>Your comments about local councils are especially interesting since you said that your policy will be <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/coalition-nbn-will-be-better-for-the-bush-turnbull-7000013780/">better for the bush</a> than Labor's policy. But if you expect councils to pay for the NBN, then your policy is actually worse for them, isn't it?</strong></p>
<p>No, it isn't.</p>
<p><strong>What about multi-dwelling units (MDUs)? The peak strata authority says that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/coalition-nbn-plan-wont-help-flats-sca-7000013776/">your policy will leave them in the dust</a>.</strong></p>
<p>No, it won't.</p>
<p><strong>Are you saying they don't know what they're talking about?</strong></p>
<p>No, I'm not.</p>
<p><strong>It sounded like you were.</strong></p>
<p>No, I wasn't.</p>
<p><strong>NBN Co has said it has <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/nbn-co-no-contingency-plan-for-coalition-government-7000013712/">no contingency plan</a> if the Coalition is elected.</strong></p>
<p>No, it doesn't.</p>
<p><strong>Is this a problem?</strong></p>
<p>No, it isn't.</p>
<p><strong>Because you're going to fire them all and contract Telstra workers to do the job instead?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, exactly. I mean, no, we won't.</p>
<p><strong>What about the rates your policy will pay to workers? From what we're hearing, workers feel they are <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/nbn-construction-pay-rates-extremely-poor-nsw-business-chamber-7000014047/">being shafted</a> by NBN Co subcontractors. You're going to have to make sure they're <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lies-damned-lies-and-nbn-rollout-statistics-7000012980/">paid better</a> to meet your ambitious targets.</strong></p>
<p>No, we won't.</p>
<p><strong>What, have you been preparing a massive army of fibre-splicing flying monkeys to help you out?</strong></p>
<p>The Coalition doesn't comment on unannounced policies.</p>
<p><strong>No, you don't.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, we do. I mean, no, we don't.</p>
<p><strong>Tony Abbott says he's "no Bill Gates", but he's sounding more and more like Bill Gates, who is notorious for his supposed claim that "640KB will be enough for anyone". Now, Abbott has said that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/abbott-25mbps-broadband-more-than-enough-for-australia-7000013721/">25Mbps broadband is more than enough for Australia</a>. Isn't this a bit lame, particularly given that Labor has just announced <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/gigabit-speeds-to-hit-nbn-by-end-of-year-7000014241/">1Gbps NBN services will be available</a> by December?</strong></p>
<p>No, it's not.</p>
<p><strong>But we came here to hear about your NBN policy being better than Labor's.</strong></p>
<p>No, you came here to hear about our NBN policy. We have delivered it. QED.</p>
<p><strong>Broadband bellwether Simon Hackett believes <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/telstra-will-decide-coalitions-nbn-hackett-7000013724/">Telstra will control</a> how your policy is actually rolled out.</strong></p>
<p>No, they won't. The Coalition will control how Telstra controls how the Coalition controls how Telstra rolls out the Coalition's policy.</p>
<p><strong>No, it won't.</strong></p>
<p>Yes, it will.</p>
<p><strong>We'll see. Will you at least tell us whether you plan to overbuild Telstra's HFC network with FttN or not?</strong></p>
<p>No, we won't.</p>
<p><strong>You won't overbuild it?</strong></p>
<p>No, we won't tell you if we're going to overbuild it.</p>
<p><strong>Isn't that important to your policy?</strong></p>
<p>You so-called "<a href="http://www.malcolmturnbull.com.au/homepage-speeches-articles/commsday-melbourne-congress-2012/">specialist commentators</a>" are so demanding. OK, here you go: We will not, not, not, not, not, not, not, not, not, not, not, not, not overbuild the HFC networks.</p>
<p><strong>How many "not's" was that?</strong></p>
<p>I don't know. But there's your answer.</p>
<p><strong>You have outlined your policy, and Labor has outlined theirs. Will you be providing more details about how you will execute it?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, on September 15.</p>
<p><strong>But that's after the election.</strong></p>
<p>No, it's not.</p>
<p><strong>I'm pretty sure it is.</strong></p>
<p>I think we're done here.</p>
<p><strong>Yes, we are.</strong></p>
<p>No, we're not.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Judging by the general tone of the discussions with Turnbull over the last week, it appears that the party has given away everything it's going to give away. It has dropped its policy, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/conroy-denies-au90-billion-nbn-price-tag-7000013647/" target="_blank">floated a few furphies</a>, and walked away to watch the industry and media battle it out with bemused detachment.</p>
<p>It seems fair to assume that we can expect no clarification on any of these points until after the election, when an elated (if elected) Coalition will proceed to start putting its money, so to speak, where its mouth is.</p>
<p>It's not the most open and honest approach — and it has laid the party bare to criticism from those who don't buy into its numbers and policy assumptions — but it's about what we could expect from a contender political party with nothing to gain from giving away too much more than it has so far.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014229</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/micromax-3d-mobile-phone-coming-soon-7000014229/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Micromax 3D mobile phone coming soon]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[One of India's leading mobile phone manufacturers, Micromax, is set to launch a 3D phone for under 15,000 rupees (US$277.9).]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 02:52:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Nitin Puri]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of India's leading mobile phone manufacturers, Micromax, is set to unveil a 3D phone to be priced at under 15,000 rupees (US$277.9).</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="micromax" alt="micromax" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014229/micromax-200x114.jpg?hash=ZmAzZmp0ZQ&upscale=1" height="114" width="200"><figcaption>Micromax phones</figcaption></figure>
<p>The mobile phone is likely to be called Canvas AD 115, and will run on Google Android 4.1.2 Jellybean OS. <a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tech/tech-news/hardware/Micromax-set-to-launch-3D-phone-under-Rs-15000/articleshow/19612616.cms" target="_blank">Sources</a> say the specifications would include a 5 inch-display with 800x400 pixel resolution, as well as a 1GHz dual core processor with 1GB of RAM, 4GB internal storage, and microSD card slot. As for camera support, the front camera will be 2 MP and the rear camera will be 8 MP with LED flash.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The phone will most likely also have a 3D interface, but will lack 3D playback capability. Having 3D playback capability would have given this phone an advantage as no other device in the market currently&nbsp;offers this within this affordable price range. In India, the only other 3D phone currently in the market is the LG Optimus 3D, and that is priced much higher at around 26,000 rupees (US$481.7).</p>
<p>It will be interesting to see if there is strong demand for 3D mobile phones within the Indian market. I've personally never used a 3D mobile device but I can imagine it would be beneficial for users who are hardcore gamers or require multiple windows to be opened simultaneously.</p>
<p>That said, for its price, can Micromax deliver this 3D phone with an adequate GPU as well? There is no mention of the graphics processing capability in terms of the specs, so if the GPU resources are being pooled or shared with the CPU, this will have an impact on the overall performance and usage of the mobile device.</p>
<p>In 2012, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/indian-phonemaker-micromax-enters-tv-biz-7000005524/">Micromax</a>&nbsp;was India's second-largest mobile phone manufacturer, and the availability of its phones is spread across India. The company's phones are particularity popular in rural India, as the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/micromax-and-karbonn-power-indian-smartphone-market-growth-7000012506/">Indian brand</a> is marketed more aggressively and made available at a more affordable price range, compared to Apple or Samsung products. The other benefit is that malfunction devices can easily be repaired at local dealers, compared to Apple or Samsung products which usually require servicing at authorized dealers or vendors.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014209</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/in/indian-public-sector-to-grow-on-back-of-modern-it-7000014209/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Indian public sector to grow on back of modern IT]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Modern forms of IT such as cloud, big data and mobility will play a large role in increasing the turnover of Indian public-sector units, from US$383 billion today to US$1 trillion by 2020.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 02:28:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Swati Prasad]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-big-data/">Big Data</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-asia/">Government Asia</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-it-priorities/">IT Priorities</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-business-intelligence/">Business Intelligence</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you thought the role of public sector units (PSUs) in the Indian economy would shrink in the days to come, you'd be wrong.</p>
<p>According to a study released this week by consulting firm Zinnov, Indian PSUs are expected to witness a turnover of more than US$1 trillion by 2020, from US$383 billion in 2011-12.&nbsp;A large part of the growth will be attributed to investments in modern forms of IT including <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/indias-iaas-market-to-grow-40-percent-until-2015-7000009113/">cloud</a>, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/indias-big-data-market-to-hit-1b-in-2015-7000003800/">big data</a>, and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/indias-mobile-vas-market-set-to-hit-9-5b-by-2015-7000013172/">mobility</a>.</p>
<p>Praveen Bhadada, Zinnov's&nbsp;director of market expansion, said in a statement: "India is a hub of 225 PSUs operating across verticals, with 16 of these companies featuring in the global list of top 2,000 companies. With their growing size and dominance, PSUs have started looking at IT to address global competition."</p>
<p>He cited the example of State Bank of India which has deployed one of the largest core banking implementation globally as well as oil-PSU Bharat Petroleum Corporation (BPCL) which has made early investments in big data.</p>
<p>IT is viewed as an enabler for cost reduction through the automation of processes and integrated IT setups. "Today PSUs are looking at IT to analyze customer information efficiently and develop targeted and customized offerings for customers," Bhadada added.</p>
<p>According to the Zinnov report, IT spend accounts for about 2 percent of total PSU revenue, which is higher than most other verticals, and was valued at US$8.5 billion in 2011-12.&nbsp;Energy and BFSI (banking, financial services and insurance) are major PSU verticals for IT investments.</p>
<p>The PSU sector gives employment to 1.4 million, with 40 percent of companies operating in the manufacturing sector.&nbsp;Indian PSUs have been witnessing revenue growth of 11 percent since 2009.</p>
<p>"PSUs are looking at investing in technology to help address the challenges they faced in early years of transition toward establishing a more transparent and accountable organization, reduce the cost of production, and enhance productivity and customer reach," the report stated.</p>
<p>It also looked at some of the challenges faced by the Indian PSU sector, pointing to talent as one such challenge. Lack of performance incentives in terms of recognition and accelerated growth paths for workforce gives rise to productivity challenges, said Zinnov.</p>
<p>In addition, other challenges like lack of quantitative benchmarks against domestic private companies or global equivalents is affecting the performance of the sector. The broad-based decision-making structure, with stakeholders holding overlapping responsibilities, among PSUs also results in lack of accountability.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014247</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/satire-how-to-write-greatawful-tech-press-releases-7000014247/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[How to write great/awful tech press releases: Satire]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[While I like knowing what's going on in the tech space, press releases can sometimes leave one hungry for the truth. So, I contacted my colleagues at the tech PR firm 'Blithering Media' to give us some (humorous) tips for writing the perfect technology press release. Enjoy.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 01:06:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Brian Sommer]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you're running a startup and wondering how those PR people do their magic, read on. (If you work for these firms, click away <em>now</em>.)</p>
<p>I checked in with my colleagues over at Blithering Media (my sub rosa PR firm). They shared their best/worst practices with me. Here goes:</p>
<p><strong>So, suppose you've got a new a new tech client and it finally got its first customer after eight years in business. How do you spin that?</strong></p>
<p>Let's see, we'd probably issue a press release that starts like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<h3>NewCo experiences record infinite sales growth</h3>
<p>NewCo, the internet's fastest-growing provider of ISP Velocity Impenders, has surpassed an amazing industry milestone with infinite sales growth. NewCo's CEO, Hardly Home III, says that "<em>Coming off last year's wildly successful year, we've now vastly exceeded all prior years' sales combined.</em>"</p>
<p>Quarter over quarter, year over year, and other metrics were simply blown away. And NewCo did all of this growth without adding any additional headcount.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>But it didn't have any sales in those prior years!</strong></p>
<p>Precisely! Brian, those years weren't zero sales years, they were instead:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>For eight years, NewCo has been developing a revolutionary new solution to take the ISP Velocity Impender market by storm. NewCo has been singularly focused on developing the most technically brilliant solutions the market has ever seen.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>So, you're saying they weren't bad salespeople, but rather brilliant product engineers?</strong></p>
<p>Now you're getting it. We'll make you into a PR machine yet.</p>
<p><strong>Don't we need to say something about the cloud, mobile, or social? Isn't there a law about this for press releases?</strong></p>
<p>You're right. When the Client Server Buzzword Mandate of 1993 was replaced in 2011 with the Cloud/Mobile/Social Dictate, we have to get at least one of these in every press release.</p>
<p><strong>Well, this firm has nothing going on in any of these areas. What do we do?</strong></p>
<p>Try this copy out:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>NewCo is currently investigating how its newest solutions will integrate with the latest social, mobile, and cloud technologies available. "We're taking our time to ensure customers will not get caught on the wrong side of future standards in these early technologies," says NewCo CTO B Hine Times.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>OK, so how do you handle the fact that these folks are all in a small town in Nebraska and have never even been to Silicon Valley?</strong></p>
<p>Hmmm, well, we'd probably say this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The global reach of NewCo is simply staggering.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>How? How can you say that?</strong></p>
<p>Oh, that's easy. I bet someone on that team lives on this planet. Don't they? So, if they exist somewhere on the globe, then they're global. Plus, I bet at least one of them has been on vacation &ndash; probably to Iowa. That's global, too, isn't it?</p>
<p><strong>So, how do you handle the press release without a customer reference?</strong></p>
<p>Oh, that's easy. We'll get some no-name industry analyst to give us a quote. We'll even write the copy for them. It'll probably be something like:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"NewCo's announcement is staggering and will send shockwaves through the industry," says Ponce Tificate of Buzzword Research Analysts. "We're starting coverage on NewCo immediately (if its check to us clears)."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>And, of course, you'll pepper the press release with a lot of three-letter acronyms (TLAs), too?</strong></p>
<p>You bet we will!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>NewCo delivers industry-leading, dynamic WXYZ and QWERTY tensioning to the already competitive Velocity Impender market. But, with its new features for Matter Inversion (MI), Choke Resonance (CR), and more, the company is poised for even more explosive growth.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>But how can it have "even more explosive growth" when this announcement is about it achieving "infinite growth"?</strong></p>
<p>Brian, you're not supposed to take these paragraphs literally. We're trying to get the reader into a whole growth gestalt with our copy.</p>
<p><strong>Growth gestalt?</strong></p>
<p>That's a PR term &mdash; you don't need to worry about it.</p>
<p><strong>OK, what else would you recommend NewCo put in its press release?</strong></p>
<p>Well, we'd want to add something about potential partners or venture capitalists.</p>
<p><strong>But it haven't got either of these. In fact, it has been rebuffed by everyone.</strong></p>
<p>No problem. For example, we'd probably add this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>NewCo has already attracted the attention of numerous venture capitalists and potential alliance partners. "<em>We're currently evaluating whether any of the current suitors are worthy of the NewCo banner," </em>adds NewCo CEO Hardly Home III.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Is there anything else you'd recommend our readers cram into their tech press releases? Have we missed anything?</strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. Your readers need to find a way to fit as many of these things into any press release if you want to get a high Google search optimization result. To make it easier for your readers, they can just paste this paragraph into their release.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>About NewCo: NewCo helps Fortune 500, SMB, B2B, and B2C firms shift paradigms and morph their 24/7 initiatives into strong, industry leading, and transformative bricks-and-clicks outcomes. This comes while customers transition best-of-breed infomediaries into world-class schemas. Granular, next-generation solutions are simply future proofed into a knowledge economy context that approaches multiple singularities. The result is ground-breaking, aspirational, revolutionary, and pivotal to propelling outsized corporate growth and employee engagement.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Do you go to church?</strong></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014243</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/stepping-into-kogan-crazy-land-7000014243/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Stepping into Kogan 'crazy land']]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[On this week's Technolatte podcast, the Australian team discusses the latest in the Kogan Mobile vs ISPOne stoush, how Australian security pros view themselves, and yet more NBN fallout.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:16:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[ZDNet Australia Staff]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-security/">Security</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-telstra/">Telstra</category>
      <enclosure url="http://media.cnetnetworks.com.au/audio/musiccentre/Technolatte/technolatte20130419.mp3" length="13100430" type="audio/mpeg"></enclosure>
      <itunes:duration>27:17</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle><![CDATA[On this week's Technolatte podcast, the Australian team discusses the latest in the Kogan Mobile vs ISPOne stoush, how Australian security pros view themselves, and yet more NBN fallout.]]></itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary><![CDATA[On this week's Technolatte podcast, the Australian team discusses the latest in the Kogan Mobile vs ISPOne stoush, how Australian security pros view themselves, and yet more NBN fallout.]]></itunes:summary>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <itunes:keywords></itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:author>ZDNet</itunes:author>
      <media:content url="http://media.cnetnetworks.com.au/audio/musiccentre/Technolatte/technolatte20130419.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" medium="audio" fileSize="13100430"></media:content>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is Kogan Mobile's service unlimited or "unlimited"? Are Australian security professionals correct in rating local businesses as sitting ducks? And what colour smoke does glass put out when it is burnt?</p>
<p>All those questions and more are answered on this week's Technolatte podcast, as the Australian team discusses:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>ISPOne returning fire and claiming that Kogan Mobile's "unlimited" naming is <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/ispone-hits-back-kogan-mobiles-unlimited-is-deceptive-7000014121/">"misleading and deceptive conduct"</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are Australian security professionals <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/australian-infosec-pros-rank-own-businesses-as-sitting-ducks-7000014045/">talking themselves down</a>, or are they incompetent?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The state of Telstra's copper network and other <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/au/many-unanswered-questions-in-coalitions-nbn-plan-macquarie-telecom-7000014058/">unanswered questions</a> in the Coalition's national broadband network (NBN) plan.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>You can subscribe to <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/podcast/technolatte-by-zdnet-australia/id398450020" target="_blank">Technolatte on iTunes</a>.</p>
<p><em>Running time: 27 minutes, 17 seconds</em></p>
<p><em>Opening theme: <a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Jason_Shaw/Audionautix_Tech_Urban_Dance/TU-EcstasyX" target="_blank">"Ecstasy X" by Jason Shaw</a>, <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" target="_blank">CC3.0</a></em></p>
<p><em>Closing theme: <a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Pierlo/Olivetti_Prodest/11_Skyroads" target="_blank">"Skyroads" by Pierlo</a>, <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" target="_blank">CC3.0</a></em></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014242</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/as-the-pc-market-turns-touchscreens-start-to-take-over-7000014242/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[As the PC market turns, touchscreens start to take over]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Samsung's Chromebook has been at the top of Amazon's list of bestselling notebooks for several months. But a closer look at the rest of that list reveals some interesting facts about an industry in transition. Most notably, touchscreens are finally starting to take off.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Apr 2013 23:31:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ed Bott]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apple/">Apple</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google’s Chrome OS isn’t exactly <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/first-real-world-usage-figures-suggest-chromebooks-are-struggling-7000014102/">setting the online universe on fire</a>, according to the latest numbers from NetMarketShare. In fact, Chromebooks are so lightly used that they don't even appear on the latest reports from the web metrics company.</p>
<p>When I wrote that news earlier this week, I heard two reactions, for the most part. The first was, "This surprises you?" The second was: "But that can’t be. The Samsung Chromebook has been at the top of Amazon’s bestselling laptops list for months!"</p>
<p>Indeed it has. That apparent contradiction surprised me, too, so I decided to take a much closer look at <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/bestsellers/electronics/565108/">that Amazon list</a>. I came away with a plausible explanation for Samsung’s success and some insights into the PC market as we head into midyear.</p>
<figure><img title="samsung-chromebook-amazon-bestseller" alt="samsung-chromebook-amazon-bestseller" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014242/samsung-chromebook-amazon-bestseller-466x186.png?hash=BGyuZGNkMJ&upscale=1" height="186" width="466"></figure>
<p>First, a little background. As a book author, I know a thing or two about Amazon’s bestseller lists. They’re based on complex (and highly secretive) algorithms that blend long-term sales with short-term momentum. So a product that sees a spike in sales in a single day can move impressively up the charts for a day or two, and then drop quickly back to its normal slot. But the products that stay atop the charts are those that sell steadily over time.</p>
<p>By that measure, there’s reason to congratulate Samsung for the Chromebook’s performance. Its tenure at the top means it has been selling consistently over time. So what’s the secret of its success?</p>
<p>Let’s start with the most obvious attribute: its price. At $249, the Samsung Chromebook is the second-cheapest device on the Amazon list. In fact, when I copied the list into a spreadsheet and sorted by price, lowest prices first, Chromebooks magically rose to the top.</p>
<figure><img title="chromebooks-are-cheap" alt="chromebooks-are-cheap" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014242/chromebooks-are-cheap-348x161.png?hash=BTD2ZTDmZ2&upscale=1" height="161" width="348"></figure>
<p>Two of the top five notebooks are dirt-cheap Chromebooks. When you sort the 100 laptops on the list by price, only one Windows-based machine, the Acer Aspire One, managed to sneak into the bargain basement. With the Samsung getting excellent reviews for its build quality, at a price of $249, it passed the “What the hell?” threshold for many gadget buyers.</p>
<p>But I found the rest of the list much more enlightening. Here’s the short version:</p>
<ul>
<li>Apple’s MacBooks are very popular indeed.</li>
<li>Touchscreens are making inroads into the mainstream.</li>
<li>Cheap PCs are still the no-profit lifeblood of the industry.</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s dig in.</p>
<p>For starters, there really aren’t 100 discrete devices in the Amazon top 100 list. I threw out 10 of the entries on the list that were available only from third-party sellers, not fulfilled by Amazon. This group included three ancient Apple iBooks powered by G4 CPUs. It also included listings for five equally antique refurbished Dell machines. After excluding those listings, we end up with a total of 90 entries in the Formerly Top 100 list.</p>
<p>And there are a lot of duplicates on that list. The Samsung Chromebook comes in a single configuration, but many of the other entries on the list represent the same device with a different CPU or memory, in a different color, or with a slightly different model number.</p>
<p>One could, in fact, make a plausible case that ASUS deserves the top spot on the list with its amazingly inexpensive low-end touchscreen notebook powered by an Intel i3. The ASUS X202E appears in the #10 spot on the list, but its siblings, the silver and pink units with the same model number and the identical device sold as the Q200E, appear on the list as well. All told, this machine appears five times. If those sales were consolidated, it would certainly move up the charts - perhaps all the way to the top.</p>
<p>I found a total of six Apple MacBooks in the top 100. They paint a picture of Apple’s amazingly successful sales strategy. Create a manageable number of models, build them very well, slap a premium price on each one, and collect the greenbacks.</p>
<figure><img title="macbooks-in-top-100" alt="macbooks-in-top-100" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014242/macbooks-in-top-100-312x241.png?hash=MQyzMQp0ZT&upscale=1" height="241" width="312"></figure>
<p>If you sort the list by price in reverse order, MacBooks float to the top of the list. All of the 12 Mac models on the bestseller list were among the 20 most expensive laptops you can buy at Amazon. Only one had an actual selling price of (barely) under $1000. Collectively, they represent only six models: the 11- and 13-inch MacBook Airs, and the 13- and 15-inch MacBook Pros, with and without Retina displays.</p>
<p>And then there’s the incredibly diverse Windows laptop lineup.</p>
<p>When I combined all the duplicate entries, I found a total of 46 Windows-powered devices on the bestseller list. Here’s the breakdown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Only 2 were running Windows 7</li>
<li>32 were running Windows 8 on conventional notebook form factors</li>
<li>12 were running Windows 8 with touchscreens</li>
</ul>
<p>That middle group is basically the strip mall of PCs: ho-hum, mostly heavy lookalike devices at price points that make you wonder how the OEMs can make a dime of profit. Of that group, 56 percent were priced at $500 or less and 88 percent were $700 or less.</p>
<p>But if you’re looking for signs of life, look at the list of touchscreen devices, most of them fairly recent additions to the bestseller list.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Acer: </strong>Aspire V5</li>
<li><strong>ASUS: </strong>Taichi Convertible Ultrabook; VivoBook S400CA and VivoBook S500CA; Q200E/VivoBook X202E</li>
<li><strong>HP: </strong>Envy X2 convertible</li>
<li><strong>Lenovo: </strong>IdeaPad Yoga 13; Thinkpad Twist; ThinkPad X1 Carbon Touch</li>
<li><strong>Samsung: </strong>ATIV Smart PC 500T; ATIV Smart PC Pro XE700T</li>
<li><strong>Sony: </strong>VAIO T Series</li>
</ul>
<p>On average, the touchscreen devices sold for $802 each. By contrast, the non-touchscreen devices sold for $515. Part of that is the current premium price for touch-enabled displays. But as volumes go up, that component price should go down, making touchscreens more popular.</p>
<p>What I found most fascinating about this list were the Lenovo entries. In the recent dismal Q1, Lenovo nearly hit the top of the worldwide PC sales charts. And it’s not doing it with just cheap PCs. The Yoga 13, ThinkPad Twist, and X1 Carbon Touch are genuinely innovative designs, sold at premium prices.</p>
<p>We are in a time of transition in the PC industry. By the end of the year, I predict this list will look very different indeed.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014239</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/reading-between-the-microsoft-cfo-lines-on-windows-blue-and-the-start-button-7000014239/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Reading between the Microsoft CFO lines on Windows Blue and the Start Button]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Think this through: Why might Microsoft be willing to look like it's 'caving' and introduce boot-to-desktop and Start Button options? ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Apr 2013 21:55:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Jo Foley]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows/">Windows</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-it-policies/">IT Policies</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It may seem like a throwaway comment when a Microsoft exec says the company is interested in being responsive to customer feedback.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="winsupersiteblueleak" alt="winsupersiteblueleak" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014239/winsupersiteblueleak-200x136.png?hash=Z2ZmZQD0ZG&upscale=1" height="136" width="200"></figure>
<p>But when we're talking about Microsoft's Windows business, every official pronouncement is carefully measured and meant to signal an intent. That's why it's worth parsing the words of Peter Klein -- the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-q3-profit-up-despite-pc-market-slump-cfo-out-7000014228/">outgoing Chief Financial Offer (CFO) at Microsoft</a> -- around the next version of Windows.</p>
<p>During the analyst call on April 18 which coincided with <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-q3-profit-up-despite-pc-market-slump-cfo-out-7000014228/">Microsoft's Q3 FY 2013 earnings release</a>, Klein reiterated that Microsoft is stepping up its Windows release cadence with the next version of Windows, codenamed "Windows Blue." Klein also reiterated that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/the-microsoft-number-we-all-want-to-know-windows-8-sales-to-date-7000014238/">smaller screen Windows devices are in development by Microsoft OEMs</a>.</p>
<p>But it was another of Klein's remarks, which many would consider an almost obligatory comment, that really caught my attention. Klein said that Microsoft was going to be "responsive to customer feedback" with Blue.</p>
<p>His exact statement (from <a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/1353291-microsoft-s-management-discusses-f3q-2013-results-earnings-call-transcript?all=true&amp;find=MSFT%2Bconference%2Bcall">a transcript from the analyst call</a>): "Looking ahead, we will release the next version of Windows, codenamed Windows Blue, which further advances the vision of Windows 8 as well as responds to customer feedback."</p>
<p>I take this as yet another confirmation that Microsoft is moving toward&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-windows-8-plan-blue-bring-back-the-start-button-boot-to-desktop-7000014075/">make the boot-to-desktop option and some kind of Windows Start button a part of Windows Blue</a>. I don't know if these options are likely to be available across all Windows 8 and Windows RT SKUs (or just Pro and Enterprise, which is what my <a href="http://twit.tv/ww">Windows Weekly</a> cohost Paul Thurrott is hearing.) I also don't know if this Start Button will just be something that brings users directly to the Metro Start Screen. But I'd be that's far more likely than something that would bring them back to the old Start Menu.</p>
<p>No, I can't prove I am connecting the dots correctly, of course. But if you look at the feedback on my blog to my earlier post about <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-windows-8-plan-blue-bring-back-the-start-button-boot-to-desktop-7000014075/">these two features making a comeback as options in Windows Blue</a>, it sure seems like the majority of my readers want these capabilities.</p>
<p>Business users are especially keen on seeing these two things return to Windows 8, especially because they don't want to incur retraining and help desk costs resulting from implementing a vastly different user interface.</p>
<p>Plus, think this through: In <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/gartner-prepare-now-for-windows-xp-death-security-at-risk-7000014164/">April 2014, Microsoft is terminating support for Windows XP</a>. There are still millions of corporate desktops running Windows XP. In fact, according to the latest NetMarketshare usage data, XP is the No. 2 version of Windows installed on desktops, second only to Windows 7.</p>
<p>Microsoft wants these folks to upgrade. But if they are fearful or uncertain about Windows 8, these users will go to Windows 7 instead. And once they are on Windows 7, it's like XP all over again. It's another version of Windows that will be too good for its own good. These corporate users will be running Windows 7 for the next decade-plus, with little/no reason or interest in going to Windows 8.</p>
<p>So if you're Microsoft, which is the lesser of two evils? Bring back two features that could spur greater corporate adoption of Windows 8 -- even if company watchers accuse you of back-tracking? Or run the risk of losing a huge part of your installed base to Windows 7, or another non-Microsoft alternative?</p>
<p>If Microsoft listens to what users want with Windows Blue, all I'll say is it's better late than never....</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014232</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/googles-page-on-facebook-home-glass-and-future-of-android-7000014232/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Google's Page on Facebook Home, Glass, and future of Android]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Google's CEO makes a mini comeback following a mixed earnings report on Thursday.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Apr 2013 20:39:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software/">Software</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google-apps/">Google Apps</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="google-hq-nyc" alt="google-hq-nyc" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/global-carousel/companies/google-hq-nyc-620x202.jpg?hash=AQqwMzRjZG&upscale=1" height="202" width="620"></figure>
<p>Google's chief executive officer <strong>Larry Page</strong> has made few apperances on the Internet giant's quarterly earnings calls since falling ill ahead of Google I/O last June.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/googles-q1-11-01b-in-adjusted-revenue-11-58-earnings-per-share-7000014174/">Google's Q1: $11.01B in adjusted revenue, $11.58 earnings per share</a></p>
<p>But the company's co-founder steered the reins throughout much of Thursday's event after the bell.</p>
<p>While Page repeatedly said he wasn't looking to offer "news" about a number of buzzed-about products, his commentary covered a diverse cross-section of Google units.</p>
<p>Here's an overview:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/10-things-about-google-glass-could-this-be-googles-ipad-7000014079/">Google Glass strategy</a> for functionality, price, and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-glass-is-finally-here-tech-specs-released-first-units-shipped-7000014066/">third-party developer ecosystem</a></strong>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"It's in the early days for the product. Just handing over small number so far. I think that we're probably pretty good at third-party ecosystems based on experience on Android. So I’m not too worried about that... I think the price tag was set for developers for our early test. We don’t have any news to announce there. I’m not sure i’d call it a luxury price, but it’s a pretty high price... What do people do with Glass? I find the photo taking, the video, phone calling, quick messaging, directions, would all be a pretty amazing experience. That’s some of the core functionality we built in the device...We’re excited to get this out to developers and have others create experiences we haven’t thought of yet."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>People using apps versus Google search on mobile</strong>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"We always get this question about apps versus Google search. I’m not super concerned about that issue. People use apps on the Web. There are many strong sites and so on. So we’ve been dealing with that issue for a long time. Fundamentally, search is an amazing thing. We go over a lot of traffic and users. In general, the information wants to be found. We’re working hard to make sure the user experience is great and we’re delivering people to the right places."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/andy-rubin-androids-founder-leaves-project-7000012563/"><strong>The future of Android</strong></a>:</p>
<p>Following Andy Rubin’s <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/andy-rubin-pens-farewell-letter-to-android-partners-7000012575/">resignation as leader of the unit</a>, Page described that Google has very "ambitious" goals for Android.</p>
<p>But he quickly noted that there wouldn't be any details about those goals revealed on Thursday.</p>
<p>"He really decided it was time to hand over the reins and start a new chapter at Google," Page added about Rubin.</p>
<p><strong>Thoughts on impact of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-moves-into-google-play-app-store-7000013959/">Facebook Home for Android</a></strong>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I think that Google is really focused on building and creating great Android experiences within the strong ecosystem that we have. And it's really great to see developers really focused on and building for Android...I'm certainly, as I mentioned, I think it's going pretty smoothly, I'm pretty excited about it."</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Debate about <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/why-facebook-home-will-blow-android-into-smithereens-7000013549/">Android fragmentation</a></strong>:</p>
<p>Describing that he has had the "pleasure of using different Android phones from a variety of manufacturers," he admitted the experiences vary.</p>
<p>"In the negative sense, that’s fragmentation," Page admitted, following up that in a positive sense, it’s innovation.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000014238</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/the-microsoft-number-we-all-want-to-know-windows-8-sales-to-date-7000014238/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[The Microsoft number we all want to know: Windows 8 sales to date]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Microsoft didn't release an updated count of Windows 8 licenses sold as part of its third quarter earnings. But here's what the company did say about Windows.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 18 Apr 2013 20:35:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Jo Foley]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On April 18, Microsoft didn't share the one number many company watchers had been awaiting: An updated count of number of Windows 8 licenses sold.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="win8pcs" alt="win8pcs" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014238/win8pcs-200x105.png?hash=AQuyAGtkAm&upscale=1" height="105" width="200"></figure>
<p>There was no guarantee the Softies would provide an updated count today, the day it released its Q3 FY2013 earnings. But many of us had been expecting it.</p>
<p>Microsoft officials said they sold more than&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-weve-sold-40-million-windows-8-licenses-to-date-7000007990/">40 million copies of Windows 8 the first month it was commercially available</a>.</p>
<p>On January 8, Microsoft officials said the company had <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-60-million-windows-8-licenses-sold-to-date-7000009549/">sold 60 million licenses of Windows 8 to date</a>. This total included sales of licenses to OEMs, as well as Windows 8 upgrades. It did not include copies of Windows 8 sold via volume-licensing agreements. It may or may not also include Windows RT license numbers. (Microsoft officials declined to comment on that when I asked.)</p>
<p>At the time, Microsoft execs said the 60 million figure was <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-60-million-windows-8-licenses-sold-to-date-7000009549/">roughly in line with the number of Windows 7 licenses sold</a> during the same period of time after its launch in October 2009.</p>
<p>Windows 8 and Windows RT went on sale on October 26, 2012. Today marks almost six months since Windows 8 launched.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.windows.com/windows/b/bloggingwindows/archive/2010/06/04/windows-7-still-going-strong.aspx">Microsoft sold more than 100 million licenses of Windows 7 in its first six months</a>, company officials said back in June 2010. At that time, they called Windows 7 "the fastest selling operating system in history."</p>
<p>Windows 7 is still the most popular version of Windows in use, with the decade-plus-old Windows XP coming in at number two. According to the latest usage share data from NetMarketshare, <a href="http://www.netmarketshare.com/">Windows 8 currently has 3.17 percent of the desktop operating system share</a>, compared to Vista with 5 percent; XP with 39 percent; and Windows 7 with 45 percent.</p>
<p><strong>What Microsoft did say about Windows 8</strong></p>
<p>The Windows division posted revenues of $5.7 billion for the quarter. After adjusting for the $1.1 billion of revenue related to the Windows Upgrade Offer, the Windows division's revenue was flat.&nbsp;Windows client net income for the third fiscal quarter of 2013 was $3.46 billion, up from $2.98 billion for the same quarter a year ago.</p>
<figure><img title="windowsq3fy2013" alt="windowsq3fy2013" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/014238/windowsq3fy2013-600x338.png?hash=AJHmMJSwLG&upscale=1" height="338" width="600"></figure>
<p>In <a href="http://apps.shareholder.com/sec/viewerContent.aspx?companyid=MSFT&amp;docid=9229890">its 10-Q statement</a>, Microsoft noted that excluding the impact of the Windows Deferral (the Upgrade Offer plus pre-sales, prior to general availability), about 65 percent of the Windows Division comes from copies of Windows purchased by OEMs, which they preinstall on PCs and tablets. The rest of the revenues are from commercial and retail sales of Windows, Surface, PC hardware products and online advertising.</p>
<p>"Revenue from Surface and increased commercial sales of Windows was offset by the impact on revenue of a decline in the x86 PC market," said Microsoft in its 10-Q. "OEM revenue grew 17%, reflecting the revenue related to the Windows Upgrade Offer, offset in part by the impact on revenue of a decline in the x86 PC market."</p>
<p>(Non-OEM revenue -- sales of Surface and Windows sold commercially/at retail -- for the Windows division <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/Investor/EarningsAndFinancials/Earnings/SegmentResults/Windows/FY13/Q3/performance.aspx">was up 40 percent</a>, according to Microsoft.)</p>
<p>Microsoft officials attributed&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-q3-profit-up-despite-pc-market-slump-cfo-out-7000014228/">Microsoft's quarterly revenues of $20.49 billion and earnings of .72 per share</a> primarily as the result of the strong performance of its other businesses and divisions.</p>
<p>The press-release quote from Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer: “The bold bets we made on cloud services are paying off as people increasingly choose Microsoft services including Office 365, Windows Azure, Xbox LIVE, and Skype.... While there is still work to do, <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/investor/EarningsAndFinancials/Earnings/PressReleaseAndWebcast/FY13/Q3/default.aspx">we are optimistic that the bets we’ve made on Windows devices position us well for the long-term</a>."</p>
<p>On the earnings call, Microsoft Chief Financial Officer Peter Klein reconfirmed Microsoft was working with OEM partners on <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-cfo-klein-were-ready-for-devices-of-all-sizes-7000011261/">"small devices powered by Windows."</a> (There's been talk of a <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887323741004578415661035812902.html">possible mini-Surface, which may be a 7-inch</a> or 8-inch device, as well, which Klein didn't mention.) He said these would be out "in the coming months." He also noted new Windows PCs would be available in time for back-to-school and that Intel "Bay Trail" Atom-based devices would be out by year-end.</p>
<p>I'm curious when and if Microsoft provides a new update on number of Window 8 licenses sold. Maybe that will happen at Computex or TechEd North America -- both happening the first week of June this year? In any case, today's silence on this front is ... interesting.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
