<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:s="http://www.zdnet.com/search" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
    <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
    <description>Latest Blog for ZDNet</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>ZDNet</copyright>
    <managingEditor>customerservice@zdnet.com (ZDNet Customer Services)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>uk-engineering@cbsinteractive.com (ZDNet Webmaster)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:29:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>2</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://i.zdnet.com/images/spry/zdnet_300x300.jpg</url>
      <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
      <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
      <width>143</width>
      <height>39</height>
    </image>
    <s:counts>
      <start>0</start>
      <return>20</return>
      <found>41597</found>
    </s:counts>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013287</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/chromebook-pixel-spoiling-me-for-other-chromebooks-7000013287/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Chromebook Pixel: Spoiling me for other Chromebooks]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[My Samsung Chromebook has kept me happy for months but that's changed and it's Google's fault.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:41:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-laptops/">Laptops</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="samsung-chromebook-v1" alt="samsung-chromebook-v1" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013287/samsung-chromebook-v1-200x186.jpg?hash=MQZ1BGtkZQ&upscale=1" height="186" width="200"><figcaption>Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook</figcaption></figure>
<p>I have been using a Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook since picking it up last year. The Samsung is a great laptop that happens to run Chrome OS, something that works very well for me. I like everything about the Samsung. Then Google sent me a Chromebook Pixel and spoiled me.</p>
<p>The Series 5 550 Chromebook works very well for me. It runs Chrome OS nicely and is a super work machine that meets my needs. There is not really anything I don't like about the Samsung, but it's no longer enough.</p>
<p><strong>Related stories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a >Chromebook Pixel: Run Ubuntu alongside Chrome OS</a></li>
<li><a >Chromebook Pixel hands on (photos)</a></li>
<li><a >The Chromebook Pixel cost me a lot of money</a></li>
<li><a >MacBook Pro (Retina display) vs. Chromebook Pixel on video</a></li>
<li><a >Chromebook Pixel: 5 tips and tricks (including pinch to zoom)</a></li>
<li><a >New Samsung Chromebook and Samsung Series 5 550 head-to-head</a></li>
<li><a >New Samsung Chromebook: ARM processor and $249</a></li>
<li><a >Samsung Chromebook in 3G slips out for $330</a></li>
<li><a >Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook: All in after a week</a></li>
<li><a >11 good Chrome web apps for the Chromebook</a></li>
<li><a >Samsung Series 5 550 Chromebook: Day one</a></li>
<li><a >New MacBook for me? No, a new Samsung Chromebook on the way</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The culprit is the Chromebook Pixel, the expensive laptop from Google that costs almost three times what I paid for the Samsung. The Pixel hardware is as good as that on any laptop, even better in some ways. Using the Chromebook Pixel is sheer joy and it's not often you can say that about a laptop.&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img title="Pixel side view" alt="Pixel side view" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013287/pixel-side-view-v1-600x440.jpg?hash=AwyxL2EyBJ&upscale=1" height="440" width="600"><figcaption>Chromebook Pixel</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Pixel keyboard is great, the trackpad is outstanding, and then there's that screen. The high resolution, even higher than the famous Retina Display, is simply wonderful to use. Text displays razor sharp and graphics pop. The integrated LTE is so darn convenient when wi-fi is not available. Then there's the touch screen. This has come in handier far more than I thought it would. Chrome OS is not fully optimized for touch but what it can do with it makes the Pixel even better than without.</p>
<p>Given the high price of the Chromebook Pixel, surely I'm not thinking of getting one? As you have probably guessed that's exactly what I am considering. My Samsung Chromebook that I liked so much is just not cutting it now that I've used the best Chromebook.</p>
<p>I haven't pulled the trigger on the Pixel yet as it was not in my budget. I recently bought the MacBook Pro and another similar purchase is not in the budget. But I admit I've come very, very close to doing so.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Pixel I am using now is going back to Google shortly and the thought of going back to a regular Chromebook is not appealing at all. Stepping down on the hardware, the build quality, the integrated LTE, the gorgeous display, the touch screen...</p>
<p>You may think I'm crazy to be considering spending this much ($1449) for a Chromebook Pixel and you're not far off the mark. I don't know anyone I would recommend to do so. But the fact is I use Chrome OS, it works well for me, and I want to run it on the best hardware available to run it. It's my money, after all.</p>
<p>That in a nutshell is the narrow audience that the Chromebook Pixel is aimed at. Someone who is already convinced that Chrome OS will work fine for them. The price is too high for those not sure about Chrome OS. But for those like me who know it's good, and want to run it on the best hardware available to do so, the Pixel is it.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013289</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/nec-mulling-mobile-phone-unit-sell-off-to-lenovo-report-7000013289/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[NEC mulling mobile phone unit sell-off to Lenovo: report]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Japanese technology firm may be considering a sell-off of its mobile phone unit to Lenovo or others, reports suggest, amid declining sales targets and financial troubles. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:35:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="lenovointelphone610x407-v1-610x407" alt="lenovointelphone610x407-v1-610x407" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013289/lenovointelphone610x407-v1-610x407-610x407.jpg?hash=BQpjBGWyLm&upscale=1" height="407" width="610"><figcaption>(Credit: Corinne Schulze/CNET)</figcaption></figure>
<p>NEC may be looking to sell off its struggling mobile phone unit to PC maker Lenovo, according to sources <a >speaking to the Reuters news agency</a>.</p>
<p>While Lenovo may be in the front-running to snap up the unit, goes the report, NEC is also looking to others in a bid to raise much needed cash, after nearly two years of consistent quarterly financial losses as well as in market share.</p>
<p>NEC confirmed with a statement through the Tokyo Stock Exchange that "considering a number of ways to bolster the competitiveness of our mobile phone business" amid a rapidly changing and evolving market.</p>
<p>"But nothing has been decided," the firm was keen to stress. It does, however, confirm earlier rumors that NEC was at very least in discussions with other firms.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117062" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-still-talk-7000010434/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/010434/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-talk-220x165.png?hash=BTZ5LmR3Aw&upscale=1" alt="Lenovo, RIM: You two should probably still talk" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-still-talk-7000010434/">Lenovo, RIM: You two should probably still talk</a></p>
<p class="more">

																	<p>Sit down, have a glass of wine over dinner, and discuss the endless possibilities of a smartphone coalition--or a hardware unit takeover, should RIM finally bite the dust. </p>

																</p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-rim-you-two-should-probably-still-talk-7000010434/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>There have been prior relationships between NEC and Lenovo. But after entering financial difficulties,&nbsp;<a >NEC ditched its entire 281.1 million shares in Lenovo</a> to raise short-term cash, generating some $227.7 million at the time. Lenovo, meanwhile, shrugged it off, saying it wouldn't harm its PC or tablet coalition between the two firms.</p>
<p>Also, six months ago NEC cut its mobile phone sales target for the year ending this month down from 5 million units to 4.3 million units. As one of its more lucrative units, NEC will likely see dinged upcoming financial results.</p>
<p>Lenovo already has a smartphone business, but it's far from the global lucrative business that Apple or Samsung have. It does, however, have a Chinese equivalent stake in the mobile market, holding second-place <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-slow-pc-market-not-to-worry-we-also-have-smartphones-7000005971/">in the region with 11.5 percent of the market</a> as of last October.</p>
<p>That said, the company has no plans to ditch its PC business in favor of taking on the smartphone market. Rumors swirled when <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-may-bid-to-acquire-rim-in-smartphone-boost-report-7000009901/">Lenovo was reportedly looking at acquiring Canadian smartphone maker BlackBerry</a>, but no deal was made.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In January, Lenovo chief executive&nbsp;Yuanqing Yang said the firm was focused <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/lenovo-ceo-forget-post-pc-were-in-the-pc-plus-era-7000009638/">on the "PC plus" age</a>&nbsp;rather than the "post-PC" era. This confirmed that it will continue to develop its position in the PC market&nbsp;— in which it's <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/idc-hp-is-still-top-pc-vendor-worldwide-amid-soft-q4-sales-7000009673/">coming in at a close second-place behind HP</a>, which holds the top spot by shipments&nbsp;— as well as bolstering its position in the smartphone space.</p>
<p>For NEC, it could be a helpful boost to the company's bottom line as it continues to slowly fall to pieces. It cut 10,000 jobs last year&nbsp;— one-tenth of its workforce&nbsp;— amid a poor economic climate and increasing losses.&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013290</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/windows-blue-under-the-hood-minkernel-and-basefs-7000013290/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Windows Blue under the hood: MinKernel and BaseFS]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Since rumors about Windows Blue first surfaced, there's been talk that the Windows 8 update would include more than just UI tweaks. Clues about some of these deeper level changes are emerging.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:31:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Jo Foley]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft-surface/">Microsoft Surface</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-server/">Windows Server</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the recently leaked Windows Blue build out for the past few days, those downloading it are continuing to find new details as they dissect the code.</p>
<p>While some of the early user-interface changes -- in some cases, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-alleged-windows-blue-build-shows-off-coming-interface-tweaks-7000013035/">making Windows Blue look and feel more like Windows Phone</a> -- have been a big focus, the under-the-hood changes have gotten less coverage.</p>
<figure><img title="basefsminkernel" alt="basefsminkernel" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013290/basefsminkernel-v1-620x277.png?hash=Z2DmZwuyAw&upscale=1" height="277" width="620"></figure>
<p>But over on ITWorld.com, long-time Microsoft watcher Sandro Villinger has shared a few of his findings.</p>
<p>Villinger found <a href="http://www.itworld.com/windows/350114/7-hidden-gems-windows-blue">mention of something called "BaseFS" buried in the Windows Blue code</a>. This doesn't seem to be a new name for <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsoft-goes-public-with-plans-for-its-new-windows-8-file-system/11666">ReFS, the new file system for Windows 8 and Windows Server 2012</a>. Instead, according to one of my contacts, BaseFS is more of an internal concept that has to do with shared functionality between the different file systems</p>
<p>Interesting. Even more interesting (to me, at least) is Villinger's find regarding "Minkernel." (A screen capture by Villinger showing <a href="http://www.itworld.com/windows/350114/7-hidden-gems-windows-blue">references in Windows Blue to BaseFS and Minkernel</a> is embedded above in this post.)</p>
<p>Microsoft has been working to detangle the Windows hairball since it was developing Windows Vista, and possibly before. MinWin is the Windows "core" that resulted. MinWin includes some kernel interfaces, but it isn't simply the Windows kernel. As I've described it in the past,<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsoft-confirms-minwin-is-in-windows-7-after-all/1690"> MinWin is the heart of Windows</a>, organized in a way so that none of the included parts has any dependencies on anything outside of MinWin.</p>
<p>So what is MinKernel in this context? According to one of my sources, MinKernel is a minimal set of functionality that is shared across the different Windows kernels that run on x86, ARM, Windows Phone and Xbox. MinKernel is the one base-level implementation on top of which these platforms are built, the same way that BaseFS may be the base-level file system that is common across different platforms.</p>
<p>Since word of Windows Blue first surfaced months ago, tipsters have said there would be <a href="/story/create/">kernel-level and driver-level changes included as part of this first operating-system update to Windows 8</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.itworld.com/windows/350114/7-hidden-gems-windows-blue">Villinger also found a few more Blue clues</a> worth noting. He discovered some references within the Blue bits to a Modern/Windows Store version of the Windows Defender antivirus app that Microsoft bundled with Windows 8 and Windows RT. (Right now, Defender is a Desktop, not a Metro-Style app.) He also found some hints that indicate that 3G/4G tethering support may be built into Blue.</p>
<p>My ZDNet colleague Ed Bott also discovered <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-windows-8-hardware-specs-hint-at-7-inch-tablets-and-a-microsoft-reader-7000013271/">a change&nbsp;in Microsoft's certification guidelines for Windows 8 hardware that clear the path for 7- and 8-inch tablets</a>.</p>
<p>Microsoft officials have been hinting for the past couple months that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-windows-8-coming-to-a-smaller-screen-size-near-you-7000010773/">smaller Windows 8 tablets were likely in the pipeline</a>. Rumors of both a <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/htc-said-to-plan-windows-tablets-to-challenge-apple-led-market.html">7-inch HTC Windows tablet</a> and an <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-report-throws-fuel-on-microsoft-xbox-surface-rumors-7000006986/">Xbox Surface media-consumption tablet</a> are out there.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013288</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/facebooks-android-play-could-be-boon-for-htc-7000013288/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Facebook's Android play could be boon for HTC]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Should HTC be Facebook's hardware partner for a social phone the smartphone maker could get a revenue boost and more scale to compete with Samsung.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 14:06:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-htc/">HTC</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>HTC is an underdog in the Android landscape, has to battle Samsung's scale and Apple's knack for design. It's a tall order that could be made a bit easier with the help of Facebook.</p>
<p>According to a Facebook invitation, the company will outline its new home on Android April 4.</p>
<figure><img title="fbandroid" alt="fbandroid" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013288/fbandroid-595x588.png?hash=LmSyZGyuAz&upscale=1" height="588" width="595"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Reports <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/28/facebook-android-phone/">from TechCrunch</a> and <a href="http://www.techmeme.com/130328/p63#a130328p63">a few others</a> are betting that Facebook's Android overlay would go along with HTC hardware. If these reports play out, HTC would likely see unit volume pick up and perhaps even have a hit on its hands.</p>
<p>A Facebook phone business model could look like Google's Nexus program. Facebook would embed natively social features on a device's home screen and hardware makers would line up as a partner.</p>
<p>For HTC, there's not much to lose. The company needs to make a few big bets to juice revenue growth.</p>
<p>More:</p>
<ul>
<li><a >A more aggressive HTC would be welcome</a></li>
<li><a >The HTC One is the best smartphone I have ever used (review)</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013277</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/pertino-serves-up-small-business-networks-in-the-cloud-7000013277/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Pertino serves up small-business networks, in the cloud]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Backed with new funding of $20 million, the startup aims to offer software-defined networks for SMBs that don't want to make - or can't afford - complex hardware.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Heather Clancy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Startup <a href="http://pertino.com/">Pertino</a>, which just raised an additional $20 million in Series B funding, is testing a cloud service that allows small businesses to set up virtual local area networks or wide area networks using just software. It's an idea similar to the one behind Meraki, the company that was snapped up by Cisco in November 2012 for a cool $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>Pertino's vision is that it should be as easy for small-business owners to set up secure networks for file sharing and chared collaboration scenarios as it is to invite someone to join your social network. In other words, very easy. All you need is Interent connectivity.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Right now, the technology works with Windows devices although support for the Macintosh operating system and various mobile devices is planned throughout 2013 as the company tests its services, said Craig Elliott, co-founder and CEO of Pertino, which is based in Los Gatos, Calif.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"You can have multiple networks, basically use to connect local, secure groups of people that need to share information," he said.</p>
<p>If Elliott's name sounds familar, it's because he used to be the CEO of Packeteer, the network optimization company that was eventually bought by Blue Coast Systems.</p>
<p>There are approximately 1,000 customers trying out the early version of the system, after a beta test of the technology with the Spiceworks IT pro community. The initial devices supported include WIndows 7, Windows Server 2008 R2 Systems with Windows 8, Windows Server 2012, with Mac OS &nbsp;systems to be supported soon. Mobile devices will be added in late 2013.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Small businesses can use Pertino to create networks for up to three users for free; after that, it is <a href="http://pertino.com/">priced</a> at $10 per month, per user.</p>
<p>Pertino's new $20 million in backing comes from Jafco Ventures. The infusion brings Pertino's total raised so far to $28.85 million. Its other funders include Norwest Venture Partners and Lightspeed Venture Partners.</p>
<p>"One of the things that attracted us to Pertino is the fact that they have built a cloud-based solution leveraging the most innovative and disruptive technology to hit networking in a decade -- software defined networking (SDN) -- and they're delivering it in a practical and consumable way to an underserved global market," said Jeb Miller, general partner at Jafco, explaining the rationale for the investment.</p>
<p>Here's more about Pertino's concept:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/JnMTLbWURv4" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013286</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/savvis-capitalizes-on-their-cloud-customer-relationships-7000013286/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Savvis capitalizes on their cloud customer relationships]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Savvis lays it on the line on providing reliable cloud services]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:49:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[David Chernicoff]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the issues that consumers of cloud services consider, as part of the selection process for determining which cloud service providers to use, is the reliability of the infrastructure that is hosting the desired services. Removing that concern from the purchase selection criteria can speed the adoption process for cloud services, and that&rsquo;s part of what <a href="http://www.savvis.com/">Savvis </a>is trying to do with their Client Connect service.</p>
<p>After all, if you are using a colo or cloud host for yourself, you must have already gone through the vetting process for that provider, otherwise why would you be using their services. And Client Connect is designed to give Savvis customer&rsquo;s an enhanced ability to connect with other Savvis datacenter users in any of the Savvis datacenter facilities.</p>
<p>The Client Connect service, which Savvis customers need to voluntarily choose to participate in, both as buyers and sellers, Is basically a directory of service providers hosting at any of Savvis&rsquo; datacenter facilities. Each client gets a profile page where they can promote their service offering and where they need to provide contact information for potential customers. &nbsp;Offering your company&rsquo;s erices in this fashion also includes the requirement for rapid deployment;&nbsp; Savvis is attempting to guarantee &nbsp;rapid client-to-client cross-connect provisioning, with a deployment completion target of within 48 hours when the service is ordered via the SavvisStation portal</p>
<p>This is one of those perfectly obvious things that every large scale coclo and hosting services vendor should be providing. While a goal of using cloud services is to be able to not worry where the actual services reside, that&rsquo;s proven to be a somewhat elusive task. Weekly reports of even the largest service providers facing outages have to make customers think twice about where the service they contract for is being hosted. Especially given the degree of finger pointing that seems to occur when problems do crop up.</p>
<p>By promoting the other services running within the environment they control, Savvis would take the heat for any outages; giving their customers the proverbial &ldquo;one throat to choke&rdquo; for infrastructure issues. So making this service model available not only promotes customers of Savvis but also shows them taking a stand for the reliability of their underlying infrastructure.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013285</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/what-is-the-business-impact-of-it-7000013285/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[What is the business impact of IT?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[What's the real business impact of information technology? What is the real cost when a workload slows down or fails?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:18:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Dan Kusnetzky]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Business executives increasingly wish to understand this impact, but, unfortunately, the knowledge and experience about the causes of slow downs or failures is not held by the same people who focus on business issues such as the loss of revenues, increase in costs or the loss of customers.</p>
<p>Although executives want to be able to quickly learn how a slow-down or outage impacts the company's revenues and intangibles such as customer satisfaction. Quick actionable answers aren't always easily created. Items such as the cost of the outage in terms of revenues, shipments, retail sales and the like require delving into both business and operational data. Teasing out the actual costs and value of lost opportunities often requires a team of people from different parts of the organization.</p>
<p>Today's management software technology has only recently developed the ability to sift through operational data, make decisions about what is happening in real time and then project the business impact. This type of technology is known generally as "predictive analytics for IT." It may also be discussed as using machine intelligence to address this complex problem.</p>
<p>It is clear that it has become time for IT decision-makers to embrace IT analytics and be able to easily understand the full impact their systems and solutions have on the business.</p>
<p>If you're interested in a quick analysis of this issue and potential solutions, I've recently released a paper focused on the business impact of IT. It can be found <a href="http://kusnetzky.net/publications/ImpactPapers/20130319%20Do%20You%20Know%20the%20Business%20Impact%20of%20IT%20final.pdf" target="_blank">here</a>, if you'd like a free copy.</p>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: this paper was sponsored by a Kusnetzky Group client.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013280</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/bb10-on-the-z10-is-making-me-a-blackberry-fan-again-7000013280/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[BB10 on the Z10 is making me a BlackBerry fan again]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[I have never been a die hard BlackBerry user, but a couple years ago the PlayBook and Bold 9930 combo appealed to me. It looks like the fresh UI and usefulness of BlackBerry 10 may be grabbing hold of me again.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 12:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Matthew Miller]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-blackberry/">BlackBerry</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="BB10 on the Z10 is making me a BlackBerry fan again" alt="BB10 on the Z10 is making me a BlackBerry fan again" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013280/bbz10-200x166.jpg?hash=Mwt1AwAwZJ&upscale=1" height="166" width="200"></figure>
<p>The BlackBerry Z10 is now available from AT&amp;T, T-Mobile, and Verizon here in the US. A couple years ago I <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/cell-phones/becoming-a-blackberry-fan-when-its-not-cool-to-do-so/6377">became a BlackBerry fan</a> due to the PlayBook and Bold 9930 combo. It looks like it's happening again as I just ordered another PlayBook and am thoroughly enjoying the Z10 experience. My love of the underdogs, including Windows Phone, BlackBerry, and HTC, continues.</p>
<p>I've been using a US GSM model of the Z10 for over a month and just received the <a href="http://shop.crackberry.com/blackberry-transform-hard-shell/4A123A13567.htm">red BB Transform Shell</a> case I ordered to go along with the device. I previously tested out the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-accessories-roundup-review-7000012982/">black Transform Shell case</a> and like the red one even better. My wife commented that it looks like Darth Maul's case due to the black and red color scheme. It offers decent protection, adds minimal size, and gives me a way to prop up the Z10 and enjoy video content.</p>
<p>I have a few devices to use with T-Mobile, including the Galaxy Note II and Nokia N9. The Note II is an extremely powerful device, but it is also a rather large device and it ends up on my desk and in my bag more than in my pocket. The Z10 works well with a single hand and has been in my pants pocket and with me quite a bit over the past couple of weeks.</p>
<p>However, it's not just an issue of size. The BlackBerry Z10 UI appeals to me, especially the BlackBerry Hub and peek functionality. I am finding that I prefer the simple way various forms of communications appear in the Hub rather than jumping in and out of apps or special notification areas.</p>
<p>I have many apps loaded on the Z10, there are great apps released almost daily now too, however I am finding that BlackBerry 10 has most of what I need built into the device and the powerful web browser lets me get things done when apps are not available. The apps that are available work well on the Z10 and the MeeGo-like multi-tasking screen lets me work very efficiently. Take an honest look at what apps are truly essential on a daily basis and you may just find those 10-15 apps are available on the Z10.</p>
<p>BlackBerry has a long ways to go, but they did have a rather <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-q4-better-than-expected-1m-blackberry-z10-devices-shipped-7000013220/">successful Q4</a> when the Z10 was only shipping in a few select countries. With the Z10 now available in the US and the Q10 coming in April, I look forward to hearing about more success from BlackBerry in the next financial period.</p>
<p>I plan to stick with the Z10 on T-Mobile exclusively if I can for the next month and give it a serious test. You need to spend dedicated time with devices for long periods of time to judge whether or not it can work well in your life.</p>
<p>I find the UI to be <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/nokia-meego-fans-will-appreciate-ui-elements-of-blackberry-10-7000010634/">much like MeeGo was</a>, but Nokia dropped MeeGo as soon as it was released and we can rest assured that BlackBerry is all in with the Z10 and BlackBerry 10. Actually, BlackBerry's strategy and dedication to succeed with BlackBerry 10 give me more confidence than Microsoft and its Windows Phone strategy. As a result, I think BlackBerry may just retain its current third place and increase in market share faster than Windows Phone.</p>
<p><strong>Related stories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-aims-to-show-it-can-keep-popular-apps-updated-7000013276/">BlackBerry aims to show it can keep popular apps updated</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-us-release-week-is-there-enough-in-bb10-to-attract-new-buyers-7000013123/">BlackBerry Z10 US release week: Is there enough in BB10 to attract new buyers?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-accessories-roundup-review-7000012982/">BlackBerry Z10 accessories roundup (review)</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-is-an-efficient-communications-focused-device-7000011793/">BlackBerry Z10 is an efficient communications-focused device</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-q4-lives-to-die-another-day-7000013239/">BlackBerry Q4: Lives to die another day?</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-daily-driver-thanks-to-these-10-apps-and-shortcuts-screenshot-gallery-7000011780/">BlackBerry Z10: Daily driver, thanks to these 10 apps and shortcuts</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-10-and-the-z10-10-things-i-like-and-5-things-i-dont-7000010757/">BlackBerry 10 and the Z10: 10 things I like and 5 things I don't</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-10-is-the-first-blackberry-to-fully-support-byod-7000010717/">BlackBerry 10 is the first BlackBerry to fully support BYOD</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-z10-daily-driver-thanks-to-these-10-apps-and-shortcuts-screenshot-gallery-7000011780/">BlackBerry Z10: Daily driver thanks to these 10 apps and shortcuts (screenshot gallery)</a></p>
</li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013284</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/its-about-frickin-time-u-s-gov-requires-security-review-for-chinese-tech-purchases-7000013284/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[It's about frickin' time: U.S. gov requires security review for Chinese tech purchases]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[We have been letting the fox guard the hen house for far too long, and it's high time the U.S. government did something about it.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:56:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[David Gewirtz]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government/">Government</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-china/">China</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you look out the window, you might notice that the moon is blue. If you check the Weather Channel, reports are that hell has indeed frozen over. As unlikely as it may seem, our politicians have apparently done something right.</p>
<p>In order for America's government to fund its operations, programs, and agencies, money has to be allocated for this purpose on a regular basis. In many years, that budget money is allocated through something called a "continuing resolution," that's passed in Congress and signed by the President.</p>
<p>A continuing resolution passed this year as well, except this time it had some teeth, in particular when it comes to China's ongoing acts of apparent espionage and skulduggery.</p>
<p>Put simply, the newly signed 240-page law requires law enforcement authorities to be consulted and perform a cybersecurity and sabotage risk assessment when buying IT gear.</p>
<p>Here's the hot button, the once-in-a-blue-moon, hell-freezing-over smart move by our politicians. The formal risk assessment by law enforcement must (and I'm quoting the <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/28/us-usa-cybersecurity-espionage-idUSBRE92Q18O20130328">Reuters article</a> quoting the bill): "...include any risk associated with such system being produced, manufactured or assembled by one or more entities that are owned, directed or subsidized by China."</p>
<p><strong>This. Is. Huge.</strong></p>
<p>I'm not going to go over the whole China risk thing in-depth here because we've been down this trail before. See the links at the end of the article for a good set of reads on China's apparent inability to play well with others.</p>
<p>But I will say this: China, by all indications, wants it both ways. They want to sell us gear, bring our currency into their country, and grow their economy with the help of American purchasing power. But they also seem to want to sneak into our computer systems, constantly testing, probing, and attacking our networks, and otherwise cause us harm.</p>
<p><strong>They want to make money from us at the same time they're willing to attack us.</strong></p>
<p>What's been deeply disturbing me for years (and I've been writing about this here, <a href="http://ac360.blogs.cnn.com/2009/04/10/is-china-friend-or-foe/">on CNN</a>, and even giving lectures and advisories on this to government officials) is that Chinese gear is inside everything we use today.</p>
<p>The motherboard inside the computer I'm using right now was made in China. In fact, the computer I'm using right now was made in China. Your iPhone was assembled in China.</p>
<p>In fact, many of the internal components and entire computers (Lenovo on its way to becoming the world's largest PC producer) are made in China. Telecommunications equipment is made in China. We even did a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/huawei-should-you-put-it-in-your-data-center/10107066/closing-statement/">Great Debate</a> here on ZDNet about whether it was wise to buy networking gear from Chinese Huawei, who has been involved in some dubious doings (and is becoming a major vendor of smartphones as well).</p>
<p>Think back to the cold war days when the Soviets and the Americans where banging shoes at each other and threatening total nuclear destruction. Would any of us (or our grandparents, I guess) have thought it made sense to buy security gear from the Soviets?</p>
<p>Of course not. Even the most pacifist peaceniks around would have thought that letting your enemy provide your security wasn't exactly a wise course.</p>
<p>And yet that's what we've been doing. Nearly all of us rely on gear made by China. Nearly all our personal and confidential passwords and logins travel over circuits made by China. Many of our networks and network switches, if not made by China directly, have Chinese components.</p>
<p>We have been letting the fox guard the hen house for far too long, and it's high time the U.S. government did something about it. I applaud this action by Congress and the President (did you <em>ever</em> think I'd ever say anything like that?), and encourage the government to take even more stringent action and due-diligence against foreign-supplied security equipment.</p>
<p><strong>ZDNet Government China coverage:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/questionable-loyalties-the-cybersecurity-implications-of-buying-system-software-from-foreign-companies/11276">Questionable loyalties: the cybersecurity implications of buying system software from foreign companies</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/huawei-should-you-put-it-in-your-data-center/10107066/closing-statement/">Great Debate - Huawei: Should you put it in your data center?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/it-might-be-time-to-throw-some-salt-on-china-7000011521/">It might be time to throw some SALT on China</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/state-of-the-union-cyberthreat-7000011248/">State of the Union: Cyberthreat</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/14-global-cybersecurity-challenges-for-2013-7000009352/">14 global cybersecurity challenges for 2013</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/dear-china-cut-out-the-sneaky-spying-shenanigans-7000005623/">Dear China: Cut out the sneaky spying shenanigans</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/hack-in-the-box-researcher-reveals-ease-of-huawei-router-access-7000005600/">Researcher reveals ease of Huawei router access </a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/u-k-to-probe-huawei-bt-relationship-over-security-concerns-7000005616/">U.K. to probe Huawei, BT relationship</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/did-chinese-security-firm-snag-too-many-american-security-secrets-before-the-barn-door-closed/11008">Did Chinese security firm snag too many American security secrets before the barn door closed?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/in-china-many-younger-military-leaders-view-america-as-the-ultimate-enemy/9517">In China, many younger military leaders view America as the ultimate enemy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/is-china-gearing-up-to-start-world-war-iii/9368">Is China gearing up to start World War III?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/welcome-to-the-new-cold-war-china-vs-the-united-states/10289">Welcome to the new Cold War: China vs. the United States</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/dear-mrs-clinton-whether-you-believe-it-or-not-china-is-a-threat-to-america/10380">Dear Mrs. Clinton: whether you believe it or not, China is a threat to America</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/us-finally-acknowledges-chinese-and-russian-cyberthreat/10971">U.S. finally acknowledges Chinese and Russian cyberthreat</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/video-should-americans-worry-about-a-chinese-cyber-threat/10760">Video: Should Americans worry about a Chinese cyber-threat?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/pace-university-forensics-expert-on-china-and-cybercrime-exclusive-video/11187">Pace University forensics expert on China and cybercrime (exclusive video)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/technology-policy-challenges-faced-by-the-u-s-federal-government-video-seminar/11029">Technology policy challenges faced by the U.S. Federal Government (video seminar)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/deconstructing-a-nasty-chinese-world-of-warcraft-phishing-scheme/10952">Deconstructing a nasty Chinese World of Warcraft phishing scheme</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/government/why-the-united-states-might-pay-china-before-we-pay-our-own-soldiers/10588">Why the United States might pay China before we pay our own soldiers</a></li>
<li><strong>Also see:</strong> There are chapters covering China in my book, <em>How To Save Jobs</em> (<a href="http://howtosavejobs.org">free PDF download</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013094</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/worst-pitch-of-the-month-qpid-me-and-sharing-std-results-via-text-7000013094/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Worst pitch of the month: Qpid.me and sharing STD results via text]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[This month's roundup of terrible PR pitches include using Facebook to find out if a spouse is cheating and "the cubicle walk of shame."]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month, we started a new column here on <em>ZDNet</em> dedicated to the worst pitches we receive from PR reps.</p>
<p>At first I was a little nervous at how this featurette would be received, but turns out a lot of my PR friends spread the word via email and Twitter -- either out of entertainment or as a warning to their colleagues.</p>
<p>Either way, let's continue as there will likely never be a shortage of fodder for this topic. The 194 voicemails on my phone can attest to that.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/worst-pitch-of-the-month-plantronics-and-the-mass-employee-wedding-7000011145/">Worst pitch of the month: Plantronics and the mass employee wedding</a></p>
<p>In February, the overwhelming theme that strung most of our winners together was Valentine's Day. Honestly, I don't see how business technology and romance mix in any plausible way. Perhaps I should give more credit to PR professionals for trying -- but really they were just trying too hard.</p>
<p>With <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/sxsw-interactive-2013-trade-show-favorites-7000012578/">South by Southwest</a> earlier in March, naturally there was a deluge of pitches each day.</p>
<p>(For reference, while I typically receive many story ideas and press releases each day in my inbox, it tends to downpour at certain times of year, such as the holiday season and the few weeks leading up to CES in January.)</p>
<p>Considering SxSW attracts a wide range of interests and characters itself, there's not much room for surprise when it comes to just how ridiculous some of the story pitches were.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, one should never underestimate how outlandish (not to mention inappropriate) some of these emails can get.</p>
<p>Here's the worst (or maybe just creepiest) one, by far:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Is South by Southwest (SXSW) the new Spring Break for Emerging Tech Geeks? The must have mobile technology for SXSW isn&rsquo;t a festival guide or chat/photo feature &ndash; it&rsquo;s a new website that allows you to verify and check someone&rsquo;s STD status on your mobile phone &ndash; Qpid.me. *Qpid.me is a free website for people who wants to privately share their verified STD results with anyone via text message or online*. </em></p>
<p><em>Geeks love it! It&rsquo;s a known fact that there is a huge amount of "Sex" that happens at SXSW as creators, indie film makers, up-and-coming stars flock there to spark ideas, find investors, create together and&hellip;have sex. The panel sessions on Sex and Creativity tend to be most popular. But is the free love of the festival worth the after effects of coming home with an unwanted gift like some Spring Breakers, an STD? </em></p>
<p><em>If you would like to speak to the creator of Qpid.me &ndash; Ramin Bastani, please let us know!</em></p>
<p>[REDACTED]</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's not that such a service isn't useful. Certainly, it's a good idea to discuss things with a partner, and this potentially removes some of the embarrassment factor.</p>
<p>But besides potentially surpassing the boundaries of mobile notifications, all the spring break/SxSW/tech geek references are all just a bit much -- especially considering, once again, this doesn't relate to business and enterprise technology at all.</p>
<p>(Or at least not on the surface, but I digress...)</p>
<p>I also feel that I should include a few honorable mentions -- albeit they are not SxSW-related. However, this is more of a subcategory for the worst email subject lines.</p><p>Or perhaps I should rephrase that as the best worst subject lines because while they certainly caught my attention, the rest of the text was drab if not a complete letdown.</p>
<p>Here are two for your enjoyment and ridicule:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Subject line: <strong>Facebook, Is My Wife Cheating On Me?</strong></p>
<p><em>Facebook&rsquo;s social search via Graph has put the first nails in the coffin of multiple industries. It threatens to make marketing agencies, detectives, lawyers and more obsolete. Graph tells you the intersection of people, places, photos and interests from a billion members. The outcomes are very different than googling someone since you are getting references rather than simple look ups. </em></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Graph&rdquo; is a computer science term for traversing data structures, not just up and down but in any direction. </em></p>
<p><em>Facebook Graph users (marketers, jealous spouses, potential employers) could potentially search your past or potential whereabouts, activities, opinions and &ldquo;friends.&rdquo; When using search engines people tend to believe the results as &ldquo;fact&rdquo; or &ldquo;news.&rdquo; The now famous State Farm, &ldquo;Where&rsquo;d you hear that?&rdquo; commercial is a spoof on what happens when fact meets opinion. </em></p>
<p><em>I put Graph to the test on two highly talked about items last month. I asked who would win Grammy&rsquo;s &ldquo;Best New Artist.&rdquo; The result &ldquo;Scotty McCreery&rdquo; (posted here) is a miss because he wasn&rsquo;t nominated in 2013 though many people &ldquo;like&rdquo; him. I then asked who would win Best Picture for the Oscars (Academy Awards, I tried several variations), with oddly no results at all. Interpreting the results is too much like Fortunetelling. The system has the potential for sowing doubt without enough facts. </em></p>
<p><em>The implication is that we must give up more of our privacy to make Graph accurate or take ourselves completely &ldquo;off the grid.&rdquo; Cheating spouses and Grammy winners aside, the evolution of Social Search outlines new job opportunities just as the first Internet search engines did. </em></p>
<p><em>I am Lawrence I. Lerner (President LLBC, LLC) a recognized and published change agent. Last year I co-wrote &lsquo;Facebook for Your Business.&rsquo; In this book I predicted the release of this latest feature in the world of Social Commerce. It&rsquo;s my prediction that information privacy will be an important platform of the next presidential election. </em></p>
<p><em>Please let me know if you are interested in an interview and I will plan accordingly. </em></p>
<p><em>Sincerely, </em></p>
<p><em>Lawrence</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Subject line: <strong>The Cubicle Walk of Shame</strong></p>
<p><em>Yahoo! has stunned the nation by its decision to no longer allow employees to work from home. Is their justification really about efficiency or is it merely a way to micro-manage? Tim Houlne and Terri Maxwell, authors of The New World of Work: From the Cube to the Cloud, offer a unique perspective on this highly controversial topic. They are phenomenal speakers and make entertaining guests. </em></p>
<p><em>Please read the following press release and let me know if I may schedule an interview with either Tim or Terri that is sure to be of interest to your audience. Thank you. </em></p>
<p><em>[REDACTED]</em></p>
<p><em>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE </em></p>
<p><em>The Cubicle Walk of Shame </em></p>
<p><em>Irving, TX, March 13, 2013 - In one of the most stunning, non-progressive moves seen from a technology company, Yahoo! has banned working from home. The justification was to improve speed and quality by working side-by-side as one. This begs the question &ndash; is the issue really virtual work or the lack of good management coupled with an inability to capitalize on the virtual work environment? </em></p>
<p><em>There is a New Currency: </em></p>
<p><em>The truth is that the new currency for top tier talent is freedom. These people came to the realization long ago that gold-watch retirements are a thing of the past, and to ensure a long-term career meant taking matters into their own hands. Since the benefits offered by corporations such as insurance and paid vacations are not part of this new world of work, freedom and flexibility became the desirable traits. </em></p>
<p><em>Spend the New Currency with Better Management: </em></p>
<p><em>Progressive companies attract creative, productive talent with the way they &ldquo;manage people,&rdquo; which truthfully is not to manage people at all. Rather than buy into the &ldquo;productivity can only be seen&rdquo; mode of thinking, companies that embrace the virtualization of work product attract that always sought after motivated self-starter. </em></p>
<p><em>To capitalize on this new work currency, companies must: </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Manage the process and outcome, not the people. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Utilize more peer to peer management to encourage collaboration. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Invest in cloud technology to manage projects. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Understand virtual collaboration both from a technology and communication standpoint in order to get the best ideas. </em></p>
<p><em>&bull; Physical presence does not improve creativity. Creative people engaged in the idea and committed to a solid outcome do. </em></p>
<p><em>$2 Bills Seemed Like a Good Idea at the Time: </em></p>
<p><em>Forcing people to return to a cubicle breeds a level of mistrust. Obviously those who have enjoyed the freedom of virtual work environments will feel that they are not empowered to perform their job on their own. The top tier talent won&rsquo;t make the cubicle walk of shame. They will simply find another place to commit their talents. Only those who feel they do not have a choice will succumb.</em></p>
</blockquote>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013282</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/apples-new-iphone-wraparound-display-no-buttons-7000013282/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Apple's new iPhone? Wraparound display, no buttons]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A new patent filed by Apple shows us how future smartphones may look.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 10:48:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="apple iphone patent design flexible display" alt="apple iphone patent design flexible display" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013282/appleiphone-620x358.jpg?hash=AQtkLmRmMQ&upscale=1" height="358" width="620"></figure>
<p>Could a future iPhone feature a wraparound display?</p>
<p>According to a new patent filed by Apple, <a href="http://appft1.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO2&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;u=%2Fnetahtml%2FPTO%2Fsearch-adv.html&amp;r=29&amp;p=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;d=PG01&amp;S1=%28apple.AS.+AND+20130328.PD.%29&amp;OS=an/apple+and+pd/3/28/2013&amp;RS=%28AN/apple+AND+PD/20130328%29">patent application 20130076612</a>, a potential smartphone design could include a full wraparound display and have no buttons. Enclosed within "transparent housing," a flexible display panel would be configured to display content at any portion of the gadget's frame.</p>
<p>The patent application explains:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"The majority of portable electronic device manufacturers utilize a common form factor consisting generally of a flat planar form factor with a single surface dedicated mainly for use as a display surface, while the other surfaces remain largely unused, save for the occasional button or switch."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Potentially, the smartphone could contain up to two AMOLED screens. Standing for Active Matrix OLED -- these types of screen pair a traditional TFT display with an OLED display. Due to their active matrix, AMOLED screens have faster pixel switching, which means that response types are higher than OLED displays. The use of AMOLED and a conical shape for the flexible panel could offer users "an illusion of depth perception [...] mimicking a 3D experience."</p>
<p>In addition, the patent explains that facial recognition technology could be used to detect a registered end-user of the smartphone.</p>
<p>The aim of the new design is to make use of "unused space" which is typical with any current mobile device, extending functionality to both the back and the sides of a gadget. Therefore, Apple may be considering the use of curved screens and a flexible display which not only is touch-responsive, but makes use of the surface on both sides of a future iPhone.</p>
<p>The patent proposes that touch replace buttons entirely -- and a coating could be added to the display to reduce smudge marks and keep the gadget looking pretty. As an example, the application says that "Instead of the hold button a multi touch gesture along one of the sides could instead act as a method of locking and unlocking the hold function."</p>
<p>The new design relies heavily on flexible display technology, but in order to limit the possibility of damage, the patent describes the phone as being incased in glass -- bent into a conical shape, but serving as protection in case you drop your gadget. With such advances being made in the smartphone industry -- and the market already crowded with operating systems, similar phone designs and application ecosystems -- perhaps Apple's move into flexible displays could help the firm keep its dominant position.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013278</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/appearance-ppug-saturday-in-philadelphia-withings-ws-50-preview-7000013278/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Appearance: PPUG Saturday in Philadelphia (Withings WS-50 preview)]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[If you're in the Philadelphia area come see an exclusive demonstration of the new Withings WS-50 Wi-Fi scale that measures weight, body composition, heart rate, and air quality at PPUG. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Mar 2013 03:27:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Jason D. O'Grady]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ios/">iOS</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-iphone/">iPhone</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ipad/">iPad</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="Come see the new Withings WS-50 Wi-Fi scale at PPUG in Philadelphia on Saturday" alt="Come see the new Withings WS-50 Wi-Fi scale at PPUG in Philadelphia on Saturday" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013278/screen-shot-2013-03-28-at-11-20-04-pm-620x227.png?hash=BTAyZJSwLw&upscale=1" height="227" width="620"></figure>
<p>I'll be presenting at the&nbsp;<strong><a href="http://ppug.net/" target="_blank">Philadelphia PowerBook User Group</a></strong>&nbsp;(PPUG) on<strong>&nbsp;</strong>Saturday, March 30, 2013 from 12 noon to 3 p.m. PPUG is&nbsp;the first dedicated PowerBook User Group (PPUG) in the United States and was founded in 1999.</p>
<p>We meet&nbsp;at the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.manayunkbrewery.com" target="_blank">Manayunk Brewing Company</a>&nbsp;along the beautiful Schuylkill River in Philadelphia, PA and our meetings is open to all. We usually have lunch (or a brew) while we talk mobile computing.</p>
<p>We've got a big slate to present.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I'm going to present the latest in wearable fitness computers, including the <strong>Jawbone Up</strong> band, the <strong>BodyMedia FIT LINK</strong> and their associated iOS apps. I'm also giving an exclusive demonstration of the <strong>Withings WS-50</strong>&nbsp;Smart Body Analyzer. It's your chance to preview the new Wi-Fi scale that&nbsp;measures weight, body composition,&nbsp;heart rate, and air quality before it starts shipping in mid-April.</p>
<p>Rob Parker will do a roundup of the latest gadgets in the ParkerDigital stable, including the&nbsp;Pebble watch,&nbsp;Nike+ Fuel Band, FitBit One,&nbsp;Mophie Juice Pack Air for iPhone 5 and some iPad mini cases.&nbsp;Apple Distinguished Educator Youngmoo Kim will give a presentation about issues and tricks he's encountered doing presentations wirelessly using AirPlay. He'll be presenting using an Apple TV connected to a BenQ 761 projector.</p>
<p>Join us for a great meeting, it’s free and open to you and your guests. Feel free to bring items to sell or swap as well.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.manayunkbrewery.com/" target="_blank">Manayunk Brewing Company </a></p>
<p>4120 Main Street</p>
<p>Philadelphia, PA 19127</p>
<p>215.482.8220&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013276</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-aims-to-show-it-can-keep-popular-apps-updated-7000013276/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[BlackBerry aims to show it can keep popular apps updated]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[BlackBerry 10 appears to be off to a solid start, but to be a long term winner popular applications have to keep up with other platforms. That reality means BlackBerry developers may be adding features. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 22:04:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BlackBerry has updated its Facebook and Twitter app with new features that integrate with its BlackBerry 10 platform. The catch: Facebook and Twitter aren't the ones adding the features.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.blackberry.com/2013/03/social-media-app-updates/">The new versions</a> of Facebook and Twitter are being built by BlackBerry developers not the social sites. BlackBerry also developed Facebook and Twitter apps for its BlackBerry 7 platform too<a href="http://forums.crackberry.com/archive/index.php?t-741634.html"> and got complaints after awhile</a>.</p>
<p>This behind the scenes development won't be a big deal to the actual app user---unless the experience is horrible---but does highlight the following nuances with the BlackBerry platform.</p>
<ul>
<li>First, BlackBerry hasn't proven its latest platform is a consumer hit so app developers aren't likely to rush to go native. These developers are likely to stick with iOS and Android until another platform proves itself.</li>
<li>BlackBerry has Android apps in its market place and that has given it scale. However, BlackBerry has to develop popular apps if it wants to integrate the features unique to its platform.</li>
<li>If BlackBerry 10 devices are going to be a contender for bring your own device set-ups it needs the experience for the core mobile applications to be a good one.</li>
</ul>
<p>More:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberrys-bes-10-real-key-to-profit-potential-7000013264/">BlackBerry's BES 10 real key to profit potential</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cheaper-blackberry-10-handset-due-around-september-blackberry-chief-confirms-7000013260/">Cheaper BlackBerry 10 handset due around September, BlackBerry chief confirms</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-earnings-10-key-things-ceo-thorsten-heins-said-on-the-call-7000013249/">BlackBerry earnings: 10 key things CEO Thorsten Heins said on the call</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-q4-better-than-expected-1m-blackberry-z10-devices-shipped-7000013220/">BlackBerry Q4 better than expected; 1M BlackBerry Z10 devices shipped</a></p>
<p>The new version of Facebook for BlackBerry 10 integrates location and check-ins, photo sharing and local saving and event planning.&nbsp;BlackBerry also updated its Twitter app with a tab to view all interactions in one place, add photos to tweets and see the number of times a mention has been favorited.</p>
<figure><img title="fbbbry" alt="fbbbry" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013276/fbbbry-v1-552x386.png?hash=ZJZ2LmpkLw&upscale=1" height="386" width="552"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Note that none of these features will make you want to drop another platform, but BlackBerry is making sure it's top applications are competitive. And for now that means BlackBerry will be building in updates to core applications. In the long run, BlackBerry will have to make sure popular apps are updated no matter who does the code.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Should BlackBerry grab market share, companies like Facebook and Twitter would theoretically take over the updates with native versions of their apps.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013275</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/ebay-projects-global-commerce-volume-will-be-worth-300-billion-in-2015-7000013275/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[eBay projects global commerce volume will be worth $300 billion in 2015]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The online auction giant has set a major goal to more than double its total commerce and payment volume targets within the next two years.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:30:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tech-industry/">Tech Industry</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>eBay</strong> revealed a handful of multi-billion dollar goals it plans to achieve by 2015, including more than doubling the value of its global e-commerce portfolio.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/amazon-acquires-goodreads-aims-to-meld-kindle-with-social-7000013272/">Amazon acquires Goodreads, aims to meld Kindle with social</a></p>
<p>Announced amid the eBay's Analyst and Investor Day event, company leaders outlined a three-year growth strategy designed to drive core business growth.</p>
<p>When all is said and done, eBay plans to enable at least $300 billion in global commerce, up from $175 billion in 2012.</p>
<p>That figure is comprised of the total commerce and payment volume across all three of eBay's core business units: Marketplaces, PayPal and GSI.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the San Jose-based business plans to grow revenue to fall within the range of $21.5 billion to $23.5 billion in 2015 (up by more than 50 percent from $14.1 billion last year) with non-GAAP earnings per share to increase by 15 to 19 percent.</p>
<p>eBay president and CEO John Donahoe <a href="http://www.ebayinc.com/in_the_news/story/ebay-inc-expects-enable-300b-global-commerce-2015">explained during the event</a> at its headquarters on Thursday that this will be accomplished primarily by rolling out new mobile and local e-commerce experiences for consumers and retailers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Led by mobile, a commerce revolution is under way. Technology is creating a new web-enabled retail interface, a new seamless, multiscreen commerce experience that connects consumers anytime, anywhere. This will expand shopping beyond conventional store environments and e-commerce sites. How we shop is being transformed, and eBay Inc. intends to be a leader in this new commerce world.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Donahoe noted that eBay expects mobile commerce and payments volume alone to be worth $20 billion within the next two years.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013274</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/technology-darwinism-hits-microsofts-licensing-policies-7000013274/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Technology Darwinism hits Microsoft's licensing policies]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The time for good old-fashioned evolutionary extinction is at hand concerning Microsoft's licensing policies. The general consensus is in favor of that extinction.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:18:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ken Hess]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software/">Software</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software-development/">Software Development</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While not unanimous, the overwhelming majority&nbsp;(83 percent)&nbsp;of you agree with me that it's time for some licensing policy change in Redmond. The Great Debate this week between Matt Baxter-Reynolds and I, "<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/can-microsofts-complicated-software-licensing-policies-survive/10116605/" target="_blank">Can Microsoft&rsquo;s complicated software licensing policies survive?</a>," yielded some interesting results on both sides of the argument. But the reality is that times are changing rapidly. No longer do individuals on or off the job want to be tethered to a single device. And that single device mentality is but one of the rubs against Microsoft's outdated licensing policies.</p>
<p>Let me preface my statements here by saying that I am not anti-Microsoft. I never have been although some readers might have assumed it from my Linux advocacy and a few random rants about rebooting and stability of Windows operating systems. Those issues have been addressed over the years and I'm glad to say that Microsoft has done an excellent job with operating systems such as Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8 (Yes, Windows 8), Windows Server 2003, Windows Server 2008 and Windows Server 2012.</p>
<p>No company is perfect. And Microsoft has had its share of imperfections over the years but they've always spoken to them and resolved them satisfactorily. I'm hoping that policy hasn't changed and that they will reconsider their very complex licensing policies that will continue to draw complaints, negative commentary and hate mail.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The solution, in my opinion, is a subscription model. Office 365 is an excellent example of what can happen with this type of software licensing. It's a proven method and it works.</p>
<p>As I stated in the debate, a software subscription model is a win-win situation for Microsoft and businesses who purchase licenses.</p>
<p>Microsoft wins because software piracy will be minimal with subscription-based use. The company loses millions, if not hundreds of millions, of dollars every year due to software piracy. And I know what you're thinking--that they can afford it--but can you?</p>
<p>One of the reasons software is so expensive is because of piracy. Think about it from their perspective. They create an application such as Visio, for example. Microsoft spends millions of dollars in software development to create Visio. They pay their programmers a salary, take care of their benefits, vacation time, sick leave, maternity/paternity leave and other expenses.&nbsp;</p>
<p>They have a lot of money invested in creating Visio. They have to make their investment back plus a profit to stay in business. Additionally, they have to factor in loss due to piracy into that price plus free code maintenance in the form of upgrades, extras, patches and service packs. It adds up.</p>
<p>They don't just create something like Visio in a vacuum. They have to support it for its entire life cycle with those updates and personnel who maintain the version you're on for years. Plus, they pay programmers to create new versions, so there's more expense. It's a never ending cycle that's very expensive to maintain. Everyone just sees them raking in billions of dollars without looking at what it takes to make those billions.</p>
<p>From an Office 365 type delivery system, everyone could always have the latest version of Visio available. Microsoft wouldn't have to deal with supporting Visio 2003 until Visio 2013 arrives on shelves. They would support one version. No compatibility problems, no copying of the CD for a brother-in-law, no additional support for service packs, updates, hotfixes or maintenance for three or four different versions floating around.</p>
<p>On the customer side of things, you'd pay a fee to use Visio per user, per month. Instead of spending thousands, tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands on software all at once, you'd spend a small, predictable amount for subscriptions every month or on an annual basis.</p>
<p>Everyone in your company would have the same versions of the software as everyone else. The company across the country, your customer, would also have the same software. No file conversion, no need to Save As and no need to make apologies or excuses for not having an application that matches your customer's or your supplier's.</p>
<p>There would also be no need for those annual software audits. No pressure from the software piracy police breathing down your necks to true up or get fined. Subscriptions make it easy to know how many software licenses you're using, how much it costs and you never have to worry about compliance. You're covered.</p>
<p>So why hasn't Microsoft embraced this model?&nbsp;</p>
<p>I don't know why.</p>
<p>It makes a lot of sense to me and to a lot of you as well. Antivirus companies are doing it. Salesforce.com is doing it. Google is doing it. Apple is doing it. Adobe is doing it. In fact, here are three customer quotes from Adobe's web site concerning the subscription model:</p>
<p><em>"The flexible monthly payments help me work more economically as a sole proprietor and choose the software I need, when I need it."&nbsp;</em>&mdash; Damian Cooke, freelance designer</p>
<p><em>"We continue to use the subscription option of Creative Suite because it is kinder on our cash flow and alleviates the need to worry about software updates on our own. By signing up for the month-to-month plan, we have the flexibility to pay for what we need, when we need it."&nbsp;</em>&mdash; Liza Bloomer, creative director at Yoohoo Web &amp; Graphic Design <strong>&nbsp;</strong> <em>"Adobe Creative Suite Subscription Edition keeps my cash flow healthy and my costs predictable &mdash; all while ensuring that I always have the latest software versions and newest features without having to upgrade on my own."&nbsp;</em>&mdash; Joel Coleman, saltmotion</p>
<p>It's a good model. To subscribe to Photoshop for $19.99 per month instead of plopping down $600 or more for it sounds fine to me. I'm on board with that.</p>
<p>Change is hard. The traditional software model has worked for x number of years but now it no longer works. Microsoft will have to change with the times.</p>
<p>So, no, Microsoft's complicated software licensing policies can't survive. And they shouldn't.</p>
<p>Everything evolves. Software has been slow to change. As much as technical people like to think that they're on the leading edge of what's going on, they more they fight to keep the status quo.</p>
<p>Allow the evolution to take place. You can't fight it forever.&nbsp;</p>
<p>What do you think of Microsoft's software licensing policies? Survival of the fittest or endangered species? Talk back and let me know.</p>
<p><em><strong>See Also:</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/debate/can-microsofts-complicated-software-licensing-policies-survive/10116605/rebuttal/#skip-intro" target="_blank">The Great Debate: Can Microsoft's complicated software licensing policies survive?</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-client-access-licensing-and-pricing-changes-to-hit-december-1-7000007916/" target="_blank">Microsoft's client-access licensing and pricing changes to hit December 1</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-radically-overhauls-license-agreements-for-windows-8-7000002866/" target="_blank">Microsoft radically overhauls license agreements for Windows 8</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-attempts-to-clarify-office-licensing-policies-fall-short-7000011697/" target="_blank">Microsoft's attempts to clarify Office licensing policies fall short</a></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013269</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/beyond-google-apps-the-top-10-related-cloud-services-7000013269/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Beyond Google Apps: The top 10 related cloud services]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Ready to make a deeper commitment to the cloud? Here's what other businesses are downloading most often on the Google Apps Marketplace.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 20:54:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Heather Clancy]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If your company has made a commitment to using Google Apps, it may be able to drive more value out of that decision by adopting one of the many related applications featured in the <a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/">Google Apps Marketplace</a>.</p>
<p>If the sheer variety of choices overwhelm you, you could start by checking out the ones that have been installed most often by other businesses (a list that appears in the far righthand side of your browser screen). Most of them are for small or midsize organizations (although a couple appear to be meant more for large accounts).</p>
<p>For the purposes of shorthand, here is the top 10 list in descending order (as of the afternoon of March 28, 2013):</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=4970+4188150475217982560&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Mavenlink</a>: A workforce and project management system that shows time sheets, budgets and costs related to ongoing projects, accounts receivable aging reeports and other information that will help with resource utilization and planning.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=3525+5361236203077141107&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">MailChimp</a>: A newsletter service that can be integrated with a bunch of other popular small business cloud apps, including Rapportive, Batchbook CRM, Zendesk and Freshbooks. It also connects with e-commerce software including Shopify and Magento.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=3956+15797827514936543044&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Insightly</a>: A <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/insightlys-formula-for-crm-keep-it-simple-7000012115/">basic application</a> for tracking customer interactions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=14304+18345705634006699039&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">FlashPanel</a>: Management and security capabilities, including the ability to manage passwords, control user access, manage email usage and consumption, or create (and delete) shared contacts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=3418+11213291116317814502&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Capsule CRM</a>: A customer relationship management (CRM) tool that integrates with Google Apps, and with cloud accounting and financial management software including <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/freshbooks-adds-balance-sheet-generation-to-feature-list-7000005725/">Freshbooks</a> and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cloud-providers-connect-accounting-time-tracking-services-7000010808/">Xero</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=4968+9776296785720246484&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Gantter Project</a>: An application for handling scheduling of complex projects, which integrates with Google Drive for sharing and collaboration. It can import files from Microsoft Project.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=2533+17854168373705313802&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Zoho CRM</a>: As with the other CRM tools mentioned, this service is for tracking leads and customer prospects. But it can also be used for customer support management and marketing automation.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=3539+9922984539899306906&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Do by Salesforce</a>: A projects and tasks manager; you can share items with people on your Google Contacts list.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=18806+14512935155953175632&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">draw.io</a>: An app for producing graphical diagrams using predefined objects. (The pricing model changes on April 1, 2013, so it should be interesting to see if this software retains is popularity.)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/enterprise/marketplace/viewListing?productListingId=12050+5175253361058487653&amp;hp=topRecentInstalled">Accounting tools by Wave</a>: A small-business accounting system that includes invoicing and reporting features.&nbsp;</p>
<p>What other Google Apps ecosystem software do you find useful? Leave us some ideas in the comment thread.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013272</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/amazon-acquires-goodreads-aims-to-meld-kindle-with-social-7000013272/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Amazon acquires Goodreads, aims to meld Kindle with social]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Amazon's big win with the acquisition of Goodreads is that it can make the Kindle more social and juice Kindle sales. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 20:35:06 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-amazon/">Amazon</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon on Thursday said it will buy Goodreads, a social site that discusses and recommends books.</p>
<p>Terms of the deal weren't disclosed.</p>
<p><a href="http://phx.corporate-ir.net/phoenix.zhtml?c=176060&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=1801563&amp;highlight=">In a statement</a>, Amazon positioned Goodreads as an acquisition that it would pair up with its Kindle platform. Amazon added that it will "build many new ways to delight readers and authors alike."</p>
<p>Goodreads CEO Otis Chandler said the Amazon purchase will give it more resources and a larger footprint beyond its 16 million members. Indeed, Goodreads launched in 2007, but hasn't had any significant updates to its site and services of late.</p>
<figure><img title="goodreads" alt="goodreads" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013272/goodreads-v1-620x359.png?hash=MzIxZGH1AJ&upscale=1" height="359" width="620"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The melding of Goodreads' social approach with the Kindle could be enticing to avid readers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Over the past 90 days, Goodreads users have added more than four books per second to their want to read lists. Amazon will obviously try to translate those desires into e-book sales.</p>
<p>Goodreads will remain based in San Francisco.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013271</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/new-windows-8-hardware-specs-hint-at-7-inch-tablets-and-a-microsoft-reader-7000013271/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[New Windows 8 hardware specs hint at 7-inch tablets and a Microsoft Reader]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A quiet change in the logo requirements for new Windows 8 devices allows Microsoft's hardware partners to build new devices that would compete with popular 7- and 8-inch tablets like the iPad Mini, Kindle Fire HD, and Google Nexus 7. Could a Microsoft Reader be just around the corner?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 20:18:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ed Bott]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-amazon/">Amazon</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ipad/">iPad</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft-surface/">Microsoft Surface</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Are smaller Windows tablets in iPad dimensions&nbsp;just around the corner? Will Microsoft's long-rumored Reader make its debut along with the Windows Blue update this summer?</p>
<p>Those are distinct possibilities, based on a&nbsp;significant change Microsoft quietly made this month in its hardware certification guidelines for Windows 8 devices.</p>
<p>The new guidelines relax the minimum resolution for Windows 8 devices to 1024 x 768 at a depth of 32 bits. That&rsquo;s a significant change from the current guidelines, which require a minimum resolution of 1366 x 768 for a device to be certified with the Windows 8 logo.</p>
<p>From the announcement, it appears that the&nbsp;new guidelines are effective immediately, but it&rsquo;s likely that any new devices that use this form factor will ship along with the forthcoming Windows Blue update.</p>
<p>The announcement was disclosed in the <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/hardware/dn148227">March 12, 2013 Windows Certification Newsletter</a>, which is prepared by the Windows Certification (formerly Logo) Program and goes out to hardware vendors who want to sell systems that are certified by Microsoft as Windows 8-compatible.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>System.Client.Tablet.Graphics.MinimumResolution relaxed for Windows 8</strong></p>
<p>We're changing the System.Client.Tablet.Graphics.MinimumResolution requirement to create a consistent minimum resolution of 1024 x 768 at a depth of 32 bits across all Windows 8 system form factors. The physical dimensions of the display panel must still match the aspect ratio of the native resolution. This doesn't imply that we're encouraging partners to regularly use a lower screen resolution. In fact, we see customers embracing the higher resolution screens that make a great Windows experience. We understand that <strong><em>partners exploring designs for certain markets could find greater design flexibility helpful</em></strong>. <em>[emphasis added]</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>That last, somewhat cryptic&nbsp;line telegraphs a possible reason for the change. It&rsquo;s no secret that some of the most successful new tablets are inexpensive (sub-$299) devices with 7- and 8-inch displays. The new resolutions would allow manufacturers to introduce devices that&nbsp;are in line with&nbsp;the resolutions of the <a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/ipad-mini/">iPad Mini</a> (1024 x 768) and the <a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/kindle-fire-hd/">Kindle Fire HD</a> and <a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/google-nexus-7/">Google Nexus 7</a> (both 1280 x 800).</p>
<p>This is a major concession on one of the key original design requirements of Windows 8, whose 16:9 aspect ratio resolution makes it awkward to use in portrait resolution. The 16:10 or 4:3 resolutions of competing tablets are better suited for use in portrait mode -&nbsp;as an ebook reader, for example.</p>
<p>Relaxing the minimum specification comes with a significant drawback for users, however, as the Microsoft announcement makes clear:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The lower resolution would disable snap, a feature that allows two Windows Store apps to be viewed simultaneously side by side. To avoid potential consumer disappointment, OEMs need to disclose the loss of snap.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Before a device can qualify to use the Windows 8 logo with a resolution of less than 1366 x 768, the new guidelines require that the OEM must &ldquo;provide appropriate, clear, and conspicuous disclaimers&rdquo; to customers. &ldquo;This disclaimer must disclose that the system doesn't support snap,&rdquo; the announcement continues. It also helpfully includes some suggested text:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The integrated display resolution of this system is below the threshold for snap, a feature that lets people view two Windows Store apps at the same time. App snapping will work if you attach an external display that supports a screen resolution of 1366 x 768 or higher.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As Matt Rosoff pointed out on Twitter, Microsoft's transformation to a devices and services company has <a href="https://twitter.com/MattRosoff/status/317386484447592448" target="_blank">"been pretty light on the devices so far..."</a></p>
<p>The company hasn't been shy about its plans to expand beyond the PC-as-tablet form factor. In a talk at a Goldman Sachs technology conference in February, Microsoft CFO Peter Klein talked about "a set of experiences that are complete, that are compelling,&nbsp;and they are consistent across a whole range of form factors and devices ...&nbsp;whether that's 4-inch, 5-inch, 7-inch, 8-inch, 10-inch, 13-inch. And along with our partners in the ecosystem we'll work through that based on underlying demand."</p>
<p>It might be just a coincidence, but this week I also received a promotional mailing from Microsoft&rsquo;s Windows team, with the subject line &ldquo;Travel the world with Windows and NOOK.&rdquo; The latter is a pitch for Barnes &amp; Noble&rsquo;s NOOK for Windows app, not the critically acclaimed but commercially unsuccessful hardware device from the struggling bookseller.</p>
<p>We haven&rsquo;t heard much about it lately, but we&rsquo;re approaching the one-year anniversary of a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/is-there-a-windows-based-barnes-and-noble-reader-in-the-works/12586">patent settlement between Microsoft and Barnes &amp; Noble.</a>&nbsp;As my colleague Mary Jo Foley wrote last April, Microsoft has discussed creating its own e-reader:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One of my sources said that Microsoft and B&amp;N had been working on a partnership for a while via which <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsoft-and-barnes-noble-settle-patent-dispute-create-new-subsidiary/12575">Microsoft would build an e-reader and B&amp;N would build the back-end bookstore</a>. According to that source, the partnership fizzled, perhaps due in part to the Microsoft Courier tablet effort (which also fizzled).</p>
<p>But the idea that there could be some kind of dedicated, Windows-powered e-reader didn't die. In fact, Microsoft execs have continued to tout the idea that an e-reader is part of the gamut of devices that will be powered by Windows. Just a month ago, in fact, Microsoft Chief Operating Officer Kevin Turner, mentioned again during a keynote that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/a-windows-8-e-reader-if-someone-builds-it-will-they-come/12206">e-readers will be one of a handful of form factors where Microsoft's Metro interface/design style will play</a> in the future.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In a separate post, Mary Jo notes the formation of a joint Microsoft/B&amp;N company (Nook Media LLC, called &ldquo;NewCo&rdquo; in the SEC disclosure), with <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/heres-the-part-of-the-microsoft-and-barnes-and-noble-agreement-everyones-ignoring/12628">this tantalizing language</a> in the agreement:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Microsoft Reader. If Microsoft creates a reader, Microsoft may include an interface to the NewCo Store in that reader and may surface in that reader all Content purchased by customers from the NewCo Store."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The idea of an inexpensive&nbsp;7-inch Surface-branded Reader, running at a resolution of 1024 x 768 with full access to Barnes &amp; Noble&rsquo;s extensive library, is indeed intriguing. And of course it wouldn't be just for e-books. With the ability to run the Amazon Kindle app and access the massive Xbox music, video, and games platform it would be instantly useful as an entertainment device.</p>
<p>It would certainly silence the critics who&rsquo;ve said that the current Surface line is too expensive.</p>
<p>A Microsoft spokesperson declined to comment on this report.</p>
<p><em>Thanks to reader <a href="http://twitter.com/explanoit" target="_blank">@explanoit</a> for the tip.</em></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013270</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/mindtouch-taps-machine-learning-to-put-customer-service-on-the-offensive-7000013270/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[MindTouch taps machine learning to put customer service on the offensive]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Helping customers in need? Too reactionary, MindTouch says. Its new "smart" platform aims to change that. (Watch out, Oracle.)]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 20:14:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-salesforce-com/">Salesforce.com</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-sap/">SAP</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="mindtouch-customize-no-background1" alt="mindtouch-customize-no-background1" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013270/mindtouch-customize-no-background1-620x620.png?hash=LGZ5ZQZ3AT&upscale=1" height="620" width="620"></figure>
<p>This morning, the San Diego-based company&nbsp;<a href="http://www.mindtouch.com">MindTouch</a> introduced&nbsp;a new version of its web-based, software-as-a-service tool that touts a new framework and algorithm set that can help it "learn" and optimize what it presents to different kinds of users.</p>
<p>The idea is to make&nbsp;customer support proactive and not reactive by "stopping customer problems before they occur," MindTouch says. The company calls it, nebulously, a "product experience platform."</p>
<p>Here are some concrete facts about it: it's in the cloud; it's got a web-based, self-service help center component; it integrates with SAP, Salesforce and Zendesk; it alllows for collaborative authoring; and it uses HelpRank machine learning to get smarter.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Officially, it's called MindTouch 4.</p>
<p>The company's value proposition hasn't changed in the almost six years since its inception: we'll help you respond to customers in need better than anyone, so they don't run off to a competitor.&nbsp;Intuit, Paypal, Autodesk, Hewlett-Packard, Palm, HTC, RSA, SAP and EMC are customers.</p>
<p>Key to that goal is the company's new, so-called LightSpeed content framework, which it says is easier to use than existing authoring tools thanks to&nbsp;automatic redirect management, version control, content reuse and a WYSIWYG editor.</p>
<p>And then there's the brain itself:&nbsp;HelpRank, a series of algorithms that continuously converts customer and agent behavior into increasingly optimized search results by incorporating factors such as&nbsp;back-links, metadata, shares, ratings, user roles and "a multitude of other metrics."</p>
<p>Both features are new to the platform.</p>
<p>"With contextual and personalized product knowledge plugged into all customer channels," &nbsp;founder and CEO&nbsp;Aaron Fulkerson said,&nbsp;"you make advocates out of your customers well in advance of them needing reactive help to a specific problem."</p>
<p>With an estimated $83 billion lost each year by U.S. enterprises due to poor customer experiences, there's a lot of money on the line. Is machine learning the answer? It certainly can't hurt.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013262</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/google-applied-materials-execs-debate-how-taking-risks-fosters-collaboration-7000013262/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Google, Applied Materials execs debate how taking risks fosters collaboration]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[How does a company properly foster "a culture of risk taking" -- especially amid a very uneasy global economic climate?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Mar 2013 19:06:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="network-globe" alt="network-globe" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/us-carousel/network-globe-620x202.jpg?hash=BGH1MGtlZG&upscale=1" height="202" width="620"></figure>
<p><strong>BERKELEY, CALIF. --</strong> Everyone in business and technology love to toss around the word "innovation" haphazardly, but at its core, perhaps it would be better to define it as plain old risk taking.</p>
<p><strong>See also on <em>SmartPlanet</em></strong>: <a href="http://www.smartplanet.com/blog/smart-takes/panel-8216reverse-innovation-serving-creating-new-markets/24803">Panel: ‘Reverse innovation’ serving, creating new markets</a></p>
<p>Speaking during a panel discussion at <em>The Economist</em>'s <a href="http://www.economist.com/events-conferences/americas/innovation-2013">2013 Innovation Forum</a> on Thursday, executives from technology and healthcare industries discussed how any kind of sustainable model for innovation requires "a culture of risk taking."</p>
<p>But how does a company&nbsp;properly foster that -- especially amid a very uneasy global economic climate?</p>
<p>Laszlo Bock, senior vice president of people operations at Google, suggested it starts with the recruitment process, which is complex (to say the least) for the Mountain View, Calif.-headquartered company, which has millions of applicants each year.</p>
<p>But Bock stressed that the Internet giant looks to hire for capability before expertise. That in itself could be viewed as a major risk considering you could be hiring someone who doesn't have enough experience to make founded business decisions.</p>
<p>Bock explained that Google would rather hire "smart, curious people" over experts because someone in the former category is "90 percent" more likely to come up with a "pretty good answer" to a potential problem or question.</p>
<p>Bock admitted that "you need a mix," but he stipulated that Google still skews heavily towards this interest in curious people.</p>
<p>Mary Humiston, senior vice president of global human resources at Applied Materials, described a new program at the semiconductor company dubbed "Innovation Academy." The project includes a program that brings together technologists from various verticals within the company, such as solar or displays, to discuss and try to answer some of the highest-value customer problems.</p>
<p>While Humiston hinted that the program is still in its infancy, even just after a year, she highlighted that the sessions have led to approximately $3 billion in revenue opportunities for Applied Materials.</p>
<p>Martin Giles, U.S. technology correspondent at <em>The Economist</em> and the panel's moderator, asked pointedly what about motivating employees with cash.</p>
<p>Bock immediately shut the concept down, citing studies that such incentives don't really foster innovation.</p>
<p>Humiston pointed towards leveraging crowd-sourcing models for internal competition with a potential reward being corporate funding for winning ideas.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
