<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:s="http://www.zdnet.com/search" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
    <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
    <description>Latest Blog for ZDNet</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>ZDNet</copyright>
    <managingEditor>customerservice@zdnet.com (ZDNet Customer Services)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>uk-engineering@cbsinteractive.com (ZDNet Webmaster)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:27:12 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 00:27:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>2</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://i.zdnet.com/images/spry/zdnet_300x300.jpg</url>
      <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
      <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
      <width>143</width>
      <height>39</height>
    </image>
    <s:counts>
      <start>0</start>
      <return>20</return>
      <found>41834</found>
    </s:counts>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013557</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/phone-home-not-facebook-home-is-another-intolerable-waste-of-time-7000013557/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Phone. Home? Not. Facebook Home is another intolerable waste of time.]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[As a Facebook hater, you might find it unsurprising that I also hate 'Home' but it goes deeper than a hate for Facebook alone. It goes all the way back to AOL of the mid-90s.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 22:13:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ken Hess]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-iphone/">iPhone</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't listen to Zuckerberg's big announcement today because if it's Facebook-related, I just don't care to hear it. Unless, of course, it's the utter dismantling of Facebook, that is. Now, that, I'd listen to. Heck, I might even make some old school popcorn* and cozy up with a brewsky for that announcement. But alas, it's not to be. Not yet at least. Instead it was an announcement about yet another useless thingamabob from Facebook that millions will flock to--to annoy, to irritate (comment), to update, to post and to Like till their little hearts are content. Things like "Home" remind me of the original AOL. Easy. Cheesy. Annoying.</p>
<p>In the same way that I hated AOL, I also hated Prodigy and to an extent, CompuServe. They were easy Internet onramps for Ma and Pa Kettle** and I just didn't think that the common man (or woman) deserved to be online with their idle chatter and pointless commentary. The Internet, including BBSs***, were for technical professionals who needed to exchange information, to explore ideas, to seek out new life, new civilizations...OK, got carried away there but I think you get the point.</p>
<p>The Internet was an intellectual tool.&nbsp;</p>
<p>These days it's simply a garbage heap where any jackass with a piece of virtual chalk can scrawl his graffiti onto someone else's work.**** It's the new equivalent of the old drawing horns and mustaches on posters and pictures. Not everything you do needs to be Facebooked, liked, tweeted or checked-in. Have a life that doesn't include all this social media nonsense.</p>
<p>Facebook Home is just another unecessary distraction from what you should be doing: working, conversing, exchanging ideas, exploring something new or growing a legal garden. Seriously, do <em>something </em>rather than nothing. Updating your status is just silly. Stop it. No one cares. Well, maybe other people doing the same thing might care and then they'll comment.</p>
<p>Rachel King, who saw a preview of this "new" thing today, summed it up best in her post, "<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/first-impressions-hands-on-with-facebook-home-for-android-7000013547/" target="_blank">First impressions: Hands-on with Facebook Home for Android</a>," when she wrote, <em>"There isn't much of a business use case here, except that it might influence other social networks (i.e. Yammer, Salesforce Chatter, etc.) do start thinking (or speed up) their own Home-like integrations."</em></p>
<p>She's trying to say, without saying it, that Facebook Home is a totally pointless effort. I hope Zuck didn't spend a lot of money or time on this thing. It just goes to show that not every swing produces a "Home" run. Yes, I just thought that up.</p>
<p>Rachel goes on to say, "<em>And while it looks nifty, it's not enticing enough (at least not yet) to buy a smartphone solely because Home is pre-loaded.</em></p>
<p><em>I'm also skeptical how much Home is going to do for its major OEM partner, HTC. The $99.99 contract price on the HTC First is a better sales pitch considering the device looked like a steal for that price tag."</em></p>
<p>I'm skeptical if there's a point to this app at all. I think Facebook is beginning to sink and just needed something to stay in the news and to stay relevant. I guess it worked, sort of. Facebook is getting a lot of virtual ink out of the deal but, in the long run, Home is just silly.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It's hard to believe that a pointless and valueless thing like Facebook can be a) worth so much money, b) anything but something to laugh at, and c) something that people spend a lot of time on.</p>
<p>It's obvious that we, as people, no longer have to hunt or gather to find food. If we did, we might find it more difficult to spend time on something like Facebook.</p>
<p>It makes me wonder if we've really evolved at all. Perhaps scientists have it all wrong. Maybe we're evolving into plants. Plants with nothing to do but text and update our Facebook statuses about what we had for breakfast or where we're having breakfast.</p>
<p>Status update: Hey, I just made some oxygen. Just made some more. Oh, I just consumed some carbon dioxide. I'm a photosynthesizing fool today. So glad the sun is out. Think I'll go for a...OK, I guess I'll stay right here and keep updating my status.</p>
<p>Facebook and Facebook Home almost make me long for the good AOL days.</p>
<p>What do you think? Are you a Facebooky? Are you going to try Home? Talk back and let me know.</p>
<p>*You know, popcorn, made in a lid-covered pot, with butter over the stove. If you don't remember, Google it and watch a YouTube video on it, then try it for yourself.</p>
<p>**Google it.</p>
<p>***Ditto.</p>
<p>****See any of my Talkbacks or for some real entertainment, check out the commentary on Jason Perlow's posts.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013558</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/google-lowers-prices-further-opens-doors-to-compute-engine-7000013558/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Google lowers prices, further opens doors to Compute Engine]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[With a little more than a month to go ahead of Google I/O, the Internet giant is sprucing up Compute Engine.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 21:22:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-google/">Google</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software-development/">Software Development</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-enterprise-2-0/">Enterprise 2.0</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-web-development/">Web development</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="zdnet-google-cloud_console" alt="zdnet-google-cloud_console" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013558/zdnet-google-cloudconsole-620x481.png?hash=Z2H3AQWwBQ&upscale=1" height="481" width="620"></figure>
<p><strong>Google</strong> introduced somewhat of an overhaul for its <a href="https://developers.google.com/compute/"><strong>Compute Engine</strong></a> virtual machine on Thursday, making the cloud service more readily available to more users.</p>
<p>Marc Cohen, a software manager on the Google Cloud Platform team, <a href="http://googledevelopers.blogspot.com/2013/04/google-compute-engine-expanded.html">outlined in a blog post</a> that today's update essentially boils down to three things: lower costs, more functionality and access for more customers.</p>
<p>Cohen also cited a recent review by Scalr founder Sebastian Stadil <a href="http://gigaom.com/2013/03/15/by-the-numbers-how-google-compute-engine-stacks-up-to-amazon-ec2/">published on <em>GigaOm</em></a>, highlighting the speed of the cloud infrastructure against competitors.</p>
<p>Starting today, the Infrastructure-as-a-Service is being made available to all customers who sign up for Google's Gold Support package, the second highest of the company's <a href="https://cloud.google.com/support/packages">four tiers of cloud customer support</a>.</p>
<p>Additionally, Google is cutting all Compute Engine pricing by four percent.</p>
<p>There are a host of new features detailed on the Google Developers blog. Some of the big ones include an revamped admin dashboard (as seen in the screenshot above), two more supported zones across Europe, and five new instance type families along with 16 new types of instances.</p>
<p>The Internet giant first introduced Compute Engine <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/google-intros-compute-engine-infrastructure-service/81269">last June at Google I/O</a>. It's highly likely that we'll continue to see some more big updates for the cloud infrastructure service over the next few weeks and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-io-registration-opens-to-developers-in-march-7000011704/">at the annual expo this May</a>.</p>
<p><em>Screenshot via <a href="http://googledevelopers.blogspot.com/2013/04/google-compute-engine-expanded.html">The Google Developers Blog</a></em></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013556</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/f5-compuware-note-q2-slowdowns-7000013556/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[F5, Compuware note Q2 slowdowns]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[F5 Networks and Compuware will fall short of expectations. Was the first calendar quarter a blip in IT spending or something worse?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 20:15:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-software/">Software</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The profit warnings for enterprise technology companies are starting to pile up.</p>
<p>On Thursday, F5 Networks said its results<a href="http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20130404006401/en/F5-Networks-Announces-Preliminary-Results-Quarter-Fiscal"> will fall short of expectations</a> and guidance. Specifically, F5 projected second quarter revenue of $350.2 million, which was below guidance of $370 million to $380 million. Non-GAAP earnings will be $1.06 a share to $1.07 a share with GAAP earnings of 79 cents to 80 cents a share.</p>
<p>Wall Street was looking for second quarter non-GAAP earnings of $1.23 a share on revenue of $375.8 million.</p>
<p>In a statement, F5 CEO John McAdam said that a slowdown in North America hurt sales. Europe Middle East and Africa sales also slowed a bit. Japan and Asia Pacific sales looked ok.</p>
<p>Some enterprise tech companies have noted that the federal government's budget showdowns hurt spending. On cue, F5 said that telecom and government bookings were down.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Compuware said that its results would miss expectations. The company said that its fiscal fourth quarter non-GAAP earnings would be between 5 cents and 6 cents a share on revenue of $237 million and $241 million.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20130403006346/en/Compuware-Announces-Preliminary-Q4-Financial-Results">In a statement</a>, Compuware CEO Bob Paul said that deals slipped into the next quarter because "many clients and prospects were unable to formalize their IT budgets during the period."</p>
<p>These quarterly hiccups come as enterprise software companies have been missing estimates. For instance, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/tibcos-q2-outlook-bombs-more-execution-issues-or-excuses-7000012975/">Tibco</a> <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/oracles-q3-miss-canary-in-enterprise-software-licensing-coal-mine-7000012951/">and Oracle</a> both delivered weak quarters. Both companies blamed sales execution and expect a rebound.</p>
<p>With earnings season on deck, it'll be interesting to watch the outlooks and color on the most recent quarter. Looks like there was definitely a drop off.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013555</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/hp-shakes-up-board-again-lane-steps-down-as-chairman-7000013555/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[HP shakes up board again, Lane steps down as chairman]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[HP turns over its board as investors are still seething over the Autonomy acquisition debacle. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:43:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-centers/">Data Centers</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hewlett-Packard Chairman Ray Lane is giving up his post as the company initiates yet another board shake-up. Lane's tenure featured a few massive debacles.</p>
<p>Ralph Whitworth, a shareholder activist, will be a stand-in until a replacement is named. Lane will stay on HP's board, but John Hammergren and G. Kennedy Thompson will step down.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="raymond" alt="raymond" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013555/raymond-135x103.jpg?hash=Lwp2AwV3Zw&upscale=1" height="103" width="135"></figure>
<p>The moves, initially reported by <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887323646604578402791487880644.html">The Wall Street Journal</a>, CNBC and others, represent another shakeup for HP's historically dysfunctional board. But CEO Meg Whitman and the company had to do something following a series of missteps.</p>
<ul>
<li>First, there was the HP acquisition of Autonomy. HP bought Autonomy in 2011 for a whopping $11 billion and drained its balance sheet.</li>
<li>Then HP wrote down $8.8 billion in goodwill for the deal.</li>
<li>And finally, HP claimed it bought Autonomy <a >based on shady accounting</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Where was the due diligence on Autonomy? While the answers are still fuzzy, the solution is clear. The board had to have some turnover. It's also worth noting that Hammergren and Thompson barely kept their board seats.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.marketwire.com/press-release/hp-announces-changes-to-board-of-directors-nyse-hpq-1775500.htm">In a statement</a> Lane (right) said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After reflecting on the stockholder vote last month, I've decided to step down as executive chairman to reduce any distraction from HP's ongoing turnaround. Since I joined HP's board a little over two years ago, I've been committed to board evolution to ensure our turnaround and future success. I'm proud of the board we've built and the progress we've made to date in restoring the company. I will continue to serve HP as a director and help finish the job.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lane managed<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/hps-lane-on-why-apotheker-had-to-go/58827"> to distance himself from former CEO Leo Apotheker</a>, who was also on the Autonomy bandwagon. Lane joined HP at the same time Apotheker was hired. The duo, which was far from dynamic, was supposed <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/surprise-hp-names-leo-apotheker-ceo-can-he-rewrite-his-legacy/39872">to push HP into the software business with gusto</a>.</p>
<p>In another board move, HP said that the role of lead independent director, held by Rajiv L. Gupta, will be eliminated. Gupta will remain on the board and will replace Thompson as chairman of the audit committee. Gary Reiner will replace Gupta as chairman of the nominating and governance committee. Whitworth will become chairman of the finance and investment committee.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013554</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/intuit-brings-mint-to-your-bank-7000013554/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Intuit brings Mint to your bank]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Intuit is making Mint, its popular online personal finance service, available to your bank or credit union. Just how much longer will Quicken stick around as a standalone PC application?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:33:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smbs/">SMBs</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.intuit.com">Intuit</a>, makers of <a href="http://quicken.intuit.com">Quicken</a> and <a href="http://quickbooks.intuit.com/">QuickBooks</a>, is making <a href="https://www.mint.com">Mint</a>, its popular online personal finance service, available to financial institutions. As Ron Shevlin, senior analyst at <a href="http://www.aitegroup.com">Aite Group</a>, told American Banker "<a href="http://www.americanbanker.com/issues/178_64/intuit-finally-lets-banks-white-label-mint-1058006-1.html">I'm surprised it took so long.</a>"</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Mintcom" alt="Mintcom" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013554/mintcom-200x59.png?hash=MJD2BGD5LG&upscale=1" height="59" width="200"><figcaption>Intuit is positioning Mint.com as your primary connection between you and your bank. </figcaption></figure>
<p>Indeed, you could see this move coming at least three years ago when Aaron Patzer, Mint's founder and then Intuit VP and GM of Personal Finance said, "<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/five-questions-for-aaron-patzer-vp-and-gm-intuit-founder-mint-com/29318">Quicken Online will be going away, and we'll be migrating to Mint.</a>" At the time, he also suggested that Intuit "will have desktop products for at least another five years simply due to comfort level more than anything else." We're two years away from that deadline. Could this be the first step to putting an end to desktop Quicken?</p>
<p>That would be premature.</p>
<p>But, for now Greg Wright, vice president of product management at&nbsp; Intuit Financial Services, said in a statement that "<a href="http://about.intuit.com/about_intuit/press_room/press_release/articles/2013/MinttoHelpFinancialInstitutionsFreshenuptheDigitalBranch.html">More than 12 million people already use Mint.com to manage their complete financial picture</a> and have identified savings of more than $30 billion toward their personal goals. By blending Mint with their digital banking home page, financial institutions can provide immediate, meaningful financial insights to their customers, help more people save money and further deepen banking relationships by recommending relevant financial products at the time when people are most interested."</p>
<p>Intuit argues that the new Mint offering will help financial institutions position themselves as trusted advisors, improving their customers' financial lives. Specifically its features, which its non-bank branded version already includes, are:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Showing customers their entire financial picture in one place: Automatically organizes spending from more than 19,000 financial accounts into categories and shows where money is going with easy-to-understand charts.</li>
<li>Offering free actionable advice on how to save money:&nbsp;Delivers personalized alerts and insights based on individual transactional behavior, financial habits and goals.</li>
<li>Providing on-the-go tracking with mobile apps:&nbsp;Provides an award-winning mobile experience that gives customers the big picture view and dollar-and-cent details of their money on their iOS and Android mobile phones and tablets.</li>
<li>Suggesting helpful products and services: Alerts customers to relevant products and services from their financial institution that are specific to their situation, at a time when they are most interested in learning more.</li>
</ul>
<p>Intuit's move is also meant to help banks with their marketing. Wright continued, "Mint is more than just online pie charts. It's an easy way for banks to provide valuable advice and services based on a customer's specific needs and use of financial products, all in the place millions of people look for help."</p>
<p>To me, if you add in Intuit's other recent online service moves, such as <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuit-optimizes-quickbooks-online-for-apple-ipad-7000011268/">QuickBooks Online for iPad</a>; the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuits-latest-service-hooks-up-small-businesses-with-accountants-7000011141">hook-up between TurboTax and local accountants</a>; and its <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuits-secret-to-going-global-lies-in-thinking-local-7000004522">promotion of QuickBooks Online</a>. it's clear that Intuit, one of the last major pure desktop software program players, is getting ready to move its product line once and for all to the cloud. Mint, with its easy-to-use Web interface, free price-tag, and compatibility with all platforms, may well be Intuit's future and Quicken's successor</p>
<p>Why not? After all, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuits-fiscal-q2-earnings-look-good-heading-into-tax-season-7000011580/">three out of four Intuit customers are already using Intuit's online services</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Related Stories:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuit-optimizes-quickbooks-online-for-apple-ipad-7000011268/">Intuit optimizes QuickBooks Online for Apple iPad</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuit-aims-to-give-small-business-spin-to-big-data-7000008771/">Intuit aims to give small business spin to big data</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuits-latest-service-hooks-up-small-businesses-with-accountants-7000011141/">Intuit's latest service hooks up small businesses with accountants</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intuit-opens-up-apis-to-its-financial-data-service-in-us-canada-7000004004/">Intuit opens up APIs to its financial data service in US, Canada</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/projectfailures/intuit-pain-and-pleasure-in-the-cloud/14880">Intuit: Pain and pleasure in the cloud</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013552</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/a-classic-microsoft-pose-32-years-later-7000013552/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[A classic Microsoft pose, 32 years later]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Bill Gates and Paul Allen reconstruct a photo from Microsoft's early days in 1981.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 18:37:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="Bill-Gates-Paul-Allen-1981-med" alt="Bill-Gates-Paul-Allen-1981-med" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013552/bill-gates-paul-allen-1981-med-620x429.jpg?hash=MQL2AGZkLG&upscale=1" height="429" width="620"></figure>
<p>Ever see the above photo? It's a classic, of Microsoft co-founders Paul Allen and Bill Gates in 1981, surrounded by then-cutting-edge computers.</p>
<p>This week, the pair came together at the <a href="http://www.livingcomputermuseum.org/">Living Computer Museum</a> in Seattle to recreate the photo with the same computers.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/PaulGAllen/statuses/319627797209444352">In a tweet</a>&nbsp;-- <em>"So much fun catching up w/ computing pioneers at the #LCMCelebration last night! Here I am with old friend @BillGates"</em> --&nbsp;Allen revealed the photo yesterday:</p>
<figure><img title="Bill-Gates-Paul-Allen-2013-med" alt="Bill-Gates-Paul-Allen-2013-med" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013552/bill-gates-paul-allen-2013-med-375x339.jpg?hash=LGqvZzZ4ZJ&upscale=1" height="339" width="375"></figure>
<p><a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2013/bill-gates-paul-allen-reprise-classic-microsoft-photo-decades/">Todd Bishop at <em>GeekWire</em> points out</a> that the photo was taken during&nbsp;"a small gathering of friends, many of them computing and technology pioneers," and that museum staff tracked down the vintage computer models in advance so that the pair could easily recreate the image.</p>
<p>Neat.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013551</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/the-love-affair-with-windows-8-powered-hybrids-is-over-before-it-started-7000013551/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[The love affair with Windows 8-powered hybrids is over before it started]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Microsoft built Windows 8 around the new touch user interface, but it seems that consumers are quite attached to their keyboards and mice.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 18:24:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Adrian Kingsley-Hughes]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="" alt="" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013551/2013-04-0420-19-11-200x225.jpg?hash=BQL0ZJZ3Lm&upscale=1" height="225" width="200"></figure>
<p>Windows 8 is built around the premise that people want to interact with their PC through touch, but deep discounts of Windows 8-powered hybrids at the Microsoft Store suggest that the love affair with these devices is already at an end.</p>
<p>The discounts are highlighted on ZDNet's sister site <em><a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-10805_3-57577634-75/microsoft-store-slashes-prices-on-windows-8-tablets-hybrids/">CNET</a></em>, and they're very deep discounts indeed, with the price of the Toshiba Satellite U925T-S2130 Convertible Ultrabook slashed by almost 35 percent. No matter how you look at it, cuts like that are huge, and are bound to raise a few eyebrows.</p>
<p>This isn't the only sign that things aren't going well with the Windows 8 sales machine. Last month, IDC analyst Bob O'Donnell told CNET that Windows 8 PC sales had "<a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-10805_3-57573370-75/four-months-in-windows-8-needs-help/">horribly stalled</a>," and IDC expected computer shipments to fall by <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-10805_3-57572451-75/sorry-pc-makers-shipments-will-likely-fall-this-year-idc-says/">1.3 percent this year</a> after it had initially predicted a 2.8 percent rise.</p>
<p>And this decline comes on top of an even precipitous 3.7 percent fall that the industry experienced in 2012.</p>
<p>And I'm hearing unofficial conformation of this from sources within OEMs too. The hope that Windows 8 would reinvigorate PCs sales has evaporated, and makers are now resigned to the fact that desktops and notebooks are going to be sitting around gathering dust as consumers choose instead to spend their money on smartphones and tablets.</p>
<p>I've said it before but I'll say it again – touch on traditional desktops and notebooks is a solution looking for a problem to fix. Microsoft had touch support built into Windows for years and consumers didn't care about it then, and it seems that outside of devices such as Microsoft's own Surface, people don't are about it now either.</p>
<p>As far as new classes of devices are concerned – devices such as hybrids and convertibles – the problem with these is that they're embryonic. While people were fast to embrace devices such as the iPhone and iPad, consumers haven't been so enthusiastic when it comes to tweaked versions of PCs. To most people a PC is either a desktop a notebook, and it seems that devices that blur the lines between desktops, notebooks, and tablets are making people nervous..</p>
<p>Microsoft bet the farm on touch with Windows 8, and so far it seems that the bet hasn't paid off. While I think that Microsoft certainly needed a response to iOS and Android, shoehorning an entire touch-based user interface into an operating system primarily designed to be driven by a keyboard and mouse made little sense to me at the time it was unveiled, and it seems that it makes little sense to buyers either. Windows RT makes sense — if Microsoft can convince people to buy the hardware — as does a touch mode for the full version, but forcing the interface on everyone was a step too far. No one in their right minds wants to trade a new user interface in exchange for a massive workflow hit.</p>
<p>Just to be clear here though, PC sales were stagnating even before Windows 8 came on the scene, so the operating system is not entirely to blame for the state of the market now, but the operating system did nothing to help revive the industry.</p>
<p>The PC is dying, and it doesn't look like Windows 8 is going to save it.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013547</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/first-impressions-hands-on-with-facebook-home-for-android-7000013547/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[First impressions: Hands-on with Facebook Home for Android]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The screenshots of Facebook Home look nifty, but how useful (or necessary) is it actually in practice? ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 18:15:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="zdnet-cnet-facebook-home-1" alt="zdnet-cnet-facebook-home-1" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013547/zdnet-cnet-facebook-home-1-600x399.jpg?hash=Zwp2MJWxZz&upscale=1" height="399" width="600"></figure>
<p><strong>MENLO PARK, CALIF. --</strong> <strong>Facebook Home</strong> made a grand debut on Thursday before it heads to the first batch of <strong>Android</strong> smartphones next week.</p>
<p>Users can opt to download the home screen interface on their own, but how useful (or even necessary) is Home going to be anyway?</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-unveils-its-new-home-on-android-7000013486/">Facebook unveils its new 'Home' on Android</a> | <a href="http://live.cnet.com/Event/Facebooks_new_home_on_Android">CNET live blog: Facebook's new home on Android</a></p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117448" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013546/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-220x165.png?hash=AwR3MQWvMQ&upscale=1" alt="Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>I managed to get a quick hands-on look at Home at the social network's Menlo Park headquarters today, and here are my first impressions:</p>
<ul>
<li>The platform is very quick and responsive to touch gestures. Home is also fairly intuitive to navigate.</li>
<li>While the large floating pictures look lovely (and are reminiscent of live wallpaper), the overall UI design could use some polish. That goes double for the extra Home screen app menu, which looks like an older version of Android such as Gingerbread or even Froyo.</li>
<li>Facebook has made it possible to update, comment and like from basically anywhere on the device. You can't get past one screen without the option to do at least one (if not all three) of these actions. In terms of engagement, Facebook might have nailed that one.</li>
<li>There isn't much of a business use case here, except that it might influence other social networks (i.e. Yammer, Salesforce Chatter, etc.) do start thinking (or speed up) their own Home-like integrations.</li>
<li>There could be a major security/privacy flaw being that news feed updates from contacts scroll by even before the unlock screen. Thus, if a device were lost or stolen, the person who ends up with the smartphone has the potential to know more about you and your contacts as long as the Cover Feed keeps going.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-builds-a-new-home-on-android-7000013553/">Gallery: Facebook builds a new 'Home' on Android</a></strong></p>
<p>If I had one of the five devices that will initially support the Home download, I'd be more than game to try it out. I don't know how long I'd keep it, but for anyone who likes using social networking to its full potential, it would be fun to play with longer.</p>
<p>However, I don't see it coming to the Galaxy Nexus (which is the device I use) anytime soon -- if ever.</p>
<p>And while it looks nifty, it's not enticing enough (at least not yet) to buy a smartphone solely because Home is pre-loaded.</p>
<p>I'm also skeptical how much Home is going to do for its major OEM partner, HTC. The $99.99 contract price on the HTC First is a better sales pitch considering the device looked like a steal for that price tag.</p>
<p>Yet given that Facebook promised that it will roll out updates for Home every month, perhaps I could be singing a different tune this time next year.</p>
<p><em>Image Credits: <a href="http://live.cnet.com/Event/Facebooks_new_home_on_Android">James Martin, CNET</a></em></p>
<p><strong>Read more on <em>ZDNet</em> about Facebook Home</strong><em>:<br></em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/update-facebook-phone-been-there-done-that-and-nobody-cared/5665">Facebook phone? Been there, done that, and nobody cared</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebooks-android-play-could-be-boon-for-htc-7000013288/">Facebook's Android play could be boon for HTC</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/forget-the-facebook-phone-facebooks-mobile-ambitions-are-way-bigger-than-that-7000013398/?s_cid=e539">Forget the 'Facebook phone', Facebook's mobile ambitions are way bigger than that</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/with-home-facebook-backs-into-a-broader-ecosystem-7000013545/">With Home, Facebook backs into a broader ecosystem</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head</a></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013543</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/new-signs-point-to-microsoft-releasing-outlook-for-windows-rt-this-year-7000013543/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[New signs point to Microsoft releasing Outlook for Windows RT this year]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[It's increasing looking like those with ARM-based Windows devices might get the option to put Microsoft's Outlook RT on them, after all.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 18:14:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Jo Foley]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-arm/">ARM</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft-surface/">Microsoft Surface</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in January 2013, there was talk that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-said-to-be-testing-an-outlook-client-for-windows-rt-7000010351/">Microsoft was considering releasing a version of its Outlook mail client for Windows RT</a>. It looks like talk is advancing into likelihood.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="surfaceRT" alt="surfaceRT" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013543/surfacert-200x117.png?hash=AwVlZTWzAw&upscale=1" height="117" width="200"></figure>
<p>According to Windows SuperSite's Paul Thurrott, <a href="http://winsupersite.com/windows-rt/what-s-happening-outlook-rt">Outlook RT is being tested outside of Microsoft now</a>, not just internally as it was a couple of months ago.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thurrott also said he heard that Microsoft delayed releasing Outlook RT due to a firmware issue in ARM that was triggering crashes. I had heard scuttlebutt that excessive battery usage might be at fault, but nothing confirmable.</p>
<p>One of my sources said that Outlook RT has turned into a "top enterprise request," so the Office team had decided it should move forward and commercialize the port of Outlook to ARM. (I'm not so sure how many enterprises are really using Windows RT devices at this point, but I've heard Microsoft plans to increase its business-focused marketing push for Surface RTs and other Windows RT devices.)</p>
<p>This same source said all of the Office apps -- not just the core Word, Excel, PowerPoint and OneNote -- have been ported to ARM already. Once the initial work was done to shift to the ARM compiler, the task of porting the apps to ARM was less arduous, given the fact that huge chunks of each app is shared code.&nbsp;This shared code was developed by the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-office-gemini-windows-blues-twin-7000013195/">Modern Office Experience (MOX) team</a> and is known as &nbsp;MSO (Modern Shared Office?), my source said. &nbsp;MSO supposedly implements huge amounts of shared code for the office apps -- all the file access code, registry access, graphics, interfaces, etc.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"In short, these (Office) apps have been runable on ARM for a long time," my source claimed.</p>
<p>If it is released commercially, Outlook RT would run on Microsoft's ARM-based Surface RT devices, as well as any/all other ARM-based Windows RT tablets and PCs. It would likely be positioned as a complement, not a replacement to, the built-in Windows Mail client on Windows 8 and Windows RT PCs. Currently, Microsoft doesn't include Outlook as part of the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-to-deliver-final-version-of-office-2013-rt-starting-in-early-november-7000004281/">Office Home &amp; Student 2013 RT suite</a> that it bundles with the Windows RT operating system. Only Word RT, Excel RT, PowerPoint RT and OneNote RT are included.</p>
<p>It's worth noting these four apps are Desktop apps, not "Metro-Style"/Windows Store apps, but Microsoft is working on <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-office-gemini-windows-blues-twin-7000013195/">Metro-Style complements to all four</a>, which it is expected to roll out this fall as part of its Gemini effort.</p>
<p>The Office team is not commenting on Gemini or Outlook RT.</p>
<p>I recently heard from one of my own sources that Outlook RT might be released this fall, possibly in conjunction with the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-windows-blue-looks-to-be-named-windows-8-1-7000013391/">Windows 8.1 (Blue)</a> and/or <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsofts-office-gemini-windows-blues-twin-7000013195/">the Office "Gemini"</a> updates. However, if Microsoft opted to deliver Outlook RT earlier -- maybe as part of an update to the Office 365 consumer and business subscription offerings -- it could even come to market sooner.</p>
<p>As Thurrott noted, the most likely way Outlook RT would probably be rolled out is as <a href="http://winsupersite.com/windows-rt/what-s-happening-outlook-rt">a paid subscription offering</a>. And once this happens -- again, if/when it does -- the road for Microsoft to roll out <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-office-for-ios-android-to-have-office-365-subscription-tie-in-report-7000007044/">some kind of an Office for iPad via a similar subscription model</a> should be cleared (at least to some degree). Microsoft would still have to come to some kind of agreement with Apple over exactly how this would be sold if any code is to be made available via Apple's App Store.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Previous leaks about Office for iPad have pointed to <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-office-for-ios-android-to-have-office-365-subscription-tie-in-report-7000007044/">Microsoft releasing only Word, Excel, PowerPoint and OneNote apps for iOS</a>; Outlook hasn't been mentioned (to date.) If Outlook is to be delivered for iPad someday, one would assume Microsoft wouldn't want to deliver it on the iPad before it delivers it on RT. That would be counter to Microsoft's usual position of "first and best on Windows." But it's a new Microsoft these days, so never say never....</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013548</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/is-facebook-on-the-htc-first-and-htc-one-the-savior-of-htc-7000013548/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Is Facebook on the HTC First and HTC One the savior of HTC?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The HTC First Facebook phone is available for pre-order now and the HTC One with BlinkFeed functionality that can be set just to Facebook updates is coming soon. Will a focus on Facebook be attractive to consumers and help HTC stem their financial slide?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 17:28:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Matthew Miller]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-htc/">HTC</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Will the HTC First and HTC One with BlinkFeed help save HTC?" alt="Will the HTC First and HTC One with BlinkFeed help save HTC?" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013548/htcfirst-200x346.png?hash=ZGuuAwZ0BG&upscale=1" height="346" width="200"></figure>
<p>You can setup <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/walk-through-of-htc-blinkfeed-on-the-htc-one-video-7000012363/">BlinkFeed on the HTC One</a> to just show Facebook updates and quickly post your own status updates and now we see HTC taking Facebook integration a step further with the upcoming HTC First from AT&amp;T. You can pre-order the <a href="https://www.wireless.att.com/businesscenter/devices/htc-first.jsp#fbid=2haF-oCnbo2">HTC First</a> today for $99.99 with availability slated for 12 April.</p>
<p>Specifications of the HTC First include:</p>
<ul>
<li>4.3 inch HD 720p display</li>
<li>1.4 GHz dual-core Qualcomm MSM8930AA chipset</li>
<li>Android 4.1 with Facebook Home</li>
<li>1GB RAM</li>
<li>Up to 16GB storage</li>
<li>5 megapixel rear camera and 1.6 megapixel front facing camera</li>
<li>WiFi, Bluetooth, NFC, GPS</li>
<li>FM radio</li>
<li>2000 mAh non-removable battery</li>
<li>Dimensions: 4.96 x 2.56 x 0.35 inches and 4.37 ounces</li>
</ul>
<p>My wife enjoyed the Facebook BlinkFeed experience and since she uses Facebook quite a bit on her phone she may like installing the Facebook Home application onto a device like the HTC One when it is released in the Google Play Store. However, like <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/update-facebook-phone-been-there-done-that-and-nobody-cared/5665">James</a>, I am not yet sold on the idea of a phone having such deep Facebook integration and focus. It's been tried before by HTC and didn't do well at all.</p>
<p>HTC needs something to generate excitement for their fantastic hardware and Facebook may help. Facebook is one of the most popular applications used on mobile phones and HTC made a good move being a part of the Facebook Home launch event.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-builds-a-new-home-on-android-7000013553/">Gallery: Facebook builds a new 'Home' on Android</a></strong></p>
<p>I think they also need to build on the HTC First discussion by letting people know that the HTC One can offer some Facebook home screen functionality while still giving the consumer full control over the experience. HTC has not done well marketing their products and should use the opportunity with Facebook to promote the heck out of the HTC First and the HTC One.</p>
<p>Specific HTC One experiences:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/smartphone-ois-video-test-htc-one-competes-well-with-nokia-lumia-920-7000013381/">Smartphone OIS video test; HTC One competes well with Nokia Lumia 920</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/htc-one-uses-windows-phone-panorama-ui-in-an-elegant-way-7000012479/">HTC One uses Windows Phone panorama UI in an elegant way</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/htc-one-hardware-and-first-impressions-gallery-7000012361/">HTC One hardware and first impressions (gallery)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/htc-one-zoes-and-highlight-videos-may-be-best-htc-innovation-ever-videos-7000012364/">HTC One: Zoes and highlight videos may be best HTC innovation ever (videos)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/htc-one-meet-the-smartphone-that-can-save-htc-7000011462/">HTC One: Meet the smartphone that can save HTC</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/htc-sense-5-includes-blinkfeed-zoe-and-tv-screenshot-gallery-7000012362/">HTC Sense 5 includes BlinkFeed, Zoe, and TV (screenshot gallery)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/leave-the-portable-speaker-behind-with-htc-boomsound-on-the-htc-one-video-7000012360/">Leave the portable speaker behind with HTC BoomSound on the HTC One (video)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/walk-through-of-htc-blinkfeed-on-the-htc-one-video-7000012363/">Walk through of HTC BlinkFeed on the HTC One (video)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/htc-one-and-chromebook-pixel-hands-on-mobiletechroundup-show-292-7000012371/">HTC One and Chromebook Pixel hands-on (MobileTechRoundup show #292)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/get-started-with-the-htc-one-easy-phone-setup-from-your-computer-7000012359/">Get Started with the HTC One; easy phone setup from your computer</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Rachel <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-unveils-its-new-home-on-android-7000013486/">posted on the HTC First and Facebook Home</a> experiences that include Cover Feed, notifications, Chat Heads, and an app launcher.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013545</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/with-home-facebook-backs-into-a-broader-ecosystem-7000013545/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[With Home, Facebook backs into a broader ecosystem]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Who said a walled garden had to exist only on the web? The Facebook Home phone concept pushes out the company's digital walls even further.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:56:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="facebook-home-presser-mark-zuckerberg-scrn-620x347" alt="facebook-home-presser-mark-zuckerberg-scrn-620x347" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013545/facebook-home-presser-mark-zuckerberg-scrn-620x347-620x347.jpg?hash=MTH1Lmt3AQ&upscale=1" height="347" width="620"></figure>
<p>I just watched Facebook founder <a href="http://newsroom.fb.com/News/597/Introducing-Home">Mark Zuckerberg introduce Home</a>, the company's <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-unveils-its-new-home-on-android-7000013486/">new Google Android-based mobile offering</a>.</p>
<p>The long and short of it is that Facebook becomes the lens through which you use your entire mobile phone. Facebook Home is powered by Google's Android operating system, but it is not apparent to the end user that it's&nbsp;Android, at least as best as I can tell from the press conference. Your mobile world is seen through blue-colored glasses.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117448" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013546/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-220x165.png?hash=AwR3MQWvMQ&upscale=1" alt="Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>That premise sounds horrific to many people: a mobile phone, operating <em>through</em> Facebook? What if you can barely stand it to begin with? What about all those family members sharing dumb political screeds or pictures of their snotty kids or funny things that just aren't funny? <em>I don't want that to infiltrate the rest of my phone!</em></p>
<p>But if you think of Facebook as a suite of services, rather than a portal or single destination, it makes complete sense. For years, the social networking company has been building -- and then gaining adoption, thanks to the not-so-subtle nudging of its massive customer base -- services that you use every day. Slowly, it has built a "smartphone" from the inside -- integrated, connected software -- out.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-builds-a-new-home-on-android-7000013553/">Gallery: Facebook builds a new 'Home' on Android</a></strong></p>
<p>What if I told you this: There's&nbsp;a new smartphone on the market. It has a big screen. It supports messaging. It's got a robust list of contacts. It can handle your life's photos easily -- and they're integrated with sharing. It's also got a calendar, already stocked with upcoming events. It has e-mail, too. All of these have notifications integration. And for marketing types reading this, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">it's a high-speed highway into targeting mobile users</a>, with support for advertisements and other money-making schemes.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sounds like Google Android, right? Or perhaps Apple iOS? It's any mobile phone, really. Because it's any mobile platform.</p>
<p>User database + suite of services = ecosystem. So it makes complete sense, then, that Facebook would want to enter this space by riding Android's open source coattails. Hardware, of course, is the missing link.</p>
<figure><img title="facebook-home-presser-device-620x348" alt="facebook-home-presser-device-620x348" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013545/facebook-home-presser-device-620x348-620x348.jpg?hash=MwOwAwqxAQ&upscale=1" height="348" width="620"></figure>
<p>Take messaging, for example. When you send a message to someone, do you care which system it uses? Which company's pipes? Most people don't, so long as it's the same person on the other end and the message is as easy to send and retrieve as any other. If I send a "text" to my wife, I could very well use SMS, iMessage, Google Chat, AIM, Yahoo, Twitter...or Facebook. It doesn't matter.</p>
<p>(Any annoyances about which path the message takes is usually just because each app is walled off from the other, and not everyone is on every platform. A wealth of options -- and messages across apps -- just makes us scream, "Pick one!" Each company has been trying valiantly to crowd out the others.)</p>
<p>You might not want to buy into this world, one in which Facebook is your primary provider. But you likely already have. Most people -- <em>one billion</em> in 2013 -- are now Facebook users of some kind. You're already in the database. You already have a Facebook e-mail address, whether you know it or not. You're already signed up for photos, and events, and yes, social sharing. It's all wrapped in to that login. It's not a step-by-step, app-by-app situation.</p>
<p>In this way, it's really not hard at all to imagine a world lived solely through Facebook. You're probably already engaged in this dance with Google or Apple or Microsoft, even if you don't have a mobile device. How is Facebook any different?</p>
<p>Zuckerberg called Home "a phone that's designed around people, not apps." In pushing his company's boundaries out, from app to entire device, he's right. And his company has a much greater foothold than people initially suspect.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6272005665</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/update-facebook-phone-been-there-done-that-and-nobody-cared/5665]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Update: Facebook phone? Been there, done that, and nobody cared]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Facebook is generating buzz with the unveiling of Home, but it seems everyone has forgotten about the Facebook phone nobody wanted.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:42:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-telcos/">Telcos</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/i/story/62/72/005665/htc-chacha-status.jpg"><img class="alignRight size-full wp-image-5667" title="htc-chacha-status" alt="" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/story/62/72/005665/htc-chacha-status.jpg" height="423" width="278" /></a><em>Facebook has unveiled the new <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Home environment</a> for Android phones that looks to turn those phones into Facebook phones. Breaking into the mobile space has long been the dream of Facebook. It's too early to tell if users will race to turn their Android phones into Facebook phones. They didn't flock to a real Facebook phone in the past as we pointed out in this article originally published in 2011.</em></p>
<p>While some have raised <a >HTC Status</a>? I didn't think so.</p>
<p>This was an unofficial, meaning HTC/AT&amp;T couldn't actually call it a Facebook phone, handset that had Facebook ingrained all the way down to the hardware layer. You could see the Facebook button right on the front of the phone, that made it a snap, er, push of a button, to share anything around you. Both AT&amp;T and HTC made a big splash about the Status/Chacha, calling it the first Facebook phone on the AT&amp;T network. It was positioned to change our world, and for the better. After all, sharing is good, right?</p>
<p>This was earlier this year (2011), and since then the Facebook phone has made no impact. No. Noise. At. All. It's as if it quietly went into hiding in the back rooms of stores. I'm sure some of them sold to customers, but I certainly haven't seen a single one in the real world.</p>
<p>If Facebook is really developing Buffy, or whatever it will eventually call the real Facebook phone, it is likely to receive the same reception as the "nobody owns one" Chacha. The fact is Facebook is too late to bring such a phone to market successfully, as every single Facebook user already has decent access to the service on their present phone. It doesn't matter what phone they use, Facebook is already front and center for those who consider that important.</p>
<p>Facebook phone? Nobody outside of the Facebook organization cares.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013546</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Facebook can hit the monetization, juice the experience, target tablets and basically circle all of Google's touch points.From a business perspective, Facebook Home is a work of art.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:39:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tablets/">Tablets</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg outlined Facebook Home, an Android overlay that aims to create a software package that takes over messaging, key communications and runs like "system software not an app you run."</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="fbhome1" alt="fbhome1" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013546/fbhome1-200x380.png?hash=BGN3Z2H4AQ&upscale=1" height="380" width="200"></figure>
<p>Zuckerberg <a href="http://newsroom.fb.com/News/597/Introducing-Home">noted that Facebook Home</a> is the "highest quality experience you can have on Android." Facebook has retooled Android's chat with "chat heads," cover overlays and other key perks. Bottom line: If you live in Facebook, Facebook Home is gold for you. If you live beyond Facebook, Facebook Home may strike you as alarming. Facebook literally becomes your phone. For good measure, Facebook forged Facebook Home&nbsp;partnerships with AT&amp;T and HTC to have its overlay work right out of the box.&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-builds-a-new-home-on-android-7000013553/">Gallery: Facebook builds a new 'Home' on Android</a></strong></p>
<p>More:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-unveils-its-new-home-on-android-7000013486/">Facebook unveils its new 'Home' on Android</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="http://live.cnet.com/Event/Facebooks_new_home_on_Android">CNET live blog: Facebook's new home on Android</a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/forget-the-facebook-phone-facebooks-mobile-ambitions-are-way-bigger-than-that-7000013398/?s_cid=e539">Forget the 'Facebook phone', Facebook's mobile ambitions are way bigger than that</a>&nbsp;| <a href="https://live.facebooklive.com/live">Facebook Live</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The larger question is whether the masses will turn their phones into a people experience, which oddly resembles Microsoft's Windows Phone live tiles in some respects.</p>
<p>But let's not lose focus on the bigger business story here. Facebook is trying to eclipse Google on its own mobile operating system. Sound familiar? It should. Samsung's Galaxy S4 launch did something similar and touted its "S" apps over Android. And oh by the way Amazon's Kindle took Android and reskinned it completely.</p>
<p>However, Facebook is most dangerous to Android and Google. Facebook can literally take over your phone. Facebook will also take over the mobile ads that go with your phone. Here's where Facebook Home is truly brilliant. Facebook can hit the monetization, juice the experience, target tablets and basically circle all of Google's touch points. Facebook Home is basically an operating system of sorts with monthly updates.</p>
<p>Facebook said it isn't going to "massively fork Android" and it will respect the open nature of it. Rest assured that Google can't be happy. Samsung isn't happy.</p>
<p>From a business perspective, Facebook Home is a work of art. Every Android phone can become a Facebook phone now. Facebook has grabbed mobile share, possibly ad share and knocked Google in one swoop.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013544</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/apples-smartphone-share-rockets-android-loses-ground-7000013544/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Apple's smartphone share rockets, Android loses ground]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Apple and Google remain at the top in their respective zones, but neither gain full marks at the top of the smartphone and platform podium. The iPhone—Android duopoly continues.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:30:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Both Apple and Google are leading the race in the U.S. smartphone and platform rankings respectively, <a href="http://www.comscore.com/Insights/Press_Releases/2013/4/comScore_Reports_February_2013_U.S._Smartphone_Subscriber_Market_Share">according to new comScore figures</a>, but neither one has the complete pieces of the jigsaw to reign as the overall ecosystem winner.</p>
<p>During the three months ended in February, Apple retained hold of its lead over second place rival Samsung in the U.S. market with 38.9 percent, up 3.9 percentage points on the previous month.</p>
<p>Samsung by comparison grew just 1 percentage point to take 21.3 percent, but the figures reflect the period just before <a href="/story/edit/7000013544/news.cnet.com/8301-31322_3-57574466-256/samsung-gs4-launch-tone-deaf-and-shockingly-sexist/">the "shockingly sexist" launch</a> of the Galaxy S4, unveiled <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/amid-great-expectations-the-samsung-galaxy-s4-has-arrived-7000012629/">in mid-March</a>&nbsp;in New York City.&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img title="oems" alt="oems" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013544/oems-573x295.png?hash=ZwtlLwx5ZG&upscale=1" height="295" width="573"><figcaption>(Credit: comScore)</figcaption></figure>
<p>All other mobile makers in the top five, including HTC, Motorola and LG, which all develop devices for the Android platform, have lost ground.</p>
<p>That probably accounts for the fact that Google's mobile platform has lost 2 percentage points from the three months ended in November, but still retains the top spot with 51.7 percent of the U.S. market&nbsp;— more than half of all the 133.7 million smartphone owners in the country.</p>
<p>Apple naturally grew by the same 3.9 percentage points since the last count as a likely result of a recent explosion in number of iPhone owners. At <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apple-q1-strong-iphone-sales-mixed-vs-expectations-7000010196/">Apple's Q1 earnings</a>, which the company announced its December holiday sales, the iPhone maker announced that 47.8 million of its smartphones had been sold during the quarter, up from 37 million during the same quarter a year ago.</p>
<p>Bad news for BlackBerry owners as the platform declined by just shy of 2 percent during the three month period, holding just 5.4 percent of the market. Considering <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blackberry-q4-better-than-expected-1m-blackberry-z10-devices-shipped-7000013220/">BlackBerry Z10 sales in the U.S. have only just kicked off</a>, the next couple of month should show some growth, albeit modestly, according to BlackBerry Q4 figures.</p>
<figure><img title="platform" alt="platform" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013544/platform-579x295.png?hash=AGp3AGR5MQ&upscale=1" height="295" width="579"><figcaption>(Credit: comScore)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile Microsoft's Windows Phone platform grew slightly by 0.2 percent, and Symbian&nbsp;— which Nokia is still holding the pillow over its face&nbsp;— remained flat, showing no growth but still a steady 0.5 percent of the market with the old, outdated and defunct platform.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013486</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-unveils-its-new-home-on-android-7000013486/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Facebook unveils its new 'Home' on Android]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[In what might have been a terribly kept secret, Facebook has unveiled its Android project.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 16:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-smartphones/">Smartphones</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-social-enterprise/">Social Enterprise</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-2" alt="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-2" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013486/zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-2-600x399.jpg?hash=ZGHjA2EuLJ&upscale=1" height="399" width="600"></figure>
<p><strong>MENLO PARK, CALIF. --</strong> There have been countless rumors about a potential "Facebook phone" over the years, and they finally came to fruition on Thursday.</p>
<p>Well, sort of.</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://live.cnet.com/Event/Facebooks_new_home_on_Android">CNET live blog: Facebook's new home on Android</a> | <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/forget-the-facebook-phone-facebooks-mobile-ambitions-are-way-bigger-than-that-7000013398/?s_cid=e539">Forget the 'Facebook phone', Facebook's mobile ambitions are way bigger than that</a> | <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebooks-android-play-could-be-boon-for-htc-7000013288/">Facebook's Android play could be boon for HTC</a> | <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/mobile-news/update-facebook-phone-been-there-done-that-and-nobody-cared/5665">Facebook phone? Been there, done that, and nobody cared</a></p>
<p>"Today we're finally going to talk about that Facebook phone," quipped CEO Mark Zuckerberg immediately after walking out during a packed invite-only event on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Zuckerberg went on to explain the inspiration behind the social network's new mobile strategy, suggesting that instead of designing phones around apps first, why not "design around people first" and then interact with the apps.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117448" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013546/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-220x165.png?hash=AwR3MQWvMQ&upscale=1" alt="Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>"We're not building a phone and we're not building an operating system," Zuckerberg remarked. "But we're building something a whole lot deeper than just an ordinary app."</p>
<p>Stressing that there "is a new use case that is becoming more and more important," Zuckerberg described that Facebook wants to bring a new "home" to smartphones.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-builds-a-new-home-on-android-7000013553/">Gallery: Facebook builds a new 'Home' on Android</a></strong></p>
<p>"The home screen is really the soul of your phone," Zuckerberg posited.</p>
<p>Enter <strong>Facebook Home</strong>, a home screen interface (or "a family of apps") that can be installed by users themselves on top of Android.</p>
<p>One of the core features to Facebook's Home platform is that notifications are based on people rather than apps, which immediately started <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23facebookphone&amp;src=tren">drawing questions and comparisons on Twitter</a> to Google Now and Windows Phone.</p>
<p>During the live demo, Adam Mosseri, Facebook's director of product, said that the purpose of Home is to shift attention away from tasks and apps to their friends instead.</p>
<p>But he also admitted that apps are still important. Thus, Home extends Facebook's app portfolio beyond the basic native social network and messaging apps to consist of a graphic-heavy cover feed of updates and an app launcher for bookmarking favorite apps.</p>
<figure><img title="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-4" alt="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-4" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013486/zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-4-576x384.jpg?hash=MzD2AzV4Zz&upscale=1" height="384" width="576"></figure>
<p>One feature that particularly integrates Facebook's messaging service is Chat Heads.</p>
<p>Similar to Apple's iMessage for iOS devices, Chat Heads basically merges Facebook Messenger and SMS conversations for individual contacts.</p>
<p>In one fell swoop, Facebook has attempted to establish itself as the core messaging and communication platform on Android.</p>
<p><strong>Read More</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-home-android-takeover-and-google-punch-to-the-head-7000013546/">Facebook Home: Android takeover and Google punch to the head</a></p>
<p>That could end up presenting serious competition not only for service providers when it comes to texting, but also Android's maker, running up against the combination of Gmail, Google Chat and Google Plus.</p>
<figure><img title="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-5" alt="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-5" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013486/zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-5-576x384.jpg?hash=AGZjZ2RlMQ&upscale=1" height="384" width="576"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Slated to launch in the next week, Facebook Home for Android can be downloaded from Google Play. It will be rolling out for at least five Android smartphones first, but support on tablets won't follow for at least "several months."</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Facebook execs promised that new features for Home will roll out "every month."</p>
<p><strong>HTC and AT&amp;T team up on Facebook Home</strong></p>
<p>Zuckerberg singled out HTC and AT&amp;T as partners on Home, noting they have worked together to build first set of phones with Facebook Home pre-loaded.</p>
<p>HTC CEO Peter Chou introduced the HTC First, which he described as the "ultimate social phone" as well as a "great opportunity to bring social and mobile together."</p>
<p>"It will give you the best Facebook experience," Chou boasted, asserting that the HTC First is the only phone pre-loaded and optimized for Home.</p>
<figure><img title="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-6" alt="zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-6" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013486/zdnet-facebook-home-phone-cnet-6-576x384.jpg?hash=AQVmBGN5LJ&upscale=1" height="384" width="576"></figure>
<p>AT&amp;T Mobility CEO Ralph de la Vega touted that he thinks that the HTC First offers the most engagement on a smartphone that he has ever seen.</p>
<p>Outfitted in four colors (black, white, red and baby blue), the HTC First runs on AT&amp;T's 4G LTE network. It will retail for $99.99 with a two-year service agreement when it goes on sale on April 12. Pre-orders open up today.</p>
<p>"At one level, this is just the next mobile version of Facebook," Zuckerberg concluding, adding that at a deeper level, he suggested it's possible this will change the relationship we have with computing devices in our lives overall.</p>
<p>"We're about to see the most empowered generation of people in history," Zuckerberg said. "It's a deeply technical problem, but it's also a deeply social problem."</p>
<p><em>Image Credits: <a href="http://live.cnet.com/Event/Facebooks_new_home_on_Android">James Martin, CNET</a><br></em></p>
<p><strong>More recent Facebook coverage on</strong><em><strong> ZDNet:</strong><br></em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-explains-ranking-system-underneath-graph-search-7000012560/">Facebook explains ranking system underneath Graph Search</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/understanding-unicorn-a-deep-dive-into-facebooks-graph-search-7000011581/">Understanding Unicorn: A deep dive into Facebook's Graph Search</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-releasing-new-social-graph-database-benchmark-linkbench-7000013356/">Facebook releasing new Social Graph database benchmark: LinkBench</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-updates-mobile-app-install-ads-process-for-developers-7000013207/">Facebook updates mobile app install ads process for developers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/facebook-announces-mobile-developer-conference-2013-7000012491/">Facebook announces Mobile Developer Conference 2013</a><em><br></em></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013542</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/samsung-apple-set-up-for-best-buy-showdown-7000013542/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Samsung, Apple set up for Best Buy showdown]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Samsung will get "experience" stores inside Best Buy to show off integration between its devices. These areas are likely to have Apple store-within-a-store concepts as a neighbor.  ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:51:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-bring-your-own-device/">Bring Your Own Device</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Samsung's partnership with Best Buy to create stores-within-a-store aims to it can integrate the multiple devices and screens just like Apple. The big question is what Samsung's rival and neighbor, Apple, inside Best Buy will do.</p>
<p>Initially, Best Buy's deal with Samsung looks like a winning combo. Best Buy gets big brand commitment and Samsung can show its integration chops. The Samsung Experience Shop will cover more than 1,400 Best Buy locations in the U.S. By early May, 900 Best Buy locations will be covered with Samsung shops.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20130404005435/en/Samsung-Joins-Forces-Buy-Provide-Consumers-Unique">According to a statement</a>, the Samsung outlets will show off smartphones, tablets, laptops and connected cameras as well as offer account set up and support. These shops will be 460 square feet at the most. A "Samsung Connected Solutions area" is supposed to illustrate how devices connect and content can be shared across various screens.</p>
<figure><img title="samsung040413" alt="samsung040413" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013542/samsung040413-477x320.png?hash=ZGV4LwHlLJ&upscale=1" height="320" width="477"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>These Samsung dedicated areas will have trained staff who can guide tech buyers. For Best Buy, the Samsung areas are a nice way to nix deadbeat DVD and CD spaces in a store.</p>
<p>The catch is that Best Buy will also have Apple shops next to Samsung. It's a consumer and bring your own device showdown within Best Buy. Analysts were generally upbeat about the deal for Best Buy. However, Oppenheimer analyst Brian Nagel said there's a risk Apple may find new partners. He said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Best Buy and Apple have historically had a very healthy relationship with a number of big box stores having a dedicated Apple section. With today's announcement, there are risks that Apple may choose to more aggressively partner with other retailers such as Staples, Target and Walmart going forward.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Earlier:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/samsung-enters-the-us-retail-space-opens-stores-7000013509/">Samsung enters the US retail space, opens stores</a></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013533</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/u-s-government-cant-intercept-imessage-but-it-can-still-serve-apple-a-search-warrant-7000013533/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[U.S. government can't intercept iMessage, but it can still serve Apple a search warrant]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[One U.S. law enforcement agency is struggling to snoop on messages sent by Apple devices, claiming they "cannot be intercepted." But lack of transparency on Apple's part may mean the technology giant is facing an influx of search warrants — and yet we don't know about it.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:24:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Zack Whittaker]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apple/">Apple</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-us/">Government US</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ios/">iOS</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-iphone/">iPhone</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ipad/">iPad</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-privacy/">Privacy</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. government is struggling to crack into Apple's encrypted messaging system for domestic lawful wiretapping,&nbsp;according to an internal U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA)&nbsp;document.</p>
<p>Because Apple stores data sent over iMessage and runs the service and encryption in-house, the iPhone and iPad maker is still open to being served a subpoena or a court-ordered search warrant.</p>
<p>As a result, Apple is also lagging behind other companies on transparency by not disclosing how many government requests have been made.</p>
<figure><img title="deaintelligencenote 2" alt="deaintelligencenote 2" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013533/deaintelligencenote-2-v1-620x275.png?hash=L2H1BGRjAJ&upscale=1" height="275" width="620"><figcaption>An internal unclassified intelligence note by the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration (Credit: <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-57577887-38/apples-imessage-encryption-trips-up-feds-surveillance/">CNET</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13578_3-57577887-38/apples-imessage-encryption-trips-up-feds-surveillance/?part=rss&amp;subj=news&amp;tag=title">CNET first reported</a> that the DEA was unable to eavesdrop on suspects' text-based communiques because the use of Apple's encryption makes it "impossible to intercept iMessages between two Apple devices"&nbsp;— even with a federal judge signed court order approving the intercept.</p>
<p>According to our sister site, the case centers around a recent criminal investigation in February, in which <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1009_3-57437391-83/fbi-looking-at-law-making-web-sites-wiretap-ready-director-says/">the FBI director Robery Mueller described it</a> as the "Going Dark" problem&nbsp;— the difficulties law enforcement and intelligence agencies face when attempting to lawfully&nbsp;intercept and acquire citizen data.</p>
<p>While Title III of the Federal Wiretap Act allows <a href="https://www.privacyrights.org/fs/fs9-wrtp.htm">real-time surveillance</a> of a device or computer, the DEA discovered in the February case that some of the records obtained from Verizon&nbsp;— the carrier of the&nbsp;suspect's device&nbsp;— were incomplete because they were sent through iMessage.</p>
<p>But if the U.S. government cannot&nbsp;legally intercept messages sent by Apple's smartphones and tablets&nbsp;— the only other route is to serve a&nbsp;subpoena to the Cupertino, Calif.-based technology giant or through a court-ordered search warrant forcing the handover of data to authorities.</p>
<h3>Does Apple store your communications?</h3>
<p>Unlike the EU, which has mandatory data retention laws to assist in law enforcement investigations, the U.S. does not. Most data protection laws compel companies to hold onto customer and user data for a set amount of time before anonymizing it or destroying it.</p>
<p>The U.S. has no such comparable laws to the EU's strong data and privacy rules.</p>
<p>The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eff.org/issues/mandatory-data-retention">opposes mandatory data retention rules</a>, saying that such a law in the U.S. would "compel ISPs and telcos to create large databases of information about who communicates with whom via Internet or phone, the duration of the exchange, and the users' location."</p>
<p>Some companies do store customer data for a number of weeks or months, or even longer, in order to make their services run more effectively, or indeed at all.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Looking through Apple's service level agreement&nbsp;— the terms that you agree to abide by when using the service&nbsp;— <a href="http://images.apple.com/legal/sla/docs/OSX108.pdf">Apple states clearly</a> [PDF]:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To facilitate delivery of your iMessages and to enable you to maintain conversations across your devices, Apple may hold your iMessages in encrypted form for a limited period of time.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This may not be news to some, as when you sign in to iMessage on your Mac or any other device, your messages suddenly arrive after a period of inactivity or device downtime.&nbsp;Apple may store your communications in an encrypted form, but the company does not disclose how long for.</p>
<p>This means Apple might be forced to hand over your messages to law enforcement if required to do so by law, but they would be in an encrypted format.</p>
<h3>Apple's encryption? Nobody knows&nbsp;</h3>
<p>Apple said when it launched iMessage in 2011 that it used "secure end-to-end" encryption, but some were skeptical at the thought, considering BlackBerry had the monopoly over secure end-to-end device encryption at the time and was favorited by governments and enterprises alike.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117430" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apples-domino-effect-how-ios-7-should-kickstart-launch-season-7000013480/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013480/when-will-apple-announce-the-next-ipad-os-x-10-9-220x165.png?hash=ZmD0AmN0Am&upscale=1" alt="Apple's domino effect: How iOS 7 should kickstart launch season" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apples-domino-effect-how-ios-7-should-kickstart-launch-season-7000013480/">Apple's domino effect: How iOS 7 should kickstart launch season</a></p>
<p class="more">

																	<p>The company is closing in on its typical (and some promised) launch deadlines but remains quiet on announcing anything, giving developers and enterprises little time to prepare. </p>

																</p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apples-domino-effect-how-ios-7-should-kickstart-launch-season-7000013480/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>Since then, Apple chief executive Tim Cook said&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/apple-media-event-by-the-numbers-7000006088/">that 300 billion messages have been sent through iMessage</a>&nbsp;since it first launched. That's 300 billion that U.S. authorities likely cannot access due to the level of encryption used by Apple's back-end service.</p>
<p><a &nbsp;</p>
<p>Little is known about Apple's iMessage service, such as if it uses the same encryption key on all devices like BlackBerry, or if it uses a system similar to that of BlackBerry's enterprise email.</p>
<p>BlackBerry Messenger, the closest rival to iMessage at the time, used one encryption key for all devices, making it easy for law enforcement and intelligence agencies to tap into such instant messages when necessary. BlackBerry enterprise email, however, pushes a unique secure encryption key on each device, meaning if one key is cracked, others remain secure.</p>
<p>To appease Indian authorities, <a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/govt-to-tap-blackberry-messenger-security-privacy/1/183403.html">BlackBerry opened a Mumbai data center</a> that would allow the government to instantly tap into communications sent across the BlackBerry Messenger system.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Apple doesn't have a BlackBerry-like enterprise email setup —&nbsp;in which it would be able to wash its hands of law enforcement requests for enterprise email requests because it simply doesn't have a universal, skeleton encryption key. <a href="http://www.quora.com/iMessage/What-is-the-basic-message-flow-in-iMessage-Is-there-a-central-switch-and-a-centralized-database-with-all-the-iPhone-users">According to Quora</a>, packet tracing suggests iMessages are in fact sent through Apple's servers rather than peer-to-peer system (or rather, device-to-device).</p>
<p>Because of Apple's centralized infrastructure, and its tight control of the ecosystem, it's more than likely that Apple directly owns the encryption keys to its iMessage service and can therefore not only decrypt customer and user data if asked or forced to, but also hand it over to authorities if ordered to by a judge.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>The bottom line</h3>
<p>Even if each Apple device, from Mac to iPhone, iPad and iPod touch, all contain unique encryption keys, Apple still holds the servers under its control, unlike BlackBerry which only controls its consumer-facing BlackBerry Messenger system.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10117431" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignLeft"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/yes-the-fbi-and-cia-can-read-your-email-heres-how-7000007319/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/007319/yes-the-fbi-and-cia-can-read-your-email-heres-how-220x165.jpg?hash=L2D2MJSyAQ&upscale=1" alt="Yes, the FBI and CIA can read your email. Here's how " width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/yes-the-fbi-and-cia-can-read-your-email-heres-how-7000007319/">Yes, the FBI and CIA can read your email. Here's how </a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/yes-the-fbi-and-cia-can-read-your-email-heres-how-7000007319/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>With this, Apple can be served a federal prosecutor signed subpoena requesting limited amounts of data, or a court ordered search warrant forcing Apple to disclose contents of data&nbsp;— and there's little it can do about it, except challenge it in court.</p>
<p>Because Apple is highly secretive, and despite the kudos that it would receive from privacy circles in <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1009_3-57430273-83/twitter-challenges-court-order-to-hand-over-user-data/">"doing a Twitter" and challenging the order</a>, it would still be a negative public relations hit from the public. In cases like this, it's more likely that Apple would keep quiet and be submissive than fight something openly in court and reveal the truth that federal authorities are requesting data from the company.</p>
<p>And because Apple doesn't have a transparency report&nbsp;— like <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/google-user-data-requests-have-increased-by-70-percent-since-2009-7000010211/">Google</a>, or <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-releases-law-enforcement-skype-user-content-disclosure-figures-7000012950/">Microsoft</a>, which recently announced its first report&nbsp;— we have no idea how many requests U.S. and foreign law enforcement and intelligence agencies are making requests to the technology giant.</p>
<p>Just because the police and the government can't intercept your communications, it doesn't mean they can't just go right to the very source.</p>
<p>We asked Apple to comment, but didn't receive a reply at the time of writing. CNET received a denial for comment by Apple when it asked.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013540</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/sap-is-hana-growth-overstated-7000013540/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[SAP: Is HANA growth overstated?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA["We believe the trend in compute is massively distributed commodity boxes, and while there is a market for products like HANA and Exadata, it is significantly smaller than optimistic descriptions by SAP and Oracle," says Cowen & Co. analyst. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:00:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-big-data/">Big Data</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-management/">Data Management</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-enterprise-software/">Enterprise Software</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-business-intelligence/">Business Intelligence</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SAP has shown strong growth with its HANA in-memory analytics systems, but at least one analyst is questioning the growth and adding that the company may be allocating other products to the category.</p>
<p>In a research note, Cowen analyst Peter Goldmacher did a deep dive into SAP's HANA results. SAP has said that HANA's two year license compound annual growth rate through fiscal 2013 has been about 120 percent. If that growth rate is true, Goldmacher noted that "the other 90% of SAP's license business, apps and business intelligence, is growing at a combined two year CAGR of roughly 2%, materially below category growth rates."</p>
<p>Ultimately, Goldmacher noted that SAP is adding licenses to HANA to show better growth.</p>
<p>His theory wouldn't be unheard of. For instance, Oracle has noted that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/oracles-hardware-business-is-all-about-the-software/51321">its Exa- hardware strategy revolves around software licenses too</a>. Tossing software deals into HANA would rhyme with that approach.</p>
<p>Goldmacher questions that approach over the long run. His take is the opposite of Oracle's Safra Catz, president and CFO, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/oracles-catz-on-premise-isnt-a-dirty-word-hardware-will-rise-7000013476/">who talked up Exa- on Wednesday</a>. Goldmacher's conclusion:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We believe the trend in compute is massively distributed commodity boxes, and while there is a market for products like HANA and Exadata, it is significantly smaller than optimistic descriptions by SAP and Oracle. We believe HANA revenue is being inflated by subjective product revenue allocation to HANA at the expense of its traditional Apps and BI businesses, and swapping HANA for unused licenses. We think this inflates seat count with no incremental cash to the firm. At some point investors will likely start to worry about the implications on the other 90% of license sales we expect will eventually turn negative. We believe the offense in this case is getting into the data management business with old product (Sybase) and high priced hardware (HANA). While the impact on the model is low, the reputational cost to management could be high.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Goldmacher arrived at his conclusion by breaking down SAP's database, mobile, business intelligence and application sales. Note that SAP doesn't break those groups out, but rolls them up under software and software related services.</p>
<figure><img title="hanarev" alt="hanarev" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013540/hanarev-620x336.png?hash=LzH1MQEvBJ&upscale=1" height="336" width="620"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In a nutshell, Goldmacher said it's likely that SAP is discounting applications and business intelligence and offering few deals on databases and mobile. That move also inflates database and mobile growth.</p>
<p>Why would SAP discount apps and not other items? Goldmacher noted:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We caution investors that our research indicates that HANA and Sybase’s growth likely stem from either arbitrary revenue allocation/discounting in enterprise license agreements, or SAP’s willingness to swap licensed products instead of reducing maintenance revenues as customers switch to SaaS alternatives like Salesforce.com and Workday. We continue to struggle to find data points in the field that HANA is going mainstream and/or gaining ground in competitive engagements.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>SAP said Goldmacher's analysis is off base. A spokesperson said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>No such discounting is taking place on any SAP product and that half of SAP HANA transactions are standalone deals. &nbsp;We have been consistent in our no-discount policy and our reporting of growth rates and revenue results. Hana, Mobile and Cloud are seeing the fastest growth in our solution portfolio and that our core business (Apps and Analytics) continue to grow, &nbsp;too.</p>
</blockquote>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013537</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/bloomberg-adds-tweets-to-terminals-7000013537/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Bloomberg adds tweets to terminals]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Traders and other financial professionals can now monitor social media buzz about companies they follow. Hello, social enterprise!]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 14:35:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the latest triumph for the real-time social network, Twitter will now be incorporated into the <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/professional/systems-support/hardware/">Bloomberg terminals</a> popular with Wall Street traders.</p>
<p><a href="http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2013/04/04/twitter-arrives-on-wall-street-via-bloomberg/">The company says</a> it plans to incorporate tweets into its data service, widely used in the financial industry, so that people can monitor social media buzz about companies.</p>
<p>The irony is that financial services firms have long blocked the service as a potential risk in violating the regulations that govern the communications of their employees.</p>
<p>In this example, though, Twitter isn't a channel for employee output, but public input.</p>
<p>More data. More insight. And no more need for traders to keep their phones nearby, just to check what the hive mind is saying about a particular company they are interested in.</p>
<p>The data service allows for tweets to be sorted by company and topic, and will incorporate tweets from companies, chief executives and key financial thought leaders (investors, press, et cetera).</p>
<p>Terminal customers can search through them using keywords and set up alerts for particular terms, underscoring Twitter's emergence as the dominant place for real-time public communication online and its supplanting of the traditional news wire.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013536</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/panasonic-north-america-names-new-cto-7000013536/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Panasonic North America names new CTO]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Japanese company's North American arm taps Todd Rytting to help it become a "solutions provider for enterprises."]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 04 Apr 2013 14:01:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="todd-rytting-headshot-620px" alt="todd-rytting-headshot-620px" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013536/todd-rytting-headshot-620px-v1-200x267.jpg?hash=MJIxBGxmZG&upscale=1" height="267" width="200"></figure>
<p>Panasonic Corp. of North America announced this morning that it has appointed Todd Rytting as chief technology officer.</p>
<p>He replaces Eisuke Tsuyuzaki, who left Panasonic in March "to pursue other opportunities," the company says.</p>
<p>In addition to the new role, he will keep his prior one as president and CEO of Panasonic Electric Works Laboratory of America, which is based in Salt Lake City.</p>
<p>Panasonic says it liked Rytting's experience in&nbsp;managing engineering teams across disciplines; Rytting has done so for the company's energy management, device networking and robotics solutions businesses. He "aligns well with Panasonic's direction as a solutions provider for enterprises," Panasonic NA chief executive Joseph Taylor said.</p>
<p>Translation: more services are in the pipeline.</p>
<p>Rytting has worked for Panasonic since 2005, when the giant acquired the startup he was working for, the networking infrastructure company emWare. Among the highlights of his career: managing engineering teams&nbsp;that produced state-of-the-art robotics systems for the entertainment industry and non-destructive testing systems for aerospace applications.</p>
<p>It's a good fit for Panasonic's B2B interests on the continent. Or as that company officially says, "innovative synergy." But I wouldn't do that to you, now would I?</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
