<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:s="http://www.zdnet.com/search" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
    <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
    <description>Latest Blog for ZDNet</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>ZDNet</copyright>
    <managingEditor>customerservice@zdnet.com (ZDNet Customer Services)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>uk-engineering@cbsinteractive.com (ZDNet Webmaster)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:59:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>2</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://i.zdnet.com/images/spry/zdnet_300x300.jpg</url>
      <link>http://www.zdnet.com/</link>
      <title>Latest Blog for ZDNet</title>
      <width>143</width>
      <height>39</height>
    </image>
    <s:counts>
      <start>0</start>
      <return>20</return>
      <found>41506</found>
    </s:counts>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013193</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/what-will-the-new-dell-look-like-7000013193/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[What will the new Dell look like?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Dell - #3 in PCs - is in play with three bids on the table to buy the company. What are the buyers planning to do?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:49:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Robin Harris]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-centers/">Data Centers</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-dell/">Dell</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-pcs/">PCs</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dell's big problem:</strong> it is losing market share in a shrinking business. The PC business is maturing and the low-price schtick that Dell rode to success is no longer enough.</p>
<p>Michael Dell has been pushing his namesake company in the direction of enterprise and cloud data center products and services. He's bought several interesting storage companies - EqualLogic, Compellent and AppAssure - a high-end networking company - Force10 - and Perot Systems in the last 5 years.</p>
<p>Especially in the cloud market margins are thin but the volumes are huge. That's a market where Dell's operational excellence can win.</p>
<p>While the company's balance sheet is strong - with about $3.50 per-share of net cash - turning Dell into a growth company is going to require major changes.</p>
<p>These include:</p>
<p><strong>Shrink the PC business.</strong> The benefits of scale aren't important to Dell in higher margin data center markets. They'll give up on the low-end consumer space to focus on more profitable notebooks for road warriors.</p>
<p><strong>Make a bold move in storage.</strong> In the new world of Big Data storage is the critical piece, both in cost and capability. If Dell could harness its low-cost expertise to scale-out storage they could have a hit. They need something, since their [dumb] deal with storage giant EMC went south.</p>
<p><strong>Recast the corporate culture</strong>. Dell is a classic stack 'em high, sell 'em cheap hardware company. They do not have the DNA to be an enterprise vendor today. Getting there will require the corporate equivalent of a heart, lung and liver transplant.</p>
<p><strong>Goodbye Mr. Dell.</strong> Mr. Dell has irritated many shareholders with his greedy lowball offer for the company.<br />Nor has he had great success refashioning the company since he took control in 2007. The new owners will ax Mr. Dell. Unless he's part of the winning bid.</p>
<p><strong>The Storage Bits take</strong>&nbsp; With over 110,000 employees and more than $50B in revenue, Dell is a substantial enterprise despite its lackluster results over the last 5 years. Let's hope that who ever ends up running the company gets it right.</p>
<p><strong>Comments welcome, as always.</strong>&nbsp; Alas, Michael Dell is no Steve Jobs.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013144</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/surprise-microsoft-really-is-a-lovely-place-to-work-7000013144/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Surprise! Microsoft really is a lovely place to work]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[A survey of the best places to work in Scandinavia has found Microsoft topping the list more than once, with fellow tech companies both large and small not far behind.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:04:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Liam Tung]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-microsoft/">Microsoft</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-eu/">EU</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft might be the ranked only 75th best place to work in the US, but it's shaping up far better in Scandinavia.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10116909" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/is-the-office-dead-to-everyone-but-yahoo-7000012447/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/global-thumbs/people/teen-girl-tablet-home-220x165.jpg?hash=BGp1Awt4Aw&upscale=1" alt="Is the office dead to everyone but Yahoo?" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/is-the-office-dead-to-everyone-but-yahoo-7000012447/">Is the office dead to everyone but Yahoo?</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/is-the-office-dead-to-everyone-but-yahoo-7000012447/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>In a survey by local chapters of the Great Place to Work Institute, Microsoft was found to be the best place to work in two Scandinavian countries, and the second best in another.</p>
<p>The company took first place for employers with 250 or more staff in both Norway and Sweden in the institute's recently-published list of best employers for 2012. On the other side of the Baltic Sea, Microsoft was found to be Finland's second best workplace in the 50 to 499-employee category.</p>
<p>Microsoft isn't the only IT company to get plaudits in the region. Sweden's <a href="http://www.greatplacetowork.se/baesta-arbetsplatser/sveriges-baesta-arbetsplatser" target="_blank">top 10 list is littered</a> with tech companies and consultancies: in the 'large organisation' category behind Microsoft, which employed 451 people in Sweden, was consulting giant Accenture, which employed 927 staff, followed by IT consultancy Enfo with 452. Payments startup Klarna, with 640 staff, was fifth, while business intelligence firm QlikTech, which employs 254 people, was ninth.</p>
<p>According to Great Places to Work Sweden, the best employers promote workplace friendships, are inclusive towards employees' families, and find ways to promote success in line with the company's culture.</p>
<p>The institute's junior consultant, Anna Fahlgrd, points to Klarna's intranet and a feature called 'Face List', which lists employee's birthdays every day and encourages staff to get to know each other, while Enfo holds <em>hackerkvller</em> or hacking evenings for staff to review new products. Microsoft <a href="http://www.mynewsdesk.com/se/pressroom/microsoft/pressrelease/view/microsoft-sveriges-baesta-arbetsplats-foer-tredje-aaret-i-rad-849375?utm_source=realtime&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=Subscription&amp;utm_content=" target="_blank">Sweden's HR chief Anne-Marie Andric put its success in the workplace survey</a> down to flexibility and that management place trust in their employees to get the job done.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Norway and Denmark</h3>
<p>A number of tech companies make Norway's <a href="http://www.greatplacetowork.no/publikasjoner-a-events/blogger-a-nyheter/631-dette-er-norges-beste-arbeidsplasser-2013" target="_blank">top 10 list for larger companies</a>. Cisco follows Microsoft in sixth place, with Canon and HP in seventh and eighth respectively. In Denmark, Microsoft is the <a href="http://www.greatplacetowork.dk/bedste-arbejdspladser/danmarks-bedste-arbejdspladser" target="_blank">only tech company in the top 10</a>, which is headed by Swiss&nbsp;pharma giant Roche.</p>
<p>In Finland, there are no tech companies in the top list in the 500-plus employee group, and one company notable by its absence is the Helsinki-headquartered Nokia. So long as you're not one of the thousands laid off recently, it's historically been regarded as a good place to work and offers outgoing employees programs <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/inside-nokia-bridge-how-nokia-funds-ex-employees-new-start-ups-7000000863/" target="_blank">such as its Nokia Bridge start-up plan</a>.</p>
<p>Companies do have to apply to the institute to be considered for inclusion in the list, so it's not a complete list of employers in the region and a few notable omissions from the Swedish list include, for example, Spotify and Ericsson. Similarly, while Swedish-founded Ikea does not make Sweden's top 10 list, it is considered the <a href="http://www.greatplacetowork.fi/julkaisut-ja-tapahtumat/blogit-ja-uutiset/645-palvelualan-toimijat-nousivat-suomen-parhaat-typaikat-tutkimuksessa" target="_blank">top workplace in Finland</a>&nbsp;at the large end with more than 500 employees.</p>
<p>For a comparison, <a href="http://www.greatplacetowork.com/best-companies/100-best-companies-to-work-for" target="_blank">the Great Place to Work US list</a> rates Google as the top workplace, followed by enterprise software company SAS. Microsoft is down at 75, behind storage vendor NetApp, chipset maker Qualcomm, Intuit, Rackspace and others. Noticeably missing from this list however is Apple, which is ranked 34th on the <a href="http://www.glassdoor.com/Best-Places-to-Work-LST_KQ0,19.htm" target="_blank">best places to work list compiled by careers site Glassdoor</a>.</p>
<p>According to the Glassdoor list, Facebook is actually the top place to work for, followed by consulting firm McKinsey &amp; Co. Ikea is ranked 43 on the list.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013013</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/equinix-netapp-team-up-on-private-storage-for-aws-7000013013/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Equinix, NetApp team up on private storage for AWS]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The idea behind the Equinix-NetApp collaboration is to offer cost and scaling benefits associated with the public cloud while having the control and security levels typically associated with private clouds.
]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-amazon/">Amazon</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-centers/">Data Centers</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-networking/">Networking</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="data-center-tour" alt="data-center-tour" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/us-carousel/data-center-tour-620x202.jpg?hash=MwV4LwWwAJ&upscale=1" height="202" width="620"></figure>
<p><strong>Equinix</strong> and <strong>NetApp</strong>&nbsp;are teaming up on a new private storage scheme directed at <strong>Amazon Web Services</strong> customers.</p>
<p>Enter the NetApp Private Storage for AWS in Equinix International Business Exchange data centers.</p>
<p>Once you get past the mouthful of a name, the new platform is touted to enable organizations to leverage on-demand cloud compute services while retaining full control of their data.</p>
<p>How it is said to work is that by leveraging AWS Direct Connect access within Platform Equinix, customers with heavy storage and compute needs can combine with NetApp Private Storage.</p>
<p>The idea is to get all of the cost and scaling benefits associated with the public cloud while having the control and security levels typically associated with private cloud environments.</p>
<p>Prior to this, Equinix boasted that NetApp Private Storage for public cloud services (when deployed on its global data services platform) allowed companies to maintain control of their data in compliance with "the most stringent privacy and security standards" while still delivering sub-5ms performance.</p>
<p>Now, with this private option, businesses should be able to still balance private and public cloud resources, which Equinix asserted can't be done from a single corporate data center.</p>
<p>The NetApp Private Storage option is also described to offer public cloud services for a wide range of applications, including big data analytics, tiered data back-up and recovery, and cost-effective disaster recovery.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013015</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/cisco-report-highlights-biggest-business-it-challenges-of-big-data-7000013015/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Cisco report highlights biggest business, IT challenges of big data]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Cisco's latest world tech report hones in on IT managers, and the challenges and opportunities they see with all of this data.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Rachel King]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-big-data/">Big Data</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cisco/">Cisco</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-enterprise-2-0/">Enterprise 2.0</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="people-big-data" alt="people-big-data" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/library/us-carousel/people-big-data-620x202.jpg?hash=MwV0LmtmMQ&upscale=1" height="202" width="620"></figure>
<p><strong>Cisco's</strong> global technology reports typically focus on the most buzzworthy (if not discussed to death) topics in business technology.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/btl/cisco-gen-y-study-mobile-devices-valued-more-than-higher-salaries/62246">Previously covering mobile</a> and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/gen-y-more-willing-to-break-it-rules-cisco-1339327961/">social media trends</a> <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cisco-most-of-gen-y-regard-smartphones-as-extra-appendage-7000008698/">among younger professionals</a>, Cisco's latest study hones in on IT managers and what they see as the biggest opportunities and challenges presented by big data.</p>
<p>For starters, it looks like IT professionals at most major businesses worldwide have at least accepted big data as more than just a flashy trend.</p>
<p>Researchers said approximately two thirds of IT managers agreed that big data will be a priority this year and over at least the next five years as well.</p>
<p>But the major roadblocks are obvious: security and risk management.</p>
<p>Roughly one in four respondents pointed to large volumes of data, the number of ways to access data, and budget constraints as the top reasons why securing big data projects is such a hassle.</p>
<p>Those budgets are only going to increase, considering any changes and investments made in big data projects are likely going to involve IT staffing changes and infrastructure upgrades, particularly around the cloud.</p>
<p>So, what's next? Well, a thought-out business model would be a good start.</p>
<p>More than a third (38 percent) of those surveyed admitted that while they have big data solutions already being deployed, they still need "a strategic plan to take advantage" of all of that unincorporated data coming in.</p>
<p>One interesting opportunity highlighted in Cisco's report is the interest surrounding machine-to-machine (M2M) communication in factory automation, which Cisco suggested could "be extremely valuable in optimizing a production process."</p>
<p><strong>See also</strong>: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/cisco-mobile-internet-data-traffic-to-grow-13-fold-by-2017-7000010931/">Cisco: Mobile Internet data traffic to grow 13-fold by 2017</a></p>
<p>This goes hand-in-hand with the growing proliferation of network-connected smart devices delivering data from digital sensors, smart meters and video.</p>
<p>So far, Cisco found that smart device adoption is still in its infancy considering only one-third of respondents worldwide replied they have plans to use these data sources.</p>
<p>For reference, the survey was conducted by independent market research firm InsightExpress in July and August of 2012 across the following 18 countries: the United States, Canada, Mexico, Brazil, Argentina, the United Kingdom, France, Germany, Netherlands, Russia, Poland, Turkey, South Africa, India, China, Japan, South Korea, and Australia. There were 100 respondents in each country.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013164</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/belkin-ultimate-keyboard-case-for-ipad-its-the-magnets-review-7000013164/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case for iPad: It's the magnets (review)]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Ultimate Keyboard Case for iPad by Belkin is one of the thinnest, lightest models available. Its unique use of magnets sets it apart from the competition.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[James Kendrick]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ipad/">iPad</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-reviews/">Reviews</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="Side view" alt="Side view" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013164/side-view-600x404.jpg?hash=LGSwZGZ5ZG&upscale=1" height="404" width="600"></figure>
<p>My quest for the best keyboard for the iPad has seen me using most of the top models. A new one from Belkin may be as good as any available. I have been using the Ultimate Keyboard Case for the iPad for a couple of weeks and its thin profile and light weight make it great for work.</p>
<p><strong>See also: <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/best-ipad-keyboards-hands-on-march-2013-7000012718/">Best iPad keyboards (hands on): March 2013</a></strong></p>
<p>The Ultimate Keyboard Case I am using has an aluminum bottom and a black plastic top with a faux leather insert. It weighs less than a pound and is only a little thicker than the iPad. It has a Bluetooth keyboard that supports fast touch typing and, most importantly, it can support the iPad in three different viewing angles to suit any situation.</p>
<p><strong>Specifications</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dimensions</strong>: 245 x 197 x 18.8 mm (9.6 x 7.75 x 0.74 inches); 411 gm (0.9 pounds)</li>
<li><strong>Key travel</strong>: 1.6 mm (0.06 inches)</li>
<li><strong>Key spacing</strong>: 2.8 mm (0.11 inches)</li>
<li><strong>Keyboard thickness</strong>: 6.9 mm (0.27 inches)</li>
</ul>
<p>The Ultimate Keyboard Case is one of the thinnest portfolio cases with a keyboard. This was accomplished by making the keyboard only 6.9 mm (0.27 inches) thick.</p>
<figure><img title="KB closeup" alt="KB closeup" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013164/kb-closeup-v1-600x408.jpg?hash=AQHkMQtjZJ&upscale=1" height="408" width="600"><figcaption>Magnetic strips (indicated by red arrow) provide three viewing angles</figcaption></figure>
<p>Belkin uses three strips of magnets above the keyboard that grip the iPad for viewing. These provide three viewing angles, all of which are good for using the keyboard. It's easy to move the iPad to any of these positions and to close the case for transport. When the iPad is gripped by one of these magnets the keyboard automatically turns on and when the magnetic seal is broken, the keyboard is powered off. No power switch is needed for this reason.</p>
<p>The Ultimate Case has smart cover technology that turns the iPad on/off when the case is open/closed.&nbsp;The iPad is completely protected when closed.</p>
<figure><img title="Tablet mode" alt="Tablet mode" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013164/tablet-mode-600x523.jpg?hash=ZTV0MGH4ZG&upscale=1" height="523" width="600"><figcaption>iPad slides over keyboard for use as a tablet in the case</figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to the magnetic grips for standing the iPad, the Ultimate Case also lets you slide the iPad forward for use as a tablet. The iPad covers the keyboard in this position so the keys are not exposed. This works surprisingly well for using the tablet without removing it from the case as required by other cases.</p>
<p>This keyboard/case has worked well for me and I enjoy using it. The only gripe I have is the lack of a screen lock key as found on most keyboards of this type. That key would make it possible to turn the iPad screen off without closing the case. I hope Belkin will include this key on future revisions in place of the current Bluetooth pairing key.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.belkin.com/us/ultimate-keyboard-case-for-ipad">Belkin Ultimate Keyboard Case for the iPad</a> is available in black and in white. The black model, as reviewed, is $99 and the white model, which is aluminum on both the top and bottom of the case, is $129. The white model should be slightly lighter than the black one.</p>
<figure><img title="Front view" alt="Front view" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013164/front-view-600x550.jpg?hash=LwN0LGWvAQ&upscale=1" height="550" width="600"></figure>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UIGQPScbVPo" height="315" width="560"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>See related:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/profolio-from-zagg-best-keyboard-case-for-the-ipad-7000012504/">Profolio+ from ZAGG review</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/clamcase-pro-review-turn-your-ipad-into-a-versatile-laptop-7000012167/">ClamCase Pro review</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/top-ipad-keyboards-2013-first-edition-7000010365/">Top iPad keyboards: 2013 first edition</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/story/edit/7000012167/Best%20keyboard/case%20combos%20for%20the%20iPad%2010%20Nexus%207%20apps%20for%20the%20writer%2010%20iPad%20apps%20for%20the%20writer%20The%20stealth%20smart%20cover%20technology%20in%20the%20Nexus%207%20It's%20not%20a%20race%20to%20the%20bottom%20for%20tablets,%20it's%20strictly%20an%20iPad%20market">New iPad and ZAGGfolio keyboard/case: Compact and fast</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/photos/best-keyboard-case-combos-for-the-new-ipad-3/6359267">Best keyboard/case combos for the iPad</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/10-nexus-7-apps-for-the-writer-7000002740/">10 Nexus 7 apps for the writer</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/10-ipad-apps-for-the-writer-7000002480/">10 iPad apps for the writer</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/the-stealth-smart-cover-technology-in-the-nexus-7-7000002057/">The stealth smart cover technology in the Nexus 7</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/its-not-a-race-to-the-bottom-for-tablets-its-strictly-an-ipad-market-7000001979/">It's not a race to the bottom for tablets, it's strictly an iPad market</a></strong></li>
</ul>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013187</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/apple-seeks-yet-another-new-trial-against-samsung-7000013187/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Apple seeks yet another new trial against Samsung]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[It's never going to end between the two tech giants.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:59:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-legal/">Legal</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-samsung/">Samsung</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple has asked to proceed with a new trial against Samsung in an attempt to scupper its rival from succeeding with an appeal.</p>
<figure class="alignRight"><img title="samsung_galaxy_s_2_270x306" alt="samsung_galaxy_s_2_270x306" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013187/samsunggalaxys2270x306-200x227.jpg?hash=ZwyvAQqyAQ&upscale=1" height="227" width="200"><figcaption>Credit: Samsung</figcaption></figure>
<p>The iPad and iPhone maker wishes to go ahead with a new trial on 14 Samsung products, as <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-27/apple-seeks-new-trial-over-appeal-in-samsung-patent-case.html">reported by Bloomberg</a>. After being granted $1.05 billion in damages, Apple's patent-infringement compensation was overturned by U.S. judge Lucy Koh, who quashed the jury's verdict and reduced the amount by $450.5 million.</p>
<p>The fracas in the San Jose court left the judge to suggest that the original damage award was based on a faulty understanding of the legal and patent issues involved, and that if the two firms weren't happy, they should try the appeals court.</p>
<p>Samsung has requested that the case be put on hold. Apple, in response, believes that an appeals court battle would "likely lead to a remand without a substantive decision."</p>
<p>As noted by <a href="http://www.fosspatents.com/2013/03/apple-alleges-85-million-error-in.html">FOSS Patents' Florian Mueller</a>, the vacation of such a large amount means that a new trial and new jury is required. Apple has also filed a motion to show that two products were sold within the period permissible for design infringement -- in contest to Koh's original findings.</p>
<p>Although the legal area and time allotment is slippery, if Apple's claims concerning the Samsung's Galaxy S II AT&amp;T and Infuse 4G are correct, this could add tens of millions to the original damages award, potentially reaching a total of $685 million, $85 million of which coming from the two additional smartphone models. The tech giant has requested that if&nbsp;Koh wants Samsung to go through the appeals process before a new trial takes place, the judge should consider reinstating this compensation.</p>
<p>Continual disputes over alleged patent infringement have taken place worldwide between the two rival smartphone and tablet makers. The most high-profile dispute fell largely in favor of Apple, which accused its South Korean rival of "slavishly" copying their devices. The trial was concluded after <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/new-trial-for-apple-v-samsung-possible-as-judge-slashes-damages-7000012039/">three days' deliberation</a> on August 24.</p>
<p >Apple Motion to Reconsider</a></p>
<p><iframe id="doc_31817" class="scribd_iframe_embed" src="http://www.scribd.com/embeds/132579545/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=scroll" height="600" width="100%" data-auto-height="false" data-aspect-ratio="undefined"></iframe></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013185</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/five-reasons-why-the-windows-desktop-isnt-going-away-7000013185/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Five reasons why the Windows desktop isn't going away]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The speculation on the next version of Windows (code-named Blue) is getting out of hand. Based on a few screenshots and one offhand remark from a prominent Windows blogger, one of my colleagues is convinced that the Windows desktop is an endangered species. Nope. Not gonna happen.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:38:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Ed Bott]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-windows-8/">Windows 8</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really didn’t want to write about Windows Blue this week.</p>
<p>For one thing,&nbsp;it’s the last day of my vacation. More importantly, there’s practically no actual information about Blue to write about. Microsoft is only talking in vague generalities. I’m not going to download bootleg software from questionable sources and try to reverse-engineer it, nor do I want to spend a lot of time staring at screen shots from people who are willing to do that.</p>
<figure><img title="new-windows-blue-snap" alt="new-windows-blue-snap" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013185/new-windows-blue-snap-560x420.jpg?hash=A2SzZmZ0Aw&upscale=1" height="420" width="560"></figure>
<p>But my ZDNet colleague Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols, who seems to write more about Windows 8 than any of the actual Microsoft experts here at ZDNet, has no such compunctions.</p>
<p>Vaughan-Nichols, on the thinnest possible evidence, is convinced that Microsoft is going to&nbsp;ditch the Windows desktop in the next major release of Windows. <a >“No Windows desktop mode!? No!”</a> he writes.</p>
<p>His post begins, “It comes as no surprise to anyone who reads my stories that I hate Windows 8's Metro interface…” Really? Well, at least we can give him some points for honesty.</p>
<p>No points for clear, factual analysis, though. Sorry.</p>
<p>I apologize that you had to read this nonsensical speculation&nbsp;on ZDNet. And even though I didn’t want to do this, I feel compelled to set the record straight.</p>
<p>No, Microsoft is not going to jettison the Windows desktop.&nbsp;Anyone who thinks that’s even remotely possible needs to just stop writing about Microsoft.</p>
<p>Let’s start at the beginning, shall we? Let's start with the “evidence.”</p>
<p>Paul Thurrott, of Windows Supersite fame,&nbsp;has now&nbsp;published two&nbsp;posts about the leaked Windows Blue build 9364.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://winsupersite.com/windows-8/windows-blue-leaks">first</a> is based on screenshots from a Polish tech blog.</p>
<p>Let me repeat that: An American blogger looked at screenshots of a leaked Windows alpha build published <em>in Polish</em> and wrote detailed captions for them, adding a few morsels of speculation.</p>
<p>Paul then downloaded a bootleg copy of the software from who knows where and did a <a href="http://winsupersite.com/windows-8/virtual-hands-windows-8-blue-build-9364">“quick run-through”</a> in a second blog post. In that post, as an aside, he writes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>More, but not all, of the settings in Control Panel have been ported to the Metro-based PC settings, yet another indication that the desktop environment is on the way out.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There. That’s the line that has my colleague&nbsp;so concerned about the future of Windows.</p>
<p>Of course, I am just a wee bit concerned that his concerns about the future of Windows are less than sincere. This is, after all, the same man who earlier this month wrote <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/five-reasons-why-windows-8-has-failed-7000012104/">Five reasons why Windows 8 has failed</a>, following in the footsteps&nbsp;of his&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/five-ways-to-skip-windows-8-7000001753/">Five ways to skip Windows 8</a>&nbsp;(July 2012) and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/five-ways-to-avoid-windows-8/11007">Five ways to avoid Windows 8</a>&nbsp;(May 2012) and <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/open-source/five-reasons-why-windows-8-will-be-dead-on-arrival/10275">Five Reasons why Windows 8 will be dead on arrival</a>&nbsp;(February 2012).</p>
<p>Hmmm. I detect a pattern here.</p>
<p>In the same&nbsp;spirit as those posts, let me lay out the five reasons why the Windows desktop is not going away.</p>
<p><strong>1. Four million desktop apps need to run somewhere. </strong>Back in 2010, at the International CES in Las Vegas, Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer noted that <a href="http://www.cnet.com/8301-31045_1-10426723-269.html">four million desktop programs run on Windows 7</a>. All of those programs run on Windows 8, too. Backward compatibility is the lifeblood of Windows. The idea that those legacy apps will be orphaned in a single release is ludicrous.</p>
<p><strong>2. Corporate customers and OEMs would&nbsp;mutiny.</strong>&nbsp;Corporate customers need to write custom apps that run on Windows. Those apps need to do things that aren’t possible in the highly constrained Windows 8 app model. And those corporate customers with their volume licenses pay billions of dollars in license fees to Microsoft every year for Windows. Say what you want about Steve Ballmer, but don’t try to tell me he’s going to willingly give up one of Microsoft’s most&nbsp;lucrative revenue streams. And if you think <em>that</em>, well, then you probably think Richard Stallman is next in line to be Chief Technical Officer of Microsoft.</p>
<p><strong>3.&nbsp;Refactoring old-fashioned dialog boxes&nbsp;into&nbsp;a more touch-friendly interface is an evolutionary step.</strong> The whole point of Windows 8 is to enable touch as a primary user input mechanism, alongside the mouse and keyboard. That makes it possible&nbsp;for Microsoft’s PC-building OEM partners to build hybrid devices that can&nbsp;smoothly shift&nbsp;from conventional PC to tablet and back again. (I <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/pcs-learn-new-tricks-but-can-tabletnotebook-hybrids-rescue-windows-8-7000012508/">looked at three such devices</a> just a few weeks ago.) In the first release of Windows 8, a limited selection of Control Panel functions were converted to the new modern/Metro UI. Did anyone not expect that the long-term goal was to move more and more of these functions to the modern UI?&nbsp;Yes, that means the old desktop Control Panel is being deprecated, and that Windows users will probably need to drop to the desktop less often in Blue. It doesn’t mean the desktop is vanishing.</p>
<p><strong>4. Removing the desktop would be more trouble than it’s worth.</strong> Many hundreds of thousands of words have been written about the complexity of Windows. Windows developers have spent years making the OS simpler, and more modular, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/bott/is-minwin-really-the-new-windows-7-kernel/418">with some success</a>. But ripping out the desktop completely is, if not impossible, at least highly unlikely. Maybe in a decade the need for the desktop will vanish. But that day won’t come this year or next.</p>
<p><strong>5. Microsoft already has a “no desktop” option: Windows RT.</strong> When Windows 8 shipped last October, Windows RT shipped right alongside it. Microsoft is committed to both platforms. One has the ability to run Windows desktop apps; the other doesn’t. Does anyone really believe that Microsoft would dump the OS that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-60-million-windows-8-licenses-sold-to-date-7000009549/">sold 60 million copies</a> in its first two months and put all its chips on the one that has sold perhaps a million or two copies in the same period? If so, I want to play poker with you.</p>
<p>As for the leaked build of Blue, all we&nbsp;have so far is a superficial analysis of some UI changes. We don’t know what’s new in the WinRT APIs. We don’t know what changes have been made to the storage subsystem or the security model or the kernel or any of the other crucial Windows internals. For that news, we’ll have to wait just a few months, for the just-announced Build 2013 conference.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I’m going to&nbsp;predict that&nbsp;bloggers who’ve been hating on Windows 8 and its radical new interface since the day it was announced are going to be dissatisfied with anything Microsoft does with the next version of Windows.</p>
<p>And now, if you'll excuse me, I'm going back to the beach.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013152</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/google-tax-gets-closer-in-germany-but-dont-expect-any-money-to-change-hands-7000013152/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA['Google tax' gets closer in Germany – but don't expect any money to change hands]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Although the so-called 'Google tax' has lost its most important features, it's on its way to becoming law, creating uncertainty for freelance journalists and business opportunities for lawyers. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:37:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Moritz Jaeger]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government/">Government</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-eu/">EU</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Germany's '<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/german-bundestag-votes-on-google-tax-7000011840/">Leistungsschutzrecht</a>' – an addendum to German copyright law that governs how aggregators can reuse media companies' content – last week cleared its second legislative hurdle and is now on its way to becoming law.</p>
<!-- Parsed pinbox:"10116898" -->
<div class="relatedContent alignRight"><h3>Read this</h3>
<div><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/german-bundestag-votes-on-google-tax-7000011840/" class="thumb"><img src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/011840/german-ruling-coalition-hastens-decision-over-google-tax-220x165.jpg?hash=AmyvAJL2Zz&upscale=1" alt="German Bundestag votes on 'Google Tax'" width="220" height="165" /></a></div><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/german-bundestag-votes-on-google-tax-7000011840/">German Bundestag votes on 'Google Tax'</a></p>
<ul class="alignRight"><li><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/german-bundestag-votes-on-google-tax-7000011840/">Read more</a></li></ul></div>
<p>The addendum passed Germany's upper house on Friday.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, the SPD, Germany's biggest opposition party and a former opponent of the Leistungsschutzrecht, didn't use its power to stop the highly controversial proposal. Instead, Peer Steinbrck, the party's challenger for the post of chancellor in Germany's upcoming general election, <a href="http://www.spd.de/aktuelles/93974/20130322_steinbrueck_zum_leistungsschutzrecht.html">is promising to "get rid of the broken law"</a> if he gets elected and the SPD gains the majority in parliament.&nbsp;</p>
<p>One of the reasons Steinbrck believes the Leistungsschutzrecht is broken has to do with the current version. Initially intended to protect media outlets and publishing houses against unlicensed use of their content, it developed into something nicknamed the 'Google tax'. It would have forced aggregators like Google News or Bing News to pay for using 'snippets' – short introduction texts that media companies use as teasers.</p>
<p>In the current version, this stipulation has been completely removed, allowing news aggregators to again use snippets and quotes for free, but any more than that and they may end up having to pay publishers. The downside: the law doesn't define the length of a snippet, a legal loophole that will have to be closed by lawyers.</p>
<h3>A victory for publishers?</h3>
<p>Despite more than a year of heated discussion, the law changes nothing for companies like Google or Microsoft – a clear win for the aggregators over the publishers. Germany's publishers, however, are trying to sell the new law as a win. According to the publishers' organisation <a href="http://www.vdz.de/medienpolitik-leistungsschutzrecht-singlenews/hash/1aadb8f8c2fb6a7aa49cfa2f362a3c14/news/xuid2840-verleger-begruessen-bundesratsbeschluss-zum-leistungsschutzrecht/">VDZ</a>, the law "acknowledges the accomplishments of publishing houses for the first time".</p>
<p>Freischreiber, an organisation that represents freelance journalists in Germany and an opponent of the Leistungsschutzrecht, sees the new law as a threat to freelancers. "It creates legal uncertainty for freelancers," the organisation says on its blog. For example, it is not yet clear how the law will influence secondary use of articles. Most freelance journalist sell articles more than once to make up for reduced budgets of publishing companies.</p>
<p>International media experts and venture capitalists have also criticised the new law. Media pundit Jeff Jarvis <a href="http://buzzmachine.com/2013/03/02/roll-over-gutenberg/">said</a>: "I am disappointed that the land of Gutenberg, the land that invented the ability to share knowledge and ideas at a mass scale and to empower speech is now haggling over the control and ownership of a few words. As they say in German, <em>schade</em>. What a shame." Albert Wenger of Union Square Ventures (whose investments include Twitter, Kickstarter and Tumblr) <a href="http://continuations.com/post/44301473713/leistungsschutzrecht-germanys-google-tax">writes</a> on his blog: "I agree that the LSR is the wrong approach because it is a blunt instrument that will have significant collateral damage."</p>
<p>The new law still needs to be signed by the German federal government and the German president, Joachim Gauck, to become a fully-fledged law. While it's still possible that the president will withhold his signature, it's highly unlikely in reality.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013159</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/u-s-government-outgunned-on-big-data-7000013159/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[U.S. government outgunned on big data]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Optimism abounds for big data's impact on federal government operations, but technical skills and knowhow are sorely lacking. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 10:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Larry Dignan]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government/">Government</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-us/">Government US</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Federal managers for the U.S. government are optimistic about what big data technology and analysis can do to revamp operations, but lack the skills and money to do much about it.</p>
<p>That's the gist of a report from a Government Business Council and Booz Allen Hamilton survey, which was based on 313 respondents in 27 agencies.</p>
<p>The findings are notable given one of the government's biggest jobs is to provide and analyze data for various reasons beyond operations. Among the key findings:</p>
<ul>
<li>18 percent of federal managers feel they are proficient in using big data.</li>
</ul>
<figure><img title="bigdatagov1" alt="bigdatagov1" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013159/bigdatagov1-493x471.png?hash=AwLjA2L1ZG&upscale=1" height="471" width="493"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Half of program managers say their agency could do more to capitalize on big data, but 47 percent noted that their groups don't have the technical skill.</li>
<li>A third of respondents said they had elementary proficiency in big data, but added that they have to rely on analysts primarily.</li>
</ul>
<figure><img title="bigdatagov2" alt="bigdatagov2" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013159/bigdatagov2-620x276.png?hash=AQL0AJSxZQ&upscale=1" height="276" width="620"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img title="bigdatagov3" alt="bigdatagov3" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013159/bigdatagov3-530x447.png?hash=ZQtkAmuuLG&upscale=1" height="447" width="530"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013182</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/the-connected-company-book-review-7000013182/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[The Connected Company: Book review]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Traditional hierarchically organised businesses are ill-suited to the modern reality of social media and connected customers. According to this book, companies need to become more flexible — like an adaptive biological system.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 09:44:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Mary Branscombe]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-reviews/">Reviews</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The business world is no longer predictable, with blindly loyal, isolated customers. Nowadays, customers can see what other people think and drop a product for the competition long before a traditional, hierarchical business can respond. The only way to compete, according to Dave Gray's view of the new business world, is to be a connected company organised in fractal, semi-autonomous 'pods' networked into a platform (a style of organisation known as a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holarchy">holarchy</a> rather than the usual top-down hierarchy) that's flexible enough to adapt quickly.</p>
<p><a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920023333.do">The Connected Company</a> starts with something no-one in business can have missed: the way the balance of power is shifting from the businesses who offer products to their customers, who have the advantage of networking and the ability to see far more information about their suppliers and the competitive options. From leaked internal memos to social media, bad news about a company is hard to keep private. So far, so familiar — but what can businesses do about it?</p>
<figure><img title="book-connected" alt="book-connected" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013182/book-connected-620x344.jpg?hash=BGN0AQWwZG&upscale=1" height="344" width="620"></figure>
<p>Don't try to put the genie back in the bottle, says Gray; build on the trends of connection, communication and customer comments to switch fundamental things like what your business does and how it works. He gathers examples from a range of industries and alternates them with business and organisation theory in a very readable way. It can sometimes feel overly simplistic, but also does a good job of covering a large topic without getting bogged down in the details, or assuming that readers are experts.</p>
<p>A look at changing economics points out that, thanks to technology and mass manufacturing, you don't have to be affluent to enjoy healthcare and travel beyond what the wealthiest could command in earlier eras. Ironically for businesses, those improvements in technology and manufacturing lead to saturated markets and lower margins — usage of 'material resources' started falling in the UK five years before the credit crunch, apparently. The result, Gray argues, is that businesses can only survive by switching to services and building relationships with those connected, complaining customers. For example, more people are moving into cities, which drives new services like <a href="https://www.onstar.com/web/portal/home">OnStar</a>, <a href="http://www.ford.com/technology/sync/">Ford Sync</a>, <a href="http://www.zipcar.com/">Zipcar</a> and <a href="https://www.uber.com/">Uber</a>'s on-demand, user-rated limo service.</p>
<p>The jury is still out on whether the business model for all these new services is as strong as the free publicity from the most vocal enthusiasts: Sync and OnStar sell more cars, but while Zipcar is doing well on Wall Street, membership is lower than you might think at 770,000 and Uber has faced regulatory hurdles in every city where it has launched. That doesn't undermine Gray's thesis, but it underlines that the transition to a service economy isn't going to be a completely smooth ride.</p>
<blockquote class="alignLeft">
<p>What with demanding customers and unpredictable, fragmented markets, businesses have to cope with a lot more variety — which is at odds with the usual drive to formalise and automate processes for efficiency.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How do you make a successful service for connected customers? As Gray points out, most customer service hardly deserves the name — although he optimistically sees this as room for improvement. Where, when and how you deliver a service matters, in Gray's view, more than the product itself. What we really want, he believes, are the services that are the end result — the messages rather than the smartphone you send them from, for example. To avoid making customers feel exploited, having to shell out for both the product and the service, those services need to be convenient — for the customer rather than the business.</p>
<p>What with demanding customers and unpredictable, fragmented markets, businesses have to cope with a lot more variety — which is at odds with the usual drive to formalise and automate processes for efficiency. In truth, most of what employees at the average business have to deal with are the exceptions — the pesky customers disrupting the perfect one-way stream of smoothly optimised processes. Having the customer service representative stay on the line while you are transferred to the person who can solve your problem might sound like an expensive solution — but it's probably cheaper than negative publicity and lost customers.</p>
<p>The Connected Company isn't a traditional book, so much as a set of linked essays or lectures. The table of contents is actually a thorough overview that sums up each chapter — at a pinch, you could read that and dip into the most interesting areas. Each chapter opens with another summary and closes with a list of sources and further reading. In between, information is packed into images, lists and bite-sized chunks of facts and analysis that keep the thesis moving swiftly, but also feel too short and leave you wanting analysis (and some nuggets of information strike the author so forcibly that he repeats them in later chapters).</p>
<p>Where this book works best is when it gets the balance of examples from businesses and analysis of trends and issues right. "Your most unhappy customers are your greatest source of learning" reads the quote from Bill Gates that opens the chapter on how companies lose touch (although Microsoft isn't covered in the mini-biographies of the fall and occasional rise of former greats). The stories of Xerox and Starbucks are well known. More interesting are the lesser-known details of how IBM reinvented itself by changing company culture to actually listen to customers, and how Kodak threw away the opportunity to get a 20-year head-start on the digital camera market after an engineer created a prototype using a Super-8 lens to record onto cassette tape that you could play back on TV.</p>
<blockquote class="alignRight">
<p>Gray gives a swift but thorough overview of modern business theory on alternative ways to structure a business as networked units — less like a machine, more like an adaptive biological system.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some examples explain things that seem puzzling but make perfect sense when explained. Amazon bought Zappos despite utterly different approaches — Amazon views customer contact as a sign that it has failed to build its system correctly, while Zappos views it as an opportunity to discover more about the customer and puts a free phone number on every page of its website. But because behind the scenes they both rely on extermely efficient logistics, they can get economies of scale by combining their warehouses and delivery systems.</p>
<p>Sometimes the examples are just too short and shallow to really tell you anything; they're also unflaggingly and uncritically positive, and feel more like marketing (see the description of Google's 20 percent time). The explanations of using customer feedback, through techniques like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_Promoter">net promoter</a> scores, are more useful — connecting systems so your customers don't have to care how you run your business (which allowed Wells Fargo to launch the first online US banking system in just 60 days) and organising your company like the interdependent but unplanned services available in a city.</p>
<p>Gray gives a swift but thorough overview of modern business theory on alternative ways to structure a business as networked units — less like a machine, more like an adaptive biological system. If that feels a little futuristic for the average business, it's worth remembering that the transformation to the fractal, holarchic, podular connected company is a hard one — and the single chapter analysing problems and failures doesn't cover nearly enough ground.</p>
<p>The final chapter on how to put the book's lessons into action is also too short, and perhaps the most depressingly realistic: if you're not in charge of the company and you can't get into a project that runs outside the stifling hierarchy and bureaucracy that's dragging the business down, try to start grassroots networking that will at least reveal the limitations of the current setup. But it's a sign of a good book on an interesting topic that it leaves you wanting more.<br><br></p>
<p><em>The Connected Company</em><br> By Dave Gray (with Thomas Vander Wal)<br> <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920023333.do">O'Reilly Media</a><br>304 pages<br>ISBN: 1-4493-1905-X <br>18.99 / $24.99</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013157</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/windows-8-moved-the-cheese-windows-blue-doesnt-put-it-back-7000013157/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Windows 8 moved the cheese, Windows Blue doesn't put it back]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[People don't like change. Unless Microsoft can start to understand that, Windows 8 and Windows Blue may never get traction in the consumer market...]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 09:06:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Matt Baxter-Reynolds]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="Shropshire_blue_cheese" alt="Shropshire_blue_cheese" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013157/shropshirebluecheese-200x150.jpg?hash=AQL4ZmtmAQ&upscale=1" height="150" width="200"><figcaption>Some blue cheese. (Blue -- geddit?)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Now that Windows Blue looks like it's leaked, we know one thing -- the Start button isn't coming back.</p>
<p>Were you surprised that it's staying away? I guess I was a little bit -- or rather I was hoping that the Softies might had had an, um, softening on the position of the Start button.</p>
<p><strong>Read:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.zdnet.com/start8-and-modernmix-windows-8s-last-best-hope-for-normality-on-the-desktop-7000012471/">Start8 and ModernMix -- Windows 8's last, best hope for normality on the desktop</a>.</strong></p>
<p>I am, to be honest, a bit fed up with talking about Start button and I'm sure you are too. But for me it's taken a meaning greater than just something to do with the user interface. It's become symbolic of a problem that Microsoft doesn't seem to understand -- enterprises and consumers experience software procurement in very different ways.</p>
<p>And that's a problem...</p>
<h4 id="enterprise">Ribbon</h4>
<p>Imagine it's 2007 and you're the CTO of a company with 1,000 users. A member of your staff has presented you with a business case to move to Office 2007. You know the toolbar is going away and being replaced with the ribbon.</p>
<p>You also know that users aren't going to like the change, but you're doing things sensibly -- you have a training plan in place, the helpdesk is geared up to support the shift.</p>
<p>You sign the PO, and you ask your staff to rollout Office 2007 with its new ribbon interface.</p>
<p>When you're in this position, you've irritated and caused some discomfort to a 1,000 of your users. Human beings, as we know, don't like change and you've just made change happen. You're in a few a few weeks of flak. If you're not being entirely mature about it, that's a good period to schedule a vacation, or a few early afternoons out playing golf, or a more rigourous policy with regards to keep your office door shut.</p>
<p>What's happened here is that you've "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Who_Moved_My_Cheese%3F">moved the cheese</a>". People are used to seeing and using toolbars -- after the upgrade those toolbars have gone away and been replaced. The result? Cross users reacting angrily to imposed change.</p>
<p>But, given time, everything eventually goes back to normal. People in enterprises use the tools they're given and tend to adapt to change reasonably smoothly. Part of this is -- I'm afraid -- because people don't care. If you roll out Dynamics CRM, for instance, you're hardly likely to get picketed by a cohort of users that demand you also roll out Salesforce.</p>
<p>Put simply, people get used to the new place where the cheese is kept.</p>
<p>Importantly, If the users are irritated at anyone, the irritation will be focused on the IT team who've mucked everything up, not on the Microsoft's engineers who developed the new ribbon.</p>
<p>More importantly, those users don't have any real power over whether to continue to buy Microsoft software or not. It remains the CTOs decision.</p>
<h4 id="start">Start</h4>
<p>Over in Consumerland, the situation is very different.</p>
<p>Technologists rarely seem to understand is that non-technologists feel entirely differently about technology than they do. A technologist tends to feel about computer systems under their control as if they are tools. They understand those tools, they have relationships with them, they know how they work. If they are broken, they can fix them.</p>
<p>A non-technologist doesn't see a computer as a tool in the same way. If a non-technologist computer "breaks" (and this can be anything from an actual breakdown to a window being one size one day and smaller the next), that user will get stuck. We've all seen perfectly competent users totally bamboozled by what seems to us to be the most simple thing.</p>
<p>Windows 8 is so wholly different to Windows 7 that, to a non-technologist, it doesn't feel like improvement, enhancement, or evolution. The only thing that it feels is&nbsp;<em>broken</em>.</p>
<p>And because the user has done this to themselves -- i.e. the change is self-inflicted coupled with the fact don't have any support to fall back on, rather than adapting to the change smoothly as they would in an "use this at work because your boss says you have to", they simply get irritated and upset with the fate that's befallen them.</p>
<p>To a non-technologist, Windows 8 moves the cheese so far it might as well be stapled to the side of Voyager 1 as it hurtles out into deep space. A typical non-technologist user has <a href="http://what-if.xkcd.com/38/">virtually no chance of retreiving the cheese</a>.</p>
<h4 id="cheese">Cheese</h4>
<p>Microsoft are used to in the enterprise space being able to move the cheese because they are dealing, generally, with a customer base that is made up mostly of technologists, and moreover those technologists are usually acting rationally basing decisions on business cases that have to be scrutinised before they are signed of.</p>
<p>A CTO will not make a judgement whether to roll out a new CRM on Oracle or SQL Server without knowing what those words actually mean.</p>
<p>In Consumerland, moving the cheese results in one of two things -- either irritated customers who are annoyed with you yet who continue to be your customers, or irritated customers who are annoyed with you and who subsequently stop being your customers.</p>
<p>This is the thing that worries me most about Microsoft's strategy at the moment -- do they actually understand that moving the cheese of a non-technologist consumer isn't a good idea?</p>
<p>Because it seems to me that they know in the enterprise space moving the cheese around appears to be a very good idea. This strategy of cheese translocation seems to have worked out very well for them for the past 20 years. It's the ability to be brave around change that's got them to a point where they have a stable of world-beating products.</p>
<p>That thing Microsoft does where it "takes three versions to get it right" is not accidental. The process is designed like that, and it's all about careful execution of change. They move the cheese around into the correct final position in full view within the market itself as opposed to delivering it to the market in the right place first time round.</p>
<p>But, that's strategy is just plain stupid in the consumer market because all you do is process customers turning them from neutral-slash-positive into "angry". How hard is to to convince someone who thinks "I bought Windows 8 and I hated it!" into buying a Mac? It's a great deal easier than someone who thinks "I like my Windows 7 laptop!"</p>
<p>I've been trying to think of examples of non-technology brands that because like this in the consumer space. The only one that I can think of, which I fear shows a certain lack of imagination, is&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Coke">New Coke</a>&nbsp;-- and we all know how that ended.</p>
<p>Reintroducing the Start menu to Windows Blue would reduce some of the distance that the cheese has moved for non-technologists coming to the operating system from Windows 7. But that cuts both ways -- Microsoft can't do that without a tacit admission that Windows 8 is in fact a sister operating system of Windows Vista. That would hurt their stock price, and nullify any of the Windows 8 marketing spend incurred thus far.</p>
<p>We all know that's not going to happen.</p>
<p>What I really need to see from Microsoft is some kind of evidence that they know that over in Consumerland, if you want to move the cheese, it has to be done carefully.</p>
<p>People do not like change.</p>
<p><strong><em>What do you think? Post a comment, or talk to me on Twitter:&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/mbrit/">@mbrit</a>.</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Image credit: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Shropshire_blue_cheese.jpg">Wikimedia</a></em></p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013180</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/ericsson-in-talks-with-microsoft-to-buy-television-streaming-software-7000013180/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Ericsson in talks with Microsoft to buy television streaming software]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[According to reports, Ericsson is in talks with Microsoft to buy Microsoft's IPTV business. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 09:02:10 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Charlie Osborne]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tech-industry/">Tech Industry</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure class="alignRight"><img title="ericcsonlogo" alt="ericcsonlogo" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013180/ericcsonlogo-200x150.jpg?hash=BTR1ZwtmZw&upscale=1" height="150" width="200"></figure>
<p>Ericsson is in talks with Microsoft to purchase the firm's IPTV business, which makes software to deliver television across the Internet.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-27/ericsson-said-to-discuss-buying-tv-software-unit-from-microsoft.html">According to Bloomberg</a>, people with knowledge of the matter said that a transaction could be announced as soon as in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>Microsoft's IPTV business provides software used by firms including AT&amp;T, CenturyLink, Deutsche Telekom and Vodafone to provide online streaming. Also known as Microsoft's MediaRoom, the platform provides access to both on-demand and live television content over a two-way IP network, and can provide entertainment services and applications for television sets, PCs and mobile devices.</p>
<p>This could be a <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/microsoft/microsofts-mediaroom-2-0-iptv-platform-a-codename-update/10531">strategic shift</a> for the tech giant, which may plan to focus on offering television services through the popular XBox console. In addition, as Ericsson is looking towards mobile technology software rather than hardware -- now it is up against heavyweights including Apple and Samsung -- such service platforms could provide a good market niche for the handset maker.</p>
<p>Colin Dixon, chief analyst of nScreenMedia, told the publication:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"MediaRoom has gone from being a centerpiece of Microsoft’s TV strategy to a kind of sideshow."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Recently, Ericsson and STMicro <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/st-ericsson-venture-broken-1600-jobs-axed-7000012733/">announced</a> that they planned to wind down the joint venture ST-Ericsson after failing to find a buyer for the unprofitable project. Ericsson will be taking on the design, development and sales of LTE products, keeping 1,800 staff and contractors mainly based in Sweden, Germany, India and China. However, the business decision also means that 1,600 employees will be given their marching orders.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013080</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/aegis-padlock-3-0-portable-hdd-offers-real-time-encryption-7000013080/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Aegis Padlock 3.0 portable HDD offers real-time encryption]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Though slightly bulky, the Aegis Padlock 3.0 offers peace of mind with its real-time encryption, which means users do not have to sit through a data encryption process.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:23:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Paul Mah]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-data-management/">Data Management</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-hardware/">Hardware</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="Aegis PadLock 3.0" alt="Aegis PadLock 3.0" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013080/aegispadlock1-620x465.jpg?hash=MTSuLwR0Az&upscale=1" height="465" width="620"><figcaption>Aegis PadLock 3.0</figcaption></figure>
<p>I wrote previously about how <a >unprotected USB flash drives</a> or portable hard disk drives (HDD) could lead to data loss if they were misplaced or stolen. Though free software encryption offerings exist, they can be unintuitive and offer users the option to skip the data encryption process when rushing for time.</p>
<p>This means that businesses serious about data protection will want to use storage devices with built-in hardware encryption, which unfortunately is still not commonly found on shop shelves in Singapore. As such, my interest was piqued when a unit of the <a href="http://www.apricorn.com/products/hardware-encrypted-drives/apricorn-padlock-usb3.html" target="_blank">Apricorn Aegis PadLock 3.0</a> with 256-bit AES encryption crossed my desk.</p>
<p>Assembled by Apricorn at its facilities in the United States, the Aegis PadLock comes with a software-free design. What that means is that data is automatically encrypted as it is copied onto the Aegis PadLock without having to install any software utilities. A number pad with rubberized buttons fronts the slightly bulky device for authentication that is independent of one's operating system.</p>
<p>Using it was a no-brainer that involves plugging it into a free USB port using the attached cable. When the sole LED indicator blinks red to indicate that the device is powered on, key in the PIN code (up to 10 digits) and click on the "Unlock" key. If the PIN is correct, the LED light will flash briefly before turning a solid green--my Windows laptop reports a new USB drive being plugged in at this stage. Unplugging it or clicking on the "Cancel" button immediately locks the drive up.</p>
<p>In my tests, I attempted to key in the wrong password repeatedly. The device stopped accepting my input after a few wrong entries, forcing me to unplug and reconnect the device to continue trying. Note that repeated mistakes will lock up the device, culminating in the permanent loss of onboard data when the <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/security/new-gpcode-ransomware-encrypts-files-demands-125-for-decryption/8505" target="_self">decryption</a> key stored in the Aegis PadLock is erased.</p>
<p>Personally, I didn't like the complicated button combinations needed when attempting to change the password, or when resetting the device back to factory default. The indicator light certainly helped, though you will need to have the instruction manual open in order to configure it. Of course, configuring the password should be a one-time process for most users, and is probably a tolerable hassle for the peace of mind.</p>
<p>As I mentioned in my earlier post, storage devices with built-in hardware encryption do cost more. In this case, the Aegis Padlock 3.0 with its fast USB 3.0 interface and 256-bit AES encryption costs US$179 for a 250GB model, going up to US$289 for 1.5TB.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013169</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/in/how-much-should-startup-founders-earn-7000013169/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[How much should startup founders earn?]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[What kind of salary should founders of startups pay themselves? Here are some factors to help determine the magic number and why this matters.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:01:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Srinivas Kulkarni]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-it-employment/">IT Employment</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How much should founders of startups&nbsp;earn?</p>
<p>A question that has no specific answer, don't you think? It's a subjective question and more often than not, the answer would vary depending on what stage the startup is at, what <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/5-tips-to-attract-startup-funding-2062304707/" target="_self">funding</a> or the kind of investments made, and the kind of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/startup-valuations-need-to-be-realistic-2062304667/" target="_self">valuation</a> a company has.</p>
<p>Depending on the lifecycle of the startup, a founder should plan and choose to pay himself a salary in accordance to his needs versus how much the startup can afford to spend. And considering it's his own business, he should look at what he can do away with in profits versus how much overheads he wants to incur. In a recent <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130322131654-7979133-how-much-should-a-startup-founder-pay-himself?_mSplash=1&amp;sessionid=jthHg6y81HGkoEFcAvyQ" target="_blank">article I read by Bob Dorf</a>, co-author of The Startup Owner's Manual, he says genuine entrepreneurs have a simple formula. They get whatever's left in the bank after everyone's been paid.</p>
<p>It got me thinking. Gosh, entrepreneurship isn't a joke. Certainly we've heard of founders who've gone without salary for more than a year, used up their savings, lived out of cars, used co-working spaces, started up from coffee shops and taken up another job while coding their way to build that next revolutionary product. But yes, once you are funded, we might think founders should pay themselves a good salary. Right?</p>
<p>Not really as easy as you think. Another question also is whether your product is going to be generating revenue right from the get-go, or if you already have clients onboard who are able to cover your costs for development, design, and other resources.</p>
<p>Vijay Singh, CEO and managing director of Aaramshop, told me in an e-mail interview: "At initial stages, the founders need to support the organization by way of minimal withdrawals for self. However, as the company matures and becomes sustainable, it is important that the founders [peg] their remuneration to the market."</p>
<p>Well, it's all a juggling act if you ask me. Of course, being a founder, you certainly have a chunk in the equity, but it doesn't pay your ongoing bills and especially if you are married or have obligations you have to fulfill. Of course, though, that's something founders already know they&nbsp;signed up for when they decided to be an entrepreneur.</p>
<p>So, is it essential for founders to have a decent salary or should they still adopt the frugal way until the startup makes some decent progress? Do founders have to, and I mean <em>have to</em> cut their personal salaries while they keep paying their linchpins the desired salary for a startup to be really successful?</p>
<p>In a <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2008/09/08/peter-thiel-best-predictor-of-startup-success-is-low-ceo-pay/" target="_blank">2008 report by TechCrunch</a>, PayPal co-founder and venture capitalist, Peter Thiel, once mentioned that one of the things he looks for before investing in a company is how much salary is the CEO taking. The lower the salary for CEOs, the better it is for a startup to succeed, he said.</p>
<p>Investors certainly would be amused looking at business plans with luxurious salaries for CEOs, but at the same time a question I'd like to ask is: "Is this a trivial question or something that makes fundamental sense and something that should be given utmost important when startups seek out funding?"</p>
<p>From an investors perspective, Mike Lebus, co-founder of Angel Investment Network, said to me in an e-mail: "Startup founders have enough to deal with without having to worry about their personal finances too, so their salary should be big enough to allow them to focus completely on building the company. If the founders are worried about whether they're going to be able to pay the rent, ultimately the startup will suffer. However, they also need to realize that their salary should be pretty modest until the company starts to become successful."</p>
<h3><strong>Factors that decide founder salaries</strong></h3>
<ol>
<li>Whether the founder has personal obligations, say, debt, mortgage, kids, or if he's single or married.</li>
<li>The percentage of equity ownership is something that will keep changing and can make a difference to &nbsp;salaries.</li>
<li>The amount of financing or seed funding and investment that happens at different stages. There are cases where founders would hike their salaries after their different rounds of funding.&nbsp;</li>
<li>It's always a good idea to survive on minimum salaries for longer periods, but at the same time, a balance should be maintained so that there is no distraction from the founders' personal obligations and there is adequate motivation for the founders to work better for the company.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Some suggest &nbsp;if there is a financial crunch, try and get yourself another job to cover those expenses, especially if you haven't launched yet. While this is a good idea, it also acts as a distraction to your startup. I'd say if you have the resources, pay yourself a little more and maybe recover that cost from your own startup later.&nbsp;</li>
<li>It's always important that you pay yourself what's needed. Nothing less or nothing more. You always have the equity and your performance to drive your team, and that would help you determine your salary at every stage of the startup.&nbsp;</li>
<li>Another important aspect is how you incentivize yourself at different stages of a startup, especially to drive your motivation levels as an entrepreneur.</li>
</ol>
<p>This topic is certainly a much talked-about issue in the startup community and many have different views about this.&nbsp;What's important at the end of the day is how the translation of those funds happens in terms of measurable success, at any given stage of the startup.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000012660</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/uk/i-need-a-life-scrobbler-7000012660/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[I Need a Life Scrobbler]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Advertisers should learn how to ‘scrobble’, or guess what we’ll be interested in based on what we already like. It works for Last.fm. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 06:00:00 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Diarmuid Mallon]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m a big music fan. A few days ago, someone asked me about listening to music online and asked which service was best. I ran through the pros and cons of all the different ones I’ve tried (Spotify, Pandora, etc.), and concluded that my favourite is <a href="http://www.last.fm">Last.fm</a>. Not because it’s 'better' in terms of the range of music, but because it <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Last.fm#Audioscrobbler_plugin">scrobbles</a>, which means that it figures out what I’ll like by evaluating what I already listen to.</p>
<p>Rather than me having to tell Last.fm what I want to hear, Last.fm just delivers it to me. I don’t even have to think about it.</p>
<p>Here’s how it works. Last.fm’s ‘Audioscrobbler’ plugin logs any music I listen to on my iPod, on my iPhone, on the Last.fm website, on my Logitech Boombox, and even my Apple TV at home. Last.fm uses what I listen to most to make really great recommendations for other bands and musicians I might like.</p>
<p>It also breaks out to the real world, so it tells me when my favourite acts are in town. I can even tell it which concerts I go to—so then it really, really knows what I like.&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img title="Album cloud picture" alt="Album cloud picture" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/012660/albumclouddiarmuidmallonoverall-v2-156x283.png?hash=ZJL1ZGOxAQ&upscale=1" height="283" width="156"></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For example, when I went to SXSW last year, I was faced with daunting task of working out which of the 1,630+ acts I would try to catch. Mercifully, Last.fm brought the list down to a more manageable 196 acts by working out which ones I’d be most interested in. I didn’t see everything on the list, which updated itself regularly as the schedule grew, but I tried. (It took two weeks to recover all the lost sleep and heal the blisters I got from racing around Austin.)</p>
<p>At the same time, I've signed up for a ‘daily deal’ service. But, it knows nothing about me, so the deals are mainly of no interest to me. They’re for things I don’t need or like, or for restaurants and stores too far away.</p>
<p>So rather than asking what I like, my postcode, age, hobbies, etc. it would be so much better if there’s some way they can scrobble my life, then I might finally get some deals that I can use.</p>
<p>Because what people actually do—rather than what they say they do—is what retailers, brands and advertisers are really after. Asking preferences gives insight. Understanding what we actually do is how you truly get to know your customer.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013172</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/in/indias-mobile-vas-market-set-to-hit-9-5b-by-2015-7000013172/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[India’s mobile VAS market set to hit $9.5B by 2015]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[There is pent up demand for sophisticated mobile services in application areas such as m-education, m-entertainment, m-finance and m-health, says a report by Wipro and IAMAI.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 05:54:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Swati Prasad]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-mobility/">Mobility</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Indian mobile value added services (MVAS) market is estimated to expand at a compound annual growth rate of 25 percent between 2012 and 2015--reaching US$9.5 billion in 2015, from an estimated US$4.9 billion in 2012.</p>
<p>This was one of the key findings of a research report titled "Future Thought of Business (FTOB): MVAS", released Tuesday by Wipro Technologies (the global IT, consulting and outsourcing business of Wipro) and the Internet and Mobile Association of India (IAMAI).</p>
<p>A similar study conducted last year by management consulting firm Zinnov had said Indian MVAS market was expected to move from the traditional SMS-based services to Internet-based and application-based services. As per the Zinnov study, the Indian MVAS industry is estimated at over US$5 billion and is expected to reach well over US$6 billion by 2013.</p>
<p>Wipro and IAMAI conducted research on over 450 consumers and providers of MVAS in India to identify the major drivers and barriers of the Indian MVAS market and provide insights that will help grow this market. The research found that there is pent up demand from consumers for sophisticated mobile services in India in application areas such as <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/bharti-airtel-launches-mobile-education-services-7000009315/" target="_self">m-education</a>, m-entertainment, m-finance and m-health.</p>
<p>Basic informational mobile services are set to decline in India, said Ayan Mukerji, senior vice president and global head of media and telecom at Wipro Technologies, in a statement.</p>
<p>"We have found that consumers in India will increasingly purchase enriched and transformational education, health, finance and entertainment services. An expected MVAS revolution in India is being made possible by the dramatic growth in mobile device penetration and mobile network capacity and this market offers abundant opportunities for growth to all industry participants," Mukerji added.</p>
<p>To realize the market's full potential, the industry requires a collaborative effort across mobile network operators, telecom equipment vendors and mobile service content providers, the report said.</p>
<p>So far, this market has been hampered by lack of innovation," said Subho Ray, president, IAMAI.</p>
<p>"By forging mutually agreeable partnerships, we can improve customization and localization of content and create services with a compelling consumer value proposition. The Indian MVAS market offers tremendous potential to all industry participants and those companies that can offer innovative services will stand to benefit the most," Ray added.</p>
<p>The report has identified the following opportunities for players in the Indian MVAS market:</p>
<ol>
<li>Domestic mobile operators could focus on providing better network and connectivity.</li>
<li>Global operators could increase their base by testing new VAS offerings in the Indian market.</li>
<li>Content and VAS technology could focus on the consumer experience and developing personalized content.</li>
<li>Original equipment manufacturers could innovate with low-cost smartphones and mobile devices to drive penetration</li>
</ol>
<p>The research findings reveal that <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/blog/igeneration/teenagers-mobile-gaming-apps-and-data-greed-infographic/15694" target="_self">m-entertainment</a> is the largest contributor to operator MVAS revenues and provides key opportunities in vernacular content, on-demand music and video content and live TV shows and events.&nbsp;</p>
<p>On the other hand, m-education can play a key role in expanding the reach and quality of education in India, through interactive English language learning services, competitive examination preparation solutions, tutor-on-call and vocational training.</p>
<p>Similarly, m-health has the potential to improve healthcare access and affordability in India especially through remote diagnostics, chronic disease management and maternal care.</p>
<p>Mobile phones will also play a key role in extending financial services to the unbanked population of India, estimated at 40 percent of the total. <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/prepaid-mobile-payments-unlock-poors-buying-power-2062304029/" target="_self">Mobile-finance</a> can contribute to revenues through mobile wallet services, mobile remittance services and business correspondence model based services, the report said.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013135</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/in/india-sets-march-31-deadline-for-aakash-2-delivery-7000013135/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[India sets March 31 deadline for Aakash 2 delivery]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Indian government is threatening to bring a halt to the country's low-cost tablet initiative if the delivery target of 100,000 isn't met by the end of the month. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 04:17:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Nitin Puri]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-android/">Android</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-government-asia/">Government Asia</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-india/">India</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-tech-industry/">Tech Industry</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><a href="http://ibnlive.in.com/news/lowcost-aakash-2-tablet-launched-in-india-at-rs-1130/305082-11.html" target="_blank"><img title="Aakash 2 Tablet" alt="Aakash 2 Tablet" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013135/aakash2-620x413.jpg?hash=A2D4AQp2Aw&upscale=1" height="413" width="620"></a><figcaption>Aakash 2 Tablet</figcaption></figure>
<p>India's Aakash 2&nbsp;project is facing a multitude of issues including&nbsp;manufacturing&nbsp;delays, a faulty processor, and low memory. These have prompted the country's new human resource and development minister, Pallam Raju, to announce the decision to shut down the initiative if it fails to meet the target of delivering 100,000 Aakash 2 tablets by March 31.</p>
<p>The Aakash project was envisioned to be a low-cost alternative to the Apple iPad and designed for the masses, <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/in/india-govt-to-foster-app-ecosystem-for-aakash-tablet-7000009371/">specifically students</a>, and change the way Indian students learned. However, when the Aakash tablet was launched by Kapil Sibal, it turned out to be a lemon. The 1,903 rupees (US$35) device has <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/indias-35-tablet-project-hits-snag-2062303971/">failed to meet expectations</a> and the Indian government finally conceded a failure in production.</p>
<p>I had placed an order for the Aakash tablet last year but delivery was delayed twice, resulting in a 3-month delay. Once it finally arrived, I was excited and thrilled to finally have my own Aakash tablet. However, basic setup with a 3G SIM itself took longer than expected.</p>
<p>When it finally worked, the required registration with DataWind was when reality struck that I really got what I paid for. Not only was the touchscreen non-responsive more than half of the time, the speed of the Aakash tablet was extremely slow. Considering how I went out of the way to obtain and register a 3G SIM just for the Aakash tablet, I was left with the feeling that it simply wasn't worth the time, effort, and money I had put into this. Since I got it, I've only used my Aakash tablet a few times, and now, it's been packed away in its original box and packaging.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.domain-b.com/infotech/itnews/20130325_Datawind.html" target="_blank">As it currently stands</a>, only 17,000 Aakash 2 tablets have been delivered. The contracted vendor, Datawind, said 29,400 units were in transit, and another 23,500 units were pending delivery to IIT Bombay. This is considerably lower than the original target of 100,000 units to be delivered by March 31. The projected cost for the original Aakash tablet&nbsp;was 1,903 rupees (US$35), but the final launch price of the Aakash 2 tablet is almost double this figure.&nbsp;</p>
<p>DataWind said it was making all efforts to deliver as many of its second-generation Aakash 2 tablets devices by March 31, according to a status report on delivery released by the&nbsp;Canadian manufacturer. The company said the delay was caused by the verifications process that customs needed to conduct on the exemption certificates for certain components issued by IIT Bombay. Of the remaining 30,000 units, a final assembly is expected within the next couple of weeks and all efforts are being made to deliver as many as possible by 31 March, the vendor said.</p>
<p>Clearly, DataWind won't be able to achieve the target of 100,000 units by March 31 if the remaining 30,000 Aakash 2 tablets are to be assembled only after the deadline. Could this really be the demise of the entire Aakash project, as stated by the Indian government?</p>
<p>In my opinion, realistically, it's the not demise but just the beginning. Here's why: in addition to orders from the general public, some of which have already been delivered, the Indian government has their own order of Aakash 2 tablets which have been paid for, and are pending delivery.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the government has plans to distribute the Aakash 2 tablets to students, and canceling the Aakash project ultimately would result in students suffering the most. In addition, this would be bad PR with India's federal elections just around the corner.&nbsp;</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013167</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/addappt-1-3-is-an-ios-group-messaging-powerhouse-7000013167/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Addappt 1.3 is an iOS group messaging powerhouse]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[My favorite business contacts app is now available without an invitation code, and it allows you to send messages and photos to groups via email or text. ]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 04:02:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Jason D. O'Grady]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-apps/">Apps</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-ios/">iOS</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-iphone/">iPhone</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I wrote about <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/tempo-for-ios-is-the-best-business-calendar-app-7000013116/">Tempo</a>, a replacement for Apple's Calendar app on iOS. Today, I want to continue that theme with a replacement for Apple's Contacts app. </p>
<figure><img title="Addappt 1.3 is an iOS group messaging powerhouse - Jason O'Grady" alt="Addappt 1.3 is an iOS group messaging powerhouse - Jason O'Grady" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013167/screen-shot-2013-03-26-at-11-47-10-pm-600x628.png?hash=BGWzZGOxLG&upscale=1" height="628" width="600"><figcaption>(Image: Addappt)</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="http://www.addappt.com">Addappt</a> (free, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/addappt/id526181666" target="_blank">App Store</a>) is a contact management app for iOS that's always up to date because it's maintained by your friends and colleagues. It's an amazing app (and one of my <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/ogradys-best-ios-apps-of-2012_p13-7000008989/" target="_blank">iOS picks of 2012</a>) that allows you to keep your contacts current, and now it allows you to share in ways that you can't with the Apple's native iOS apps. </p>
<p>When you install it, Addappt scans your contacts and tells you if any of your contacts are using it. Then you can invite the contacts that you want to keep up-to-date information on. It's completely opt-in, so the recipient needs to confirm your request and verify their email address. </p>
<p>If someone's not already in your imported contacts, you can just add their email address and tap invite. The person will receive an email invitation asking them to join Addappt. If they accept and install the app, you'll be linked to them and their contact information will get updated any time they make a change. And vice-versa.</p>
<p>Addappt was just updated to version 1.3 and is now open to all, and dropping the invitation-only model will make it easier to get your colleagues to use it. </p>
<p>Other new features are outlined below.</p>
<h3>Group management</h3>
<p>The iOS Contacts app doesn't allow you to create groups, Addappt does. Just touch the pencil icon on the right of "My Groups" on the home screen. Addappt allows you to create a new group, delete one, or rename one — and changes are synced with the iOS contacts app. Adding contacts to a group is easy, too. Just navigate to the individual contact and touch the "group +" icon on the left of the name on the photo and select the groups you want to add to.</p>
<h3>Group messaging</h3>
<p>Addappt makes it easy to email or text a group of colleagues. With it, you can communicate with a group of contacts with a single touch. You can also attach multiple photos and send them to a group. If you don't like sharing photos on social networks, Addappt makes it easier to share photos, especially with people who aren't on Facebook.</p>
<p>The iOS Photos app limits sharing to five photos by email. If you individually attach them, there are no limitations but it takes 60 touches to attach 10 photos — not to mention the number of touches needed to add multiple contacts to send them to. With Addappt, you can attach 10 photos in 14 touches and you can share an album of 10 photos with only five touches. And sharing isn't limited to other Addappt users. It uses the native iOS Email and Messages apps, so you can email, text, or share photos with anyone.</p>
<p>Here's a <a href="http://video.foxbusiness.com/v/2245927528001/new-app-helps-keep-iphone-contacts-updated/?playlist_id=933116634001" target="_blank">video</a> of Addappt CEO Mrinal Desai being interviewed on Fox Business Network.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013161</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/google-chrome-takes-spell-checking-into-the-cloud-7000013161/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Google Chrome takes spell checking into the cloud]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[The latest release of Google Chrome adds the ability to use the same spell checker as Google Search. Is it another Scroogle feature?]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Mar 2013 01:29:05 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Chris Duckett]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-browser/">Browser</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's that time in Chrome's six-weekly release cycle where another stable version is pushed out the door. Leading the <a href="http://googlechromereleases.blogspot.com.au/2013/03/stable-channel-update_26.html">feature list this time</a> is an addition entitled <a href="http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;answer=95604">"Ask Google for suggestions"</a>.</p>
<p>This feature sends the text that a user types to Google's servers for context-sensitive spell checking, homonym suggesting, and grammar checking.</p>
<figure><img title="googlesuggestions" alt="googlesuggestions" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013161/googlesuggestions-620x125.png?hash=AwuzAGExZw&upscale=1" height="125" width="620"><figcaption>(Image: Google)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Also added in this Chrome release is a feature that synchronises the custom words added to dictionaries between different devices using Chrome.</p>
<p>These changes are available on Windows, Linux, and Chrome OS — Mac support is still being worked on.</p>
<p>For the tin-foil hat wearers who are using Chrome, the good news is that this feature is optional. But I would love to see the marketing geniuses behind <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/three-sides-to-every-scroogled-microsofts-googles-and-the-truth-7000011202/">Microsoft's Scroogle campaign</a> get to work on this.</p>
<p>The truth of the way people are working at the present time is that Google is the easiest, generally correct spell checker available for those instances where a baked-in spell check is not available, or is too troublesome to turn on.</p>
<p>I would not dare to turn on a spell checker when coding (especially in vim), that would merely turn my code into a never-ending river of red underlining and blocks. But when I need to double check a word that I have questionably spelled, it is too easy to check it by simply typing the word into my browser's address bar and letting Google take care of the rest.</p>
<p>If Microsoft and the tin-foil hat brigade are right, then Google is already reading all of my emails anyway. The least that Google could do is make sure that they are spelled right, and that the grammar makes sense.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7000013158</guid>
      <link><![CDATA[http://www.zdnet.com/badgeville-brings-business-gamification-to-force-com-7000013158/]]></link>
      <title><![CDATA[Badgeville brings business gamification to Force.com]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[Put a badge on it? U.S. startup Badgeville brings its brand of engagement to the Salesforce cloud.]]></description>
      <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:04 +0000]]></pubDate>
      <media:credit role="author"><![CDATA[Andrew Nusca]]></media:credit>
      <s:doctype><![CDATA[Text]]></s:doctype>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-cloud/">Cloud</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-salesforce-com/">Salesforce.com</category>
      <category domain="http://www.zdnet.com/topic-start-ups/">Start-Ups</category>
      <media:text type="html"><![CDATA[<figure><img title="badgeville-gamification-roles" alt="badgeville-gamification-roles" src="http://cdn-static.zdnet.com/i/r/story/70/00/013158/badgeville-gamification-roles-620x161.png?hash=AQR1ZQx5Mz&upscale=1" height="161" width="620"></figure>
<p>Let's face it. Your customers and employees? Most of them don't care. They could, but they don't. They're too busy; their attention too limited in this age of information.</p>
<p>Got something good but you can't break through? That's where gamification comes into play.</p>
<p>The relatively recent term is just a fancy word for playing into the addictive qualities found in video games -- you know, the dopamine-producing aspects that make you sink your teeth into something otherwise trivial. It's in vogue lately as a user engagement tactic, because hey, if you can will yourself to keep running from digital castle to castle in search of a pixelated princess, why can't you force yourself to finish your damn tax return?</p>
<p><a href="http://badgeville.com">Badgeville</a> and many others have built a business model around this concept. This morning, the&nbsp;Redwood City, Calif.-based company announced its entry onto <a href="http://www.force.com">Force.com</a>, the Salesforce social and mobile application platform. Beginning today, its "behavior platform" can be layered on top of Force.com apps to fast-track desired behavior for external customers and internal employees alike.</p>
<p>Think of it like an additive to a car's fuel tank.&nbsp;Marketo, Engine Yard, Docusign, Shaw Industries and Phoenix Idea Labs are already customers.</p>
<p>To learn how companies plan to use social mechanics to trick employees into filling out their expense reports (ahem), I spoke with the company's VP of worldwide marketing,&nbsp;Chandar Pattabhiram.</p>
<p><strong>ZD: So...gamification.</strong></p>
<p>CP: We are in the business of increasing employee productivity and customer advocacy.&nbsp;We essentially increase engagement with applications by using a set of engagement mechanics. We reward users, showcase their reputations amongst peers, and so forth.&nbsp;</p>
<p>More motivation, more recognition, more rewards ultimately equals more engagement and companies will get more value out of those applications.</p>
<p>One example of a challenge is, how do I get customer service people to deliver superior customer support and close tickets faster? In that case, we're trying to reward certain behaviors directly in the Zendesk application. There's a leaderboard that's constantly visible in the application.</p>
<p><strong>ZD: With regard to employee-facing apps, how much of an impact should gamification really have? Don't we already have long-established motivation levers like pay, title, responsibilities and roles? Isn't that enough?</strong></p>
<p>CP: It's icing on the cake; it's about trying to get the most value. It's augmenting traditional methods with new motivations. My daughter is expected to go to school and do well. But if I give her a badge to do well, that motivation drives her to do better than to just say, "This is your job."</p>
<p><strong>ZD: Fair point. How often do companies come to you seeking gamification as a silver bullet for more systemic problems?</strong></p>
<p>CP: Gamification is not a fix to strategy. You can't fix corporate culture and underlying management problems with it. Yes, there are people that have looked at it that way, but a lot of organizations have understood that gamification taps into key human behaviors and drivers and they want to apply that to their existing landscape. It is not an alternative.</p>
<p>The ones that are smart treat it as a program, not a project. It's a closed-loop process. It's not about giving you badges for three months and leaving your behavior [to return to what it was previously].</p>
<p>Learning and compliance is one example. I was an executive at IBM, and we had to take harassment training, and nobody takes those in the first few days. They wait until the end.</p>
<p>Or Marketo, which focuses on community. A marketer wakes up in the morning and wonders, how do I acquire more customers? The lead after that is, how do I keep them? By rewarding them for sharing things on Facebook and other things, they get virtual rewards, which can translate to tangible rewards, which helps them become brand advocates.</p>
<p>If you translate just one percent of your customers into advocates, that is a 10X return.</p>
<p><strong>ZD: How does Force.com play into your own strategy?</strong></p>
<p>CP: Today, if you're a CIO and want to deliver a new capability to your business, you have a binary choice: build it using Java or something, or buy it using a cloud-based platform. More people are using platforms like Force.com. We are now providing a toolkit that lets you drive gamification and engagement on those applications.</p>
<p>A company like [personal health products giant]&nbsp;Kimberly-Clark&nbsp;has a bunch of instances on Force.com. So it gives us the ability to approach large organizations. It gives us a great channel, a great market. More than 185,000 cloud applications are being built on Force.com.</p>
<p>For Salesforce or any cloud provider, [the ecosystem] is their engagement application. It's more likely that customers will not cut the cord.</p>]]></media:text>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
