<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Guardian World News</title><link>http://www.guardian.co.uk</link><description>Latest news and features from guardian.co.uk, the world's leading liberal voice</description><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. 2013</copyright><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:59:57 GMT</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:59:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><image><title>The Guardian World News</title><url>http://image.guardian.co.uk/sitecrumbs/Guardian.gif</url><link>http://www.guardian.co.uk</link></image><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/theguardian/rss" /><feedburner:info uri="theguardian/rss" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item><title>Manchester police to record attacks on goths, emos and punks as hate crimes</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/8nYoINkb7xw/manchester-police-goths-punks-hate-crime</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/18309?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Amanchester-police-goths-punks-hate-crime%3A1889237&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Crime+-+UK+%28News%29%2CManchester%2CGreater+Manchester%2CUK+news%2CPolice+and+policing&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Associated+Press&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+07%3A14&amp;c8=1889237&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Manchester+police+to+record+attacks+on+goths%2C+emos+and+punks+as+hate+crimes&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FCrime" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Decision follows campaign by Sophie Lancaster Foundation, a charity set up in memory of girl fatally attacked in 2007&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police in Manchester have said they will begin recording offences against members of alternative subcultures in the same way they do attacks based on race, religion, disability, sexual orientation or transgender identity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greater Manchester police force – the first in Britain to take the step – said that "goths, emos, punks and metallers" and members of other alternative groups have often endured abuse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"People who wish to express their alternative sub-culture identity freely should not have to tolerate hate crime," Assistant Chief Constable Garry Shewan said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manchester police said the change would enable officers to give more support to victims of anti-punk or anti-Goth crime. But it won't necessarily mean tougher sentences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although British judicial guidelines call for people convicted of hate crimes to receive tougher sentences, the Manchester decision has not been recognised nationally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The police decision follows campaigning by the Sophie Lancaster Foundation, a charity set up in memory of a 20-year-old who was fatally attacked in a park near Manchester in 2007 because of her appearance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The judge at the trial of the five teenage attackers called the assault on Lancaster and her boyfriend a hate crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The foundation is campaigning to get hate crime laws expanded to include "alternative subcultures or lifestyle and dress" and has gained support from musicians including Gary Numan and Courtney Love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The victim's mother, Sylvia Lancaster, said the police move was "a validation of the work we have undertaken in the past five years and hopefully other forces will follow [Manchester police's] lead."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are no immediate plans to change the national hate crimes register, but last year equalities minister Lynne Featherstone acknowledged that the five recognised categories of hate crime was "an incomplete list."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/ukcrime"&gt;Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/manchester"&gt;Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/greater-manchester"&gt;Greater Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/police"&gt;Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4dbf7c/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990934346/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4dbf7c/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990934346/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4dbf7c/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990934346/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4dbf7c/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/8nYoINkb7xw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Manchester</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Greater Manchester</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Police</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Crime</category><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 07:38:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/manchester-police-goths-punks-hate-crime</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-04T07:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406636676</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Crime, Manchester, Greater Manchester, UK news, Police</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365012691278/Sophie-Lancaster-court-ca-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Lancashire Police/PA</media:credit><media:description>Manchester police decision follows campaign by Sophie Lancaster Foundation, a charity set up in memory of a 20-year-old who was fatally attacked in a park near Manchester in 2007. Photograph: Lancashire Police/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365012696975/Sophie-Lancaster-court-ca-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Lancashire Police/PA</media:credit><media:description>Manchester police decision follows campaign by Sophie Lancaster Foundation, a charity set up in memory of a 20-year-old who was fatally attacked in a park near Manchester in 2007. Photograph: Lancashire Police/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/manchester-police-goths-punks-hate-crime</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Hollande denies covering up for disgraced former tax tsar</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/nu-WNYCg5vc/hollande-denies-covering-up-tax-tsar</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/47727?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ahollande-denies-covering-up-tax-tsar%3A1889262&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=France%2CFrancois+Hollande%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Angelique+Chrisafis&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+08%3A04&amp;c8=1889262&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Hollande+denies+covering+up+for+disgraced+former+tax+tsar&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FFrance" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;French president says Jérôme Cahuzac's actions 'unforgivable' as he announces reforms to lessen impact of scandal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The French president, François Hollande, has insisted he did not cover for his disgraced former budget minister Jérôme Cahuzac, whose shock confession to having hidden €600,000 from the taxman in a secret foreign bank account has plunged the government into crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to lessen the impact of a scandal threatening to derail his government, Hollande made a surprise TV address on Wednesday following Cahuzac's spectacular admission that, despite four months of vowing on TV and in parliament that he had no foreign bank account, he had in fact hidden money abroad for around 20 years. Cahuzac, who until last month &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/19/french-budget-minister-resigns" title=""&gt;was Hollande's tax tsar and budget minister&lt;/a&gt; in charge of a crackdown on tax evasion, now faces charges for laundering money from tax fraud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hollande said Cahuzac did not benefit from any protection from the government. Shaking his fist, he called Cahuzac's actions unforgivable and "an outrage to the republic". He announced a string of reforms, including banning convicted fraudsters from holding public office and requiring all government ministers and members of parliament to publish details of their personal finances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But opposition politicians demanded a parliamentary inquiry and criticised Hollande for standing by Cahuzac for four months after the investigative website Mediapart broke the story of the bank account in December. Cahuzac only resigned two weeks ago, in order to "defend his honour", when the French justice system stepped up its inquiry into the alleged account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean-Francois Copé, head of the rightwing UMP party, said the president either "knew nothing, and that's extremely serious because it means he showed a certain amount of naivety" or "he knew and that means he lied to the French people". Thierry Mariani, UMP's vice-president, said of the Socialist leadership: "Frankly I find it hard to believe that they only learned the truth 48 hours ago, or else I guess we're being led by a big simpleton."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At parliamentary questions, MPs piled pressure on to the finance minister, Pierre Moscovici, accusing him of using his ministry's administration to try to clear Cahuzac's name before the legal inquiry had run its course. The UMP MP Claude Goasguen said Moscovici should resign, but Moscovici said: "If you're looking to accuse someone, you're knocking on the wrong door." He told Le Monde of Cahuzac: "Every time, and it was more than 50 times, when I interrogated him, he gave me numerous and vigorous denials, looking straight into my eyes." Moscovici said his only mistake had been showing "too much trust".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As opposition politicians wondered how the Élysée could not have established the truth of the account months ago, the interior ministry issued a statement saying there was no "parallel inquiry" or involvement of the secret services. The prime minister insisted that unlike previous administrations, the Socialist government was letting the justice system take its course and not pressuring investigators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cahuzac, 60, was a cardiologist who later made a fortune in plastic surgery by setting up a hair-transplant clinic near the Champs-Élysées. He famously spruced up the balding pates of some of France's most high-profile men for substantial fees. "When you can't see the join, it means he did it," one Socialist MP told Le Nouvel Observateur of Cahuzac's trichological expertise. Elected MP in 1997, he headed the parliament's commission on public finances. As Hollande's budget minister, his entourage called him the star of government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The French media continued to question where the money in the secret foreign accounts had come from. In the late 1980s, Cahuzac worked in the health ministry, in charge of dealing with the powerful French pharmaceutical industry. At the time, he flatly denied any question of payments from pharmaceutical companies. Cahuzac's lawyer, Jean Veil, said the money in the foreign account, which had not been topped up for 12 years, came from "his income as a surgeon" and "his activity as a consultant". After leaving the health ministry, Cahuzac set up a consultancy firm working with pharmaceutical groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intrigue surrounding the account deepened when Le Monde reported that the Swiss bank account set up by Cahuzac in 1992, before being transferred to Singapore, was opened for him by a former lawyer who had been a member of a far-right students' union and who was close to the leader of the far-right Front National, Marine Le Pen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Swiss prosecutors confirmed that Cahuzac had agreed to allow details of the Swiss account to be transferred to French investigators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/francois-hollande"&gt;François Hollande&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/angeliquechrisafis"&gt;Angelique Chrisafis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4da1ce/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990931348/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4da1ce/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990931348/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4da1ce/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990931348/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4da1ce/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/nu-WNYCg5vc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">France</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">François Hollande</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 19:04:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/hollande-denies-covering-up-tax-tsar</guid><dc:creator>Angelique Chrisafis</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-04T06:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406638114</dc:identifier><media:keywords>France, François Hollande, Europe, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365015822800/Fran-ois-Hollande-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Fadel Senna/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Francois Hollande. The opposition's Jean-François Copé said that if the president knew nothing, 'that's extremely serious because it means he showed naivety'. Photograph: Fadel Senna/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365015829017/Fran-ois-Hollande-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Fadel Senna/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Francois Hollande. The opposition's Jean-François Copé said that if the president knew nothing, 'that's extremely serious because it means he showed naivety'. Photograph: Fadel Senna/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/hollande-denies-covering-up-tax-tsar</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Afghan suicide attack on provincial courthouse kills scores</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/lPA5QjMOm_U/afghan-suicide-attack-provincial-courthouse</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/90261?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aafghan-suicide-attack-provincial-courthouse%3A1889234&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Afghanistan+%28News%29%2CTaliban%2CHamid+Karzai+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CTerrorism+-+international&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Emma+Graham-Harrison&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+07%3A06&amp;c8=1889234&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Afghan+suicide+attack+on+provincial+courthouse+kills+scores&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FAfghanistan" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Suicide squad dressed as soldiers leaves 44 people dead and over 100 injured in deadliest day for civilians in more than a year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine suicide attackers disguised as Afghan army soldiers stormed a provincial courthouse and then battled security forces for hours, killing 44 people and injuring over 100 more on the deadliest day for Afghan civilians in more than a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The assault on Wednesday in remote western Farah province, on the border with Iran, came the day the country's powerful spy chief returned home from months of medical treatment in the US to recover from &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/dec/07/afghanistan-suicide-bomber-genitals" title=""&gt;a December assassination attempt that nearly claimed his life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The suicide squad drove into the capital of Farah in an army pickup and detonated a car bomb at the entrance to the complex before rushing inside, provincial police chief Agha Noor Kimtuz told the Guardian by phone. One group took over the court and another barricaded themselves inside the office of the attorney general for an hours-long battle with the police and army.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bodies of the dead lay in the bloodied courtyard of the complex, and a member of parliament for the province said the attackers had also herded hostages into the basement of the complex and mowed them down with assault rifles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"When they were trying to enter they shot and killed a policeman. After that anyone that was in their way they just opened fire and killed – civilians, prosecutors, judges," said Kabul-based MP Ustad Humayra Ayoubi, who spoke to constituents in Farah by phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Some of the civilian employers of both buildings were taken into the basement and shot. The majority of them were killed and some of them were wounded."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were 10 police officers and soldiers among the dead but all the rest were civilians, said Abdul Rahman Zhwandi, a spokesman for the provincial governor. Some of them were judges, he added, but authorities were still reeling from the scale of the attack and did not have a full list of victims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security has been weak for years in the border province, which in 2009 was also the site of one of Nato's worst civilian casualty incidents of the war. An air strike hit village homes killing dozens of women and children, although the toll is still disputed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last May an insurgent assault on the Farah governor's compound used similar tactics to those deployed on Wednesday; suicide bombers in police uniform killed seven people, although the governor escaped unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Taliban claimed the latest attack, saying it was designed to free 10 fighters who were on trial in the building, Reuters reported. Afghan officials said 15 prisoners who had been brought in for sentencing were among the dead and wounded, but it was not clear if they were part of the same group or if any Taliban prisoners were actually in the court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Afghan president, Hamid Karzai, in a strongly-worded statement denounced the attack as a "genocide" that would not go unanswered, but did not condemn the Taliban by name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The president, who has described the insurgent group as wayward brothers in the past, and is seeking to broker peace talks, instead said attacks on civilian targets "serve foreign evil objectives". He promised help for families of the victims and an investigation into the killings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Taliban are already responsible for the majority of civilian casualties in Afghanistan, according to UN data, but the direct assault on a court building sets a worrying precedent for a movement whose leadership has ordered its fighters to avoid civilian casualties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"A great concern is that the attack appeared to be against civilian government employees, targeting judges and prosecutors, which we have not previously seen," said Georgette Gagnon, director of human rights for the UN mission in Afghanistan. The attack was among the worst in recent years, she added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the toll is confirmed, it would be the deadliest single attack on Afghan civilians since a &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/dec/06/al-qaida-kabul-attack-shia-pilgrims" title=""&gt;bomber targeted Ashura ceremonies in Kabul&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2011, killing over 50.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the attack unfolded in western Afghanistan, Karzai was welcoming intelligence chief Asadullah Khalid back to the job after months in a US hospital, where visitors included US president Barack Obama. He had been badly wounded by a suicide bomber who concealed his explosives by wrapping them around his genitals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mokhtar Amiri contributed reporting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/afghanistan"&gt;Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/taliban"&gt;Taliban&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/hamid-karzai"&gt;Hamid Karzai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/terrorism"&gt;Global terrorism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/emma-graham-harrison"&gt;Emma Graham-Harrison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4d9868/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990930344/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d9868/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990930344/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d9868/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990930344/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d9868/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/lPA5QjMOm_U" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Global terrorism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Taliban</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Afghanistan</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Hamid Karzai</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 18:06:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/afghan-suicide-attack-provincial-courthouse</guid><dc:creator>Emma Graham-Harrison</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:05:52Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406636578</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Afghanistan, Taliban, Hamid Karzai, World news, Global terrorism</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365012314288/An-injured-Afghan-army-so-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Anonymous/AP</media:credit><media:description>An injured Afghan army soldier is taken to hospital in Farah after a suicide squad stormed a provincial courthouse and then battled security forces for hours. Photograph: Anonymous/AP</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365012320718/An-injured-Afghan-army-so-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Anonymous/AP</media:credit><media:description>An injured Afghan army soldier is taken to hospital in Farah after a suicide squad stormed a provincial courthouse and then battled security forces for hours. Photograph: Anonymous/AP</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/afghan-suicide-attack-provincial-courthouse</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Amazon tribe threatens to declare war amid row over Brazilian dam project</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/HRbDF0xZdSM/brazil-dam-activists-war-military</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/32632?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abrazil-dam-activists-war-military%3A1889040&amp;ch=Environment&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Amazon+rainforest+%28environment%29%2CBrazil+%28News%29%2CAmericas+%28News%29%2CRivers+%28environment%29%2CTrees+and+forests+%28environment%29%2CDeforestation+%28environment%29%2CHydrogen+power+%28environment%29%2CEnergy+%28Environment%29%2CRenewable+energy+%28Environment%29%2CEnvironment%2CHydropower+%28environment%29%2CWorld+news%2CGlobal+development%2CDilma+Rousseff&amp;c5=Environment+Conservation%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEnergy%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=Jonathan+Watts&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+03%3A14&amp;c8=1889040&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Amazon+tribe+threatens+to+declare+war+amid+row+over+Brazilian+dam+project&amp;c66=Environment&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FEnvironment%2FEnvironment%2FAmazon+rainforest" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Munduruku leaders hit out at 'betrayal' after government pushes on with dam construction without community's consent&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Amazonian community has threatened to "go to war" with the Brazilian government after what they say is a military incursion into their land by dam builders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Munduruku indigenous group in Para state say they have been betrayed by the authorities, who are pushing ahead with plans to build a cascade of &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/hydropower" title=""&gt;hydropower&lt;/a&gt; plants on the Tapajós river without their permission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public prosecutors, human rights groups, environmental organisations and Christian missionaries have condemned what they call the government's strong-arm tactics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to witnesses in the area, helicopters, soldiers and armed police have been involved in Operation Tapajós, which aims to conduct an environmental impact assessment needed for the proposed construction of the 6,133MW São Luiz do Tapajós dam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The facility, to be built by the Norte Energia consortium, is the biggest of two planned dams on the Tapajós, the fifth-largest river in the Amazon basin. The government's 10-year plan includes the construction of four larger hydroelectric plants on its tributary, the Jamanxim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under Brazilian law, major infrastructure projects require prior consultation with indigenous communities. &lt;a href="http://www.prpa.mpf.gov.br/news/2013/mpf-questiona-ministerio-de-minas-e-energia-e-secretaria-geral-da-presidencia-sobre-operacao-no-tapajos" title=""&gt;Federal prosecutors say this has not happened&lt;/a&gt; and urge the courts to block the scheme which, they fear, could lead to bloodshed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The Munduruku have already stated on several occasions that they do not support studies for hydroelectric plants on their land unless there is full prior consultation," the prosecutors noted in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a court ruling last week gave the go-ahead for the survey. Government officials say that neither researchers nor logistical and support teams will enter indigenous villages. The closest they will get is about 30 miles from the nearest village, Sawré Maybu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ministry of mines and energy noted on its website that 80 researchers, including biologists and foresters, would undertake a study of flora and fauna. The army escort was made possible by President Dilma Rousseff, who decreed this year that military personnel could be used for survey operations. Officials say the security is for the safety of the scientists and the local population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Missionaries said the presence of armed troops near Sawré Maybu village, Itaituba, was intimidating, degrading and an unacceptable violation of the rights of the residents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"In this operation, the federal government has been threatening the lives of the people," the &lt;a href="http://www.cimi.org.br/site/pt-br/?system=news&amp;conteudo_id=6788&amp;action=read" title=""&gt;Indigenous Missionary Council&lt;/a&gt; said. "It is unacceptable and illegitimate for the government to impose dialogue at the tip of a bayonet."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group added that Munduruku leaders ended a phone call with representatives of the president with a declaration of war. They have also issued open letters calling for an end to the military operation. "We are not bandits. We feel betrayed, humiliated and disrespected by all this," a letter states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the community's leaders, Valdenir Munduruku, has warned that &lt;a href="http://g1.globo.com/pa/para/noticia/2013/04/lideranca-indigena-busca-apoio-de-tribos-do-para-contra-hidreletricas.html" title=""&gt;locals will take action&lt;/a&gt; if the government does not withdraw its taskforce by 10 April, when the two sides are set to talk. He has called for support from other indigenous groups, such as the Xingu, facing similar threats from hydroelectric dams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Environmental groups have expressed concern. The 1,200-mile waterway is home to more than 300 fish species and provides sustenance to some of the most biodiverse forest habitats on Earth. Ten indigenous groups inhabit the basin, along with several tribes in voluntary isolation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With similar conflicts over other proposed dams in the Amazon, such as those at Belo Monte, Teles Pires, Santo Antônio and Jirau, some compare the use of force to the last great expansion of hydropower during the military dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The Brazilian government is making political decisions about the dams before the environmental impact assessment is done," said Brent Millikan of the International Rivers environmental group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The recent military operations illustrate that the federal government is willing to disregard existing legal instruments intended to foster dialogue between government and civil society."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/amazon-rainforest"&gt;Amazon rainforest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/brazil"&gt;Brazil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/americas"&gt;Americas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/rivers"&gt;Rivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/forests"&gt;Trees and forests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/deforestation"&gt;Deforestation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/hydrogen-power"&gt;Hydrogen power&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/energy"&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/renewableenergy"&gt;Renewable energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/hydropower"&gt;Hydropower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/dilma-rousseff"&gt;Dilma Rousseff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jonathanwatts"&gt;Jonathan Watts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4b9e67/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922671/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b9e67/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922671/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b9e67/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990922671/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b9e67/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/HRbDF0xZdSM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Energy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Deforestation</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Amazon rainforest</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Americas</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Hydrogen power</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Trees and forests</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Brazil</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Hydropower</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Editorial</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Rivers</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Renewable energy</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/apr/03/brazil-dam-activists-war-military</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Watts</dc:creator><dc:subject>Environment</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T18:02:41Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406624820</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Amazon rainforest, Brazil, Americas, Rivers, Trees and forests, Deforestation, Hydrogen power, Energy, Renewable energy, Environment, Hydropower, World news, Global development, Dilma Rousseff</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365008343996/The-Amazon-rainforest--003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Gerd Ludwig/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>The facility, to be built by the Norte Energia consortium, is the biggest of three planned dams on the Tapajóst river in the Amazon basin Photograph: Gerd Ludwig/Corbis</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365008349843/The-Amazon-rainforest--008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Gerd Ludwig/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>The São Luiz do Tapajós dam is the biggest of three planned facilities on the Tapajós river in the Amazon basin. Photograph: Gerd Ludwig/Corbis</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2011/9/29/1317310247455/Brazil-judge-orders-const-007.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Evaristo Sa/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>'We don't want Belo Monte' reads a sign at an anti-dam rally in front of the Brazilian parliament building in Brasilia. Photograph: AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Admin/BkFill/Default_image_group/2011/5/25/1306308285789/Dilma-Rousseff-007.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Evaristo Sa/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Brazil's president, Dilma Rousseff, has decreed that military personnel can be used for dam survey operations. Photograph: Evaristo Sa/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/apr/03/brazil-dam-activists-war-military</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Assets worth €1.3bn seized from Italian businessman 'with mafia links'</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/dSBc3L84xJs/vito-nicastri-assets-seized-mafia</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/17589?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Avito-nicastri-assets-seized-mafia%3A1889185&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Italy+%28News%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CMafia+%28News%29%2COrganised+crime+%28News%29%2CWind+power+%28Environment%29%2CEnergy+%28Environment%29%2CRenewable+energy+%28Environment%29%2CEnvironment&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEnergy%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=Lizzy+Davies&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+06%3A02&amp;c8=1889185&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Assets+worth+%E2%82%AC1.3bn+seized+from+Italian+businessman+%27with+mafia+links%27&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FItaly" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Vito Nicastri, known as the 'king of wind' for his renewable energy interests, loses companies, property, cars and boats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anti-mafia investigators in Italy have made their largest confiscation of assets to date: €1.3bn (£1.1bn) worth of property, cash and alternative energy companies owned by a man known as the "king of wind".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a decision hailed by Italy's anti-mafia police chief as unprecedented, a court in Sicily ordered the definitive confiscation of assets first seized and frozen in September 2010 from Vito Nicastri, 57, a former electrician and businessman believed to have close ties with the Cosa Nostra.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the assets were 43 companies, 98 properties, 66 bank accounts, credit cards, investment funds, cars and boats. Most were located in Sicily and in Calabria, the southern region of Italy that is home to the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%27Ndrangheta" title=""&gt;'Ndrangheta&lt;/a&gt; criminal organisation, but the investigation also reached northern Lombardy and Rome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investigators said Nicastri, who made his name as an alternative energy entrepreneur, had "high-level" contacts in the mafia and invested money made from criminal activities. "This is a sector in which money can easily be laundered," Arturo de Felice, head of Italy's anti-mafia agency, told SkyTG24.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In separate comments, De Felice described the confiscation of the assets as "unprecedented".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police said Nicastri had close ties to Matteo Messina Denaro, a Cosa Nostra kingpin who has been on the run since the early 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Matteo Messina Denaro is behind many businessmen considered above suspicion who manage and take care of the assets of the real boss of Cosa Nostra," tweeted Ivan Lo Bello, vice-president of business lobby Confindustria. "The fight against money laundering is fundamental to the crushing of the mafia."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Italian police said the confiscation of assets would impact "in a significant way" on the economic power of Messina Denaro. "We are talking about productive businesses, which will now go to the state; in this particular economic context that we are living in, it's not to be sniffed at," said De Felice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicastri has been placed under surveillance and told to remain in his home town of Alcamo, on the west coast of Sicily, for three years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/italy"&gt;Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/mafia"&gt;Mafia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/organised-crime"&gt;Organised crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/windpower"&gt;Wind power&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/energy"&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/renewableenergy"&gt;Renewable energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/lizzydavies"&gt;Lizzy Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4d45b8/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922166/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b8/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922166/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b8/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990922166/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b8/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/dSBc3L84xJs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Energy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Mafia</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Organised crime</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Wind power</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Italy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Renewable energy</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:02:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/vito-nicastri-assets-seized-mafia</guid><dc:creator>Lizzy Davies</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T17:15:07Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406633679</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Italy, Europe, World news, Mafia, Organised crime, Wind power, Energy, Renewable energy, Environment</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365008521283/Vito-Nicastri-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Vito Nicastri has been ordered by Italian police to remain in his Sicilian home town of Alcamo for three years. Photograph: Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365008527421/Vito-Nicastri-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Vito Nicastri has been ordered by Italian police to remain in his Sicilian home town of Alcamo for three years. Photograph: Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/vito-nicastri-assets-seized-mafia</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>IMF sets terms of Cyprus bailout</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/yIthMrOPh5U/imf-cyprus-bailout-terms</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/31983?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aimf-cyprus-bailout-terms%3A1889187&amp;ch=Business&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=IMF%2CWorld+news%2CEconomics+%28Business%29%2CBusiness%2CCyprus+%28News%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CEurozone+crisis&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CCredit+Crunch%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBudget&amp;c6=Phillip+Inman&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+06%3A00&amp;c8=1889187&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=IMF+sets+terms+of+Cyprus+bailout&amp;c66=Business&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FBusiness%2FBusiness%2FInternational+Monetary+Fund+%28IMF%29" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;International Monetary Fund managing director Christine Lagarde said Cyprus must press ahead with measures to bring the island's budget into surplus by 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Monetary Fund has demanded that Cyprus cut state pension costs and reform its welfare system as the price of a €1bn (£854m) loan to help bail out the stricken island.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IMF's managing director, Christine Lagarde, said the poorest Cypriots would be protected from the worst of the cuts, but Cyprus must press ahead with measures to bring its annual state budget into surplus by 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The deal, agreed in principle by the Cypriot government, provoked an immediate reaction from trade unions, which called on bank workers to strike over potential pension cuts. Officials from the Cyprus Union of Bank Employees called on bank staff in Nicosia to walk off their jobs at lunchtime on Thursday, and gather in a protest march towards the parliament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Underlining the sense of panic, the Cypriot central bank was reportedly preparing to extend capital controls to prevent a run on the banks despite previously lifting some more draconian elements earlier in the week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The statement by Lagarde followed confirmation that the IMF will provide one-tenth of a €10bn bailout loan, leaving the European Union and the European Central Bank to pick up the remaining €9bn tab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus needs the money to refinance its stricken banking sector and reduce government debts that were on course to reach 180% of GDP. The crisis brought Cyprus to the brink of collapse after it was in effect locked out of private markets and forced to seek funds from the EU and IMF. The Cypriot president, Nicos Anastasiades, has struggled to bring the situation under control after a series of mishaps that included imposing a tax on bank deposits of less than €100,000 – protected under EU guarantees – which was later reversed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The three-year IMF loan was secured against a series of reforms agreed by the government two weeks ago that involved shutting the island's second largest bank, Laiki, and restructuring the biggest lender, Bank of Cyprus. A tax on bank deposits of more than €100,000 was also put in place to raise €5.8bn from domestic funds, amid reports that the haircut could be between 40% and 80% of deposits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, public sector cuts and tax rises already under way are estimated to save around 5% of GDP. The IMF said further measures amounting to an additional 2% of GDP will be needed by raising the corporate income tax rate from 10% to 12.5% and the tax rate on interest income from 15% to 30%. Cuts in pensions and welfare benefits will bring savings worth another 4.5% of GDP in the medium term "to achieve a 4% of GDP primary surplus by 2018, which is required to put debt on a firmly downward path".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It said the social welfare system will be reviewed to "streamline administration costs", minimise the overlap of existing programs, and improve their targeting to ensure that public resources "reach those in need".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lagarde said: "A combined financing package of €10bn is designed to help Cyprus cover its financing needs, including to service debt obligations, while it implements the policies needed to restore the health of the economy and regain access to capital market financing."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/imf"&gt;International Monetary Fund (IMF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/economics"&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/cyprus"&gt;Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/debt-crisis"&gt;Eurozone crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/phillipinman"&gt;Phillip Inman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4d45b7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922165/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b7/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922165/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b7/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990922165/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b7/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/yIthMrOPh5U" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Economics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Cyprus</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Eurozone crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">International Monetary Fund (IMF)</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:00:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/apr/03/imf-cyprus-bailout-terms</guid><dc:creator>Phillip Inman</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:37:35Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406633691</dc:identifier><media:keywords>International Monetary Fund (IMF), World news, Economics, Business, Cyprus, Europe, Eurozone crisis</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/2/1364907510476/5f37e67d-32f6-42dd-bc6b-adf768a394e5-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Petros Giannakouris/AP</media:credit><media:description>Cyprus' new finance minister Haris Georgiades, second from left, in a meeting ahead of the country's bailout. Photograph: Petros Giannakouris/AP</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/2/1364907507070/5f37e67d-32f6-42dd-bc6b-adf768a394e5-460x276.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Petros Giannakouris/AP</media:credit><media:description>Cyprus' new finance minister Haris Georgiades, second from left, in a meeting ahead of the country's bailout. Photograph: Petros Giannakouris/AP</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/apr/03/imf-cyprus-bailout-terms</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Beanz meanz linez: baked-bean lorry crash causes motorway mess</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/VQkc6c3A0SY/baked-bean-lorry-crash-motorway</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/61264?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abaked-bean-lorry-crash-motorway%3A1889184&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Transport+UK+news%2CUK+news%2CRoad+transport+%28News%29&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Press+Association&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+05%3A59&amp;c8=1889184&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Beanz+meanz+linez%3A+baked-bean+lorry+crash+causes+motorway+mess&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FTransport" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Motorists urged to avoid M6 near Haydock as truck sheds its load and creates chaos in both directions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lorry carrying tins of baked beans has crashed and shed its load across a motorway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drivers in Merseyside were tonight being urged to steer clear of the M6 at Haydock where one lane in each direction remained closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The crash happened shortly before 11am between junctions 22 and 23 when the lorry struck the central reservation barrier and came to rest in the southbound carriageway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for the Highways Agency said: "After a brief closure of the motorway to right the vehicle, two lanes of the carriageway in each direction have been running this afternoon but both outside lanes will remain closed for the lorry to be removed, the shed load to be recovered and for temporary barrier repairs to be carried out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It is likely that permanent barrier repairs will need to be carried out overnight tonight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This will involve further lane closures but at a time when traffic is at its lightest and with little impact on motorway users' journeys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Highways Agency traffic officers from the out-station at Newton-le-Willows have been at the scene helping to manage traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Colleagues at the north-west regional control centre at Newton-le-Willows and the national traffic operations centre at Birmingham have set signs across the local, regional and national motorway network to advise drivers of the incident."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/transport"&gt;Transport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/road-transport"&gt;Road transport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4d45b9/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922164/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b9/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922164/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b9/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990922164/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4d45b9/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/VQkc6c3A0SY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Road transport</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Transport</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:59:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/baked-bean-lorry-crash-motorway</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:16:04Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406633674</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Transport, UK news, Road transport</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2008/09/03/beanz84.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Phil Sills/Getty</media:credit><media:description>Baked beans in a can. Photograph: Getty</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2008/09/03/beans460.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Phil Sills/Getty</media:credit><media:description>Motorists warned to avoid a potentially sticky situation on the M6. Photograph: Getty</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/baked-bean-lorry-crash-motorway</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>China voices fears as South Korean workers are barred from Kaesong</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/yO1v1i9O_LA/china-north-korea-kaesong</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/87735?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Achina-north-korea-kaesong%3A1888833&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=North+Korea+%28News%29%2CSouth+Korea+%28News%29%2CChina+%28News%29%2CAsia+Pacific+%28News%29%2CJohn+Kerry%2CUS+news%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMotorsport&amp;c6=Justin+McCurry&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+11%3A08&amp;c8=1888833&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=China+voices+fears+as+South+Korean+workers+are+barred+from+Kaesong&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FNorth+Korea" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Beijing expresses 'serious concern' over escalating crisis after Pyongyang bans South Koreans from jointly run complex&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China voiced "serious concern" about rising tensions on the Korean peninsulaon Wednesday, as North Korea barred South Korean workers from entering a jointly run industrial complex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Kaesong industrial complex, six miles north of the heavily fortified border that has separated the two countries for six decades, is viewed as the last remaining symbol of inter-Korean co-operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The North has disrupted operations there before, but the latest move caused particular concern as South Korea and the US attempt to respond to a catalogue of provocations by the Pyongyang regime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, North Korea said it would resume operations to produce weapons-grade plutonium. In recent weeks, it has also threatened a nuclear attack against the US and its overseas bases – a hollow threat, experts say, given the regime's &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/12/us-north-korea-nuclear-strike-unlikely" title=""&gt;relatively primitive nuclear and missile technology&lt;/a&gt; – and &lt;a href="www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/north-korea-state-war-south-korea" title=""&gt;declared a "state of war" with South Korea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chinese foreign ministry spokesman Hong Lei told reporters in Beijing that the country's deputy foreign minister, Zhang Yesui, had expressed serious concern over the crisis in a meeting with ambassadors from the US and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"In the present situation, China believes all sides must remain calm and exercise restraint and not take actions which are mutually provocative and must certainly not take actions which will worsen the situation," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;China is North Korea's only remaining ally and its biggest aid donor. Its description of the situation in such bleak terms is being interpreted as a sign of growing frustration with the unpredictable behaviour of North Korean leader, Kim Jong-un.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier, the US secretary of state, John Kerry, described the rhetoric emanating from Pyongyang as unacceptable. "What Kim Jong-un has been choosing to do is provocative," he said. "It is dangerous, reckless and the United States will not accept [North Korea] as a nuclear state."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kerry was responding to North Korea's announcement that it would &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/02/north-korea-plans-nuclear-complex" title=""&gt;restart its plutonium reactor at the Yongbyon nuclear complex&lt;/a&gt; and resume the production of highly enriched uranium, a move that officials in Pyongyang conceded was designed to bolster the state's nuclear weapons arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts had warned that any disruption to the Kaesong complex, which draws on investment from more than 100 South Korean firms and employs workers from both countries, would signal a swift deterioration in an already tense situation on the peninsula.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unification ministry in Seoul said about 480 South Korean managers who had planned to travel to Kaesong on Wednesday morning had been prevented from crossing into the North.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"South Korea's government deeply regrets the entry ban and urges that it be lifted immediately," said ministry spokesman Kim Hyung-seok. "Ensuring the safety of our citizens is our top priority and the South Korean government will take necessary measures based on this principle."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the South Korean workers who had stayed in Kaesong the previous night, three had returned by mid-afternoon, with about 800 more expected to follow. The unification ministry later said 46 workers would return by early evening, while the remainder would stay in Kaesong, according to the Yonhap news agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The country's defence minister, Kim Kwan-jin, said he would do everything possible to ensure the safety of workers who remained inside the zone. Those contingencies reportedly include "military action" as a last resort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kaesong, which started producing goods in 2004, is also an important source of hard currency for the North, earning the impoverished state an estimated $2bn (£1.3bn) a year in trade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 120 South Korean firms run factories in the border town, paying more than $80m (£53m) a year in wages to the workforce, which includes 53,000 North Koreans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was not clear how long the ban on workers from the South would last; permission from North Korea for employees to cross the border into its territory is granted on a daily basis. Kaesong has been the victim of diplomatic spats before, having closed briefly in March 2009 during US-South Korea military exercises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But an extended ban would, in effect, lead to the closure of Kaesong as it cannot operate without raw materials trucked in from the South.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I feel worried that I'm unable to do business and also feel anxious," Joe In-suk, a 54-year-old South Korean who had planned to travel to Kaesong on Wednesday, told Associated Press at a border checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/north-korea"&gt;North Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/south-korea"&gt;South Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/china"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/asia-pacific"&gt;Asia Pacific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/john-kerry"&gt;John Kerry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/justinmccurry"&gt;Justin McCurry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a49393f/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922206/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49393f/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922206/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49393f/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990922206/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49393f/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/yO1v1i9O_LA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Asia Pacific</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">South Korea</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">China</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">John Kerry</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">North Korea</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:49:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/china-north-korea-kaesong</guid><dc:creator>Justin McCurry</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T16:49:14Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406606900</dc:identifier><media:keywords>North Korea, South Korea, China, Asia Pacific, John Kerry, United States, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364983380593/Kaesong-North-Korea-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Park Jin-Hee/Park Jin-hee/Xinhua Press/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>A South Korean truck returns after being turned back from the joint industrial complex at the Kaesong, close to the border with the North. Photograph: Park Jin-Hee/Park Jin-hee/Xinhua Press/Corbis</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/china-north-korea-kaesong</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Barclays tax avoidance division generated £1bn a year – Salz review</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/oI8KqWc8heg/barclays-tax-avoidance-salz-review-scm</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/7346?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abarclays-tax-avoidance-salz-review-scm%3A1889034&amp;ch=Business&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Barclays+%28Business%29%2CBanking+%28Business+sector%29%2CBusiness%2CUK+news%2CTax+avoidance+%28DO+NOT+add+to+ongoing+proceedings%29%2CCorporate+governance+%28Business%29%2CPayment+protection+insurance+%28Money%29%2CMoney%2CAntony+Jenkins%2CLibor&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CPersonal+Finance%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets%2CInsurance%2CInvestments+%26+Savings&amp;c6=Jill+Treanor&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+02%3A59&amp;c8=1889034&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Barclays+tax+avoidance+division+generated+%C2%A31bn+a+year+%E2%80%93+Salz+review&amp;c66=Business&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FBusiness%2FBusiness%2FBarclays" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Independent review also shows Barclays paid just £82m in corporation tax&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barclays' controversial tax avoidance division generated revenue of more than a £1bn a year between 2007 and 2010, according to data published in a scathing review of the embattled bank's culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The assessment by City lawyer Anthony Salz, commissioned by Barclays in the wake of the Libor-rigging scandal, produced data for the first time showing that in the 11 years to 2011 the structured capital markets arm generated revenue of more than £9.5bn. Profit numbers were not published but Lord Lawson, the former Conservative chancellor who sits on the parliamentary commission on banking standards, has accused the secretive division of "industrial scale tax avoidance".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new chief executive of Barclays, Antony Jenkins, has insisted the division is being shut down as he attempts to clean up the image of the bank. But Salz found that the 100 highly-paid bankers in SCM have been redeployed around the organisation, instead of being fired.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2009 &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2009/mar/20/barclays-guardian-tax-claim" title=""&gt;the Guardian revealed how SCM structured complicated deals to root money to offshore centres to avoid tax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Salz review also sheds light on the amount of tax paid by Barclays in 2012. Just £82m in corporation tax was paid to the exchequer after top line profits of £7bn shrank to £246m, as a result of an accounting standard relating to how it values its own debt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barclays has also faced fierce criticism for its admission that it &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2011/feb/18/barclays-bank-113m-corporation-tax" title=""&gt;paid just £113m in corporation tax in 2009&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salz, who describes Barclays bankers as losing a "sense of proportion and humility", also described a pay structure in the retail bank which may have encouraged the mis-selling of payment protection insurance. He reveals that the bank had a market-leading share of PPI sales in 2005 and was bringing in revenues of £400m a year from the discredited insurance. High street banks have now taken provisions of more than £12bn in mis-selling claims related to PPI products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/barclay"&gt;Barclays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/banking"&gt;Banking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/taxavoidance"&gt;Tax avoidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/corporate-governance"&gt;Corporate governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/payment-protection-insurance"&gt;Payment protection insurance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/antony-jenkins"&gt;Antony Jenkins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/libor"&gt;Libor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jilltreanor"&gt;Jill Treanor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4b87ed/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922058/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b87ed/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990922058/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b87ed/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990922058/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b87ed/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/oI8KqWc8heg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Banking</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Tax avoidance</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Editorial</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Corporate governance</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Barclays</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/apr/03/barclays-tax-avoidance-salz-review-scm</guid><dc:creator>Jill Treanor</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T18:34:43Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406624434</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Barclays, Banking, Business, UK news, Tax avoidance, Corporate governance, Payment protection insurance, Money, Antony Jenkins, Libor</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364997487558/Barclays-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:credit><media:description>Barclays' structured capital markets division generated revenue of more than £9.5bn between 2000 and 2011. Photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364997493518/Barclays-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:credit><media:description>Barclays' structured capital markets division generated revenue of more than £9.5bn between 2000 and 2011. Photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/apr/03/barclays-tax-avoidance-salz-review-scm</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Forty mobile phone facts: cellphones for dogs, 'butt-dialling' and Ernie Wise</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/EbNvAkSft1Y/forty-mobile-phone-facts-cellphones-dialling</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/17590?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aforty-mobile-phone-facts-cellphones-dialling%3A1889083&amp;ch=Technology&amp;c3=G2&amp;c4=Mobile+phones+%28Technology%29%2CTelecoms+%28Technology%29%2CSmartphones%2CApple+%28Technology%29%2CInternet+phones+and+broadband+%28UK+consumer%29%2CSamsung+%28Technology%29%2CTechnology%2CConsumer+affairs+%28Money%29%2CMoney&amp;c5=Personal+Finance%2CUnclassified%2CTechnology+Gadgets%2CCorporate+IT%2CConsumer+Electronics%2CConsumer+News&amp;c6=Tom+Meltzer&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+05%3A42&amp;c8=1889083&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Feature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Forty+mobile+phone+facts%3A+cellphones+for+dogs%2C+%27butt-dialling%27+and+Ernie+Wise&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FTechnology%2FMobile+phones" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;The 40-year history of the mobile phone in 40 illuminating and unexpected facts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is 40 years this week since the first public mobile phone call. On 3 April, 1973, &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/node/13725793?story_id=13725793," title=""&gt;Martin Cooper&lt;/a&gt;, a pioneering inventor working for Motorola in New York, called a rival engineer from the pavement of Sixth Avenue to brag and was met with a stunned, defeated silence. The race to make the first portable phone had been won. The Pandora's box containing &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/theguardian/shortcuts/2012/may/11/davidcameron-rebekahwade" title=""&gt;txt-speak&lt;/a&gt;, pocket-dials and &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/angry-birds" title=""&gt;pig-hating suicidal birds&lt;/a&gt; was open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people at Motorola, however, felt mobile phones would never be a mass-market consumer product. They wanted the firm to focus on business carphones. But Cooper and his team persisted. Ten years after that first boastful phonecall they brought the portable phone to market, at a retail price of around $4,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thirty years on, the number of mobile phone subscribers worldwide is estimated at six and a half billion. And Angry Birds games have been downloaded 1.7bn times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of the mobile phone in 40 facts:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; That first portable phone was called a DynaTAC. The original model had 35 minutes of battery life and weighed one kilogram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; Several prototypes of the DynaTAC were created just 90 days after Cooper had first suggested the idea. He held a competition among Motorola engineers from various departments to design it and ended up choosing "the least glamorous".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; The DynaTAC's weight was reduced to 794g before it came to market. It was still heavy enough to beat someone to death with, although this fact was never used as a selling point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; Nonetheless, people cottoned on. DynaTAC became the phone of choice for fictional psychopaths, including Wall Street's Gordon Gekko, American Psycho's Patrick Bateman and Saved by the Bell's Zack Morris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; The UK's first public mobile phone call was made by comedian &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2010/jan/01/25-years-phones-transform-communication" title=""&gt;Ernie Wise in 1985 from St Katharine dock to the Vodafone head offices&lt;/a&gt; over a curry house in Newbury.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; Vodafone's 1985 monopoly of the UK mobile market lasted just nine days before Cellnet (now O2) launched its rival service. A Vodafone spokesperson was probably all like: "Aw, shucks!"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; Cellnet and Vodafone were the only UK mobile providers until 1993.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt; It took Vodafone just less than nine years to reach the one million customers mark. They reached two&amp;nbsp;million just 18 months later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt; The first smartphone was &lt;a href="http://www.androidauthority.com/ibm-simon-birthday-134255/" title=""&gt;IBM's Simon&lt;/a&gt;, which debuted at the Wireless World Conference in 1993. It had an early LCD touchscreen and also functioned as an email device, electronic pager, calendar, address book and calculator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2012/03/06/philippe-kahn-camera-phone/" title=""&gt;The first cameraphone&lt;/a&gt; was created by French entrepreneur Philippe Kahn. He took the first photograph with a mobile phone, of his newborn daughter Sophie, on 11 June, 1997.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; By 2002, researchers had established that a driver's reactions were a third slower when talking on a mobile phone than when driving under the influence of alcohol. Driving a car while &lt;a href="https://www.whatdotheyknow.com/request/drivers_using_their_mobile_phone_2#incoming-293859" title=""&gt;talking on a mobile&lt;/a&gt; was eventually banned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt; Talking on a car while driving a mobile remains legal, but inane.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; Since 2008, around 8,000 people a year in England and Wales have been charged and taken to court for driving while using a mobile phone. Around a quarter of all such offences take place in London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 &lt;/strong&gt;In 2002, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2002/nov/11/mobilephones1" title=""&gt;a quarter of Italians&lt;/a&gt; surveyed claimed their lack of a mobile phone was a blow to their confidence and caused sexual problems with partners. No further context could be found for this fact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;/strong&gt; In September 2007, an Arizona-based firm marketed PetCell, a mobile phone for dogs with a built-in GPS satellite system, at $500.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt; PetCell did not take off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; One in six UK adults now live in a home &lt;a href="http://media.ofcom.org.uk/facts/" title=""&gt;with a mobile phone but no landline.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt; In the early 2000s, scientists theorised that handset sizes would halve every 18 months. They did not explain how this would be useful and, mercifully, it hasn't happened. If it had, we'd currently be typing text messages on baked beans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19 &lt;/strong&gt;Not actual baked beans, obviously. Phones the size of baked beans. Bean phones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; The original 160-character size limit for text messages is credited to German engineer &lt;a href="http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/technology/2009/05/invented-text-messaging.html" title=""&gt;Friedhelm Hillebrand&lt;/a&gt;. He arrived at the number by typing a series of random questions and thoughts into his typewriter (such as "What am I doing with my life?") and counting the characters involved. He found 160 to be "perfectly sufficient" for expressing almost any thought or question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21 &lt;/strong&gt;Later studies of the length of postcards and business telegrams confirmed his theory and the limit became industry standard in 1986. Though the limit no longer applies to texts, its influence can still be seen in Twitter's even more stringent 140-character cap. It's also now possible to follow Hillebrand on Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FriedhelmHilleb" title=""&gt;@FriedhelmHilleb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; That may not be his real account. If it is then he's not taking Twitter very seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; 1.7bn mobiles were sold in 2012. The three largest sellers were Samsung, Nokia and Apple handsets. &lt;a href="http://mobithinking.com/mobile-marketing-tools/latest-mobile-stats/a#subscribers" title=""&gt;Combined sales of the three were 850m&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; By 2001, one in four 999 calls to Scotland Yard were accidental dials, forcing the Metropolitan Police to introduce a national scheme called Silent Solutions: in its first month, it diverted around 2,000 accidental 999 calls a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; Between July 2001, when Silent Solutions was introduced, and September 2008, there were an average of 5.5m accidental 999 calls a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; On several occasions criminals have been arrested after "pocket dialing" the police. US officers in Daytona Beach in 2010 were able to prevent a car burglary after one of the thieves "butt-dialed" the police halfway through the crime. "Butt-dialed" is a technical term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://news.sky.com/story/1019377/first-text-was-sent-to-a-mobile-20-years-ago" title=""&gt;The first SMS message to a mobile&lt;/a&gt; phone in the UK was sent in 1992 by engineer Neil Papworth to his friend Richard Jarvis's Orbitel 901 handset. It read simply "Merry Christmas", which was a bit early, since it was sent on 3 December.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt; People who text everyone they know to say "Merry Christmas" on Christmas Day are weird. This one is arguably more of an opinion than a fact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt; The most prolific texters in the UK are 12- to 15-year-olds, who send an average of 193 texts a week. In total, British texters sent more than 150bn messages in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30&lt;/strong&gt; In 2011, Florida resident Celina Aarons opened a phone bill for $201,000 after clocking up colossal roaming charges on a two-week holiday in Canada. The company eventually reduced the fee to $2,500. The bill has been described as the biggest ever. But probably isn't.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt; Research shows that smartphone users spend an average of 12 minutes a day on phonecalls. They spend more time playing games (14 minutes), listening to music (16 minutes), using social media (17 minutes) and browsing online (25 minutes). The most common use of all mobiles is to check the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; The biggest-selling handset of all time was the dirt-cheap &lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2007/05/07/nokias-1100-handset-over-200-million-served/" title=""&gt;Nokia 1100&lt;/a&gt;, launched in 2003, with over 250m sales. Secondhand 1100 handsets were briefly sold for over $10,000 following a rumour that they could be used to hack online money transfers. They can't. And you can't even beat someone to death with them. Unless you're really strong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt; Internet security firm &lt;a href="http://www.bullguard.com/bullguard-security-center/mobile-security/mobile-threats/mobile-security-what-you-need-to-know.aspx" title=""&gt;Bullguard&lt;/a&gt; estimated there were 2,500 malicious software programs operating on mobile phones in 2010. But then they would say that, wouldn't they?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt; The iPhone was introduced in the US in June 2007. Thousands of people – many of them insufferable – queued overnight to get their hands on the phones first. After a honeymoon period, many re-examined their priorities and began to feel&amp;nbsp;unfulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35&lt;/strong&gt; By the end of 2011, there were 78 mobile phone subscriptions per 100 people in the developing world. In the developed world there were 122 subscriptions per 100. Meaning every fifth person you meet has two phones and is probably a crystal meth dealer/having an affair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt; That or there was one guy in every 100 who went massively overboard and bought 22 backups. Or a guy in every 1,000 who bought 220. Or a guy in every 10,000 – do you see where we're going with this? OK, good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37&lt;/strong&gt; Mobile phones are the&amp;nbsp;fastest-growing technology in &lt;a href="http://www.voanews.com/content/wold-bank-reports-says-mobile-phones-transform-lives-in-developing-africa/1592270.html" title=""&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;. There are around 650 million mobile phone subscribers in sub-Saharan Africa alone and the World Bank credits the mobile phone &lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;industry with creating more than 5m jobs in the continent last year. There's an uplifting note for those of you who have stuck with this list to the&amp;nbsp;end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt; By 2016, annual mobile phone sales are expected to rise to around 2.1bn. Most of that is attributed to Apple's plans for an iPhone for dogs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt; Not really. But you wouldn't be that surprised if they did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;40&lt;/strong&gt; Saved By The Bell's Zack Morris was not a psychopath. Apologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/mobilephones"&gt;Mobile phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/telecoms"&gt;Telecoms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/smartphones"&gt;Smartphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/apple"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/internetphonesbroadband"&gt;Internet, phones &amp; broadband&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/samsung"&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/consumer-affairs"&gt;Consumer affairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/tom-meltzer"&gt;Tom Meltzer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4dbf7d/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/EbNvAkSft1Y" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Apple</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Smartphones</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Technology</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Telecoms</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Mobile phones</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Samsung</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:42:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2013/apr/03/forty-mobile-phone-facts-cellphones-dialling</guid><dc:creator>Tom Meltzer</dc:creator><dc:subject>Technology</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-04T07:50:15Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406627646</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Mobile phones, Telecoms, Smartphones, Apple, Internet, phones &amp; broadband, Samsung, Technology, Consumer affairs, Money</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365005889057/DynaTAC-mobile-phone-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Motorola Archives</media:credit><media:description>A DynaTAC mobile phone, being used in China in 1986 Photograph: Motorola Archives</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365005895422/DynaTAC-mobile-phone-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Motorola Archives</media:credit><media:description>A DynaTAC mobile phone, being used in China in 1986. Photograph: Motorola Archives</media:description></media:content><media:content height="330" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="210" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365006357748/Mobile-phone-in-a-bag-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">TS/Keystone USA/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Early massmarket mobiles incorporated a phone – and a shoulder bag. Photograph: TS/Keystone USA/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365006241562/1990-mobile-phone-user-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Rex Features/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>It's 1990 and people with sore arms are doing business on their mobiles. Photograph: Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365006123520/iPhone-camera-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Scott Olson/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Taking a picture on a blinged-up iPhone during the Republican National Convention in 2012. Photograph: Scott Olson/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2013/apr/03/forty-mobile-phone-facts-cellphones-dialling</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Paolo Di Canio insists he does not support 'the ideology of fascism'</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/bNPO1iyvrIk/paolo-di-canio-ideology-fascism</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/59681?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Apaolo-di-canio-ideology-fascism%3A1889102&amp;ch=Football&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Paolo+Di+Canio%2CSunderland+%28Football%29%2CRace+issues+%28News%29%2CFootball%2CWorld+news%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Press+Association&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+04%3A14&amp;c8=1889102&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Paolo+Di+Canio+insists+he+does+not+support+%27the+ideology+of+fascism%27&amp;c66=Sport&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FSport%2FFootball%2FPaolo+Di+Canio" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;• Di Canio responds to 'vicious and personal accusations'&lt;br /&gt;• Sunderland manager: 'I am not racist … I respect everyone'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paolo Di Canio has attacked what he called the "vicious and personal accusations" made against him since he took the Sunderland job, denying he is racist and insisting: "I do not support the ideology of fascism."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Di Canio's &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/31/paolo-di-canio-sunderland-talks-manager" title=""&gt;appointment to the role&lt;/a&gt; prompted a wave of criticism. The former foreign secretary David Miliband &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/apr/01/david-miliband-resign-sunderland-di-canio" title=""&gt;resigned as Sunderland's vice-chairman&lt;/a&gt;, and the Durham Miners' Association &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/apr/02/paolo-di-canio-sunderland-miners-banner" title=""&gt;wrote to the club&lt;/a&gt; to attack the decision as an insult to those from the north-east who fought and died fighting fascism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Di Canio refused to confirm or deny whether he was a fascist at &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/apr/02/paolo-di-canio-sunderland-manager" title=""&gt;a news conference on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; but has previously stated he is "a fascist but not a racist". He has also been pictured giving a fascist salute to Lazio ultras and photographed attending the funeral of a leading Italian fascist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, in a statement on &lt;a href="http://www.safc.com/news/club-news/2013/april/statement-from-paolo-di-canio" title=""&gt;Sunderland's website&lt;/a&gt;, Di Canio said: "I have clearly stated that I do not wish to speak about matters other than football, however, I have been deeply hurt by the attacks on the football club.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This is a historic, proud and ethical club and to read and hear some of the vicious and personal accusations is painful. I am an honest man, my values and principles come from my family and my upbringing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I feel that I should not have to continually justify myself to people who do not understand this, however I will say one thing only – I am not the man that some people like to portray. I am not political, I do not affiliate myself to any organisation, I am not a racist and I do not support the ideology of fascism. I respect everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I am a football man and this and my family are my focus. Now I will speak only of football."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier on Wednesday the dean of Durham had &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/apr/03/paolo-di-canio-dean-durham" title=""&gt;increased the pressure on Di Canio to make a statement&lt;/a&gt;, calling on Sunderland's new manager to renounce fascism publicly or risk being associated with "toxic far-right tendencies".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Very Reverend Michael Sadgrove, a Sunderland supporter and the son of a Jewish war refugee, said he was struggling to stay loyal to the club and that he found Di Canio's previous "self-confessed fascism deeply troubling".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his open letter to Di Canio, the dean of Durham wrote: "Fascism was nearly the undoing of the world. It cost millions of innocent lives. Mussolini, who you say has been deeply misunderstood, openly colluded with it. You are said to wear a tattoo DUX which speaks for itself. This all adds up to what I find baffling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"You say that you are not a racist, but it needs great sophistication to understand how fascism and racism are ultimately different. I can promise you that this distinction will be lost on the people of the North East where the British National Party is finding fertile ground in which to sow the seeds of its pernicious and poisonous doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"You did not necessarily know this before you came. But I believe that unless you clearly renounce fascism in all its manifestations, you will be associated with these toxic far-right tendencies we have seen too much of in this region."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/paolo-di-canio"&gt;Paolo Di Canio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/sunderland"&gt;Sunderland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/race"&gt;Race issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4c53fc/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990920871/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4c53fc/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990920871/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4c53fc/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990920871/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4c53fc/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/bNPO1iyvrIk" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Sunderland</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Race issues</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Football</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Paolo Di Canio</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:29:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/apr/03/paolo-di-canio-ideology-fascism</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>Football</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T16:29:09Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406628812</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Paolo Di Canio, Sunderland, Race issues, Football, World news, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/columnists/2013/4/3/1365002212337/Paolo-Di-Canio-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Lee Smith/Action Images</media:credit><media:description>Paolo Di Canio, pictured during his first Sunderland training session, has denied supporting fascism. Photograph: Lee Smith/Action Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/columnists/2013/4/3/1365002218715/Paolo-Di-Canio-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Lee Smith/Action Images</media:credit><media:description>Paolo Di Canio, pictured during his first Sunderland training session, has denied supporting fascism. Photograph: Lee Smith/Action Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/apr/03/paolo-di-canio-ideology-fascism</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Eurozone crisis live: Portuguese government faces no-confidence vote</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/GWkTJl-X_3c/eurozone-crisis-live-portuguese-government-no-confidence-vote</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prime minister Passos Coelho is expected to survive fourth bid to oust him from power – but vote will destroy consensus in crisis-hit state&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/josephine-moulds"&gt;Josephine Moulds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/nickfletcher"&gt;Nick Fletcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4778c5/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990904552/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4778c5/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990904552/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4778c5/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990904552/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4778c5/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/GWkTJl-X_3c" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Blogposts</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Minute by minutes</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Eurozone crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Portugal</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:15:34 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/apr/03/eurozone-crisis-live-portuguese-government-no-confidence-vote</guid><dc:creator>Josephine Moulds, Nick Fletcher</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T16:15:42Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>406597340</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Eurozone crisis, Portugal, Business, World news, Europe</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364972628947/6c187649-e630-4388-9ccc-2bf6bcb8cbe0-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Armando Franca/AP</media:credit><media:description>A demonstrator wearing a mask of Portuguese prime minister Pedro Passos Coelho, carries a sign with the words "Leader of organized crime against the people", at a protest in Lisbon last week. Photograph: Armando Franca/AP</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/apr/03/eurozone-crisis-live-portuguese-government-no-confidence-vote</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Iain Banks diagnosed with gall bladder cancer</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/IXCl2mwHLek/iain-banks-gall-bladder-cancer</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/51554?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aiain-banks-gall-bladder-cancer%3A1888899&amp;ch=Books&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Iain+Banks+%28Author%29%2CBooks%2CCulture%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Alison+Flood%2CClaire+Armitstead&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+12%3A20&amp;c8=1888899&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Iain+Banks+diagnosed+with+gall+bladder+cancer&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FBooks%2FIain+Banks" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Scottish author unlikely to live longer than a year and latest novel The Quarry set to be his last, he revealed on his website&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iain Banks, whose darkly humorous presence has enlivened Scottish literature for 30 years, has announced he is "officially very poorly" with gall bladder cancer and may have only months to live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks, 59, is recovering from jaundice caused by a blocked bile duct. "But that – it turns out – is the least of my problems," he said on his website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The author's trademark deadpan humour was to the fore as he broke the news: "I've withdrawn from all planned public engagements and I've asked my partner Adele if she will do me the honour of becoming my widow (sorry – but we find ghoulish humour helps)," he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His website soon broke under pressure from wellwishers who wanted to read the news and leave tributes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks has delighted fans with his prolific output under two names, and outraged literary puritans with his blithe assertion that he aimed to devote no more than three months a year to writing, because there were so many more interesting things to do – like driving fast cars and playing with fancy technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it must have seemed a very black joke indeed when he discovered a back problem he had ascribed "to the fact I'd started writing at the beginning of [January] and so was crouched over a keyboard all day" was something much more serious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"When it hadn't gone away by mid-February, I went to my GP, who spotted that I had jaundice. Blood tests, an ultrasound scan and then a CT scan revealed the full extent of the grisly truth by the start of March," he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I have cancer. It started in my gall bladder, has infected both lobes of my liver and probably also my pancreas and some lymph nodes, plus one tumour is massed around a group of major blood vessels in the same volume, effectively ruling out any chance of surgery to remove the tumours either in the short or long term."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said he and his new wife intend "to spend however much quality time I have left seeing friends and relations and visiting places that have meant a lot to us".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His publishers, meanwhile, are doing all they can to bring forward the publication date of his new novel, The Quarry, "by as much as four months, to give me a better chance of being around when it hits the shelves".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks, who made his literary debut in 1984 with The Wasp Factory, is really two authors: he writes bestselling, mainstream, literary fiction as Iain Banks, and award-winning science fiction as Iain M Banks, about the Culture universe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last summer he described his development as a writer in a typically jocular column for the Guardian Review book club, which featured the first of his Culture novels, Use of Weapons. "The original draft … dates from 1974 and was packed with purple prose of the look-I've-got-a-thesaurus-and-I'm-going-to-use-it/never-use-one-adjective-when-six-will-do school. (Oh, I should add that, having written three unpublished novels by this time, one of them immensely long, and a 30,000-word novella, I must have decided that writing one book at a time was somehow too easy, so when I started writing UoW I started another novel at the same time.)"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His happy-go-lucky front conceals a stubborn streak, which he also revealed in the column, recalling how he had initially ignored the advice of two mentors – science fiction writer Ken MacLeod and publisher James Hale – as to how to liberate the novel from its "manically complicated structure that was really only comprehensible with a diagram". Having initially told both men "they were mad", he eventually realised they might have a point. "As a result, what may still be my best SF novel is largely the work of others."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MacLeod, the award-winning Scottish science fiction author, who is a friend of Banks from high school days, said the support went both ways. "It's very hard to take. Iain has been a tremendous support and encouragement over the years. You couldn't ask for a better friend, and I'm just holding out for a statistically improbable recovery."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks said he was still deciding whether to undergo chemotherapy "to extend the amount of time available". He told friends and colleagues about his cancer diagnosis a few weeks ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The way Iain has reacted to his situation is not really with a sense of unfairness but more that it's just the way the universe works, the way matter works, that there's nobody out to get us, nobody to blame for it all," said MacLeod. "It's a very courageous and stoical attitude in his situation. There's no doubting the style of the man. What you see is what you get, and the Iain who comes across in his books is very much how he is."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MacLeod said Banks thought of himself as principally a science fiction writer who happened to have published a literary novel first. "He wrote several of the Culture novels in first drafts before The Wasp Factory and he got many rejections. He was almost embarrassed when he wrote a mainstream novel in The Wasp Factory and wondered if his friends would think he was selling out."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks's friend Ian Rankin, creator of the archetypal Scottish detective Inspector Rebus, said he preferred the literary novels to what Banks called his "skiffy" [sci-fi] books. "The exciting thing about reading Iain Banks is that you never know what kind of book it's going to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It could be weird, it could be other-worldly, it could be literary fiction, a family saga, about a disc jockey – you don't know what you're going to get, so every time a new book comes out there was that excitement."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rankin said he and Banks were part of a group of writers who would get together "fairly regularly, either for a few beers in Edinburgh, or a curry."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"He has this huge belly laugh with his head thrown back … He's a really interesting guy to spend time with – a mind fizzing with energy and ideas, with a childlike wonder at the world. He's also quite engaged with politics – I remember him destroying his passport in protest at what he saw as Tony Blair's warmongering, and then suddenly realising he needed it for a tour to Australia. He wears his politics and his passion on his sleeve, and he's full of quirks – really engaging quirks. He was attempting at one point to drive along every single road in Scotland, for example, keeping very detailed road maps."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rankin said Banks's comment about asking Adele if she would do him the honour of "becoming my widow" was typical of the author.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"That combination of the macabre with the comedic is something he pulled off time and again in his fiction," said Rankin. "He's taken it with good grace and humour and stoicism. I hope I have the chance to have that drink with him in Edinburgh."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks wrote an exploration of the history of malt whisky, Raw Spirit, which gave him an excuse to expound his political beliefs. He began his journey, shortly after Iraq had been invaded, in a car festooned with anti-war posters. Given its timing, he wrote, the book "can't help being about the war", but then whisky had always been "up to its pretty bottle neck" in politics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days, Banks flaunts his political views with a FTT (Fuck the Tories ) T-shirt. But a courteous side was shown in his statement that the treatment he had received from the NHS in Scotland had been "exemplary, and the standard of care deeply impressive. We're all just sorry the outcome hasn't been more cheerful."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's very moving indeed how many people are very sad," said MacLeod. "Everybody who knows him is just devastated by this."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks's statement was reposted on a new website called &lt;a href="http://friends.banksophilia.com/guestbook/" title=""&gt;Banksophilia: Friends of Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt;, which has been set up for friends, family and fans to leave messages and check his progress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/iainbanks"&gt;Iain Banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/alisonflood"&gt;Alison Flood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/clairearmitstead"&gt;Claire Armitstead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a49ecce/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990917840/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49ecce/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990917840/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49ecce/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990917840/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49ecce/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/IXCl2mwHLek" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Books</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Iain Banks</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:57:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2013/apr/03/iain-banks-gall-bladder-cancer</guid><dc:creator>Alison Flood, Claire Armitstead</dc:creator><dc:subject>Books</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-04T06:52:38Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406611965</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Iain Banks, Books, Culture, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364987398119/Iain-Banks-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Murdo Macleod/Murdo Macleod</media:credit><media:description>Iain Banks has withdrawn from public engagements and has asked his partner Adele 'if she will do me the honour of becoming my widow'. Photograph: Murdo MacLeod</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2013/apr/03/iain-banks-gall-bladder-cancer</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Farmers call for help over mounting sheep deaths</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/8v-XoPNpiNc/farmers-help-sheep-deaths</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/94526?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Afarmers-help-sheep-deaths%3A1889129&amp;ch=Environment&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Farming+%28environment%29%2CEnvironment%2CAnimals+%28News%29%2CWeather+UK+%28News%29%2CUK+news%2CRural+affairs%2CAgriculture+%28Science%29&amp;c5=Environment+Conservation%2CWildlife+Conservation%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=Sarah+Butler&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+04%3A55&amp;c8=1889129&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Farmers+call+for+help+over+mounting+sheep+deaths&amp;c66=Environment&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FEnvironment%2FEnvironment%2FFarming" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Total of 150,000 dead animals during recent snow excludes losses from badly hit regions where farms remain unreachable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Farmers are calling on the government to help them with at least £2.5m in costs from the death of 20,000 more sheep and lambs than usual during the recent heavy snows across England and Wales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least 15.5% more dead sheep and lambs were picked up under the National Fallen Stock Company scheme, which co-ordinates collectors around the country, in the first three months of this year compared with the same period last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The service warned that the total of about 150,000 dead animals excluded losses from the most badly hit regions, where snow is still covering dead animals and some farms remain unreachable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael Seals, chairman of the National Fallen Stock Company, said he expected there would be a significant rise in the number of animals needing to be dealt with this month as most of those collected so far had died as a result of continued bad weather before the heaviest snow falls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's a disaster, that's it and, as in all disasters, the full impact is never immediate," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Farmers Union (NFU) said farmers in affected areas, such as north Wales, south-west Cumbria, Shropshire and Staffordshire, were likely to pay at least £500,000 between them for dead animals to be collected, while they would lose more than £2m in sales at market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One Cumbrian farmer who lost 80 ewes said he would have to pay £2,000 to have them collected, a hefty fee when the average profit of a livestock farm is just £14,000, according to government figures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NFU president Peter Kendall was expected to meet Owen Paterson, the environment secretary, on Thursday in an attempt to organise a free collection service. It said £5m had been made available in Northern Ireland and £500,000 in Scotland to fund similar schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government said on Wednesday that it would allow farmers in difficult to reach parts of England and Wales to burn or bury dead animals on their farms, a practice usually banned. It has also asked the National Fallen Stock Company to consider reducing costs for multiple collections of dead animals from one farm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NFU, however, said it would not be practical for farmers to bury large numbers of animals, particularly in areas where the ground was frozen solid, and farmers were struggling to cope with the cost of disposing of animals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peter Garbutt, chief livestock adviser for the NFU, said: "There might not be snow in Westminster but there is a massive problem in other areas of the country. Very little stock has been collected so far as farmers are still trying to pull animals out of snow drifts and gather them for collection."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The loss of animals could potentially lead to higher lamb prices this summer when farmers would normally be delivering the bulk of their animals to market. Already wholesale auction prices have risen 70% since the beginning of this year to more than £85 a lamb because the weather has caused difficulties in transporting animals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Garbutt said supply would be hit by the loss of spring lambs but also the loss of breeding ewes for next year. "The real impact on farming businesses won't come through until later this year," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, with 12m to 14m lambs brought to market every year in the UK, he said it was not clear that the loss of 20,000 animals would affect prices in shops. Other factors, such as the level of imports from New Zealand could have a bigger impact. Oversupply of lamb from the other side of the world has driven a boom in sales of the meat in the UK, thanks to a wave of retail price cuts in recent weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/farming"&gt;Farming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/animals"&gt;Animals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/weather"&gt;Weather&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/ruralaffairs"&gt;Rural affairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science/agriculture"&gt;Agriculture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/sarahbutler"&gt;Sarah Butler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4cada5/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/8v-XoPNpiNc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Farming</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Rural affairs</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Animals</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Weather</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science">Agriculture</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:55:21 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/apr/03/farmers-help-sheep-deaths</guid><dc:creator>Sarah Butler</dc:creator><dc:subject>Environment</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:06:09Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406630680</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Farming, Environment, Animals, Weather, UK news, Rural affairs, Agriculture</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365004465853/The-loss-of-animals-could-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Ian Forsyth/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>The loss of animals could potentially lead to higher lamb prices this summer. Photograph: Ian Forsyth/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365004473004/The-loss-of-animals-could-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Ian Forsyth/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>The loss of animals could potentially lead to higher lamb prices this summer. Photograph: Ian Forsyth/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/2013/apr/03/farmers-help-sheep-deaths</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Joss Stone plotters convicted of conspiracy to murder</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/_WOQNvGiq2s/joss-stone-plotters-convicted-murder</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/83272?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ajoss-stone-plotters-convicted-murder%3A1889066&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Crime+-+UK+%28News%29%2CUK+news%2CMusic%2CCulture&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Steven+Morris%2CCaroline+Davies&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+03%3A34&amp;c8=1889066&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Joss+Stone+plotters+convicted+of+conspiracy+to+murder&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FCrime" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Junior Bradshaw and Kevin Liverpool found guilty of plot to abduct and kill singer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/joss-stone-would-be-killers-jumbled" title=""&gt;How the would-be killers' disorganised plot unfolded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One man has been jailed for life and another awaits sentence after being convicted of conspiring to rob and kill the singer Joss Stone in a plot that, at times, bordered on a sinister farce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kevin Liverpool, 35, and Junior Bradshaw, 32, planned to decapitate the pop star and dump her body, but were stopped by police within a few miles of her rural Devon home after a series of blunders aroused suspicions. A jury took four hours on Wednesday to convict the two of conspiracy to murder and conspiracy to rob after a three-week trial at Exeter crown court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sentencing Liverpool to a minimum 10&amp;nbsp;years and eight months before being eligible for parole, Judge Francis Gilbert QC told him: "You intended to rob her and kill her and dump her body in the river, according to your words, and then leave the country with your accomplice Junior Bradshaw." Sentencing on Bradshaw was adjourned to a later date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trial heard the would-be killers crashed as they drove to the scene of their planned crime and later got lost and had to ask for directions. They made no real attempt to hide an arsenal of weapons packed in their battered old Fiat Punto and helped detectives enormously by detailing their scheme to kill the singer – real name Jocelyn Stoker – in a bundle of notes culminating in one saying: "Once Jocelyn's dead … find a river to dump her."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the day of their capture, Stone was at home relaxing. She had recently launched her own label, Stone'd Records, and had finished her fifth album LP1 in Nashville.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unemployed assailants – childhood friends who shared a one-bedroom flat in the Longsight area of Manchester – left home at 2am on 13 June 2011 in their newly purchased car and headed for the Cullompton area of Devon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They were armed with a samurai sword, hammers, a metal spike and knife and equipped with balaclavas, gloves, body bags, gaffer tape and a roll of plastic bags. They also had maps showing the area where the singer lived, including one marked: "Here Joss Stone."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stopping at a service station on the M5 in Gloucestershire at dawn, they filled up with petrol and drove off without paying. As they left the service station Bradshaw crashed into metal railings and a mechanical digger. The front of the vehicle was badly damaged and Gloucestershire police attended. Officers said they would report the pair for motoring offences but did not believe the vehicle could be moved – and did not know they had previously left the service station without paying – so departed without searching the car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plot could have stopped there. But Liverpool and Bradshaw were nothing if not persistent. They got the car back on the road and arrived in Devon two hours later. However the lanes around Stone's home are narrow, complicated and confusing, and they got lost. In desperation they showed a postman a picture of Stone asking him where she lived, but he told them he did not know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, three residents seeing them in their car appearing "agitated and behaving abnormally" all called police. A patrol car stopped the Fiat. The weapons and equipment were found and the pair were arrested for possessing offensive weapons and going equipped. As police searched the car more carefully – and later the men's flat in Manchester – they realised that something bigger than a robbery had been in the offing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the flat were a crossbow, a BB gun, and notes, one of which read: "Joscelyn [sic] Stoker … RIP for ever" and: "I don't kill just for dollars, only for good cause or reason." One mentioned decapitation and another read: "Once Jocelyn's dead … find a river to dump her." They also described her as a "she-devil" and took umbrage at her links to the monarchy (Stone has sung for the royals and was invited to Prince William's wedding). "Invited to Will's wedding by Queen. Where's the sense in that?" mused one note.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When she gave evidence, Stone told the jury she had been enjoying a "really nice" day until police banged on her door and told her they believed Liverpool and Bradshaw had been planning to rob her. It got worse when they returned later and told her that, actually, the pair had been planning to kill her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two refused to reveal their motivation. They did not appear to be fixated on Stone, and they did not even have copies of her CDs. Detectives have not ruled out others may have been involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liverpool has previous convictions for assault and having bladed articles or knives in public places. In 2010 he was given a community sentence with a mental health requirement. Bradshaw has an IQ level often associated with a learning disability and has been diagnosed with schizophrenia. He has been jailed 11 times for persistently breaching a court order after being convicted of exposing himself on the steps of Leeds town hall in 2006. After he was found sleeping rough in London and appearing at the Old Bailey, he was given a hospital order, and cared for in a mental health unit in Manchester between June 2009 and April 2010. On his discharge he went to stay with Liverpool, and stopped taking his medication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By January 2011, police believe, the conspiracy plot was hatched. The pair had no computer at the flat. Instead Liverpool used a computer at his local library to research various artists, from Girls Aloud to Beyoncé, Dizzee Rascal and Eminem, before they fixed on Stone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Texts to contacts in Manchester found by the police showed Liverpool had tried to source semi-automatic guns, silencer and night-vision kit. Bradshaw's fingerprints were not found on any of the weapons nor could any text messages or notes relating to the plot be attributed to him directly. He told the jury he had not even heard of Joss Stone before he was arrested and was just on a "day out".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sentencing Liverpool the judge said it was clear he had been planning to rob someone of what he "hoped would be in excess of £1m". He had chosen Stone as a "random target" because he thought she was wealthy and assumed "she was a friend of the royal family" and would be able to give them that sort of amount.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said Liverpool had recruited Bradshaw into the scheme. "It may have been … 'a crazy scheme from a crazy person and must be likely to fail' but when you decided to travel from Manchester to Devon you intended to carry it out," he said. He was considering a hybrid sentence for Bradshaw, meaning he would receive a custodial sentence but would most likely serve it in a secure psychiatric unit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stone lived among the community where she ran an "open house" to which neighbours were encouraged to pop in. She told the court she did not have a proper lock on her door or set her alarm. "But I do now," she added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement after the verdicts, she said: "I am relieved the trial is now over and that these men are no longer in a position to cause harm to anyone".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/ukcrime"&gt;Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/stevenmorris"&gt;Steven Morris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/carolinedavies"&gt;Caroline Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4bed62/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990907011/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4bed62/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990907011/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4bed62/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990907011/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4bed62/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/_WOQNvGiq2s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music">Music</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Crime</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/joss-stone-plotters-convicted-murder</guid><dc:creator>Steven Morris, Caroline Davies</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406626463</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Crime, UK news, Music, Culture</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/27/1364394884239/Joss-Stone--001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Ian West/PA</media:credit><media:description>Joss Stone encouraged neighbours to drop in and never locked her door. Photograph: Ian West/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/joss-stone-plotters-convicted-murder</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Spain's Princess Christina named as suspect in corruption case</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/E6xvBVrLMfs/spain-princess-christina-suspect-corruption</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/17118?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aspain-princess-christina-suspect-corruption%3A1889093&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Spain+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CEurope+%28News%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Giles+Tremlett&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+04%3A30&amp;c8=1889093&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Spain%27s+Princess+Christina+named+as+suspect+in+corruption+case&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FSpain" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Royal to give evidence on her role in not-for-profit foundations amid allegations of corruption and money laundering&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ı&lt;/strong&gt;Allegations of corruption and tax fraud struck at the heart of Spain's royal family on Wednesday as the king's daughter, Princess Cristina, was formally named as a suspect in a court investigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dramatic decision by investigating magistrate José Castro will see the princess called to give evidence at a courthouse in Palma de Mallorca, capital of the Balearic Isles, on 27 April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision is a blow for King Juan Carlos, as a once model royal family begins to buckle under the weight of public scandal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A spokesman at the king's Zarzuela Palace in Madrid expressed surprise at the decision. "The royal household is in absolute agreement with a decision by state anti-corruption prosecutors to appeal against the decision," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Princess Cristina, aged 47, must explain her role as a board member of a non-profit foundation set up by her husband, former Olympic handball player Iñaki Urdangarin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Castro said that, by lending her name and titles to her husband's business affairs, Princess Cristina may have aided and abetted his allegedly crooked dealings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urdangarin is under investigation for allegedly using not-for-profit companies and foundations to strike deals involving millions of euros of taxpayers money with corrupt regional officials in Valencia, the Balearic Islands and Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also allegedly committed tax fraud and syphoned money off to offshore bank accounts and his own companies, including one co-owned by his wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Castro said Princess Cristina's name may have helped persuade private companies and corrupt politicians to "forget the necessary administrative channels and controls, and for her to profit – along with her husband – from that".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urdangarin told the magistrate his wife did not know how the supposedly not-for-profit foundation where she was a board member was run. But Castro listed 14 reasons to challenge that – pointing out that deals were negotiated with politicians at the royal family's palaces and that, according to witnesses, the king had expressed his concern.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spain's media immediately splashed the news over websites and journalists gathered outside the couple's €6m Barcelona home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Urdangarin is reportedly struggling to come up with his share of the €8.1m bail set for him and his former business partner Diego Torres, who both deny the allegations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Court evidence published by El País newspaper revealed that the royal secretary who works with the princess had told Castro the king did not know his daughter was involved in her husband's business dealings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Republican deputies in parliament welcomed the decision to make the princess – who will visit the court on a Saturday so that special security measures can be set up – declare before the investigating magistrate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Better late than never," said the leader of the United Left coalition in parliament, Cayo Lara. "Perhaps, with this, the king's words about us all being equal before the law are being proved."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Spanish legal system, an investigating magistrate can declare someone to be a suspect when they are under investigation. This does not necessarily mean they will be charged, but points to evidence that raises a suspicion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/spain"&gt;Spain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/gilestremlett"&gt;Giles Tremlett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4c72b3/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/E6xvBVrLMfs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Spain</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:30:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/spain-princess-christina-suspect-corruption</guid><dc:creator>Giles Tremlett</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:06:02Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406628358</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Spain, World news, Europe</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365001866935/Spain-Princess-Christina--003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Bertil Ericson/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Princess Cristina must give evidence on her role in not-for-profit foundations set up by her husband, former Olympic handball player Inakî Urdangarin. Photograph: Bertil Ericson/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1365001873131/Spain-Princess-Christina--008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Bertil Ericson/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Princess Cristina must give evidence on her role in foundations set up by her husband, former Olympic handball player Inakî Urdangarin. Photograph: Bertil Ericson/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/spain-princess-christina-suspect-corruption</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Rolling Stones to return to Hyde Park for concert after 44 years</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/2PBJM_R1H10/rolling-stones-hyde-park-concert</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/29600?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Arolling-stones-hyde-park-concert%3A1888985&amp;ch=Music&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Rolling+Stones%2CMusic%2CLondon+%28News%29%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Folk+Rock+Music%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Mark+Brown+%28Guardian+arts+correspondent%29&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+02%3A15&amp;c8=1888985&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Rolling+Stones+to+return+to+Hyde+Park+for+concert+after+44+years&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FMusic%2FThe+Rolling+Stones" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Ageing rock band hit the road again, with Hyde Park concert and Glastonbury festival among gigs lined up for this summer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Rolling Stones are to return to the scene of one of their most memorable and poignant concerts by once more playing at Hyde Park in London, the band has announced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concert, scheduled for 6 July, will take place almost 44 years to the day &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global/from-the-archive-blog/2011/jul/07/from-the-archive-rolling-stones-brian-jones-1969" title=""&gt;since they performed there as young men&lt;/a&gt;, who were at the time mourning the death of guitarist Brian Jones, who drowned in his swimming pool only two days earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many fans wore white in tribute, and Mick Jagger asked the crowd to "cool it for a minute" while he read from Shelley's poem Adonais: "Peace, peace! He is not dead, he doth not sleep."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Observer reporter John Gale wrote: "From far off you might have supposed that this great gathering had come to hear a famed religious leader or some Eastern mystic."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Guardian Richard Gott called the concert a "great and epoch-making event in British social history".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gig also marked the Stones debut for Mick Taylor, Jones's replacement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The newly announced concert follows the five 50th anniversary gigs the band played in London and New York last year, as well as news that they are to play at the Glastonbury festival for the first time in June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jagger said: "We had such a great time playing the five concerts last year, we want to keep it going. Hyde Park holds such great memories for us and we can't think of anywhere better to perform to our UK fans this summer."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guitarist Keith Richards said: "We had such a ball last year and the energy between the band is so good, we can't wait to get back on that stage where the Stones belong."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hyde Park 1969, as it was called, was free – but this year's equivalent will be ticketed. And, in another sign of the times, it will be sponsored by Barclaycard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rob Hallet of promoters AEG Live said: "This will be the biggest gig of the summer in London. The Rolling Stones are a true British institution and the true spirit of rock'n'roll. Their return to Hyde Park is a landmark event."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tickets for the gig go on general sale on Friday 5 April. However, Barclaycard Unwind customers can purchase tickets from 3pm on Wednesday 3 April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/therollingstones"&gt;The Rolling Stones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/london"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/markbrown"&gt;Mark Brown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4b0fb8/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990917245/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b0fb8/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990917245/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b0fb8/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990917245/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4b0fb8/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/2PBJM_R1H10" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music">Music</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">London</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Editorial</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music">The Rolling Stones</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 14:28:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/2013/apr/03/rolling-stones-hyde-park-concert</guid><dc:creator>Mark Brown</dc:creator><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T14:28:13Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406619032</dc:identifier><media:keywords>The Rolling Stones, Music, London, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364993712117/Rolling-Stones-Hyde-Park--003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">David Newell Smith</media:credit><media:description>Rolling Stones, Hyde Park, 1969. Photograph: David Newell Smith</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364993718036/Rolling-Stones-Hyde-Park--008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">David Newell Smith</media:credit><media:description>Rolling Stones, Hyde Park, 1969. Photograph: David Newell Smith/Observer</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364993626731/Rolling-Stones-frontman-M-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Chris Walter/WireImage</media:credit><media:description>Mick Jagger reads the poem Adonais in tribute to guitarist Brian Jones. Photograph: Chris Walter/WireImage</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2012/12/13/1355370109114/219970ab-0300-44a0-b02d-b67e1ed49f13-460.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">DON EMMERT/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Jagger at the Hurricane Sandy relief concert in New York last year. Photograph: Don Emmert/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/2013/apr/03/rolling-stones-hyde-park-concert</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Australia launches child sex abuse inquiry</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/wwBRG1w8z-I/australia-child-sex-abuse-inquiry</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/36328?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aaustralia-child-sex-abuse-inquiry%3A1889016&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Australia+%28News%29%2CJulia+Gillard%2CAsia+Pacific+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CChildren+%28Society%29%2CSociety&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CChildren+Society&amp;c6=Agencies+in+Melbourne&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+02%3A46&amp;c8=1889016&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Australia+launches+child+sex+abuse+inquiry&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FAustralia" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Prime minister Julia Gillard says royal commission – in which 5,000 victims may give evidence – is 'moral moment' for country&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australia has launched a national inquiry into allegations of child sex abuse in state and religious institutions and NGOs, a process in which more than 5,000 victims are likely to give evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A panel of six commissioners launched the inquiry, known in Australia as a royal commission. Witnesses can be compelled to testify and risk imprisonment for lying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inquiry was unlikely to achieve the late 2015 deadline set by the government because so many people wanted to give evidence, said Justice Pete McClellan, the commission's chairman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;McClellan said he expected at least 5,000 people would want to give evidence, but the number could be much higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The task we have is large; the issues are complex," he said. "But we are now in a position to actively begin the work of gathering the stories and examining the responses of institutions."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prime minister, Julia Gillard, announced the commission in November in the face of a string of sexual abuse accusations against priests and claims of a Roman Catholic church cover-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New South Wales state government had ordered an inquiry a week earlier into allegations of a sexual abuse cover-up by Catholic priests in the Hunter Valley region north of Sydney. Victoria state officials had also begun investigating a separate series of priest sex abuse allegations in their state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the federal inquiry was announced, more than 6,000 people have contacted staff in writing or by phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has offered free legal advice to people who want to make submissions to the inquiry before public hearings begin after September.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gillard said the royal commission was an important "moral moment" for the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It is going to require our country to stare some very uncomfortable truths in the face," she told Australian Broadcasting Corp radio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/australia"&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/julia-gillard"&gt;Julia Gillard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/asia-pacific"&gt;Asia Pacific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/children"&gt;Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4b1af6/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/wwBRG1w8z-I" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Asia Pacific</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Children</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Julia Gillard</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Australia</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:46:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/australia-child-sex-abuse-inquiry</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T13:54:58Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406622521</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Australia, Julia Gillard, Asia Pacific, World news, Children, Society</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364996598940/-Julia-Gillard-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Str/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Julia Gillard announced the commission in November after a string of sexual abuse accusations against Catholic priests. Photograph: Str/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364996605727/-Julia-Gillard-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Str/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Julia Gillard announced the commission in November after a string of sexual abuse accusations against Catholic priests. Photograph: Str/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/australia-child-sex-abuse-inquiry</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Michael Jackson's life to be laid bare once more in $40bn court battle</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/br_NvXxfmLQ/michael-jackson-wrongful-death-lawsuit</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/51914?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Amichael-jackson-wrongful-death-lawsuit%3A1888978&amp;ch=Music&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Michael+Jackson%2CPop+and+rock+%28Music+genre%29%2CCalifornia+%28News%29%2CUS+news%2CWorld+news%2CCulture%2CUS+television+%28TV+and+radio%29&amp;c5=Pop+Music%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CTV&amp;c6=Rory+Carroll&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+02%3A16&amp;c8=1888978&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News%2CFeature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Michael+Jackson%27s+life+to+be+laid+bare+once+more+in+%2440bn+court+battle&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FMusic%2FMichael+Jackson" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Private and public dramas back in the spotlight as King of Pop's mother brings wrongful death suit against concert promoter AEG&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trial has yet to start but already the fans, the satellite trucks and the cameras have staked out the courthouse in downtown Los Angeles for what promises to be Michael Jackson's last and most melancholy show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jackson died four years ago but rival legal teams are preparing to pitch competing versions of his demise in a $40bn lawsuit which will put Jackson's private and public dramas back in the spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/02/showbiz/conrad-murray-talks/index.html"&gt;A bizarre jailhouse serenade on CNN&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday night by Conrad Murray, the doctor convicted in Jackson's death, augured a potentially macabre circus to come. The disgraced doctor sang Nat King Cole's The Little Boy That Santa Claus Forgot in an interview with Anderson Cooper to stress his love for Jackson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Details of Jackson's drug-taking, mental state and lowest moments, including the child molestation charges, are due to be scrutinised anew in a wrongful death lawsuit brought by Jackon's mother, Katherine, against the concert promoter AEG Live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She claims the company was negligent in hiring Murray to care for her son, and pressured Jackson to breaking point while he prepared for a planned series of 50 This Is It comeback shows starting in July 2009 in in London. The $40bn figure is for forfeited earnings and other damages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AEG Live claims Jackson hired Murray, pictured, and that the company could not have anticipated the doctor would prescribe a lethal dose of the surgical anaesthetic propofol for Jackson's insomnia. He died at his home in Los Angeles two weeks before the first scheduled concert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/02/entertainment-us-michaeljackson-trial-idUSBRE9310UF20130402"&gt;Jury selection began on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; in advance of a trial expected to last months and to include testimony from Murray as well as Jackson's mother and children, Prince, 16, and Paris, who turns 15 on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If superior court judge Yvette Palazuelos grants CNN and NBC's request to broadcast live from the courtroom, viewers will have a ringside seat to a tale of greed and duplicity. The question facing jurors – prospective jurors were quizzed about their attitudes to the performer's life and music – will be to decide whose greed and duplicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That of the Jackson family in trying to squeeze the equivalent of Kenya's GDP from the concert promoter? Or that of AEG Live in denying culpability in the 50-year-old singer's death?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I don't know how you can't look to Mr Jackson's responsibility there," AEG's lawyer, Marvin Putnam, &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/01/showbiz/jackson-death-trial/index.html"&gt;told CNN in a pre-emptive media blitz&lt;/a&gt;. The singer had selected Murray himself and was known for eccentric behaviour, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We're talking about Michael Jackson. This is a man who would show up in pyjamas. This is a man who would stop traffic and get out and dance on top of his car. This is a man who would go to public events with a monkey named Bubbles. This is a man who said he slept in an oxygen chamber."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AEG Live's lawyers have signalled they will revisit charges that Jackson molested a 13-year-old boy at his Neverland ranch because it was relevant to his history of drug abuse and psychiatric problems. Jackson was cleared but the case shredded his reputation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AEG team has opposed the request to televise the trial and, have voiced concern that Jackson's children will testify solely to whip up emotions. Jackson family lawyers, who favour the broadcasts, have signalled they will cast the concert promoter as an avaricious corporate bully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key part of their case is an email the promoter's co-CEO, Paul Gongaware, wrote to show director Kenny Ortega 11 days before Jackson's death amid doubts over his ability to perform. "We want to remind [Murray] that it is AEG, not MJ, who is paying his salary. We want to remind him what is expected of him."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ortega, in an email to AEG Live's president, Randy Phillips, worried about the star shivering during rehearsals. "It is like there are two people there. One (deep inside) trying to hold on to what he was, and still can be, and not wanting us to quit him; the other in this weakened and troubled state. I believe we need professional guidance in this matter."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ortega said Jackson had "strong signs of paranoia, anxiety and obsessive-like behavior" and recommended urgent psychiatric help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murray, who was accused of indulging Jackson's demand for drugs while earning $150,000 month as his personal physician, will be the most eagerly awaited witness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He pleaded the fifth amendment during his own trial in 2011 and was sentenced to four years for involuntary manslaughter. In his phone call to CNN he conveyed his version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"My entire approach may not have been an orthodox approach, but my intentions were good." He said other doctors routinely had prescribed Jackson propofol and it was his bad luck to be on duty when it went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I did not agree with Michael, but Michael felt that it was not an issue because he had been exposed to it for years and he knew exactly how things worked … Michael Jackson was not the kind of person you can just say 'Put it down' and he's going to do that."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said he would testify for the Jackson family even though the late singer would not have approved of the trial. "Michael would be absolutely upset, he would be so unhappy with what is happening. Michael said to me 'I no longer want to be a bank for my family.' All we see is the continuation of that."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Murray then sang the Cole Porter song to underline, he said, his humble roots and empathy with Jackson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/michaeljackson"&gt;Michael Jackson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/popandrock"&gt;Pop and rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/california"&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tv-and-radio/us-television"&gt;US television&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/rorycarroll"&gt;Rory Carroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4af0fc/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/br_NvXxfmLQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tv-and-radio">US television</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">California</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music">Michael Jackson</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music">Pop and rock</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:16:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/2013/apr/03/michael-jackson-wrongful-death-lawsuit</guid><dc:creator>Rory Carroll</dc:creator><dc:subject>Music</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T13:18:18Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406617860</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Michael Jackson, Pop and rock, California, United States, World news, Culture, US television</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/4/3/1364993821959/Michael-Jackson-at-Wemble-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Michael Jackson at Wembley Stadium in 1988. Photograph: Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2013/4/3/1364993830263/Michael-Jackson-at-Wemble-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Katherine Jackson's lawsuit claims AEG pressured Michael to breaking point while he prepared for his comeback tour in 2009. Photograph: Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="132" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="220" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2011/9/30/1317385784761/Conrad-Murray--004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Al Seib/AP</media:credit></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/2013/apr/03/michael-jackson-wrongful-death-lawsuit</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Jimmy Savile investigation: former BBC driver charged with sex offences</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/Ur1ie4IXKCc/jimmy-savile-former-bbc-driver</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/55371?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ajimmy-savile-former-bbc-driver%3A1888987&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Media%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly&amp;c6=Josh+Halliday&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+02%3A02&amp;c8=1888987&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Jimmy+Savile+investigation%3A+former+BBC+driver+charged+with+sex+offences&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FMedia%2F" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;David Smith accused of offences that allegedly took place in 1984 and is the first suspect charged under Operation Yewtree&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Josh Halliday &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A former driver for celebrities has been charged with five offences of sexual assault dating back to the 1980s, becoming the first suspect to face charges under the Operation Yewtree investigation into Jimmy Savile and others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;David Smith, who drove BBC personalities including Savile in the 1980s, is accused of committing buggery with a boy aged under 16 years old in July 1984.He has also been charged with two counts of indecent assault and two offences of gross indecency on a boy under the age of 14, the Crown Prosecution Service said on Wednesday. Each of these incidents relate to one alleged victim and are said to have taken place between 1 June and 21 July 1984.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smith, 66, will appear at Westminster magistrates court to face the charges on 8 May. He was arrested on 10 December last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alison Saunders, the chief crown prosecutor for the CPS, said: "The CPS has carefully considered the evidence gathered as part of Operation Yewtree in relation to David Smith, who was employed as a driver at the time of the allegations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The CPS received a file of evidence on 21 December 2012. Further enquiries were necessary and the result of those enquiries was received by the CPS on 18 March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We have concluded, in accordance with the code for crown prosecutors, that there is sufficient evidence for a realistic prospect of conviction, and that it is in the public interest for David Smith to be charged with five offences."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eleven men, including the comedians Freddie Starr and Jim Davidson, have been arrested and bailed since Operation Yewtree was launched last October. Others held include the singer Gary Glitter, publicist Max Clifford and DJ Dave Lee Travis. Davidson, Clifford, Starr and Travis have denied allegations of sexual offences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An 82-year-old man from Berkshire was arrested last week under Operation Yewtree, after being interviewed under caution by police detectives on 29 November. He has been bailed to a date in May pending further police enquiries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of the arrests fall under the Operation Yewtree strand termed "others", meaning that the offences are not alleged to involve Savile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Metropolitan police is investigating a flood of historic complaints of sexual abuse from alleged victims who came forward following ITV1's Exposure documentary on Savile in October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A joint report by Scotland Yard and the NSPCC released in January recorded 214 criminal offences spanning six decades against Savile. Almost 600 people contacted Operation Yewtree with information between October and January, including 450 relating to Savile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The failure to cut short Savile's abuse when he was alive prompted several inquiries into police failures. A damning report released by Her Majesty's Inspectorate of Constabulary in March revealed that Savile could have been stopped in the 1960s but police mishandled evidence and dismissed victims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The findings in this report are of deep concern, and clearly there were mistakes in how the police handled the allegations made against Savile during his lifetime," said Drusilla Sharpling of HMIC last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;•&amp;nbsp;To contact the MediaGuardian news desk email media@guardian.co.uk or phone 020 3353 3857. For all other inquiries please call the main Guardian switchboard on 020 3353 2000. If you are writing a comment for publication, please mark clearly "for publication".&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;• To get the latest media news to your desktop or mobile, follow MediaGuardian on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/mediaguardian" title=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/mediaguardian" title=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/josh-halliday"&gt;Josh Halliday&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4a8281/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/Ur1ie4IXKCc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Media</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:02:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/apr/03/jimmy-savile-former-bbc-driver</guid><dc:creator>Josh Halliday</dc:creator><dc:subject>Media</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:05:55Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406619148</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Media, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Media/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364994014088/Jimmy-Savile-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Gary Calton/Observer</media:credit><media:description>Jimmy Savile Photograph: Gary Calton for the Observer</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Media/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364994021382/Jimmy-Savile-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Gary Calton/Observer</media:credit><media:description>Jimmy Savile investigation: a former BBC driver has been charged under Operation Yewtree. Photograph: Gary Calton for the Observer</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/apr/03/jimmy-savile-former-bbc-driver</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Music school at heart of abuse scandal failed to safeguard pupils, reports find</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/HPWT1MfjEMM/chethams-school-abuse-scandal-reports</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/23102?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Achethams-school-abuse-scandal-reports%3A1888909&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Child+protection+%28Society%29%2CSchools%2CEducation%2CManchester%2CChildren+%28Society%29%2CGreater+Manchester%2CSociety%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEducation+Weekly+Education%2CSchools+Education%2CChildren+Society&amp;c6=Helen+Pidd&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+01%3A50&amp;c8=1888909&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Music+school+at+heart+of+abuse+scandal+failed+to+safeguard+pupils%2C+reports+find&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FChild+protection" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Chetham's school of music in Manchester is criticised for failures of leadership over children's welfare&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Senior staff and governors of a specialist music school at the heart of a child sexual abuse inquiry have failed to ensure the safeguarding of pupils' welfare, two independent reports have found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspectors from &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/interactive/2013/apr/03/manchester-chethams-school-music-document" title=""&gt;Manchester city council's children's services department&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://isiservice.devprocess.com/DownloadReport.aspx?s=0211&amp;t=h&amp;r=Chethams.pdf" title=""&gt;Independent Schools Inspectorate (pdf)&lt;/a&gt; were called to Chetham's school of music in Manchester last month to carry out urgent reviews of child protection procedures at the £31,000-a-year private institution following a number of serious allegations of sex abuse against teachers past and present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Council inspectors concluded that the local authority "is not confident about the overall effectiveness of the leadership and governance of safeguarding arrangements in the school".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They warned: "Arrangements are present to promote a culture and climate of effective safeguarding at Chetham's school of music but the arrangements are not routinely and reliably implemented, robustly applied, monitored or evaluated by the senior leadership team, governors and Feoffees [trustees of the charity which runs the school]."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition the inspectors found "little evidence that the governing body/school committee have sufficiently held the senior leaders of the school to account regarding providing assurances that the current arrangements for safeguarding are actually being implemented, applied robustly, monitored appropriately or evaluated effectively. In the context of recent convictions, allegations and ongoing police investigations, where extra assurances would be expected, this is a cause for concern."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Manchester council report said that if Chetham's were a state school, "the nature of these findings … would lead us to invite the chair of governors or trustees to a formal review meeting to discuss the capacity for governance and senior leadership to address the failings identified" and noted that since the visit the school had begun to implement improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report found "pupils report that they are happy and feel safe and secure in the school".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chetham's accepted the reports but said the inspections were carried out too quickly. A spokeswoman noted that an overwhelming majority of parents and students told inspectors they were satisfied the school provided a safe environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exclusive music school was thrust under an unwelcome spotlight in February when Michael Brewer, formerly director of music at the influential establishment, was found guilty of sexually abusing a student when she was 14 and 15. Last week he was &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/26/chelthams-teacher-michael-brewer-jailed" title=""&gt;sentenced to six years in jail&lt;/a&gt; for what he did to Frances Andrade, a professional violinist who killed herself after giving evidence against him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In early February, another Chetham's teacher, the violinist Wen Zhou Li, was arrested on suspicion of rape. He denies the allegations but has been suspended by the school pending the police investigation. Detectives are also looking into claims made against other current and former teachers at the school, the Guardian understands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following Brewer's conviction the school sought to distance itself from his crimes and draw a line under the past. Claire Moreland, headteacher since 1999, &lt;a href="http://www.chethams.com/news/statements-by-chethams-school-of-music" title=""&gt;issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; on the steps of Manchester crown court in which she declared: "The child protection measures we have in place are robust and extensive and reflect the huge improvements in child protection across the education sector."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet both sets of inspectors found the school had failed as recently as March to follow its own guidelines to keep children safe. They also discovered that no formal, minuted meetings had taken place at the school to discuss the recent allegations and consider changes to its child protection policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspectors discovered a catalogue of worrying evidence, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Chetham's does not meet the national minimum guidelines around safeguarding the welfare of children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Overseas teachers were not properly vetted before starting work at the school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• One foreign member of staff had not been subject to a criminal records bureau check in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The school failed to check out teachers' professional qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The school had taken disciplinary action or issued a suspension against four staff because of concerns about their suitability to work with children between 1999 and 2013, but these incidents were not always properly referred to the local authority as required within good time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The school's procedure for reporting allegations of abuse against members of staff is unclear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The school's procedure for dealing with issues of concern against members of staff is not always carried out in practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• The school's policy and procedures for safeguarding its pupils are in place but they are not robustly understood and followed by all staff and governors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was confusion over whether teachers ever taught pupils at home. Despite some pupils telling inspectors that they regularly had lessons at teachers' houses, this was denied by at least one member of the school's staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Manchester council report states: "There are inconsistencies in relation to the child protection officer, designated governor for safeguarding and the head of academic music's understanding of school policy and procedures for teaching at the home of a tutor. This ranges from an understanding that pupils 'wouldn't ever have home tuition', to it is not encouraged or sanctioned by the school and would only be agreed and arranged by parents, to if there was an exceptional circumstance that required teaching at the home of a tutor, there would be a risk assessment completed and parental consent sought. No reference is made to home tuition in the staff, pupil or parents handbooks. During interviews with pupils some pupils stated that home tuition regularly takes place."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responding to the reports, a school spokeswoman said the school had given "careful and detailed consideration" to the findings. But, she said: "Unfortunately we believe the time allowed for the review was insufficient."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The school had made detailed written representations and submitted further documentation to both sets of inspectors, she said, adding: "There is enormous interest in the school at the current time and it is imperative that Chetham's, and all students, staff and parents associated with it, are treated and represented accurately."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The school was already committed to "a thorough review of our current processes and historic events", she said, and would be seeking a meeting with the Department for Education to discuss the review's findings and share a detailed action plan to demonstrate how it was remedying the issues highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said: "We are determined to ensure that we consistently achieve best practice in safeguarding standards at Chetham's. We are extremely proud of our school, its students and its staff and believe that Chetham's makes an invaluable contribution to the community and the musical life of the nation. However, the safety and happiness of our pupils is our top priority, above all else."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week Moreland, the headteacher, sent out an email to all parents, claiming the police investigation was focusing on events 20 to 40 years ago. After the Guardian &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/26/chethams-music-school-sexual-abuse-inquiry" title=""&gt;pointed out that detectives were looking at allegations relating to incidents as recently as 2006&lt;/a&gt;, Moreland sent out another email the following day, saying that after talking to police she could confirm that "a number of more recent allegations/complaints are being treated as part of their wider investigation".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/childprotection"&gt;Child protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/schools"&gt;Schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/manchester"&gt;Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/children"&gt;Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/greater-manchester"&gt;Greater Manchester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/helenpidd"&gt;Helen Pidd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4ae835/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990924439/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4ae835/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990924439/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4ae835/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990924439/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4ae835/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/HPWT1MfjEMM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Manchester</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Children</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Greater Manchester</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Child protection</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education">Education</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education">Schools</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:50:53 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/apr/03/chethams-school-abuse-scandal-reports</guid><dc:creator>Helen Pidd</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T23:50:00Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406612853</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Child protection, Schools, Education, Manchester, Children, Greater Manchester, Society, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364989444714/Chethams-school-of-music-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dave Thompson/PA</media:credit><media:description>Chetham's school of music in Manchester. Photograph: Dave Thompson/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364989451949/Chethams-school-of-music-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dave Thompson/PA</media:credit><media:description>Chetham's school of music in Manchester. Photograph: Dave Thompson/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/apr/03/chethams-school-abuse-scandal-reports</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Second world war bomb defused near Berlin's main railway station</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/KcHA9T_S_Ec/second-world-war-bomb-berlin</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/37477?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Asecond-world-war-bomb-berlin%3A1888982&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Germany%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CSecond+world+war+%28News%29%2CWeapons+technology%2CTechnology%2CScience&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CCorporate+IT&amp;c6=AP+in+Berlin&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+01%3A47&amp;c8=1888982&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Second+world+war+bomb+defused+near+Berlin%27s+main+railway+station&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FGermany" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Operation to make 100kg Soviet bomb safe disrupts trains and flights and causes nearby buildings to be evacuated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An operation to defuse an unexploded second world war bomb found near Berlin's main railway station has caused trains to be diverted, nearby houses evacuated and flights to the city's main airport to be briefly disrupted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 220lb (100kg) bomb was found on Tuesday night at a building site near the Hauptbahnhof, which stands in a relatively sparsely populated area near what used to be the border between west and east Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts decided to defuse the Soviet bomb at the site, a former freight depot. They evacuated people from nearby buildings and diverted trains heading north to Hamburg. Most trains, however, were able to continue running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a precaution, authorities also stopped planes landing at the city's Tegel airport, a few miles away, during the 30-minute operation to defuse the bomb on Wednesday. It wasn't immediately clear how many flights were delayed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some 150 people who lived nearby waited at a nearby school while the bomb was defused, police spokesman Jens Berger said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allied planes dropped huge quantities of ordnance on Germany during the second world war in an effort to cripple the Nazi war machine. Tens of thousands of unexploded bombs are believed still to be in the ground, 68 years after the end of the war. The explosives are usually defused or detonated by experts without causing injuries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bomb defused on Wednesday, though in a prominent location, was not particularly large or disruptive by German standards. Bomb disposal efforts sometimes require thousands of people to be evacuated as a precaution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2011, 45,000 residents were evacuated from Koblenz – nearly half the city's population – after a 1.8-ton bomb was discovered in the Rhine river.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year the detonation of a wartime bomb in Munich caused fires in several buildings that had been evacuated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/germany"&gt;Germany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/secondworldwar"&gt;Second world war&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science/weaponstechnology"&gt;Weapons technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4ae836/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990924437/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4ae836/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990924437/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4ae836/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990924437/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a4ae836/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/KcHA9T_S_Ec" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Germany</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Technology</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Second world war</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science">Weapons technology</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science">Science</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:47:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/second-world-war-bomb-berlin</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T12:52:15Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406618722</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Germany, Europe, World news, Second world war, Weapons technology, Technology, Science</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364993127411/Berlin-bomb-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Johannes Eisele/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Joerg Neumann of the bomb disposal team poses next to a the defused bomb that was found near Berlin's Hauptbahnhof. Photograph: Johannes Eisele/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364993133499/Berlin-bomb-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Johannes Eisele/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Joerg Neumann of the bomb disposal team poses next to the defused bomb. Photograph: Johannes Eisele/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/second-world-war-bomb-berlin</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Central African Republic hunt for Kony suspended</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/HHwavfH1gkE/central-african-republic-troops-suspend-hunt-kony</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/95483?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Acentral-african-republic-troops-suspend-hunt-kony%3A1888955&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Central+African+Republic+%28News%29%2CAfrica+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CJoseph+Kony%2CAfrican+Union&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Associated+Press&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+01%3A12&amp;c8=1888955&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Central+African+Republic+hunt+for+Kony+suspended&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FCentral+African+Republic" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Hunt for fugitive warlord Joseph Kony on hold because new government said to be not co-operating with African Union mission&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;African troops in Central African Republic have suspended the hunt for the fugitive warlord &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/joseph-kony" title=""&gt;Joseph Kony&lt;/a&gt; because the new government there is not co-operating with the mission, Uganda's top military official said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operations against Kony were put on hold until the mission's status is clarified by the African Union, under whose mandate the forces are deployed in the expansive central African country where &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/26/central-african-republic-turmoil-rebels" title=""&gt;rebels deposed a president and took the capital, Bangui, more than a week ago&lt;/a&gt;, said Ugandan army chief General Aronda Nyakairima.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We put a halt to operations until we consult," Nyakairima said. "We're still there and we are going nowhere until we have consulted. We're officially there under the African Union."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 3,000 African troops, the bulk from Uganda, are currently deployed against Kony's Lord's Resistance Army in Central African Republic, where a former rebel leader named Michel Djotodia has since appointed himself president and &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/01/central-african-republic-leader-government" title=""&gt;announced a new government&lt;/a&gt;. The African Union forces are supported by about 100 US military advisers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nyakairima said Ugandan troops would stay in Central African Republic until the AU clarifies their status. The AU has suspended Central African Republic's membership and imposed travel restrictions on the country's self-appointed leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kony, who over the years has taken advantage of weak governments and porous borders to regroup and recruit fighters, would get a lifeline if those deployed to catch or kill him are forced to leave Central African Republic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be a "catastrophe for civilians in the Central African Republic" if the African troops left the country, said Kasper Agger, a researcher with the US-based Kony watchdog group &lt;a href="http://www.enoughproject.org/" title=""&gt;Enough Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"A full withdrawal of the Ugandans will also mean that the Americans have to leave as well," Agger said. "All the top commanders of the LRA are in the Central African Republic. That is where the centre of gravity of the operations should be. This will only give the LRA a new safe haven."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former Central African Republic President François Bozizé was a strong supporter of the military effort to eliminate the LRA. African and US forces use two military bases in Central African Republic for their operations against Kony, an elusive warlord whose precise whereabouts are not known.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early last year &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/reality-check-with-polly-curtis/2012/mar/08/kony-2012-what-s-the-story" title=""&gt;Kony became the subject of a popular online video by the charity Invisible Children&lt;/a&gt;, which wanted to bring global attention to his many crimes. The LRA is accused of recruiting child soldiers and taking girls as sex slaves in a brutal campaign for power that originated in Uganda in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the LRA continues to abduct children and raid villages in Congo and Central African Republic, the group is not as strong as it once was. Ugandan officials estimate the rebel group's strength at about 250 men, most of them scattered in small groups that are constantly moving in the jungle to elude detection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most LRA fighters are operating in Central African Republic, according to Ugandan officials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/central-african-republic"&gt;Central African Republic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/africa"&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/joseph-kony"&gt;Joseph Kony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/africanunion"&gt;African Union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a4a503c/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/HHwavfH1gkE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">African Union</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Central African Republic</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Joseph Kony</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Africa</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:12:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/central-african-republic-troops-suspend-hunt-kony</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T12:34:01Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406615802</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Central African Republic, Africa, World news, Joseph Kony, African Union</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/cartoon/2013/4/3/1364991035449/Joseph-Kony-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Pool/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Joseph Kony has, over the years, taken advantage of weak governments to regroup and recruit fighters. Photograph: Pool/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/cartoon/2013/4/3/1364991042160/Joseph-Kony-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Pool/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Joseph Kony has, over the years, taken advantage of weak governments to regroup and recruit fighters. Photograph: Pool/Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/apr/03/central-african-republic-troops-suspend-hunt-kony</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Aid from rich countries falls for second year in a row, says OECD</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/XxQCEiRU6oo/aid-rich-countries-falls-oecd</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/60343?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aaid-rich-countries-falls-oecd%3A1888884&amp;ch=Global+development&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Aid%2CGlobal+development%2COECD%2CGlobal+economy+%28Business%29%2CBusiness&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Mark+Tran&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+12%3A41&amp;c8=1888884&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Aid+from+rich+countries+falls+for+second+year+in+a+row%2C+says+OECD&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FGlobal+development%2FAid" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Thinktank says economic crisis in west has brought 4% drop in aid, and spending shift from poorest to middle-income nations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Official development assistance &lt;a href="http://www.oecd.org/newsroom/aidtopoorcountriesslipsfurtherasgovernmentstightenbudgets.htm" title=""&gt;fell by 4% in real terms&lt;/a&gt; last year, following a 2% dip in 2011, but a moderate recovery is expected in 2013, according to the &lt;a href="http://www.oecd.org/" title=""&gt;Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Paris-based thinktank attributed the drop in aid for the second year in a row to the continuing economic crisis and turmoil in Europe. Since reaching a peak in 2010, ODA has fallen by 6% in real terms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excluding 2007, which saw the end of exceptional debt relief operations, the fall in 2012 is the largest since 1997. It is also the first time since 1996-97 that aid has fallen in successive years. However, on the basis of the OECD's Development Assistance Committee (DAC) survey on donors' plans, a moderate recovery in aid levels is expected in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It is worrying that budgetary duress in our member countries has led to a second successive fall in total aid," said Angel Gurría, the OECD secretary general, "but I take heart from the fact that, in spite of the crisis, nine countries still managed to increase their aid. As we approach the 2015 deadline for achieving the millennium development goals [MDGs], I hope that the trend in aid away from the poorest countries will be reversed."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2012, aid provided by members of the DAC – the club of rich countries – came to $125.7bn (£83bn), or 0.29% of their combined gross national income (GNI), well short of the UN target of 0.7%. The 2012 figure was a 4% drop in real terms compared with 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is also a noticeable shift in aid away from the poorest countries and towards middle-income countries, said the OECD. The shift benefited countries such as China, India, Indonesia, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Uzbekistan and Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;By contrast, aid is likely to stagnate to countries with the largest MDG gaps and poverty levels, including sub-Saharan African countries such as Burundi, Chad, Madagascar, Malawi and Niger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bilateral aid to sub-Saharan Africa last year fell 7.9% in real terms to $26.2bn compared with 2011. Aid to the whole continent fell by 9.9% to $28.9bn, following exceptional support to some countries in north Africa after the Arab spring in 2011. Bilateral net ODA to the group of least developed countries (LDCs) also fell, by 12.8% in real terms, to about $26bn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adrian Lovett, Europe executive director at the ONE campaign, said the drop in aid to the LDCs went against the rhetoric of focusing on the needs of the poorest people. "The world's poorest countries are paying a high price for economic failure in the richest," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"These figures show aid for the least developed countries falling more sharply than aid overall. This does not fit the intent of many major donors – to focus increasingly on countries most in need."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new DAC chair, Erik Solheim, urged members to live up to their commitments, and mentioned the UK as a country that had done that despite austerity. "I welcome the efforts of those nine DAC members that increased their aid in 2012, and urge others to increase their aid as soon as their budget circumstances allow," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Maintaining aid is not impossible even in today's fiscal climate. The UK's 2013-14 budget increases its aid to 0.7% of national income, which gives hope that we can reverse the falling trend."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his budget, the chancellor, George Osborne, said Britain would &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development/2013/mar/20/george-osborne-historic-moment-aid" title=""&gt;meet the UN target&lt;/a&gt; set in 1970 this financial year, although this has not gone down well with members of his own party who believe that the aid budget should not be protected when other departments, including defence, are taking hits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;European NGOs criticised governments for trying to balance the books at the expense of poor people. "European leaders are in a scramble to cut what they can, despite the very real damage this could do to the lives and livelihoods of the world's poorest people," said Zuzana Sladkova of Concord, the European NGO umbrella group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Aid has the support of the public in Europe, but support to poor countries is being hit hard by cuts that balance the books on the back of the world's poor."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NGOs are bailing out of projects as a direct result of aid cuts, said Concord, citing &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development/poverty-matters/2013/feb/26/spain-trailblazer-age-aid-austerity" title=""&gt;the example of Spain&lt;/a&gt;, where aid levels have sunk to their lowest level in 22 years. "This has resulted in Spanish NGOs pulling out of developing countries. 68% of NGOs have had to close some of their aid projects on the ground. This is axing life-saving support to some of the poorest people in need," said Mercedes Ruiz-Jimenez, director of the Spanish NGO platform Coordinadora.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ben Jackson, chief executive of Bond, the group of British NGOs, said: "A fall of 4% in global aid in 2012 is very disappointing … It's great news that the UK will reach the 0.7% aid target in 2013, but it is crucial that other EU member states live up to their international commitments. We have only two years left to meet the millennium development goals, and need urgent action to get back on track."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The largest donors, in absolute terms, were the US, the UK, Germany, France and Japan. Denmark, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Norway and Sweden continued to exceed the &lt;a href="http://www.unmillenniumproject.org/press/07.htm" title=""&gt;UN's ODA target of 0.7% of GNI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development/aid"&gt;Aid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/oecd"&gt;OECD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/global-economy"&gt;Global economy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/marktran"&gt;Mark Tran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a49d07c/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990912722/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49d07c/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990912722/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49d07c/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990912722/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49d07c/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/XxQCEiRU6oo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">OECD</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development">Aid</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development">Global development</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Global economy</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 11:41:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development/2013/apr/03/aid-rich-countries-falls-oecd</guid><dc:creator>Mark Tran</dc:creator><dc:subject>Global development</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T14:04:26Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406611041</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Aid, Global development, OECD, Global economy, Business</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Environment/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364987095493/women-farming-a-land-near-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Albert Gonzalez Farran/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>The OECD says aid is likely to stagnate to countries with the largest MDG gaps and poverty levels. Photograph: Albert Gonzalez Farran/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Environment/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364987101555/women-farming-a-land-near-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Albert Gonzalez Farran/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>The OECD says aid is likely to stagnate to countries with the largest MDG gaps and poverty levels. Photograph: Albert Gonzalez Farran/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/global-development/2013/apr/03/aid-rich-countries-falls-oecd</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Mick Philpott was loving father, lawyer tells court in mitigation</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/SghZLrcvxwQ/mick-philpott-loving-father-court</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/91416?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Amick-philpott-loving-father-court%3A1888883&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Crime+-+UK+%28News%29%2CDerby+%28news%29%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Vikram+Dodd&amp;c7=2013%2F04%2F03+12%3A07&amp;c8=1888883&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Mick+Philpott+was+loving+father%2C+lawyer+tells+court+in+mitigation&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FCrime" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Defence says there is no evidence children were harmed deliberately as judge prepares for sentencing, now adjourned to Thursday&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sentencing of Mick and Mairead Philpott, who killed their six children in a house fire, has been adjourned until Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mrs Justice Thirlwall, who heard mitgation from lawyers acting for the couple, said sentencing would take place at 10.30am at Nottingham crown court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court was told on Wednesday that Philpott was a loving father despite a history of violence towards women.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mick and Mairead Philpott, together with Paul Mosley were found guilty on Tuesday of the manslaughter of six children as they slept in a house in Derby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court heard there had been violence in all of Philpott's relationships, which the judge, Mrs Justice Thirlwall, said troubled her: "There has been violence in every single relationship, has there not?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mitigation Philpott's barrister Anthony Orchard QC said he was a very good father who did not mean to harm his children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orchard said the plan to set the fire had gone "disastrously wrong" because it spread too quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Philpott home was set ablaze in a conspiracy involving the parents in May last year. Mick Philpott wanted to frame a former lover, Lisa Willis, for the arson attack as revenge for her leaving him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orchard asked for the minimum term possible for Philpott. Orchard said: "Despite Mr Philpott's faults he was a very good father and loved those children. All the witnesses, even Lisa Willis, agree on this. There is no evidence at any stage that he deliberately harmed any of them."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orchard continued: "He is, as is Mairead, a parent who lost six children. He has never been able to grieve or even to bury them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"His behaviour when he was with the doctors was consistent with extreme grief when he was at the hospital."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orchard said Philpott, 56, would have to live with the jury's verdicts, and the fact that they said he had killed his children.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"He will have to live with the hatred and hostility of the press and the public for the rest of his life," he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The crown outlined Philpott's past offences, which the judge said she would take into account in deciding how long the sentences should be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Philpott has a previous conviction in 1978 for attempting to kill a woman who wanted to leave him, whom he stabbed a dozen times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Philpott, aged 21 at the time of the attack, was convicted of the attempted murder of Kim Hill and of grievous bodily harm to her mother in December 1978. He was sentenced to seven years, with the judge then warning that he was a dangerous man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the attack Hill had to be revived twice and the court heard on Wednesday that she still lived with the effects of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before the murder attempt Philpott had attacked her, breaking her fingers. When Hill wanted to leave him, he became so enraged he decided to kill her so that no other man could have her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orchard said Philpott's conviction for attempted murder was a "long time ago" and there was no evidence of anything like that being repeated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nottingham crown court was told that in 1991 Philpott headbutted someone while working and received a conditional discharge for actual bodily harm. He was also cautioned for attacking his wife after slapping her in the face and dragging her out of the house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2011 he was involved in a road rage incident to which he pleaded guilty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shaun Smith QC, for Mairead Philpott, said she would "forever be known as a child killer", and accepted she faced punishment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said her real sentence would be the loss of her children and that she had been dominated by her husband during their 12-year relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smith told the judge: "There was only one dominant person in that relationship."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added: "She would do whatever he said, whatever he wanted," and described her attempts to keep her husband's affections as "utter folly".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the children led happy lives despite living for a time with their mother, father and their father's girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smith said there was no evidence "any of these children were in any sort of danger or peril prior to that night [of the fire] whatsoever."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said: "They were well looked-after. They were well nourished. They were happy children."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smith said: "There were absolutely no problems as far as these children were concerned [with the living arrangements]; no suggestion they were out on the street causing trouble."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smith told the judge: "The entirety of the evidence in this case is that Mairead Philpott was an extremely good mother to all 11 children. No one, we respectfully submit, can dispute the grief that she feels. Nobody can even understand it. It's palpable. It has been visible."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the sentencing and mitigation the Philpotts were in the dock of the court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Philpott wore a grey suit, pink tie and medallion. His wife wore a black cardigan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manslaughter carries a maximum term of life imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/ukcrime"&gt;Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/derby"&gt;Derby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/vikramdodd"&gt;Vikram Dodd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a49ecca/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990917839/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49ecca/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990917839/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49ecca/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990917839/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a49ecca/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/SghZLrcvxwQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Crime</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Derby</category><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 11:07:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/mick-philpott-loving-father-court</guid><dc:creator>Vikram Dodd</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-04-03T13:37:59Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406611027</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Crime, Derby, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/4/3/1364987201881/Mairead-and-Mick-Philpott-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Rui Vieira/PA</media:credit><media:description>Mairead and Mick Philpott at a press conference after the deaths of their six children in a house fire in Derby. Photograph: Rui Vieira/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/apr/03/mick-philpott-loving-father-court</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
