<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Guardian World News</title><link>http://www.guardian.co.uk</link><description>Latest news and features from guardian.co.uk, the world's leading liberal voice</description><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. 2013</copyright><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 15:21:43 GMT</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 15:21:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><image><title>The Guardian World News</title><url>http://image.guardian.co.uk/sitecrumbs/Guardian.gif</url><link>http://www.guardian.co.uk</link></image><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/theguardian/rss" /><feedburner:info uri="theguardian/rss" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item><title>Saturday clockwatch – live! | John Ashdown</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/p510jm2Q4WU/saturday-clockwatch-live-premier-league</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minute-by-minute report:&lt;/strong&gt; It's another big day at the top and bottom of the Premier League. Follow all the action here&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/johnashdown"&gt;John Ashdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a297e2b/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990803602/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a297e2b/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990803602/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a297e2b/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990803602/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a297e2b/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/p510jm2Q4WU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Blogposts</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Football</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport">Sport</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Minute by minutes</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Premier League</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 15:21:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/30/saturday-clockwatch-live-premier-league</guid><dc:creator>John Ashdown</dc:creator><dc:subject>Football</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T15:21:38Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>406476213</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Premier League, Football, Sport</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Sport/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364648943504/Chelsea-v-Wycombe-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Phil Cole/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Anyone who can tell me why this picture is here wins a prize! (Please note: prize may be 'good vibes', 'respect' or something equally intangible). Photograph: Phil Cole/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/30/saturday-clockwatch-live-premier-league</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Teachers threaten to boycott Ofsted school inspections</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/Ru60TEdASuo/teachers-threaten-boycott-ofsted-inspections</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/28890?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ateachers-threaten-boycott-ofsted-inspections%3A1887731&amp;ch=Education&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Teaching%2COfsted%2CSchools%2CEducation%2CMichael+Gove%2CUnions+%28UK%29%2CPolitics&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CEducation+Weekly+Education%2CSchools+Education&amp;c6=Jessica+Shepherd&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+02%3A39&amp;c8=1887731&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Teachers+threaten+to+boycott+Ofsted+school+inspections&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FEducation%2FTeaching" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;NUT conference overwhelmingly passes resolution calling for abolition of Ofsted and resignation of chief inspector&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teachers have threatened to boycott classroom inspections and called for the resignation of the chief inspector of England's schools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delegates at the National Union of Teachers annual conference in Liverpool said their colleagues were "dropping like flies" due to the pressure of inspections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A boycott of inspections would be illegal, but teachers urged the NUT to investigate "as a matter of urgency" ways in which they could stage a walkout when inspectors arrived at their school.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liam Conway, an NUT member from central Nottinghamshire, told the union's annual conference in Liverpool that teachers should "stop hiding behind legal impediments" to a boycott. "All things being equal, I think we should have boycotted Ofsted years and years ago," he told the conference. "We owe it to all of our teachers who are literally being torn to bits by education secretary Michael Gove and Sir Michael Wilshaw, the chief inspector of England's schools, and their band of crocodiles and lions," he said. "The union must do more to work out a way to boycott Ofsted. It is time to stop hiding behind legal impediments."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conference heard that teacher suicide rates had gone up by 80% amid the increasing pressures of inspections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A resolution calling for the abolition of Ofsted and for the resignation of Wilshaw was overwhelmingly passed. Wilshaw angered teachers by saying high stress levels were a good thing for the profession.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toby Cadoux, an NUT member from Lambeth, south London, described Wilshaw as "an odious creature".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We need to oppose inspection, we need to oppose a target-driven culture, we need to get rid of Sir Michael Wilshaw because he is an odious creature," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We need to reclaim our professionalism. Ofsted needs to wither and die."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Simon Horne, a union member from Haringey, urged caution, suggesting that if the NUT pushed ahead with its campaign it could find itself isolated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"In seeking to oppose everything and showing no willingness to compromise, I think we leave the union isolated," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Horne argued that the union needed to show a "willingness to engage" with Ofsted, saying: "We can't be scared to open up our schools and we should have the professional confidence to be proud of what goes on in our schools."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Ofsted spokeswoman insisted that the inspectorate was there to "champion the right of all children and learners to a good education".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She said: "Sir Michael has said from the outset that any provision that is less than good is not acceptable. That's a tough message, especially for those schools and colleges that have been coasting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's inevitable that when you challenge the system to do better, you will get some pushback."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Ofsted's first priority is to report on whether schools are providing children and young people with the quality of education they deserve," she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Inspectors understand that teaching is hard work and can be stressful and do all they can to put staff at ease."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/teaching"&gt;Teaching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/ofsted"&gt;Ofsted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/schools"&gt;Schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/michaelgove"&gt;Michael Gove&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/tradeunions"&gt;Trade unions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jessicashepherd"&gt;Jessica Shepherd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a2911a7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808295/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2911a7/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808295/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2911a7/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990808295/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2911a7/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/Ru60TEdASuo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education">Ofsted</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Trade unions</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education">Teaching</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education">Education</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Michael Gove</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education">Schools</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 14:39:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/2013/mar/30/teachers-threaten-boycott-ofsted-inspections</guid><dc:creator>Jessica Shepherd</dc:creator><dc:subject>Education</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T14:39:23Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406478776</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Teaching, Ofsted, Schools, Education, Michael Gove, Trade unions, Politics</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364654337380/Sir-Michael-Wilshaw-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:credit><media:description>Sir Michael Wilshaw angered teachers by saying high stress levels were a good thing for the profession. Photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364654343077/Sir-Michael-Wilshaw-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:credit><media:description>Sir Michael Wilshaw angered teachers by saying high stress levels were a good thing for the profession. Photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/2013/mar/30/teachers-threaten-boycott-ofsted-inspections</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Maasai fear Tanzania game reserve will banish them from ancestral land</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/Cezat3eoX9g/maasai-game-hunting-tanzania</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/53704?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Amaasai-game-hunting-tanzania%3A1887679&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Obs&amp;c4=Indigenous+peoples+%28News%29%2CTanzania+%28News%29%2CWildlife+%28Environment%29%2CEnvironment%2CAfrica+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CWildlife+Conservation%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=Jason+Patinkin&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+02%3A00&amp;c8=1887679&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Maasai+fear+Tanzania+game+reserve+will+banish+them+from+ancestral+land&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FIndigenous+peoples" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Tribal leaders vow to resign posts in protest against being denied access to their pastures in 'wildlife corridor' on Serengeti border to make way for Dubai-based luxury safari company&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A battle has erupted in Tanzania over the future of 30,000 Maasai people who claim the expansion of a big-game hunting reserve for foreigners will lead to their eviction from ancestral lands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tanzania's ministry of tourism announced this week that it will set aside 1,500 square kilometres bordering the Serengeti National Park for a "wildlife corridor". The Maasai will as a result be prevented from getting to their pasture land in the corridor, destroying their traditional nomadic cattle-herding lifestyle. Access will however be granted to a Dubai-based luxury hunting and safari company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daniel Ngoitiko, a Maasai politician representing part of the corridor, said the announcement amounted to an existential threat for thousands of Maasai tribespeople. "My people's livelihood depends on livestock totally," he said. "We will die if we don't have land to graze."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NGOs say nearly all of the Maasai living in Loliondo district, where the proposed corridor will be, rely on cattle herding for food and to raise money for expenses such as school fees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fifty-five Maasai leaders have petitioned the government against the corridor, which would place out of bounds savannah that is lush and grassy in the wet season and dusty scrubland in the dry. They have vowed to resign their posts as local administrators at a mass rally and protest in the Loliondo town of Wasso on Tuesday. Ngoitiko, who wraps himself in the traditional bright red cloth of the Maasai, will march 20km with his constituents to the demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ngoitiko said violence could not be ruled out if the government were to proceed. "We will fight against it until the last person is gone," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the passionate resistance to the proposals, the Tanzanian government appears determined to push ahead with the proposed corridor. The minister for natural resources and tourism, Khamis Kagasheki, told one newspaper this week: "If the civic leaders want to resign, they can go ahead. There is no government in the world that can just let an area so important to conservation to be wasted away by overgrazing."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samwel Nangiria, government programme manager for a group of local NGOs, told the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt; that the Maasai lifestyle, which forbids eating wild game, is harmonious with nature. "The government does not appreciate the way that the Maasai is living with wildlife," he said. "They've been using it for centuries, living with wildlife all over."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Maasai have followed seasonal rains with their cattle across what is now northern Tanzania and southern Kenyan since pre-colonial times. But they have been gradually squeezed out of their territory. The process began in 1959 when the colonial British evicted the tribe from the Serengeti.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"My grandfather was born in the Serengeti where the national park is," Ngoitiko said, arguing that the idea of further relocation was unacceptable. "The land we are claiming is ours because we inherited it from our parents."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, of the million-plus Tanzanian Maasai population, at least 66,000 live in the 4,000sq km Loliondo district. The proposed corridor will reduce their land by nearly 40%. The Loliondo highlands are nestled between two jewels of Tanzania's tourist industry – the Serengeti National Park to the west and the Ngorongoro Conservation Area (NCA) to the south. To the east lie the salt flats of Lake Natron, while to the north is the Kenyan border.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crucially, the reduction in land access would come at a time when climate change is already placing the tribe's lifestyle under pressure. Jill Nicholson, programme director for local NGO the Women's Pastoralist Council, said: "The rainy seasons are coming later and that's putting stress on water sources."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The highlands are crucial for the June to November dry season.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The area which is being established in the corridor is used in the dry season grazing," said Nangiria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This is the time they need it most so they can have a fallback. Another reason is the wildebeest are coming to calve in Loliondo, so the Maasai have to have access to the highland to keep their cattle away from possible diseases brought by the migrating wildebeest."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principal hunting outfit which will be able to exploit the corridor is the Ortello Business Corporation of United Arab Emirates. The OBC has operated in Loliondo for 20 years, flying over high-profile clients such as Prince Andrew and the United Arab Emirates royal family on 747s which land on a private airstrip. But their clients' wealth has not filtered down to the Maasai.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ngoitiko said the hunting lodges did not employ local people, and skirmishes had broken out between herders and OBC security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Maasai and national police clashed after the government tried to force evictions, allegedly to allow the OBC to hunt. Ngoitiko's younger brother Paul said he lost 50 cattle because they could not reach pasture. Paul remembers how losing livestock, a source of identity for Maasai men, broke his father's will. "During the morning he would ask, 'how many livestock have died today?' When you mentioned the number he didn't even speak."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul also claims that police burnt down his family's bomas – homes made of mud, thatch, and cow dung. After protests, the government has allowed the people to return, but a court case is still in progress to decide their future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government tried to evict Maasai from Loliondo again last year, but backed down after an &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/aug/15/tanzania-evict-maasai-uae-royals" title=""&gt;outcry led by international advocacy group Avaaz&lt;/a&gt;. According to campaign director Ian Bassin "nearly a million people called on [Tanzanian president Jakaya] Kikwete to stop the evictions of the Maasai. The government is responsiveto global opinion."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kikwete has a record of dismissing the Maasai lifestyle. This month, he told a group of pastoralists that "living a nomadic life is not productive".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul Ngoitiko disagrees, and on Tuesday he will march with his people in protest. "We have our way of living," he said. "Without land we cannot keep livestock, and without livestock it is a kind of death."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/indigenous-peoples"&gt;Indigenous peoples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/tanzania"&gt;Tanzania&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/wildlife"&gt;Wildlife&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/africa"&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jason-patinkin"&gt;Jason Patinkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a2916f2/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/Cezat3eoX9g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Observer</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Indigenous peoples</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Tanzania</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Wildlife</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 14:00:04 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/maasai-game-hunting-tanzania</guid><dc:creator>Jason Patinkin</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T14:00:04Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406468643</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Indigenous peoples, Tanzania, Wildlife, Environment, Africa, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/cartoon/2013/3/29/1364596601983/Maasai-tribesman--003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Radu Sigheti/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>A Maasai tribesman stands beside his cattle near a water point in Makindu, southwest of Nairobi. Photograph: Radu Sigheti/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Business/Pix/cartoon/2013/3/29/1364596607751/Maasai-tribesman--008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Radu Sigheti/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>A Maasai tribesman stands beside his cattle near a water point in Makindu, southwest of Nairobi. Photograph: Radu Sigheti/Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/maasai-game-hunting-tanzania</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Russia urges US and North Korea to show restraint</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/hW02eqo1UQc/russia-us-north-korea-restraint</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/88121?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Arussia-us-north-korea-restraint%3A1887723&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=North+Korea+%28News%29%2CAsia+Pacific+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CSouth+Korea+%28News%29%2CUS+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMotorsport&amp;c6=Ewen+MacAskill&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+01%3A58&amp;c8=1887723&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Russia+urges+US+and+North+Korea+to+show+restraint&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FNorth+Korea" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;'We hope that all parties will exercise maximum responsibility,' says Russian foreign ministry as tensions continue to rise&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia has urged the US and North Korea to show restraint after Pyongyang said it was entering a "state of war" with South Korea in a further escalation of its bellicose rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We hope that all parties will exercise maximum responsibility and restraint and no one will cross the point of no return," said senior Russian foreign ministry official Grigory Logvinov on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday the Pentagon declared that the US was flly capable of defending itself and its allies against a missile attack from North Korea, whose leader, Kim Jong-un, had declared that rockets were ready to be fired at American bases in the Pacific. Kim's words came in response to the US flying two nuclear-capable B-2 stealth bombers over the Korean peninsula this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, a spokesman for the Foreign Office warned North Korea that its statements would lead to further isolation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We have made clear to North Korea that its long-term interests will only be served by constructive engagement with the international community. These threatening statements will only seek to isolate it further," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The armistice agreement has enabled the Korean peninsula to benefit from 60 years' peace. Maintaining it is in the best interests of all."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josh Earnest, a White House spokesman, told reporters travelling with Barack Obama on Air Force One to Miami: "The bellicose rhetoric emanating from North Korea only deepens that nation's isolation. The United States remains committed to safeguarding our allies in the region and our interests that are located there."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked if the joint US-South Korean military exercises and the use of the stealth bombers had fuelled the escalation, Earnest replied: "It's clear that the escalation is taking place from the North Koreans based on their rhetoric and on their actions."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Pentagon said on Friday that the US would not be intimidated, and was ready to defend both its bases and its allies in the region. Lt Col Catherine Wilkinson, a Pentagon spokesperson, said: "The United States is fully capable of defending itself and our allies against a North Korean attack. We are firmly committed to the defence of South Korea and Japan."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The secretary of state, John Kerry, will visit the region in a week or so for meetings with Japan, China and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;North Korea announced that its forces had been placed on high alert on Tuesday but the threats became graver when a picture was published of Kim reiterating the order at an emergency meeting on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US defence department keeps secret its assessment of the distance North Korea's missiles can reach. But Admiral James Winnefeld, vice-chairman of the joint chiefs of staff, said a fortnight ago it had one type of missile capable of reaching the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While defence analysts agreed that North Korea was theoretically capable of firing a missile, they expressed scepticism about whether its technology was as advanced as it claims and were doubtful about its accuracy in hitting targets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But there is more concern in Washington than previous standoffs with North Korea have elicited because Kim is a new leader, young and inexperienced and a largely unknown quantity in the west.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major worry is the possibility that North Korea might attack a South Korean ship – it was blamed for the sinking of a South Korean vessel in 2010 – or a land target. Seoul has said that it would retaliate this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wilkinson said: "North Korea's bellicose rhetoric and threats follow a pattern designed to raise tensions and intimidate others. DPRK will achieve nothing by threats or provocations, which will only further isolate North Korea and undermine international efforts to ensure peace and stability in north-east Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We continue to urge the North Korean leadership to heed President Obama's call to choose the path of peace and come into compliance with its international obligations."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She added: "We remain committed to ensuring peace and stability on the Korean peninsula. This means deterring North Korean aggression, protecting our allies and the complete denuclearisation of the Korean peninsula. The United States will not accept North Korea as a nuclear state, nor will we stand by while it seeks to develop a nuclear-armed missile that can target the United States."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a Pentagon briefing on Thursday, the defence secretary, Chuck Hagel, said: "There are a lot of unknowns here. But we have to take seriously every provocative, bellicose word and action that this new, young leader has taken so far since he's come to power."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Fitzpatrick, director of the non-proliferation and disarmament programme of the International Institute for Strategic Studies, played down the threat. "North Korea is upping its rhetoric to a world-class level, but it's still just rhetoric. They have no capability to hit the US mainland with anything – except through cyberspace. Their only tested missiles can fly a maximum of 1,600km, less than half the distance to Guam."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fitzpatrick, who is scheduled to lead a thinktank discussion at the institute's Washington office next Thursday on whether the US policy of patience has run its course and whether it should instead pursue reunification of the Korean peninsula, said on Friday that while North Korea was limited in its ability to hit US targets, it posed a threat to South Korea and Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Their Scuds and Nodongs can hit anywhere in South Korea and Japan. Using them would be suicidal, of course. The far more likely scenario is a pin-prick attack in the nature of the 2010 attacks. This time, however, South Korea is determined to respond with an eye for an eye, in order to restore deterrence. North Korea's ensuing response could trigger a larger conflagration."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jim Walsh, a specialist on security and nuclear weapons at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, played down the prospect of an attack on the US, but said: "The reason it is scary is you can get war even when no one intends to have a war. All the sides – South Korea, North Korea and others – are now leaning into each other, and if someone makes a mistake, I am concerned that that mistake will escalate into something larger than anyone expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Suddenly you have a young man in a closed country who has to decide whether he is going to respond to your actions."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The risk was not of a North Korean attack on the US but of one on South Korea that would bring in the US, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walsh, who has visited North Korea and has had talks with its officials in Switzerland, Sweden and the US, said the present confrontation felt different because of the harsher rhetoric from North Korea, the secret defence pact agreed by the US and South Korea and the US military drills this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"If we are lucky it will all be bluster on everyone's side. That is the good outcome," Walsh said. "The bad outcome is that it is bluster until someone screws up and then war happens."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michael O'Hanlon, one of the leading military analysts in the US, expressed worries that the US approach of tit-for-tat and imposition of additional permanent sanctions after North Korea's third nuclear test could exacerbate the situation. Like Walsh, he sees this confrontation as being different from previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an email, O'Hanlon, a security specialist at Washington's Brookings Institution, said: "I favour temporary sanctions in response to the third nuclear test, to give Pyongyang an incentive not to provoke again." He argues that setting a time limit such as two, three or four years could encourage North Korea not to conduct another nuclear test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I am talking about automatic sunset provisions with a specific timeframe, unless of course there is another nuclear test or another act of violence," O'Hanlon said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/north-korea"&gt;North Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/asia-pacific"&gt;Asia Pacific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/south-korea"&gt;South Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/ewenmacaskill"&gt;Ewen MacAskill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a28c771/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808294/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28c771/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808294/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28c771/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990808294/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28c771/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/hW02eqo1UQc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Asia Pacific</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">South Korea</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">North Korea</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:58:28 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/russia-us-north-korea-restraint</guid><dc:creator>Ewen MacAskill</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T13:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406477801</dc:identifier><media:keywords>North Korea, Asia Pacific, World news, South Korea, United States</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364651885307/North-Korean-soldiers-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Feature China / Barcroft Media/Feature China / Barcroft Media</media:credit><media:description>North Korean soldiers seen from across the border in China. Photograph: Feature China / Barcroft Media</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364651891221/North-Korean-soldiers-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Feature China / Barcroft Media/Feature China / Barcroft Media</media:credit><media:description>North Korean soldiers seen from across the border in China. Photograph: Feature China / Barcroft Media</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/russia-us-north-korea-restraint</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Tech titans raise millions to enter the political arena: but what is it they want?</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/ukoaMu3prMU/facebook-google-twitter-political-lobbying</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/79239?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Afacebook-google-twitter-political-lobbying%3A1887709&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Obs&amp;c4=US+political+lobbying%2CGoogle+%28Technology%29%2CFacebook%2CTwitter+%28Technology%29%2CSocial+networking%2CUS+politics%2CMark+Zuckerberg+%28Technology%29%2CBarack+Obama+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CInternet%2CMedia%2CTechnology%2CUS+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CDigital+Media%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly%2CTechnology+Gadgets%2CUS+Elections%2CCorporate+IT%2CFamily+and+Relationships&amp;c6=Paul+Harris&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+01%3A57&amp;c8=1887709&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Feature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Tech+titans+raise+millions+to+enter+the+political+arena%3A+but+what+is+it+they+want%3F&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FUS+political+lobbying" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;As Facebook and Google begin to flex their lobbying muscle, critics warn that their values are very different from those of millions of ordinary Americans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One day last month about 40 noisy protesters gathered outside the home of the Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg in Palo Alto in California's Silicon Valley. They chanted slogans and held up signs as a small, select group of people arrived in sleek sports cars and were ushered inside the relatively modest residence where the billionaire lives with his wife, Priscilla Chan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It must have been an unusual experience for Zuckerberg, 28, whose position as head of Facebook is more likely to inspire admiration or plain curiosity from ordinary Americans rather than outraged, placard-waving demonstrators shepherded by local police. But this was no ordinary party Zuckerberg was holding. It was his first political fundraiser and his choice of candidate raised eyebrows: the Republican governor of New Jersey, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/chris-christie" title=""&gt;Chris Christie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the gaze of the protesters, Republican bigwigs such as Condoleezza Rice started arriving to pay homage to – and write cheques for – a governor who has taken stances against gay marriage and raising taxes on rich people while embarking on a union-bashing crusade against teachers in his home state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the fundraiser was just one of Zuckerberg's moves into politics. This week the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; reported that he was in the middle of helping to organise a political advocacy group with other top tech leaders. The as yet unnamed organisation would lobby for reform on issues such as immigration, education and scientific research. The newspaper said it had already raised millions of dollars from its cash-rich donors and had an initial target of&amp;nbsp;$50m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a remarkable development but also inevitable. The tech sector that has sprung up from Silicon Valley and other development hotspots across the US has grown into a multibillion-dollar industry whose top companies – such as Google, Facebook and Twitter – have fundamentally reshaped how most of us live. As it grew in power and influence, it was bound to enter the realm of politics, seeking to change policy and win allies across the political spectrum. To Big Oil, Big Pharma, Big Tobacco and Big Banking, you can now add Big Tech. Which raises an important question that is only rarely asked: as they increasingly seek to shape American politics, what do the titans of tech actually want?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kate Losse thinks that question needs a lot of attention. She should know. She was an early employee at Facebook and rose to being Zuckerberg's speechwriter before leaving to write a book about her experiences, &lt;a href="http://www.guardianbookshop.co.uk/BerteShopWeb/viewProduct.do?ISBN=9781451668254" title=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Boy Kings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems that her book was aptly titled, and recent tech advances into the political world, especially the creation of a well-funded political organisation, are probably only the tip of an iceberg. "The fact that this sort of development is happening suggests there is a political project," Losse said. "That is why it is important to ask questions now. Otherwise we might wake up one day and there is a whole system in place that we did not see coming."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with any major industry, the people involved in Silicon Valley have political views across the spectrum. But in general they are often a blend of social liberalism and free-market economics. It is a world where people are happy with ethnic diversity and sexual freedoms but distrustful of big government and see the "heroic entrepreneur" as an aspirational ideal. It is a political culture that owes a debt to libertarian novelist and philosopher Ayn Rand, who preached that free-market self-interest was the future and the hand of government was little more than a dead weight on human creativity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To many, those sort of beliefs in the very young, very rich and very powerful minds of Silicon Valley could be a dangerous mix. "The youth is there in Silicon Valley culture and the hubris is pretty high too," said Paul Argenti, a communications professor at the Tuck school of business at Dartmouth, New Hampshire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the agenda can be seen in the issues and politicians the industry is seeking to back. For example, it is lobbying aggressively to relax immigration laws on the highly educated. That might or might not be good policy, but as a values system it is no vision of egalitarianism of the sort that America was founded upon. It is replacing the huddled masses yearning to be free with not-so-huddled elites bearing PhDs. That might suit the belief system of tech start-up people, but less so union members, the working class or the millions of Americans still struggling with high levels of joblessness. "By attaching himself personally to this sort of issue, Mark Zuckerberg is young, arrogant and naive," Argenti said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The way the sector is seeking to wield power politically is anything but naive, and actually old school. Tech bosses are pouring millions of dollars into lobbying firms. They are bucking a trend too. Overall, the amount spent on lobbying by all industries has been falling since 2010 and the number of lobbyists in Washington has been declining since 2007. But not in tech; the sector has grown each year since 2009, signing up more big-name firms and pouring in millions more dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google, is the top company in the sector, and has hired former top politicians – such as former congressman Richard Gephardt and former congresswoman Susan Molinari – to fight for its interests. Facebook has lobbied on bills about privacy, seeking to protect its business model of exploiting its users' content and data as a way of marketing to advertisers. It has a former congressman onboard as well in the shape of John Shadegg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top tech executives have also wooed politicians at the highest level. Zuckerberg and Google chief executive Eric Schmidt were two of the dozen tech titans who &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/home/moslive/article-1386409/Worlds-richest-dinner-party--including-guests-Obama-Mark-Zuckerberg.html" title=""&gt;attended a private dinner&lt;/a&gt; with Barack Obama in 2011. In one of his state of the union addresses, Obama called out Facebook and Google by name as the natural heirs to the great industrial innovators of America's past. &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/theobserver/2013/feb/24/sheryl-sandberg-facebook-boss-mission-lean" title=""&gt;Facebook's chief operating officer Sheryl Sandberg&lt;/a&gt; has just published a book aimed at creating a social movement of women in the office. She too spans the private and public sectors, having worked as a top official at the US treasury: no doubt her contacts book still contains a host of powerful government officials on speed-dial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Observers say this is a tried and tested model for any major industry. "They are singing from the same playbook as everybody else and this is big money. You will find that rarely does a big corporation spend big money except to protect its own commercial concerns," said Sheila Krumholz, executive director of the &lt;a href="http://www.publicintegrity.org/news/Center-for-Responsive-Politics" title=""&gt;Centre for Responsive Politics&lt;/a&gt;, a watchdog group which seeks to monitor the power of money in US politics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet tech has tried to paint itself as different. Google's informal mantra of "Don't be evil" has helped to craft its image as a socially responsive firm that would be fun to work for. Facebook markets itself simply as a way of connecting people. Advocates of Twitter say the company helped to bring down dictatorships in the Arab spring. The legions of Apple fans believe their favourite firm's sleek products make the world a better – and much more aesthetically pleasing – place to live and work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But wary critics see that happy, hippyish public image as a potential trojan horse for a mega-powerful industry hellbent on pursuing its self-interest. Facebook, Google, Twitter and a million other internet-based products might be fun and convenient and make our lives better, but their commercial interests are as real as any oil company, defence manufacturer or bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"They have had a honeymoon period," said Krumholz. "But it might be starting to wear off. They have the same corporate interests as anyone else."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Except maybe they are on an even bigger scale. Other big industries' products do not shape peoples' lives in the way search engines and social media sites do. Google and Facebook and Twitter have not created new products that stand alone like a car or a new house; they have created things that invade every other aspect of the economy and our culture. That is a different level of power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Losse has seen this close-up. Working with Zuckerberg, she says he would frequently see Facebook as becoming a rival to nation states in the future. "Companies over countries," he would say in meetings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Zuckerberg talks of a "Facebook nation", it is not idle marketing-speak; he means it. "They are trading the very nature of social interaction. They are very much in people's lives. Don't mistake these companies for fun. They don't see it that way," Losse said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/us-political-lobbying"&gt;US political lobbying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/google"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/facebook"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/twitter"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/socialnetworking"&gt;Social networking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/us-politics"&gt;US politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/mark-zuckerberg"&gt;Mark Zuckerberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/barack-obama"&gt;Barack Obama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/internet"&gt;Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/paulharris"&gt;Paul Harris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a297e2a/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/ukoaMu3prMU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Facebook</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Barack Obama</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Mark Zuckerberg</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Media</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US political lobbying</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Social networking</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Technology</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Twitter</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Internet</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Google</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Observer</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:57:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/facebook-google-twitter-political-lobbying</guid><dc:creator>Paul Harris</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T13:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406476152</dc:identifier><media:keywords>US political lobbying, Google, Facebook, Twitter, Social networking, US politics, Mark Zuckerberg, Barack Obama, World news, Internet, Media, Technology, United States</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Money/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364646908744/Obama-Holds-Facebook-Town-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Justin Sullivan/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Barack Obama debates with Mark Zuckerberg, co-founder of Facebook. Photograph: Justin Sullivan/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Money/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364646917320/Obama-Holds-Facebook-Town-006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Justin Sullivan/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Barack Obama debates with Mark Zuckerberg, co-founder of Facebook. Photograph: Justin Sullivan/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/facebook-google-twitter-political-lobbying</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Nato air strike 'kills two children' in south-eastern Afghanistan</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/adVFicxSYlU/nato-air-strike-children-afghanistan</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/66706?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Anato-air-strike-children-afghanistan%3A1887721&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Afghanistan+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CNato+%28News%29%2CUS+military+%28News%29%2CUS+news%2CUS+foreign+policy&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Agencies&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+01%3A53&amp;c8=1887721&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Nato+air+strike+%27kills+two+children%27+in+south-eastern+Afghanistan&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FAfghanistan" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Nato helicopter fire reportedly kills two children along with nine suspected Taliban fighters near the town of Ghazni&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Nato helicopter has reportedly killed two children during an attack on Taliban fighters.The helicopter opened fire as it supported Afghan soldiers near the town of Ghazni in south-east Afghanistan, despite president Hamid Karzai forbidding troops to call for foreign air support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Afghan police had been patrolling in Ghazni when they came under attack by insurgents, Nato spokesman Major Adam Wojack said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"International Security Assistance Forces [ISAF] supported the Afghan unit in contact by engaging the insurgent forces with helicopter-delivered direct fire," he said, adding that ISAF was investigating reports of civilian casualties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine Taliban fighters were killed and eight civilians were wounded, according to senior Afghan police detective Colonel Mohammad Hussain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Reuters reporter saw the bodies of two children, whom local people said had been killed in the air strike.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month Karzai forbade Afghan forces from calling for Nato air support and Nato from striking "in Afghan homes or villages" after an air strike that killed 10 civilians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Civilian casualties caused by air strikes are a significant source of friction between Karzai and his international allies as Washington and Kabul negotiate over the size of a future US military presence after most international troops depart by the end of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some Afghan officials say privately that limiting air strikes exposes the 352,000-strong Afghan security forces to greater danger as they take over the responsibilities of international forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foreign air power is especially critical to cover the mountainous regions near the Pakistani border.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/afghanistan"&gt;Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/nato"&gt;Nato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/us-military"&gt;US military&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usforeignpolicy"&gt;US foreign policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a2911ab/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808293/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2911ab/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808293/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2911ab/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990808293/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2911ab/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/adVFicxSYlU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US foreign policy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Nato</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US military</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Afghanistan</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:53:07 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/nato-air-strike-children-afghanistan</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T14:32:10Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406477767</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Afghanistan, World news, Nato, US military, United States, US foreign policy</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2009/5/29/1243554926269/A-US-Apache-helicopter-fi-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Bazuki Muhammad/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>A US Apache helicopter fires a missile during training in Afghanistan. Photograph: Bazuki Muhammad/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2009/5/29/1243554924900/A-US-Apache-helicopter-fi-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Bazuki Muhammad/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>The air strike was launched despite the Afghan president Hamid Karzai forbidding his troops to call in foreign air support. Photograph: Bazuki Muhammad/Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/nato-air-strike-children-afghanistan</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Nelson Mandela 'comfortable and breathing without difficulty'</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/1yuTu8yoRqg/nelson-mandela-comfortable</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/44693?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Anelson-mandela-comfortable%3A1887717&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Nelson+Mandela%2CWorld+news%2CSouth+Africa+%28News%29%2CAfrica+%28News%29&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Agencies&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+01%3A26&amp;c8=1887717&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Nelson+Mandela+%27comfortable+and+breathing+without+difficulty%27&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FNelson+Mandela" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;South African president Jacob Zuma's office says 94-year-old hero of anti-apartheid struggle responding well to treatment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nelson Mandela's health is improving and he is responding well to treatment for a lung infection, according to the office of the president of South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The former South African president has spent three nights in hospital but is now able to breathe without problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jacob Zuma's office said on Saturday: "Madiba is now able to breathe without difficulty. He continues to respond to treatment and is comfortable."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Madiba is Mandela's by clan name, by which he is widely known in South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 94-year-old hero of the anti-apartheid struggle is believed to be at 1 Military Hospital in Pretoria and to have been visited by close family. This is his third stint in hospital in four months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week Zuma said people should "slow down the anxiety" about the health of the country's first black president.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Of course I have been saying to people, you should bear in mind Madiba is no longer that young and if he goes for check-ups every now and again, I don't think people must be alarmed about it. I would like to really say the country must not panic."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When asked if people should prepare for the inevitable, Zuma replied: "In Zulu, when someone passes away who is very old, people say he or she has gone home. I think those are some of the things we should be thinking about."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But he stressed that Mandela had been able to handle the situation very well so far. "Very few outstanding personalities in the world live to his level," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/nelsonmandela"&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/southafrica"&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/africa"&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a28e3cd/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808292/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28e3cd/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808292/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28e3cd/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990808292/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28e3cd/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/1yuTu8yoRqg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Nelson Mandela</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">South Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Africa</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:26:03 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/nelson-mandela-comfortable</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T13:26:03Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406477323</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Nelson Mandela, World news, South Africa, Africa</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/28/1364484699369/Nelson-Mandela-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Barbara Kinney/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Nelson Mandela has a history of lung problems dating back to when he contracted tuberculosis as a political prisoner. Photograph: Barbara Kinney/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/28/1364484705492/Nelson-Mandela-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Barbara Kinney/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Nelson Mandela has a history of lung problems dating back to when he contracted tuberculosis as a political prisoner. Photograph: Barbara Kinney/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/nelson-mandela-comfortable</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Casanova unveiled: new edition of his book reveals the man who loved liberty as much as women</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/yVsjMRAlgcc/casanova-man-who-loved-liberty-as-much-as-women</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/99999?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Acasanova-man-who-loved-liberty-as-much-as-women%3A1887697&amp;ch=Books&amp;c3=Obs&amp;c4=Autobiography+and+memoir+%28books+genre%29%2CBooks%2CCulture%2CFrance%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Kim+Willsher&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+01%3A04&amp;c8=1887697&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Casanova+unveiled%3A+new+edition+of+his+book+reveals+the+man+who+loved+liberty+as+much+as+women&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FBooks%2FAutobiography+and+memoir" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Corrected version of his life story will give fuller details of sexual adventures while portraying a complex personality&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bored and exiled in the pine forests of rural Bohemia, far from the cities and the women he had loved and left, the ageing Giacomo Casanova spent his final years writing his memoirs. The Venice he grew up in no longer existed. The Paris he loved was riddled with revolution. Writing was, he said in the preface, "the only remedy I could think of to keep me from going mad or dying of grief".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book, &lt;em&gt;Histoire de Ma Vie&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Story of My Life&lt;/em&gt;), published two decades after his death in 1798, would ensure that the man whose name was to become synonymous with womanising did not vanish into obscurity. Until now, however, the range and detail of Casanova's sexual exploits have been veiled, first by German puritanism, then in the haze of what modern experts describe as careless, even "faulty", transcription of his writings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, a new book from French publisher Laffont, coming out in late April, aims to reveal Casanova in his full glory. It is based on the original 3,682-page manuscript, acquired by the Bibliothèque Nationale de France in 2010 for about €7.5m from an anonymous donor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean-Christophe Igalens, a lecturer at Nice University and a specialist on Casanova, who co-produced the book, said it reveals the notorious libertine as "a much more complex character than the cliche he has become. Yes, he was a seducer, but he was also seduced. He loved women, the women he had affairs with. He wasn't just a superficial character who took a woman to bed then left her. He had rich relationships with women," Igalens told the &lt;em&gt;Observer&lt;/em&gt;. "For the reader, Casanova is often identified with the art of reinvention. He was able to change his name, change country, reinvent himself with a different future. This idea of not giving into one destiny is something that speaks to our modern world."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1821, 23 years after Casanova died, the manuscript of &lt;em&gt;Histoire de Ma Vie &lt;/em&gt;was sold by his nephew to a German editor interested in 18th-century Italian writers. But Friedrich Arnold Brockhaus judged the work unpublishable because of its immorality and the fact that the French text was peppered with Italian. It was published only after the text was cleaned up and passages considered too coarse removed, and for 140 years it was to be the only available version, while the original remained under lock and key.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even so, it seduced French writers, among them Henri Beyle, better known as Stendhal, and Alfred de Musset, the poet and dramatist. "In the 19th century, when Casanova was effectively discovered, it was a very bourgeois period, and for those writers like Stendahl and Musset who read him he represented a moral order, a moral age that was less constrained and restrictive than the one they lived in," said Igalens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original manuscript was almost lost for ever when the offices of Brockhaus took a direct hit from an Allied bomb in 1943. Winston Churchill is reported to have inquired as to its fate. Almost miraculously, it emerged unscathed and was rushed to a bank security vault.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1960 the original manuscript was published in its entirety in the original French, followed by an English version in 1966. "The problem was that it [the French version] was published in a hurry and there were many errors and faults in the transcription," Igalens said. "This edition is more serious. There is no shock discovery that will change our image of Casanova, but what makes this new and special are the variants and pages that are completely different."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Igalens cites the account of Casanova's first visit to Paris in 1750, when he writes about visiting a &lt;em&gt;maison de plaisir&lt;/em&gt; called the Hotel de Roule, run by a certain Madame Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"In the new transcription we have much more detail; it is more precise. Casanova describes the women in the &lt;em&gt;maison&lt;/em&gt; – a brothel – how they looked, how they were paid, and is precise about what happened ... there are big differences between the original manuscript and what was published in 1960."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new book publishes the two versions of &lt;em&gt;Histoire de Ma Vie&lt;/em&gt; side by side, to highlight these differences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Casanova opens his memoirs with: "I begin by declaring to my reader that in all that I have done throughout my life, good or bad, I am sure that I have earned merit or blame, and as a consequence I believe myself free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Man is free, but he is only free if he believes himself to be … The only system I have had ... is that of letting myself go where the blowing wind took me."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Histoire de Ma Vie will be published by Laffont in four volumes. Volume One, 1,500 pages in length, will be published on 25 April.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/autobiography-and-memoir"&gt;Autobiography and memoir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/france"&gt;France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/kim-willsher"&gt;Kim Willsher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a28e10c/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808291/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28e10c/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808291/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28e10c/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990808291/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28e10c/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/yVsjMRAlgcc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Books</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Autobiography and memoir</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Observer</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">France</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:04:25 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2013/mar/30/casanova-man-who-loved-liberty-as-much-as-women</guid><dc:creator>Kim Willsher</dc:creator><dc:subject>Books</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T13:04:25Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406473994</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Autobiography and memoir, Books, Culture, France, Europe, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364648535500/David-Tennant-as-Casanova-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">BBC/RED PRODUCTIONS/Red Productions</media:credit><media:description>David Tennant as Casanova in a BBC adaptation of his life story. Photograph: BBC/RED PRODUCTIONS/Red Productions</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364648541541/David-Tennant-as-Casanova-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">BBC/RED PRODUCTIONS/Red Productions</media:credit><media:description>David Tennant as Casanova in a BBC adaptation of his life story.</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2013/mar/30/casanova-man-who-loved-liberty-as-much-as-women</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Bank of Cyprus depositors could lose up to 60% of their savings</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/erv3xRomkVA/bank-of-cyprus-depositors-lose-savings</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/2047?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abank-of-cyprus-depositors-lose-savings%3A1887707&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Cyprus+%28News%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CEurozone+crisis%2CEuropean+Union+EU+%28News%29%2CEuropean+monetary+union+EMU%2CEconomics+%28Business%29%2CEuropean+banks+%28business%29%2CFinancial+crisis+%28Business%29%2CFinancial+sector+%28business%29%2CEuro+%28Business%29%2CBusiness&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CCredit+Crunch%2CBusiness+Markets%2CPolicy+Society%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CProperty+Mortgages+and+Interest+Rates&amp;c6=Staff+and+agencies&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+12%3A40&amp;c8=1887707&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Bank+of+Cyprus+depositors+could+lose+up+to+60%25+of+their+savings&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FCyprus" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Cypriot finance officials say initial losses will be 37.5%, but up to 22.5% more could be taken if bank needs further capitalisation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Savers with the Bank of Cyprus could lose up to 60% of their savings according to officials from the central bank and the finance ministry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The officials said on Saturday that deposits over €100,000 (£84,000) at the country's largest bank will lose 37.5% of their value after being converted into bank shares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the bank were to need further capitalisation the savers could lose as much as 22.5% more, depending on an assessment by officials who will determine the exact figure needed to restore the troubled bank back to health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus agreed Monday to make depositors contribute in order to secure a €10bn bailout from the eurozone and the International Monetary Fund.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banks opened in Cyprus on Thursday for the first time in two weeks, but transactions were subject to new regulations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cash withdrawals from banks have been limited to €300 a day, while only €1,000 in cash can be taken out of the country and there are restrictions on the use of credit cards abroad. Cypriot authorities loosened some restrictions on the use of cheques on Friday, but only to allow payments to government agencies of up to €5,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus's central bank has also imposed limits on the money that can be taken "beyond the control of the Cypriot authorities", a reference to the northern part of the island under Turkish control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After an initial estimate that the capital controls would be in place for a matter of days, the government then warned later in the week they could last for as long as a month. Capital controls in Iceland remain in place more than five years after its economic crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/cyprus"&gt;Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/debt-crisis"&gt;Eurozone crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/eu"&gt;European Union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/emu"&gt;European monetary union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/economics"&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/europeanbanks"&gt;European banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/financial-crisis"&gt;Financial crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/financial-sector"&gt;Financial sector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/euro"&gt;Euro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a28415f/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808290/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28415f/kg/349/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990808290/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28415f/kg/349/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990808290/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28415f/kg/349/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/erv3xRomkVA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Financial sector</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Euro</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">European Union</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Economics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Cyprus</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Eurozone crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">European banks</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Financial crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">European monetary union</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 12:40:10 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/bank-of-cyprus-depositors-lose-savings</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T12:40:10Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406475865</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Cyprus, Europe, World news, Eurozone crisis, European Union, European monetary union, Economics, European banks, Financial crisis, Financial sector, Euro, Business</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364646510100/Cyprus-banks-reopen-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Katia Christodoulou/EPA</media:credit><media:description>People queue outside a Bank of Cyprus branch in Nicosia on Thursday, when the island's banks reopened for the first time in nearly two weeks. Photograph: Katia Christodoulou/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364646517344/Cyprus-banks-reopen-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Katia Christodoulou/EPA</media:credit><media:description>People queue outside a Bank of Cyprus branch in Nicosia on Thursday, when the island's banks reopened for the first time in nearly two weeks. Photograph: Katia Christodoulou/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/30/bank-of-cyprus-depositors-lose-savings</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Sunderland v Manchester United – as it happened | Jacob Steinberg</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/NlfW0cfBNrY/sunderland-manchester-united-live</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minute-by-minute report: &lt;/strong&gt;Titus Bramble's own goal was the difference as Manchester United took another step towards their 20th title&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jacob-steinberg"&gt;Jacob Steinberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a2877ca/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990785475/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2877ca/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990785475/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2877ca/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990785475/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2877ca/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/NlfW0cfBNrY" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Match reports</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Blogposts</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Sunderland</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Manchester United</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Football</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport">Sport</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Minute by minutes</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football">Premier League</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:59:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/30/sunderland-manchester-united-live</guid><dc:creator>Jacob Steinberg</dc:creator><dc:subject>Football</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T14:40:24Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>406473995</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Premier League, Sunderland, Manchester United, Football, Sport</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364645127121/62386ab6-633a-46e8-af72-adad09618896-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Ed Sykes/Action Images</media:credit><media:description>Danny Graham will lead the Sunderland line, after Steven Fletcher's ankle injury curtailed the Scot's season. Photograph: Michael Regan/Getty Images Photograph: Ed Sykes/Action Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/2013/mar/30/sunderland-manchester-united-live</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Leeds General child heart surgery suspended for 'constellation' of reasons</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/O8gaa9pwegs/leeds-general-infirmary-child-heart-surgery</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/38368?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aleeds-general-infirmary-child-heart-surgery%3A1887699&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=NHS+%28Society%29%2CHealth+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CChildren+%28Society%29%2CLeeds+%28News%29%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CHealth+Society%2CChildren+Society&amp;c6=David+Batty&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+10%3A59&amp;c8=1887699&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Leeds+General+child+heart+surgery+suspended+for+%27constellation%27+of+reasons&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FNHS" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Concerns over mortality figures and fact that relatively junior surgeons left in charge of unit among reasons for suspension&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Concerns that two relatively junior surgeons had been left in charge of surgery on children with congenital heart defects at Leeds General Infirmary were among a number of reasons behind the decision to suspend operations there, a key NHS adviser has said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hospital, which is engulfed in a row over the future of its children's heart services, is carrying out an internal review after data suggested a death rate twice the national average. The accuracy of the mortality figures has been questioned after it emerged that they preliminary and that scores of patients from Leeds had been omitted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Professor Sir Roger Boyle, the director of the National Institute of Clinical Outcomes Research (Nicor), which oversees mortality data across the NHS, said the figures were among a number of reasons he advised that the unit should be suspended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told BBC Breakfast that concerns were raised that two relatively junior surgeons had been left in charge of the unit, which carries out around 400 heart operations on children a year. He was also aware of claims from the families of patients that their requests to be transferred to other units were ignored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I was aware last weekend of other concerns being raised about Leeds, concerns raised by distinguished surgeons who don't work in the area," Boyle said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Concerns raised by families through the Children's Heart Foundation that they weren't being given the opportunity to be transferred to other units when they'd requested that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"And I was also aware a senior surgeon was away on holiday, another surgeon was suspended and that left the service being offered to the public by two relatively junior, local surgeons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"To have two relatively inexperienced people holding fort, without the ability for any senior advice, is a precarious situation in my view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's a question of experience and fine balance between being able to offer a safe service and one that is precarious."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Campaigners have reacted angrily to the suspension of operations, which was announced a day after a high court judge ruled that the hospital could carry on performing such procedures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doubts were cast over the early draft of mortality figures as it emerged that information from up to 150 cases had been omitted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr John Gibbs, chairman of the steering committee for the Central Cardiology Audit Database (CCAD), which supplied the data, said he was furious that the figures had been leaked as they had not undergone the "usual rigorous checking process".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Boyle, the government's former national director of heart disease, said further analysis including the omitted cases still showed similar results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"In fact, the data has been reanalysed with these extra cases and we still see this gap in mortality rate," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I would not have been able to sleep this weekend knowing that there were people who might have been operated on in a potentially unsafe environment."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boyle told the BBC Radio 4 Today programme it was pure coincidence that the suspension had come just a day after the high court ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said: "The email I had from my analysts appeared as the judge was giving her views in the royal courts of justice. It was pure coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It is remarkable, but we had been working on this for over a year … trying to respond to the challenge of trying to separate out the hospitals on the basis of the mortality figures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The Safe and Sustainable review had to rely on a quality assessment of each centre and that was the point the judge found fault with."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sir Bruce Keogh, the medical director of the NHS, defended the suspension, saying on Friday that it had had been taken for a "constellation" of reasons, including warnings from the Children's Heart Federation, which was concerned about aspects of decision-making at the hospital and had suspicions that staff "were not referring complex cases on to other centres with better expertise".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keogh said there had been "rumblings" among the cardiac surgical community for some time that "all was not well" in Leeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg Mulholland, the Lib Dem MP for Leeds North West, said he was "stunned and appalled" by the suspension and called for Keogh to resign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement on his website, Mulholland said: "To have arrived in Leeds and done this, without warning, just one day after the decision to close the Leeds unit was proved in a court of law to have been unlawful, beggars belief.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I believe that Sir Bruce Keogh should resign as he has both authorised this wholly unreasonable and deeply questionable action and also presided over the fundamentally flawed Safe and Sustainable review, which has proved an exercise in how not to effect major change to the NHS."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/nhs"&gt;NHS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/health"&gt;Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/children"&gt;Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/leeds"&gt;Leeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/davidbatty"&gt;David Batty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a28210a/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990800592/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28210a/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990800592/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28210a/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990800592/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a28210a/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/O8gaa9pwegs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Children</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Health</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Leeds</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">NHS</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 10:59:08 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/30/leeds-general-infirmary-child-heart-surgery</guid><dc:creator>David Batty</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T11:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406474069</dc:identifier><media:keywords>NHS, Health, Society, Children, Leeds, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364547863634/Leeds-General-Infirmary-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Christopher Thomond/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>A campaign has been waged to save children's heart surgery at the Leeds General Infirmary after the unit was earmarked for closure. Photograph: Christopher Thomond for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2012/9/11/1347375114135/Leeds-General-Infirmary-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Christopher Thomond/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Leeds General Infirmary is engulfed in a row over the future of its children's heart services. Photograph: Christopher Thomond for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/30/leeds-general-infirmary-child-heart-surgery</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Make second homes very expensive, says Sir Andrew Motion</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/6VM3hpNEbG8/second-homes-expensive-andrew-motion</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/70481?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Asecond-homes-expensive-andrew-motion%3A1887696&amp;ch=Books&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Andrew+Motion%2CRural+affairs%2CPoet+laureate%2CBooks%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Conal+Urquhart&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+10%3A35&amp;c8=1887696&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Make+second+homes+very+expensive%2C+says+Sir+Andrew+Motion&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FBooks%2FAndrew+Motion" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Former poet laureate, now head of the Campaign to Protect Rural England, calls for tax increases to preserve communities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taxes should be increased to make owning a second home difficult for all but the very wealthy, according to the head of the Campaign to Protect Rural England.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sir Andrew Motion, the former poet laureate, said that second home owners were sucking the life out of villages and causing a national housing shortage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I think there's a question about whether second homes mean you have inert dormitory communities in the countryside through most of the week, very often lived in by people who scoot down in their cars, see their smart friends, don't join in the life of the community and don't feed into it," he told the Times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"They're townies in the countryside. They make sure they're back in London to catch the 10 o'clock news on Sunday night. That means rural communities are gutted."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 165,000 people have second homes in the UK and in some parts of Devon and Cornwall they account for almost half of all properties. Many argue that second home owners and the services they require provide vital employment in rural areas and maintain property values for all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Motion said that England's countryside was culturally more important than Shakespeare and should be preserved from new building and second homes. "I would increase taxes on second homes to make it very expensive," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, second home owners only had to pay a fraction of council tax on their second home. Next month, most will have to pay the full amount on both their properties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrew George, MP for St Ives in Cornwall, wants councils to be given the right to regulate outsiders buying property in much the same as they currently manage planning permission and use of premises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/andrewmotion"&gt;Andrew Motion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/ruralaffairs"&gt;Rural affairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/poet-laureate"&gt;Poet laureate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/conalurquhart"&gt;Conal Urquhart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a281d05/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990800093/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a281d05/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990800093/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a281d05/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990800093/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a281d05/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/6VM3hpNEbG8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Andrew Motion</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Poet laureate</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books">Books</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Rural affairs</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 10:35:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2013/mar/30/second-homes-expensive-andrew-motion</guid><dc:creator>Conal Urquhart</dc:creator><dc:subject>Books</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T11:05:29Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406473875</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Andrew Motion, Rural affairs, Poet laureate, Books, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364639675363/Andrew-Motion-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Karen Robinson For The Observer/Karen Robinson</media:credit><media:description>Sir Andrew Motion has spoken out about 'inert dormitory communities'. Photograph: Karen Robinson For The Observer/Karen Robinson</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364639682369/Andrew-Motion-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Karen Robinson For The Observer/Karen Robinson</media:credit><media:description>Sir Andrew Motion has spoken out about 'inert dormitory communities' in the countryside. Photograph: Karen Robinson For The Observer</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2013/mar/30/second-homes-expensive-andrew-motion</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Ecuador raises Julian Assange case with Labour</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/3jL9v40x7EM/ecuador-julian-assange-labour</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/45297?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aecuador-julian-assange-labour%3A1887686&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Julian+Assange+%28Media%29%2CExtradition%2CLaw%2CEcuador+%28News%29%2CLabour%2CUK+news%2CUS+news%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Ben+Quinn&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F30+12%3A09&amp;c8=1887686&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Ecuador+raises+Julian+Assange+case+with+Labour&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FMedia%2FJulian+Assange" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Diplomat brings up subject of WikiLeaks founder taking refuge in embassy at meeting with Kerry McCarthy MP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ecuadorean diplomats have raised the case of Julian Assange with the Labour party as part of attempts to lay the groundwork for a resolution of the diplomatic standoff between Britain and the South American state over the WikiLeaks' founder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of its continuing search for an end to the impasse, Ecuador has been seeking a commitment from the coalition that it would not support Assange's onward extradition to the US should he choose to go to Sweden to face allegations of rape and sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an indication that the Ecuadoreans are now also setting their sights on a possible change of government after the 2015 election, Ecuador's ambassador, Ana Alban, raised Assange's case during a meeting with the shadow foreign minister, Kerry McCarthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting had been requested by Ecuador to discuss environmental issues and bilateral trade, and the Labour side were taken by surprise when the Australian's case was raised by the Ecuadoreans towards the end of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Labour source was eager to distance the party from the issue, saying: "The meeting was on the basis of a discussion about other issues and was one part of a series of regular contact meetings with foreign governments in London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This [Assange] is not a policy issue for the Labour party."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WikiLeaks founder has been living in the embassy in central London since June in order to avoid arrest and extradition to Sweden to face allegations of sexual offences. There is a permanent police guard and he will be arrested if he leaves the premises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ecuadorean diplomats have been in discussions with the Swedish and UK governments since Assange unexpectedly sought refuge at the embassy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discussions last year focused on what was likely to happen to him once legal proceedings in Sweden were completed, according to the Ecuadoreans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2012/jul/26/ecuador-julian-assange-extradition-us" title=""&gt;A senior legal adviser to the embassy has said&lt;/a&gt; that the home secretary, Theresa May, would need to waive specialty – a legal concept that ensures an individual can only be extradited to one country – under section 58 of the Extradition Act 2003 before Assange could be extradited from Sweden to the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Foreign Office has stated that the UK has a binding legal obligation to extradite him to Sweden to face questioning over the allegations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Swedish prosecutors have dismissed claims that their case is part of a political move to see Assange stand trial in the US over his work with WikiLeaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• &lt;em&gt;The standfirst of this article was amended at 12.55 on 30 March 2013 to reflect the fact that the Ecuadorean diplomat's meeting was with Kerry McCarthy MP, not the shadow foreign secretary as originally stated&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/julian-assange"&gt;Julian Assange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/extradition"&gt;Extradition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/ecuador"&gt;Ecuador&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/labour"&gt;Labour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/benquinn"&gt;Ben Quinn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a255370/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990792562/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a255370/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990792562/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a255370/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990792562/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a255370/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/3jL9v40x7EM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Ecuador</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Julian Assange</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Law</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Extradition</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Labour</category><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:09:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/mar/30/ecuador-julian-assange-labour</guid><dc:creator>Ben Quinn</dc:creator><dc:subject>Media</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T12:59:53Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406469715</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Julian Assange, Extradition, Law, Ecuador, Labour, UK news, United States, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364602117045/Julian-Assange-Ecuador-em-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Julian Assange has been holed up in the Ecuadorean embassy since June 2012. Photograph: Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/30/1364602124318/Julian-Assange-Ecuador-em-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Julian Assange has been holed up in the Ecuadorean embassy since June 2012. Photograph: Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/mar/30/ecuador-julian-assange-labour</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Former archbishop lambasts David Cameron</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/0mgWfEsbKEQ/archbishop-attack-david-cameron</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/74842?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aarchbishop-attack-david-cameron%3A1887685&amp;ch=Politics&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=David+Cameron%2CAnglicanism+-+Church+of+England+%28News%29%2CReligion+%28News%29%2CGay+marriage%2CChristianity+%28News%29%2CCoalition+Liberal-Conservative+coalition%2CConservatives+tories+tory+party%2CLiberal+Democrats+Lib+dems%2CSociety%2CPolitics%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Press+Association&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+11%3A55&amp;c8=1887685&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Former+archbishop+lambasts+David+Cameron&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FPolitics%2FDavid+Cameron" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Government is aiding and abetting secularisation of UK and leaving Christians feeling persecuted, says Lord Carey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A former archbishop of Canterbury has attacked David Cameron for doing more than any other recent political leader to feed Christian anxieties that they are part of a persecuted minority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lord Carey said it was a bit rich to hear Mr Cameron tell religious leaders to face down aggressive secularisation when the coalition seemed to be aiding and abetting such practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an article for the Daily Mail, he wrote: "I like David Cameron and believe he is genuinely sincere in his desire to make Britain a generous nation where we care for one another and where people of faith may exercise their beliefs fully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"But it was a bit rich to hear that the prime minister has told religious leaders that they should 'stand up and oppose aggressive secularisation' when it seems that his government is aiding and abetting this aggression every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"At his pre-Easter Downing Street reception for faith leaders, he said that he supported Christians' right to practise their faith. Yet many Christians doubt his sincerity. According to a new ComRes poll, more than two-thirds of Christians feel that they are part of a persecuted minority. Their fears may be exaggerated because few in the UK are actually persecuted, but the prime minister has done more than any other recent political leader to feed these anxieties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"He seems to have forgotten, in spite of his oft-repeated support for the right of Christians to wear the cross, that lawyers acting for the coalition argued only months ago in the Strasbourg court that those sacked for wearing a cross against their employer's wishes should simply get another job."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lord Carey said he was very suspicious that behind plans for gay marriage "there lurks an aggressive secularist and relativist approach towards an institution that has glued society".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added: "The danger I believe that the government is courting with its approach both to marriage and religious freedom is the alienation of a large minority of people who only a few years ago would have been considered pillars of society."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/davidcameron"&gt;David Cameron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/anglicanism"&gt;Anglicanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/religion"&gt;Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/gay-marriage"&gt;Gay marriage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/christianity"&gt;Christianity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/liberal-conservative-coalition"&gt;Liberal-Conservative coalition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/conservatives"&gt;Conservatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/liberaldemocrats"&gt;Liberal Democrats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a259a81/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990775243/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a259a81/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990775243/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a259a81/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990775243/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a259a81/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/0mgWfEsbKEQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">David Cameron</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Anglicanism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Liberal-Conservative coalition</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Gay marriage</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Liberal Democrats</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Christianity</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Conservatives</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Religion</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 23:55:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/29/archbishop-attack-david-cameron</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>Politics</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-29T23:55:15Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406469536</dc:identifier><media:keywords>David Cameron, Anglicanism, Religion, Gay marriage, Christianity, Liberal-Conservative coalition, Conservatives, Liberal Democrats, Society, Politics, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364601214307/george-carey-former-archb-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Murdo Macleod/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>George Carey: 'This government is in danger of alienating a large minority who only a few years ago would have been considered pillars of society.' Photograph: Murdo Macleod for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364601221467/george-carey-former-archb-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Murdo Macleod/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>George Carey: 'This government is in danger of alienating a large minority who only a few years ago would have been considered pillars of society.' Photograph: Murdo Macleod for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/29/archbishop-attack-david-cameron</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Asda welfare cards to be given to Birmingham's poor</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/6C0FcQkVGws/asda-welfare-scheme-birmingham</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/36268?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aasda-welfare-scheme-birmingham%3A1887677&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Benefits+%28Society%29%2CAsda+%28Business%29%2CSupermarkets+%28business%29%2CSociety%2CWelfare+%28Politics%29%2CPolitics%2CBirmingham+%28News%29%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets%2CSocial+Care+Society%2CUS+Economy&amp;c6=Shiv+Malik&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+10%3A16&amp;c8=1887677&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Asda+welfare+cards+to+be+given+to+Birmingham%27s+poor&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FBenefits" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Supermarket teams up with council to give out 'crisis welfare payments' to neediest residents in form of prepaid cards&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asda has joined the UK's biggest local authority to provide emergency welfare to some of the country's poorest people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Birmingham council, which represents around 1 million people, said that from 1 April Monday it would give out crisis welfare payments in the form of prepaid cards that could be redeemed only in Asda supermarkets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Labour authority said the cards – which Asda said were similar to their gift cards – would restrict spending to a list of predetermined goods, which would exclude tobacco, alcohol, phone-related expenditure and fuel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of welfare changes in April, local authorities will take over running the non-statutory emergency welfare loans and grants known as the social fund, which are meant to help people deal with crises such as leaking roofs, broken boilers and lack of food.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the Department for Work and Pensions said it would no longer administer social fund payments centrally, Birmingham said that, unlike other councils, it had decided &lt;a href="http://www.birmingham.gov.uk/LWP" title=""&gt;not to give out small one-off cash grants and loans&lt;/a&gt; from its newly devolved £6.1m fund.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead it would offer prepaid Asda store cards and directly provide bigger items such as white goods to those in emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year the fund, described by Labour peer Lady Lister as "a safety net under the safety net", helped more than 50,000 people in financial crisis in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The council said it was working out how to stop people purchasing inappropriate items but said the cards were not food vouchers or tokens, and were indistinguishable from other prepayment cards accepted by supermarket chains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/26/payment-cards-emergency-assistance-food-stamps" title=""&gt;Other councils &lt;/a&gt;have said they would also use voucher schemes or plough their social fund budget into food banks. But Birmingham appears to be the first local authority to pair up with just one supermarket chain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asda, which is owned by US retail giant Walmart, said its low prices offered an "efficient use of the public purse".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked why Birmingham was restricing choice by partnering only with Asda, a council spokesman said the chain had been "the only main supermarket in the city willing to work with the council". He said the council hoped the scheme would be extended to other stores after a period of evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The scheme is being introduced and will be closely monitored and evaluated for the first three to six months. This is so we can assess how the scheme is being used, by whom, and the levels of grant, crisis payments and overall expenditure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This will entail very close working with the supermarkets to address any issues that arise and make further improvements ."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The council added it had decided not to issue cash payments in order to "build in an element of control by utilising payment cards".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asda said: "We responded to an approach from Birmingham city council, which was looking for a simple way of delivering social fund payments to claimants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Making money available via Asda gift cards rather than cash is a safe way to ensure claimants have access to a huge range of products at low prices, and is an efficient use of the public purse."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Claudia Wood, deputy director of thinktank Demos, said that by using store prepayment cards, it was not possible to stop people spending on certain products. "In a supermarket you can also buy alcohol, toys, pet food, lottery tickets, everything else … you can't stop particular products."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wood, who recently wrote a report on &lt;a href="http://www.demos.co.uk/publications/thepowerofprepaid" title=""&gt;prepay cards&lt;/a&gt; and the benefit system, said that – aside from officials going through receipts retrospectively – the only other way to ensure spending was restricted to certain items was to get checkout staff to monitor goods as they were being bought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The only thing you could do would be to have someone at the checkout picking out the things you're not allowed to use. But … the idea that checkout staff would be enforcing government policy is just ludicrous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"[It would be] a massive inconvenience, really humiliating at the checkout, a massive imposition on staff to apply that ruling … It just wouldn't work … I don't think the supermarkets would stand for it."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/benefits"&gt;Benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/asda"&gt;Asda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/supermarkets"&gt;Supermarkets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/welfare"&gt;Welfare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/birmingham"&gt;Birmingham&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/malik-shiv"&gt;Shiv Malik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a253cfe/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990789530/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a253cfe/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990789530/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a253cfe/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990789530/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a253cfe/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/6C0FcQkVGws" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Welfare</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Birmingham</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Benefits</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Asda</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Supermarkets</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 22:16:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/asda-welfare-scheme-birmingham</guid><dc:creator>Shiv Malik</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:08:54Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406468380</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Benefits, Asda, Supermarkets, Society, Welfare, Politics, Birmingham, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364595318095/Asda-supermarket-front-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">David Sillitoe/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Asda claimed that its low prices offered an 'efficient use of the public purse'. Photograph: David Sillitoe for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364595325523/Asda-supermarket-front-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">David Sillitoe/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Asda claimed that its low prices offered an 'efficient use of the public purse'. Photograph: David Sillitoe for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/asda-welfare-scheme-birmingham</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Richard Griffiths by James Corden: goodbye Rizzo – we miss you already</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/jyDWlPg2FyA/richard-griffiths-james-corden-rizzo</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/4848?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Arichard-griffiths-james-corden-rizzo%3A1887636&amp;ch=Culture&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Richard+Griffiths%2CCulture%2CJames+Corden%2CStage%2CTheatre%2CFilm&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CTheatre&amp;c6=James+Corden&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+08%3A30&amp;c8=1887636&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Feature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Richard+Griffiths+by+James+Corden%3A+goodbye+Rizzo+%E2%80%93+we+miss+you+already&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FCulture%2FRichard+Griffiths" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;The comedian and actor recalls fun, kindness – and Uncle Monty's brief return – in tribute to Griffiths, who has died aged 65&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first time I met Richard Griffiths I was standing in the vast space of rehearsal room 2 at the National Theatre and about to begin my first day as a History Boy. I'd never done a play before. I was standing by the tea and coffee station, clutching my script and hoping my northern accent was up to scratch when Richard walked over. "Don't look so frightened," he said with the broadest smile. "The scary days working here are when you get your first payslip."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He popped a custard cream into his mouth and walked off. Neither of us knew that day what the play was going to become or quite how much time we as a company were about to spend together. We'd all signed up to do 75 shows at the National in London but we went on to give more than 500 performances around the world, shoot &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/movie/114677/history.boys" title=""&gt;a movie&lt;/a&gt; and finish up on Broadway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole process lasted about three years, and Richard was at the centre of its success. He became the ninth History Boy: we nicknamed him Rizzo, and he was one of us. He'd invite us to his dressing room for cocktails after the show or even the odd poker game. He had the most brilliant sense of fun. He wanted to make sure we were enjoying what we were doing – that we knew how very special this moment was for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His performance as Hector, like every other performance he gave in his career, was perfect – and he was quite unaware of how brilliant he was. Audiences and critics loved him from the very first scene.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like many others of my generation, the first time I became aware of Richard as an actor was when I watched &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/movie/95779" title=""&gt;Withnail and I&lt;/a&gt;. His &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AicDvRko4a4" title=""&gt;brief performance as Uncle Monty&lt;/a&gt; is, I believe, one of the greatest comic creations in film – and the finest piece of scene stealing you will ever see. His voice so rich, his eyes so full of lust and vigour, it gets better with every viewing. Richard had an ability in even the biggest comic creations to give his characters a humane quality – he always played the truth of the scenes, never the jokes. He saw Monty for what he was, a lonely man in desperate need of company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would often stand in the wings and plead with him to repeat some lines from Withnail and I and he would just laugh and tell me not to be so silly. That he'd even forgotten how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I never stopped asking him and he never stopped saying no. Until one day, we were performing The History Boys in Sydney and during one of the classroom scenes I said one of my lines too early and accidentally cut two of his. I was mortified. We just had to carry on and hope the audience hadn't noticed but as soon as the curtain came down I rushed to his dressing room to apologise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He placed his hands firmly on my shoulders, squinted and in that deep voice of Uncle Monty said, "I'm preparing myself to forgive you, boy!" He knew that timing was everything. It was the most wonderful way to be forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My abiding memory comes from our last performance together on Broadway. Towards the end of act two, Richard's character, Hector, dies in a motorbike accident and the eight boys whom he has inspired so much sing the song &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BGSkI33UIxQ" title=""&gt;Bye Bye Blackbird&lt;/a&gt; at his memorial service. Francis De La Tour had a speech about where each of the boys had ended up in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then from the back of the stage, Richard would appear almost like a ghost and speak to the boys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were all so sad because it was our final show that many of us were crying before we reached the interval, but I always presumed that Richard – being such an old pro – wouldn't get caught up in the moment like that. But when he came out to deliver his final lines he was as moved as the rest of us. In the role of Hector, he had shown the world he was so much more than a brilliant scene stealer. He could be, if the part was right, a leading man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He began to speak but paused for a moment, his voice cracking under the emotion. The lines were so meaningful it was as if he wanted we eight young actors to really hear them. Then he gathered himself and continued.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Pass the parcel, that's sometimes all you can do," he said. "Take it, feel it, and pass it on. Not for me. Not for you. But for someone. Somewhere. One day. Pass it on, boys, that's the game I wanted you to learn. Pass it on." We miss you already, Rizzo. Rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/richard-griffiths"&gt;Richard Griffiths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/james-corden"&gt;James Corden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/theatre"&gt;Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a24cadb/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990790230/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a24cadb/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990790230/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a24cadb/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990790230/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a24cadb/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/jyDWlPg2FyA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">James Corden</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Richard Griffiths</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage">Stage</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage">Theatre</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film">Film</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:30:01 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/2013/mar/29/richard-griffiths-james-corden-rizzo</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>Culture</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:00:51Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406464173</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Richard Griffiths, Culture, James Corden, Stage, Theatre, Film</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364583136386/James-Corden-Frances-de-l-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alastair Muir/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>James Corden, Frances de la Tour and Richard Griffiths in The History Boys, 2005. Photograph: Alastair Muir/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364583142471/James-Corden-Frances-de-l-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alastair Muir/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>James Corden, Frances de la Tour and Richard Griffiths in The History Boys, 2005. Photograph: Alastair Muir/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/2013/mar/29/richard-griffiths-james-corden-rizzo</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Hospitals that fail patients will be fined, says NHS chief</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/lLunHfi9syA/nhs-fine-poor-service</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/83355?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Anhs-fine-poor-service%3A1887659&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=NHS+%28Society%29%2CGPs+%28Society%29%2CDoctors+%28Society%29%2CHealth+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CHealth+Society&amp;c6=Denis+Campbell&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A59&amp;c8=1887659&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Hospitals+that+fail+patients+will+be+fined%2C+says+NHS+chief&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FNHS" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Medical director Bruce Keogh says operation fees will be held back if patient does not receive highest level of treatment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hospitals will face financial penalties if they fail to give patients with problems such as a stroke or heart attack the best possible care, under controversial plans spelled out by the NHS's top doctor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Sir Bruce Keogh, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/bruce-keogh-nhs-open-season" title="Guardian: Bruce Keogh interview"&gt;speaking to the Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, said the new GP-led clinical commissioning groups (CCGs) that will take control of £65bn of health spending on Monday will hold back from a hospital part of the fees for an operation if the patient has not been treated to the highest possible standards. "The idea is that the CCG would say: 'We will withhold a certain amount of payment from you until you can demonstrate that you've met these standards.' So it's a bit like the building industry – you pay 90% of the [cost of] the building upfront, and then the final payments comes a bit later, when you're sure everything is OK," Keogh said in his only interview before the new NHS system starts in England on 1 April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such differential payments – it is hoped – will compel hospitals to provide high-quality care and force units that do not embrace the latest medical thinking in their specialism to overhaul what they do. Medical teams that do not implement the latest clinical guidance – called quality standards – on how to manage those with a particular condition will forfeit an as yet to be agreed part of the payment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hospitals should view the new payment system as carrots rather than sticks, Keogh said. "So the idea for commissioning quality and innovation is to withhold a little bit of money. It's not a penalty, but it's an incentive to make sure that people reach a set of standards."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His tough message to hospitals on quality of care was reinforced by the decision late on Thursday to suspend children's heart surgery in Leeds General Infirmary following concerns about the quality of lifesaving procedures offered there and the number of its patients who died. An inquiry into practice at LGI has begun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Monday, the new NHS Commissioning Board takes over the day-to-day running of the NHS in England from the Department of Health as part of the coalition's radical shakeup of the service instigated by Andrew Lansley after the 2010 election. It intends to use what Keogh called its "financial muscle" – its £95.6bn budget – to make all hospitals abide by quality standards covering 180 different conditions and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also wants to explore how differential payments could be used to tackle variation in the quality of care provided by GPs. That could mean part of the money that GP practices receive in future would depend on how many patients they diagnosed correctly or how many for whom they organised home-based care rather than in hospital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keogh, the board's national medical director, said the quality standards, drawn up by the National Institute of Health and Clinical Excellence, were "quite gold-plated and do represent best practice". The new CCGs will write them into contracts they sign with local hospitals for providing certain types of care to make receipt of the full payment conditional on them being followed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NHS Confederation, which represents hospitals, voiced unease at the plan. It would be better to give high-performing hospitals small bonuses over and above the full tariff rather than use penalties against the weaker ones, said Mike Farrar, its chief executive and a former boss of the NHS's north-west region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Bruce is right that commissioners [CCGs] need to use levers. But the downside of penalties is that if hospitals don't reach the standards set, then they don't get the rest of the tariff fee and the risk is of a downward spiral in which they have less resources next year in which to try and meet the standards," Farrar said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Guardian interview Keogh urged the NHS to help stick to its tight spending limits by cracking down on patients receiving unnecessary tests and procedures – known as "overtreatment".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He voiced concern that the NHS is conducting too many x-rays and blood tests without a good medical reason, subjecting some patients to operations they do not need, and prescribing too many antibiotics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"[By] giving people antibiotics when they have just got a viral infection ... you're treating a psyche; you're not treating an infection. That's a waste of money and clinically utterly useless – it's worse than useless, actually, because it's dangerous" owing to the growing number of infections that were immune to most antibiotics, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also defended the NHS and its workforce following the barrage of criticism they have faced recently, especially since last month's report into the Mid Staffs scandal. "What is unfair is the impression that the whole NHS is bad. In a system as big as our NHS there will inevitably be bad pockets, but there will be huge areas of excellence and massive areas that are good," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sprang to the defence of Sir David Nicholson, the new board's chief executive, whom MPs, Mid Staffs victims' relatives and some newspapers want to resign for failing to detect and stop the scandal in its early days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We have to separate the myth from the man. David Nicholson is seen by many people as very, very tough, and indeed he is. He's very good at keeping a grip on the finances of the NHS. If we get the finances wrong, patients suffer. I also hear accusations that David Nicholson is not caring. That's not my experience."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/nhs"&gt;NHS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/gps"&gt;GPs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/doctors"&gt;Doctors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/health"&gt;Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/deniscampbell"&gt;Denis Campbell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a2434b5/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990772152/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2434b5/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990772152/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2434b5/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990772152/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a2434b5/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/lLunHfi9syA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">GPs</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Doctors</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Health</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">NHS</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:59:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/nhs-fine-poor-service</guid><dc:creator>Denis Campbell</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T01:18:43Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406465747</dc:identifier><media:keywords>NHS, GPs, Doctors, Health, Society, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364597338996/Surgeons-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Frances Roberts/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Keogh hopes that differential payments will compel hospitals to provide high-quality care. Photograph: Frances Roberts/Alamy</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364597345466/Surgeons-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Frances Roberts/Alamy</media:credit><media:description>Keogh hopes that differential payments will compel hospitals to provide high-quality care. Photograph: Frances Roberts/Alamy</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/nhs-fine-poor-service</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>David Miliband would shun shadow cabinet job, says brother Ed</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/VHBznIhzzd4/david-miliband-ed-miliband</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/49514?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Adavid-miliband-ed-miliband%3A1887648&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Bedroom+tax%2CPolitics%2CUK+news%2CWelfare+%28Politics%29%2CHousing+%28Society%29%2CHousing+benefit%2CBenefits+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CFrank+Field+%28politician%29&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CCommunities+Society%2CSocial+Care+Society&amp;c6=Nicholas+Watt&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A33&amp;c8=1887648&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=David+Miliband+would+shun+shadow+cabinet+job%2C+says+brother+Ed&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FBedroom+tax" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Labour leader says former foreign secretary would have been unlikely to serve under him, in glimpse of strained relationship&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ed Miliband believed "from the moment" he became Labour leader that his brother, David, was unlikely ever to wish to serve under him in the shadow cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a sign of the estrangement between the two brothers, which helps explain why David Miliband has abandoned British politics, the Labour leader accepted as far back as 2010 that there was unlikely to be a political reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ed Miliband outlined his thinking about the departure of his brother, who has resigned his South Shields seat to become chief executive of the International Rescue Committee in New York, in an &lt;a href="http://labourlist.org/2013/03/ed-on-david-it-was-quite-clear-to-me-that-he-probably-didnt-want-to-come-into-the-shadow-cabinet/" title=""&gt;interview with the Labour List website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked whether he tried to talk his elder brother out of leaving British politics, the Labour leader said he had always been serious about inviting his brother to join the shadow cabinet. The former foreign secretary was understood to have been offered the post of shadow chancellor on two occasions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ed Miliband said: "I wanted him to feel there was a choice. At the same time, I didn't want to try and push him into doing something he didn't want to do. And it was quite clear to me from the moment I became leader that he probably didn't want to come into the shadow cabinet."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miliband added that he hoped his brother's thinking would change, though it became clear in recent months that he was serious about taking the charity job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I think he said to me in our second conversation: 'If I get offered this I'm likely to take it.' So in a way I think the die was cast in terms of what was going to happen if he was offered the job. It was a big opportunity, it speaks to our family history, it suits his talents."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is understood to be a reference to the early years of the IRC, whose predecessor organisation was founded in 1933 at the suggestion of Albert Einstein to help victims of the Nazis in the year Adolf Hitler was appointed chancellor of Germany. The Milibands' Jewish parents survived the Holocaust. Their father, Ralph, fled to Britain from Belgium in 1940; their mother, Marion Kozak, was protected by Poles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ed Miliband said he was sad David was leaving Britain though happy about his excitement over his new job. He said the media "soap opera" about them had died down though he admitted there had been uncertainty about his plans. "There was clearly a sense of uncertainty about what he was going to do, and so it's brought a sense of clarity. So in that sense I think it's good. For him – and for me – that it sort of came out in the right way. I think there was generosity on all sides of the Labour party for the contribution he has made."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/bedroom-tax"&gt;Bedroom tax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/welfare"&gt;Welfare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/housing"&gt;Housing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/housing-benefit"&gt;Housing benefit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/benefits"&gt;Benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/frank-field"&gt;Frank Field&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/nicholaswatt"&gt;Nicholas Watt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a27793b/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/VHBznIhzzd4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Housing benefit</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Welfare</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Benefits</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Housing</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Bedroom tax</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Frank Field</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:57:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/david-miliband-ed-miliband</guid><dc:creator>Nicholas Watt</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:35:57Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406465005</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Bedroom tax, Politics, UK news, Welfare, Housing, Housing benefit, Benefits, Society, Frank Field</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/27/1364411479842/David-Miliband-hugs-Ed-Mi-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Leon Neal/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>David Miliband hugs younger brother Ed after the latter won the Labour leadership battle. Photograph: Leon Neal/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/27/1364411485631/David-Miliband-hugs-Ed-Mi-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Leon Neal/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>David Miliband hugs younger brother Ed after the latter won the Labour leadership battle. Photograph: Leon Neal/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/david-miliband-ed-miliband</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Nick Clegg under pressure over complaint letter about Mike Hancock</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/usjfOXhJmVo/nick-clegg-pressure-mike-hancock</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/91910?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Anick-clegg-pressure-mike-hancock%3A1887653&amp;ch=Politics&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Nick+Clegg%2CPolitics%2CLiberal+Democrats+Lib+dems&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Nicholas+Watt&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A42&amp;c8=1887653&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Nick+Clegg+under+pressure+over+complaint+letter+about+Mike+Hancock&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FPolitics%2FNick+Clegg" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Lib Dem leader's office claims it did not receive letter from lawyer of woman accusing MP of sexually inappropriate conduct&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nick Clegg is facing fresh pressure over his claim that his office "never" received a letter from the solicitor of a woman who complained about allegedly inappropriate sexual behaviour by the veteran Liberal Democrat MP Mike Hancock.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The woman's solicitor, Harriet Wistrich of Birnberg Peirce and Partners, said she wrote to the party in October 2011 after her client failed to receive a proper reply having written "one email and two full letters of complaint" to Clegg's office earlier that year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intervention by Wistrich raises questions about a claim by the deputy prime minister in his weekly LBC radio interview on Thursday that his office was not contacted by the woman's solicitor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clegg was asked by the LBC radio presented Nick Ferrari why he did not reply to a written complaint he received in March 2011 about Hancock's behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clegg told Ferrari: "My office never received one of the letters from the complainant's solicitors. We did receive a letter in February of this year. You'll be aware, I hope, because I think it's only fair to point this out, that the police have looked into this matter before, have dismissed it because I don't think that they can take it forward on advice from the Crown Prosecution Service. But you're right, we did receive a fuller letter from the complainant in February of this year."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is understood the woman wrote to Clegg in March 2011 at Lib Dem headquarters. This was followed by an email to his office a month later, which prompted a standard acknowledgment. She wrote a second letter in May 2011 after receiving no proper reply to her first letter or email. She again got no reply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wistrich wrote to the Guardian: "My client, the constituent, wrote one email and two full letters of complaint in 2011. The email received an automatic acknowledgment, but when the complainant received no reply to the letters, she became sufficiently paranoid to tape-record two telephone calls in attempt to discover why she had not received a response. She was then given to believe a reply would be sent to her, but received none.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Subsequently, the complainant instructed me and I wrote to the Liberal Democrat party in October 2011. They wrote back in February 2012 indicating that a 'relevant committee' had considered the complaint but decided not to investigate, as both the police and parliamentary standards commissioner had decided not to investigate."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his radio interview Clegg said that the "fuller" letter from the woman this February prompted him to despatch Alistair Carmichael, the Lib Dem chief whip, to investigate. "My chief whip has gone down to Portsmouth, has spoken to Mike Hancock's solicitors, has written to the complainant's solicitors offering to meet them, I hope they will do that. So I hope you won't imply in any way that we're not acting very, very thoroughly and quickly in response to what of course are serious allegations which are also very vigorously denied by Mike Hancock."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wistrich suggested that the Lib Dems acted only when the party was criticised over its failure to take action over separate allegations of inappropriate behaviour by the Lib Dem peer Lord Rennard. "It was only following the Lord Rennard scandal, that I wrote again to the Lib Dems asking them to review their decision. I was told the matter was receiving urgent consideration. However, it was not until 28 March, the day of Nick Clegg's broadcast, that I received a letter requesting a meeting with myself and the complainant."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lib Dems conduced an exhaustive search for the March 2011 letter from the complainant after her solicitor enclosed a copy when she submitted a detailed complaint last month. But the Lib Dems did not find any record of it. A party spokesperson said: "We understand from the complainant's solicitor that she did write to us in March 2011. We apologise but as we have no record of the letter we did not reply at the time."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/nickclegg"&gt;Nick Clegg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/liberaldemocrats"&gt;Liberal Democrats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/nicholaswatt"&gt;Nicholas Watt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a24c8dc/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/usjfOXhJmVo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Nick Clegg</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Liberal Democrats</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:42:47 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/29/nick-clegg-pressure-mike-hancock</guid><dc:creator>Nicholas Watt</dc:creator><dc:subject>Politics</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-29T20:20:47Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406465600</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Nick Clegg, Politics, Liberal Democrats</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364586128280/Mike-Hancock-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Chris Ison/PA</media:credit><media:description>Veteran Liberal Democrat MP Mike Hancock who is to be investigated following a complaint of a breach of its code of conduct. Photograph: Chris Ison/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364586134256/Mike-Hancock-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Chris Ison/PA</media:credit><media:description>Veteran Liberal Democrat MP Mike Hancock who is to be investigated following a complaint of a breach of its code of conduct. Photograph: Chris Ison/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/29/nick-clegg-pressure-mike-hancock</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Bedroom tax is worthy of Stalin, says government's poverty tsar</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/xziut6_T6f0/bedroom-tax-worthy-stalin-poverty-tsar</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/42756?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abedroom-tax-worthy-stalin-poverty-tsar%3A1887652&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Housing+benefit%2CFrank+Field+%28politician%29%2CWelfare+%28Politics%29%2CPolitics%2CBenefits+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CHousing+%28Society%29%2CCommunities+%28Society%29%2CLocal+government+%28Society%29%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CCommunities+Society%2CSocial+Care+Society%2CLocal+Government+Society&amp;c6=Nicholas+Watt&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A41&amp;c8=1887652&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Bedroom+tax+is+worthy+of+Stalin%2C+says+government%27s+poverty+tsar&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FHousing+benefit" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Frank Field condemns change to housing benefit as 'flawed' and says scheme will eventually prove to be more expensive&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government's poverty tsar, Frank Field, has condemned the "bedroom tax" as a form of social engineering that would have made Joseph Stalin proud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the introduction of the change, in which housing benefit will be cut for tenants in social housing with a spare room, the former welfare reform minister predicted that the new system would eventually prove to be more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Field told the Guardian: "Housing officers are having to go round and tell people and they are in tears. These people have not wanted to be in what the government now defines as the 'wrong' house for them to be in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The government is introducing social and physical engineering on a scale that Stalin would have been proud of. The way they are doing it is so extraordinary."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Field, who was appointed by David Cameron as a poverty adviser in 2010, has &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2012/sep/23/poverty-tsar-frank-field-ignored" title=""&gt;become disenchanted with the government&lt;/a&gt; after he said that ministers had ignored the findings of a report that called for childhood development to be measured at the ages of three and five.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has established the Springboard project in his Birkenhead constituency, which aims to improve parenting skills by helping mothers from their 12th week of pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We are imprisoned in an education debate which thinks that social class determines children's educational achievements and their life chances," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We now know enough that, while that is so often true, it doesn't have to be. It doesn't have to be true if we do the sort of smart interventions we are proposing, which work with the grain of human nature."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The former minister believes that the coming week will be crucial in the evolution of the government's welfare reforms as the "bedroom tax" is introduced on Monday and Iain Duncan Smith's flagship universal credit system starts to be rolled out. Amid concerns in Whitehall that universal credit, in which all benefits will be rolled into one, is hopelessly complicated the scheme will now be piloted in just one area rather than four.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Field said: "Universal credit is down to one pilot area because it ain't working. I thought they could do all the pilot areas because the numbers are going to be so tiny you could fiddle it by doing the calculations manually. But it can't even do that so where are we with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Universal credit brilliantly deals with the graphs – are you better off or not. But it fails dismally to deal with real people in that a growing number of people do not think just being better off by a few quid is worth working for and want a multiple of their benefit levels."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Field believes the "bedroom tax" – or the "spare room subsidy", as the prime minister prefers to call it – is doomed to fail: "It is Treasury driven. There are always schemes in the department like this horrible one which civil servants take off the shelf."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Field says the change is flawed because housing associations have been encouraged to build two- and three-bedroom accommodation "irrespective of what the size of the population is". He says the government will initially save £500m because many people will take a cut in housing benefit because they cannot move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But he added: "I have constituents who don't want to but may break up their own circle of friends and go and live somewhere else. But it will cost more. The housing benefit bill will go up because rent levels you can go up to in the private sector are larger than in the public sector."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/housing-benefit"&gt;Housing benefit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/frank-field"&gt;Frank Field&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/welfare"&gt;Welfare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/benefits"&gt;Benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/housing"&gt;Housing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/communities"&gt;Communities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/localgovernment"&gt;Local government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/nicholaswatt"&gt;Nicholas Watt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a24b19f/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990786827/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a24b19f/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990786827/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a24b19f/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990786827/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a24b19f/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/xziut6_T6f0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Housing benefit</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Welfare</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Benefits</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Housing</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Communities</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Local government</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Frank Field</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:41:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/bedroom-tax-worthy-stalin-poverty-tsar</guid><dc:creator>Nicholas Watt</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:08:22Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406465597</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Housing benefit, Frank Field, Welfare, Politics, Benefits, Society, Housing, Communities, Local government, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364586051176/Frank-Field-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Martin Godwin/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Frank Field: 'The government is introducing social and physical engineering on a scale that Stalin would have been proud of.' Photograph: Martin Godwin for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364586058152/Frank-Field-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Martin Godwin/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Frank Field: 'The government is introducing social and physical engineering on a scale that Stalin would have been proud of.' Photograph: Martin Godwin for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/bedroom-tax-worthy-stalin-poverty-tsar</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Silvio Berlusconi reiterates call for grand coalition government in Italy</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/-UbHnQEDr9w/silvio-berlusconi-grand-coaltion-italy</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/27876?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Asilvio-berlusconi-grand-coaltion-italy%3A1887639&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Italian+elections+2013%2CItaly+%28News%29%2CSilvio+Berlusconi%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CBeppe+Grillo%2CFive+Star+Movement%2CMario+Monti&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CUnclassifed+Contributors&amp;c6=Lizzy+Davies&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A02&amp;c8=1887639&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Silvio+Berlusconi+reiterates+call+for+grand+coalition+government+in+Italy&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FItalian+elections+2013" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Former PM says 'no other solution' than a coalition including his own Freedom People party can break political deadlock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Silvio Berlusconi has positioned himself as a benevolent statesman acting in the best interests of Italy as he reiterated his call for a grand coalition government with his opponents to break the political deadlock after last month's election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As he emerged on Friday from a meeting with President Giorgio Napolitano, the head of state who has led a series of day closed-doors consultations with the parties, Berlusconi said there was "no other solution" than a broad coalition government that included his own centre-right Freedom People (PdL) party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Touting it as a government of "professionalism and responsibility as well as common sense", the three-time prime minister said his rightwing alliance with the regionalist Northern League would accept Pier Luigi Bersani, the centre-left Democratic party (PD) leader, as premier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a technocrat or "quasi-technocrat" government was unacceptable, Berlusconi said, "given the negative and tragic experience" of the one led by Mario Monti, which is still in charge in a caretaker capacity and marks 500 days in office this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Berlusconi, 76, has been advocating the formation of a PD-PdL government since the paralysingly inconclusive election results nearly five weeks ago. Bersani, whose party has an outright majority in one house of parliament but not in the other, has consistently rejected it, not least because of the billionaire media mogul's desire to exert influence over the selection of Napolitano's successor as head of state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday, even after the embattled PD head admitted to Napolitano on Thursday that he had not been able to find the numbers for a government, the party's stance appeared no different.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The anti-establishment Five Star Movement of former comedian Beppe Grillo, meanwhile, maintained its resolute opposition to giving its support to any government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such was the continuing deadlock that Napolitano, whom some had expected to announce a new name to try to form a government, was said to be taking more time to reflect on the impasse. A statement was expected&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One scenario would be a so-called "government of the president", led by a well-known but less political figure, which would have a relatively short term and a restricted remit of reform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If neither that nor a broad coalition can be agreed on, Monti's mandate as caretaker prime minister could theoretically be extended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Napolitano is keen to avoid a quick return to the polls – which could, theoretically, happen as soon as June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Berlusconi's PdL, meanwhile, is outperforming the PD in some recent polls, while attention in the PD is shifting to the mayor of Florence, Matteo Renzi. An SWG survey published on Friday found 66% of Italians would like to see Renzi leading the centre-left in a new election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/italian-elections-2013"&gt;Italian elections 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/italy"&gt;Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/silvio-berlusconi"&gt;Silvio Berlusconi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/beppe-grillo"&gt;Beppe Grillo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/five-star-movement"&gt;Five Star Movement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/mario-monti"&gt;Mario Monti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/lizzydavies"&gt;Lizzy Davies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a241077/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990786266/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a241077/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161990786266/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a241077/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161990786266/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/2a241077/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/-UbHnQEDr9w" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Silvio Berlusconi</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Italian elections 2013</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Italy</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:29:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/29/silvio-berlusconi-grand-coaltion-italy</guid><dc:creator>Lizzy Davies</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:08:55Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406464454</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Italian elections 2013, Italy, Silvio Berlusconi, Europe, World news, Beppe Grillo, Five Star Movement, Mario Monti</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364583720246/Silvio-Berlusconi-address-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alessandro Di Meo/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Silvio Berlusconi addresses the media after his meeting with Italian president in Rome. Photograph: Alessandro Di Meo/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/29/1364583726246/Silvio-Berlusconi-address-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Alessandro Di Meo/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Silvio Berlusconi addresses the media after his meeting with the Italian president in Rome. Photograph: Alessandro di Meo/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/29/silvio-berlusconi-grand-coaltion-italy</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Cyprus has a future in the euro, insists president</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/pJaOuka_XMI/cyprus-stay-euro-president</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/27416?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Acyprus-stay-euro-president%3A1887647&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Cyprus+%28News%29%2CEurozone+crisis%2CEuropean+Union+EU+%28News%29%2CEuropean+monetary+union+EMU%2CEconomics+%28Business%29%2CEuropean+banks+%28business%29%2CFinancial+crisis+%28Business%29%2CFinancial+sector+%28business%29%2CEuro+%28Business%29%2CBusiness%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CCredit+Crunch%2CBusiness+Markets%2CPolicy+Society%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CProperty+Mortgages+and+Interest+Rates&amp;c6=Jennifer+Rankin%2CHelena+Smith%2CKim+Willsher&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A25&amp;c8=1887647&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Cyprus+has+a+future+in+the+euro%2C+insists+president&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FCyprus" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Nicos Anastasiades says crisis has been averted but blasts eurozone members for turning island into an 'experiment'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus's president on Friday insisted his country has a future in the euro in a speech that also criticised his eurozone partners for forcing the Mediterranean island to be an "experiment".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We have no intention of leaving the euro. In no way will we experiment with the future of our country," Nicos Anastasiades said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking the day after Cypriot banks reopened after a two-week closure to stave off financial collapse, the Conservative head of state said the threat of bankruptcy had been averted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also promised that restrictions on banking transactions – the first ever to be imposed on a eurozone member state – would be gradually lifted, but did not specify when.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cash withdrawals from banks have been limited to €300 (£253) a day, while only €1,000 in cash can be taken out of the country, and there are restrictions on the use of credit cards abroad. Cypriot authorities loosened some restrictions on using cheques on Friday – but only to allow payments to government agencies of up to €5,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In another turnaround of capital controls placed on a euro member state, the finance ministry announced that debit and credit card transactions with the borders of the country could also be unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus's Central Bank has also imposed limits on the money that can be taken "beyond the control of the Cypriot authorities" – a reference to the northern part of the island under Turkish control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After an initial estimate that the capital controls would be in place for a matter of days, the government then warned later in the week they could last for "about a month".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anastasiades, who was elected in a landslide victory on a pro-bailout platform last month, has faced a backlash over the terms of the rescue. On Friday he accused eurozone leaders of making "unprecedented demands that forced Cyprus to become an experiment". He also criticised European banking authorities for allowing money to flood into Laiki, the island's second biggest bank, which had racked up billions of debt in bad loans and is now being wound up as part of the rescue deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"How serious were those authorities that permitted the financing of a bankrupt bank to the highest possible amount?" Anastasiades said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barely a month in power, the government has appointed an investigating committee of former supreme and international criminal court judges to probe possible criminal misconduct in the collapse of the Cypriot economy. With shocked Greek Cypriots now facing years of economic pain, there are mounting calls for punishment to be meted out to the politicians and bankers found to be responsible for the dire straits in which the island now finds itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Swedish foreign minister, Carl Bildt, who flew into Cyprus to hold talks with Anastasiades, said Cyprus was heading for years of economic recession. "It is going to go into recession, a big slump," he told the Guardian. "A lot could have been done to stop it reaching this point. I cannot say I am optimistic, but I am also not alarmed."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus secured a €10bn (£8.4bn) bailout from the "troika" of lenders – the European Union, the European Central Bank and the International Monetary Fund – to avert financial collapse. As well as the winding up of Laiki, the island had to agree to an unprecedented levy on bank savings of more than $100,000 to fund the bailout. Earlier plans to raid the accounts of small depositors were abandoned amid fury from ordinary savers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cypriot banks were calm on Friday, with no big queues reported. "The situation, despite all its tragedy, has been contained," said Anastasiades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cypriot president's attempt to draw a line under the crisis that has gripped the eurozone came as Slovenia, another minnow of the currency union, insisted it did not need the eurozone to rescue its troubled banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We will need no bailout this year," said the Slovenian finance minister, Uros Cufer. "I am calm." Borrowing costs for the former Yugoslav republic, which has a population of two million, have jumped as investors look for the next weak link in the single currency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cypriot crisis has sent shudders throughout the eurozone, where the outlook remains gloomy and unemployment rises to record levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figures released on Friday showed that France failed to meet its budget deficit target in 2012 and will miss it again this year. The country's public debt has also risen to a record level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest bad news came only hours after French president François Hollande had gone on live television to reassure the nation of his ability to lead it out of the economic mire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;INSEE, France's national statistics agency reported that public debt rose to €1.8 trillion, a record 90.2 per cent of GDP, in 2012, up from 85.8 per cent in 2011. France's Socialist government has already admitted it will not be able to keep a pledge to bring the deficit down to 3 per cent by the end of 2013 as agreed with the European Commission. The figure is now expected to be around 3.7 per cent, and France has asked for an extension to the deadline for reaching the target. France has not balanced its books since 1974 under successive governments of different political hue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/cyprus"&gt;Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/debt-crisis"&gt;Eurozone crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/eu"&gt;European Union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/emu"&gt;European monetary union&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/economics"&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/europeanbanks"&gt;European banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/financial-crisis"&gt;Financial crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/financial-sector"&gt;Financial sector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/euro"&gt;Euro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jennifer-rankin"&gt;Jennifer Rankin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/helenasmith"&gt;Helena Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/kim-willsher"&gt;Kim Willsher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a244481/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/pJaOuka_XMI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Financial sector</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Euro</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">European Union</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Banking</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Economics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Cyprus</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Eurozone crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">European banks</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Financial crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">European monetary union</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:25:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/29/cyprus-stay-euro-president</guid><dc:creator>Jennifer Rankin, Helena Smith, Kim Willsher</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T12:36:58Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406464937</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Cyprus, Eurozone crisis, European Union, European monetary union, Economics, European banks, Financial crisis, Financial sector, Euro, Business, Europe, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364584952434/Nicos-Anastasiades-Cyprus-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Philippos Christou/AP</media:credit><media:description>Cypriot president Nicos Anastasiades has faced a backlash from voters over the terms of the EU bailout. Photograph: Philippos Christou/AP</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/29/cyprus-stay-euro-president</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>European watchdog accuses Britain of shameful rhetoric on migrants</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/Ntrp3u4k9kU/eu-watchdog-britain-shameful-rhetoric-migrants</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/75459?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aeu-watchdog-britain-shameful-rhetoric-migrants%3A1887638&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Immigration+and+asylum+%28UK+news%29%2CUK+news%2CHuman+rights%2CLaw%2CDavid+Cameron%2CPolitics%2CUkip+UK+Independence+party%2CBenefits+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CSocial+exclusion+%28Society%29&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CSocial+Care+Society&amp;c6=Alan+Travis%2CShiv+Malik&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A08&amp;c8=1887638&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=European+watchdog+accuses+Britain+of+shameful+rhetoric+on+migrants&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FImmigration+and+asylum" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Bulgarians and Romanians 'treated like a scourge' as immigration debate in UK takes worrying turn, says watchdog&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The debate over immigration in Britain has taken a worrying turn and is fuelling stereotypes and hostility towards migrants, Europe's human rights watchdog has warned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nils Muiznieks, the Council of Europe's human rights commissioner, has said it is simply unacceptable to treat Bulgarian and Romanian citizens like a scourge and says it is time to blow the whistle on such shameful rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also warned that British government moves to restrict the access of new European migrants to social security, housing and social security, will only increase their social exclusion, fuel anti-immigration rhetoric and create even more social problems in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Muiznieks told the Guardian: "The UK debate has taken a worrying turn as it depicts lower-skilled migrants as dangerous foreigners coming to steal jobs, lower salaries and spoil the health system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"A stigma is put on Bulgarian and Romanian citizens just because of their origin. This is unacceptable because a state cannot treat Bulgarian and Romanian citizens differently from other EU citizens. They need to be treated as everyone else, not on the basis of assumptions or generalisations about their ethnic origin," said Muiznieks, a Latvian politician and human rights activist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says that British political leaders have a crucial role in turning round the heated political debates in Britain and Germany on the threat posed by a supposed imminent flood of Roma from Bulgaria and Romania once employment restrictions are lifted in January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His warning comes after David Cameron's immigration speech on Monday, which he said risked feeding stereotypes and hostility towards migrants."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cameron laid out plans to restrict health and housing benefits to migrant groups. In a speech widely seen as an attempt to fend off an electoral challenge from Ukip, the prime minister said he wanted to stop migrants claiming NHS treatment for free, and also ensure that UK residents got preferential treatment in social housing. But &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/25/david-cameron-immigration-speech-trouble" title=""&gt;Cameron's speech unravelled later in the week &lt;/a&gt;when government estimates about the un-recouped cost of health provision to migrants from the 30-member European Economic Area varied between £20m as suggested by Downing Street, and £200m according the health secretary, Jeremy Hunt. The total NHS budget is £100bn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministers have been drawing up other plans to keep overall immigration down. On Wednesday, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/27/ministers-immigration-crackdown-education-tourists" title=""&gt;the Guardian revealed that ministers are considering asking schools to check whether pupils are illegal migrants&lt;/a&gt;. According to a series of leaked emails, the inter-ministerial group on migrant access to benefits also contemplated banning an estimated 120,000 illegal migrant children from education.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Friday the joint chairmen of the cross party balanced migration group, Labour's Frank Field and Conservative Nicholas Soames, called on Cameron to do more to restrict European immigration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an article for the Telegraph, &lt;a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/immigration/9959813/Britain-cant-afford-this-level-of-immigration.html" title=""&gt;they wrote that low skilled European migration &lt;/a&gt;was making it harder on the UK's young unemployed. "Most migrants who come to the UK to work take low-skilled jobs, as we saw following the earlier wave of eastern European migrants. With one million 18- to 24-year-olds out of work, allowing this to continue does not make sense, quite apart from the increasing pressure on our infrastructure.''&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Muiznieks's intervention comes as a close political ally of Cameron, Sweden's prime minister, Fredrik Reinfelt, described the British plan to curb access for new migrants to public services as "unfortunate". Reinfelt said that when Sweden opened its borders to Romanians and Bulgarians it saw no evidence of people from those countries trying to abuse his country's generous benefits system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We didn't see this big social tourism that everyone warned us about and it might be wise to share that experience with others," said the Swedish PM. "I believe in a Europe that is open, where we have freedom of movement and where we should rather be asking the question of how to make it easier for people to come here and work."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe's human rights watchdog reinforced this telling the Guardian: "Let's face up to reality: people migrate because migrant labour is in demand. Migrant workers often fill gaps in sectors that locals have deserted and they contribute a great deal to the prosperity of a country both in terms of economic and financial output, as well as services offered."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Muiznieks said that British political leaders had to provide a positive lead in the immigration debate and acknowledge that the wealth produced by migrants profited everyone: "Migrants are crucial for our economies," he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said that states had to take integration policy seriously for migration to contribute positively to society: "If migrants have no access to quality education, housing, health care and social security from the start, this will only increase their social exclusion. This in turn fuels anti-immigration rhetoric and xenophobia, and creates even more social problems in the long run. Immigrants should therefore enjoy the same social rights as other Europeans."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/immigration"&gt;Immigration and asylum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/human-rights"&gt;Human rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/davidcameron"&gt;David Cameron&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/ukip"&gt;UK Independence party (Ukip)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/benefits"&gt;Benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/socialexclusion"&gt;Social exclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/alantravis"&gt;Alan Travis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/malik-shiv"&gt;Shiv Malik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a249ac9/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/Ntrp3u4k9kU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">UK Independence party (Ukip)</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">David Cameron</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Immigration and asylum</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Benefits</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Law</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Human rights</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Social exclusion</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:08:50 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/29/eu-watchdog-britain-shameful-rhetoric-migrants</guid><dc:creator>Alan Travis, Shiv Malik</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:35:57Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406464444</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Immigration and asylum, UK news, Human rights, Law, David Cameron, Politics, UK Independence party (Ukip), Benefits, Society, Europe, World news, Social exclusion</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/25/1364243098919/David-Cameron-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Andy Rain/EPA</media:credit><media:description>David Cameron said he wanted to give a 'very clear message' to European immigrants that there was no absolute right to unemployment benefit. Photograph: Andy Rain/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/25/1364243106358/David-Cameron-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Andy Rain/EPA</media:credit><media:description>David Cameron said he wanted to give a 'very clear message' to European immigrants that there was no absolute right to unemployment benefit. Photograph: Andy Rain/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/29/eu-watchdog-britain-shameful-rhetoric-migrants</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>BBC chief must purge middle management, says Melvyn Bragg</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/SvXy-3kypVs/bbc-chief-hall-bragg</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/77354?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abbc-chief-hall-bragg%3A1887641&amp;ch=Media&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=BBC%2CTony+Hall+%28Media%29%2CMelvyn+Bragg+%28Media%29%2CMedia%2CTelevision+and+radio+TV%2CTelevision+industry+%28Media%29%2CTelevision+%28Culture%29%2CGeorge+Entwistle%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Press+Media%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMedia+Weekly%2CTelevision+Media&amp;c6=John+Plunkett&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A07&amp;c8=1887641&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=BBC+chief+must+purge+middle+management%2C+says+Melvyn+Bragg&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FMedia%2FBBC" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Broadcaster says Jimmy Savile crisis has exposed the BBC's 'dire structure' and that Lord Hall will need a 'cleansing sword'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lord Hall, the BBC's incoming £450,000-a-year director general, will outline his vision for the future of the corporation when he takes up his new role next week in an attempt to draw a line under the Savile crisis, which saw off his predecessor after just 54 days in charge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking up his post on Tuesday, Hall is planning a blitz of broadcast interviews, part of a concerted response to accusations that the previous regime was not responsive enough to the media. His predecessor, George Entwistle, was reluctant to appear on camera – and in particular repeatedly declined to appear on ITV, Channel 4 or Sky News.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The arts broadcaster Lord Bragg said Hall, who moves to the BBC from running the Royal Opera House, had no option but to cut a swath through BBC middle management in the wake of the damning conclusions of the Pollard report into the Savile crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The Savile crisis has exposed a dire structure and I think he should go in with a cleansing sword. It's not just individuals – it's the system. He has shown he can do it – he was very good at the Royal Opera House. Savile exposed the problems with the middle management at the BBC, which clogs everything up. I speak as a great admirer of the BBC [but] it is amazing that they can get any programmes done at all," said Bragg at a launch of his latest Sky Arts series last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hall will hold his first meeting with the BBC's management board on Tuesday morning at New Broadcasting House, with key executives including creative director Alan Yentob, BBC Worldwide chief executive Tim Davie and the newly recruited strategy and digital director, former culture secretary and Labour MP James Purnell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He then plans to hold an informal staff meeting later in the day, and will follow that up with a Reithian tour of the organisation's "inform, educate, and entertain" operations by visiting BBC1's Panorama, its science department, Radio 1 and the "tech ops" team that has kept the BBC's various services on air despite the recent bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the executive meeting, Hall is expected to outline his future strategy for the BBC and where he wants it to be in a decade from now in terms of programme-making, technology and culture. He will not look to undo any of the £700m of cost-cutting measures contained in Mark Thompson's Delivering Quality First initiative, but will outline key areas that he wants his management team to prioritise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, although the initial impact of the Savile scandal has subsided, more than 850 members of staff have raised concerns with a review into sexual harassment and bullying at the corporation. The BBC's difficulties over the handling of the Savile crisis, as exposed in Nick Pollard's report, also revealed a culture of mistrust amongst executives and between executives and its journalists, divisions that meant BBC executives were reluctant to believe Newsnight reporters who thought they could expose sexual abuse perpetrated by the late presenter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new leader's most immediate task will be to restore faith in BBC News in the wake of Savile and Newsnight's calamitous report erroneously linking former Tory party chairman Lord McAlpine to child abuse, but the subject is familiar to him, as he ran BBC News and Current Affairs between 1989 and 2001, largely during the ascendency of John Birt at the corporation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has to begin with the appointment of a new director of news after the incumbent, Helen Boaden, criticised in the Pollard report, was moved to fill the vacant director of radio role. Some senior insiders believing that the job could go to James Harding, the former editor of the Times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"News and current affairs is absolutely at the core of the BBC's brand and trustworthiness and is the number one reason we have the licence fee," said one senior industry source. "Arguably in the internet era of news and gossip you need the BBC more than you ever needed it before. It is tarnished post-Savile and the whole meltdown on Newsnight. He has got to make the whole thing trustworthy again."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hall's office is next to the corporation's sprawling news department on the fourth floor of the newly refurbished Broadcasting House in central London. The new director general is also expected to make an early appearance on the Today programme, located a floor below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the inquisition on Today by John Humphrys, on 10 November last year, that finally sealed the fate of his predecessor, with Entwistle resigning about 12 hours later. It remains to be seen, though, whether Humphrys will be given the job of interviewing his new boss.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What's in Hall's in-tray?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Restore trust in BBC News in the wake of the meltdown at Newsnight over the Jimmy Savile scandal. See through the final ramifications of the Savile crisis, including a review by Dame Janet Smith.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Resolve the industrial dispute with trade unions over job cuts, excessive workload and alleged bullying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Fill the two vacancies at the top of BBC management: director of news and director of television.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Complete the £700m round of cost-cutting begun by former director general Mark Thompson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Redress the imbalance that has led to too few women appearing on BBC television channels and radio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Respond to criticism from, among others, the broadcaster Lord Bragg and Nicholas Hytner, director of the National Theatre, that the BBC does not do enough arts coverage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Develop a technology strategy, post-iPlayer, for the mobile era.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Prepare for his first Commons select committee appearance as director general on 25 April and pave the way for a new charter and licence fee settlement in the runup to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/bbc"&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/tony-hall"&gt;Tony Hall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/melvyn-bragg"&gt;Melvyn Bragg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/television"&gt;Television industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture/television"&gt;Television&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/george-entwistle"&gt;George Entwistle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/johnplunkett"&gt;John Plunkett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a27b0f1/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/SvXy-3kypVs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Television industry</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tv-and-radio">Television &amp; radio</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Media</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tv-and-radio">Television</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">George Entwistle</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">BBC</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Melvyn Bragg</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/media">Tony Hall</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:07:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/mar/29/bbc-chief-hall-bragg</guid><dc:creator>John Plunkett</dc:creator><dc:subject>Media</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-30T00:08:03Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406464519</dc:identifier><media:keywords>BBC, Tony Hall, Melvyn Bragg, Media, Television &amp; radio, Television industry, Television, George Entwistle, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364583977293/Tony-Hall-BBC-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Graeme Robertson/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Tony Hall is planning a blitz of interviews after he takes up his role as chief executive of the BBC. Photograph: Graeme Robertson for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/29/1364583984310/Tony-Hall-BBC-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Graeme Robertson/Guardian</media:credit><media:description>Tony Hall is planning a blitz of interviews after he takes up his role as chief executive of the BBC. Photograph: Graeme Robertson for the Guardian</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/media/2013/mar/29/bbc-chief-hall-bragg</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Electrosensitivity: is technology killing us?</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/YMkAi2NbAAU/electrosensitivity-is-technology-killing-us</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.4/39237?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aelectrosensitivity-is-technology-killing-us%3A1886206&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Health+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CHealth+and+wellbeing+%28Life+and+style%29%2CLife+and+style%2CMobile+phones+%28Technology%29%2CTelecoms+%28Technology%29%2CTechnology%2CEnergy+%28Environment%29%2CEnvironment%2CPsychology+%28Science%29%2CScience&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEnergy%2CEthical+Living%2CTechnology+Gadgets%2CHealth+Society%2CCorporate+IT%2CHealth&amp;c6=Nicholas+Blincoe&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F29+07%3A00&amp;c8=1886206&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Feature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Electrosensitivity%3A+is+technology+killing+us%3F&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FHealth" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Is modern life making us&amp;nbsp;ill? Yes, say those who&amp;nbsp;suffer from electrosensitivity. Are&amp;nbsp;they cranks, or should we all be throwing away our mobile phones?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim Hallam is just tall enough to seem gangly. His height makes the bedroom feel even smaller than it is. Muddy sunlight filters through the grey gauze hung over his window. His narrow bed appears to be covered with a glistening silver mosquito net. The door and the ceiling are lined with tinfoil. Tim tells me there is also a layer of foil beneath the wallpaper and under the wood-effect flooring. He says, "The room is completely insulated; the edges are sealed with aluminium tape and connected with conducting tape so I could &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ground_%28electricity%29" title=""&gt;ground&lt;/a&gt; the whole room. It's a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Faraday_cage" title=""&gt;Faraday cage&lt;/a&gt;, effectively. Grounding helps with the low frequencies radiation, apparently. The high frequencies just bounce off the outside."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim is trying to escape atmospheric manmade radiation caused by Wi-Fi, phone signals, radio, even TV screens and fluorescent bulbs. It's a&amp;nbsp;hopeless task, he admits: "It's so hard to get away from, and it's taken a toll on my life." I&amp;nbsp;offer to put my phone outside the room and he happily accepts, firmly closing the door. He explains the phone would have kept searching for a signal. "And because it wouldn't find one, it would keep ramping up." With the tinfoil inside his cage, the signal would hurtle around the room like a&amp;nbsp;panicked bird.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim estimates he spent £1,000 on the insulation, taking photographs at every stage to share with others via &lt;a href="http://www.es-uk.info/" title=""&gt;ElectroSensitivity UK&lt;/a&gt;, the society for sufferers. He found the whole process stressful, especially after a summer sleeping in the garden of his shared house in Leamington Spa to escape a new flatmate's powerful Wi-Fi router. How did he feel about the flatmate at the time? "Oh, I hated him. It wasn't really him, of course. But I was so angry." Among the symptoms Tim experiences – headaches, muscular pain, dry eyes – there are memory lapses and irritability. He now says his bed is the single most important thing he owns. "I climb in and zip it up so I'm completely sealed. Inside, I sleep extremely well. Without it, my sleep is fragmented, and without sleep, then lots of other things go wrong."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim demonstrates the effectiveness of the tinfoil using a radiation detector called Elektrosmog, manufactured in Germany. It is blocky and white, which makes it look both retro and futuristic. On the front of the box, a picture of an electricity pylon is surrounded by jagged black lightning flashes. The machine gives a reading close to zero: Tim's room is radiation-free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a child in the 70s, I watched a BBC science-fiction serial called &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CYkkfBMK-7c" title=""&gt;The Changes&lt;/a&gt;, which imagined a future after humans became allergic to electricity. Pylons were the greatest danger, making people violently sick. On cross-country runs, I would speed up when I had to pass beneath a power cable, feeling the weight of the buzzing electricity above me. The idea that electromagnetic fields affect our health took root in the 1960s. A US doctor named &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_O._Becker" title=""&gt;Robert O Becker&lt;/a&gt; became the face of the campaign against pylons after appearing on the US TV show 60 Minutes. &lt;a href="http://andrewamarino.com/" title=""&gt;Professor Andrew Marino&lt;/a&gt;, now of Louisiana State&amp;nbsp;University, was Becker's lab partner. Marino&amp;nbsp;says, "He's the reason nobody wants to live near power lines."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If electromagnetic radiation is dangerous to humans, there are far more risks now than 40 years ago, thanks to the telecommunications industry. More than a billion people worldwide own mobile phones. In the UK, there are more mobile contracts than people. The new 4G spectrum will cover 98% of the country, erasing all but the most remote "not spots".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Mireille Toledano runs &lt;a href="http://www.ukcosmos.org/" title=""&gt;Cosmos&lt;/a&gt;, a 30-year, five-nation study into the effects of telecoms radiation on humans. She knows how rapidly things are changing. In 2000, &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=2&amp;ved=0CDgQFjAB&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.iarc.fr%2Fen%2Fmedia-centre%2Fpr%2F2010%2Fpdfs%2Fpr200_E.pdf&amp;ei=rXhMUfD3G4jXPMXIgMAF&amp;usg=AFQjCNHX3q8_HZAQLA_VE5oq7fSV6klK2A&amp;bvm=bv.44158598,d.ZWU" title=""&gt;a 10-year study into mobile phones and brain tumours&lt;/a&gt; pegged heavy use at 30 minutes a day. The study found the 90th &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Percentile" title=""&gt;percentile&lt;/a&gt; had spent 1,640 hours of their lives on their phones. In the UK, Toledano says, "heavy use is now defined at 86 minutes a day; 30 minutes is in the median range. Across the whole [international Cosmos study], the top 10% of users have now clocked up 4,160 or more hours."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The earlier study found no evidence linking phone use and cancer in the short term, yet as our love affair with technology keeps deepening, anxieties grow. Two years ago, the European Assembly passed &lt;a href="http://www.assembly.coe.int/Mainf.asp?link=/Documents/AdoptedText/ta11/ERES1815.htm" title=""&gt;Resolution 1815&lt;/a&gt;, which, among other things, calls for restrictions on Wi-Fi in schools and the use of mobile phones by children. The &lt;a href="http://www.who.int/en/" title=""&gt;World Health Organisation&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/feedarticle/9673216" title=""&gt;classified electromagnetic fields of the kind used in mobile telephony as Group 2b carcinogens&lt;/a&gt; – that is, as possibly cancerous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue of electromagnetic sensitivity is&amp;nbsp;immediately political. It places sufferers on the&amp;nbsp;other side from both industry and the governments that profit from leasing wavelengths. Over and over, I hear the phrase, "We are the canaries in the coal mine": sufferers believe we are approaching a tipping point. Tim&amp;nbsp;Hallam worries about the effects of electromagnetic fields on the most vulnerable: on his sister's young family; on children in schools bathed in Wi-Fi rays; or old people in sheltered accommodation, each with their own internet router. "I think it's affecting everyone's cells. There are test-tube experiments which show it damages DNA and affects the blood-brain barrier. I do think there's going to be a surge in the people who are sensitive in years to come. But my sister's not fully taken that on board."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet electro hypersensitivity syndrome is controversial. Sweden recognises EHS as a&amp;nbsp;"functional impairment", or disability, but it is the patients, not doctors, who make the diagnosis. The fact is, everyone who suffers from EHS is self-diagnosed – and each has their own story to explain the cause of their problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim was 15 years old, at a gig by the industrial band &lt;a href="http://www.sheepondrugs.net/" title=""&gt;Sheep on Drugs&lt;/a&gt;, when the singer produced a pistol and fired blanks into the ceiling. Tim, who is now 36, says, "It was the loudest thing I&amp;nbsp;had ever heard." His ears began ringing but he continued going to gigs without using ear plugs and the problem grew worse. He played clarinet in two orchestras but had to stop: "Immediately, my musical life and my social life ended." Today, his sister is a professional classical musician. Tim, a Cambridge graduate, is a van driver for Asda. He works shifts that allow him time alone when his flatmates are out and the house is free of Wi-Fi and phones. It was the arrival of Wi-Fi in his house, just 10 months ago, that led Tim to identify the cause of his problems, but it was the &lt;a href="http://www.tinnitus.org.uk/" title=""&gt;tinnitus&lt;/a&gt; that started it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michelle Berriedale-Johnson has worked in the field of food intolerances and allergies for more than 20 years. She runs the industry awards for "Free From" foods from her home in north-west London, as well as &lt;a href="http://www.foodsmatter.com/" title=""&gt;foodsmatter.com&lt;/a&gt;, a website that raises awareness around food intolerances. Five years ago, at the age of 60, she began to feel unwell. She was sitting at her desk when she identified the cause. "I looked up and there was the Royal Free Hospital with the phone masts on the top, beaming straight through my window, and it just clicked." Michelle is bright and lively, happy to dive beneath her desk to show the precautions she has taken to shield herself from the spaghetti of wires. Her walls are painted with carbon paint, lined with foil and papered over. The windows have the same netting as Tim's, though when she uses her Elektrosmog meter she discovers to her consternation that the netting is old and no longer works. Her front rooms buzz with electromagnetic radiation, though her office – now at the back of the house – shows far better readings. She says, "I'm lucky to work from home, but I often feel like a prisoner." When she leaves the house, she wears hats lined with material similar to Tim's mosquito netting and even has blouses made of the same material. "The&amp;nbsp;important thing is to protect your head and upper torso," she says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Michelle precisely identifies the moment she became sensitised to radiation. She was an early user of mobile phones. "Do you remember the type with the little aerial? I had one where the antenna had broken off, but I continued to use it pressed to my ear, which people who know tell me meant that I was using my entire head as an aerial." In her view, we are all sensitive to electromagnetic fields, but events can tip us over into hypersensitivity, like a kitchen sink filling so fast that the overflow becomes overwhelmed and water cascades to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem, in clinical terms, is that "hypersensitivity" refers either to allergies or to auto-immune conditions. EHS may be like hay fever or, in extreme cases, like rheumatoid arthritis but only via analogy. If we speak of "hypersensitivity" we are using a metaphor – or we are talking about something entirely new. Does this "new" condition exist?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Long-time researcher &lt;a href="http://ki.se/ki/jsp/polopoly.jsp?d=21984&amp;a=54583&amp;l=en" title=""&gt;Dr Olle Johansson&lt;/a&gt;, from Sweden's Karolinska Institute, coined the term "screen dermatitis" to explain why computer users in the depths of the Stockholm winter could complain of sunburn-like symptoms. Johansson has a theory that could explain how extremely high levels of radiation could affect &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Histamine" title=""&gt;histamine&lt;/a&gt; levels in cells. Yet telecoms radiation is low and becoming lower as gadgets become more efficient. Johansson acknowledges that if anyone is found to be truly allergic to their phone it would be an entirely new kind of allergy, but he hopes that an awareness of EHS will lead to revolutionary changes. "In Sweden, we take accessibility measures seriously for disabilities. You think of changes to sidewalks, or wheelchair access, or ramps on buses. These are also helpful to mothers with prams, people with shopping or to rollerskaters. The big winner is everyone." Similarly, he believes that cutting off the telecoms signals would not only help EHS sufferers, it would benefit all of us, returning us to a society based on face-to-face human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr James Rubin of King's College Institute of Psychiatry is adamant EHS is not a genuine syndrome. "With most conditions, patients don't necessarily know what's going on. But with electrosensitivity there's an absolute certainty about the cause. Self-diagnosis is at the core of it." He prefers the term "idiopathic environmental intolerances", or IEI, which covers conditions with no obvious cause, like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiple_chemical_sensitivity" title=""&gt;multiple chemical sensitivity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sick_building_syndrome" title=""&gt;sick building syndrome&lt;/a&gt;, food intolerances – even a physical reaction to wind turbines. "The problem is, if you look for a coherent set of symptoms, you are not going to find it. You even find that people's symptoms change over time. Many have other intolerances in addition to the electrical sensitivity."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tim is intolerant to milk and gluten. He is also allergic to wool, and cannot sleep in a room with a carpet. Michelle has no intolerances but admits she is unusual in the community: "Most people do." She made her diagnosis because she was familiar with EHS through her work. She is familiar with Rubin's research and has written blogs condemning his methods: "These stupid so-called &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Provocation_test" title=""&gt;provocation studies&lt;/a&gt; where they place a mobile in your hand and ask if you feel unwell. And if you say yes, they go, ho-ho, the phone wasn't switched on." These tests pay no attention to the way that people are sensitised, or react to their sensitivity in different ways, she believes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rubin is a bogeyman in the electrosensitive community thanks to a 2008 paper that suggested the condition was psychosomatic. Yet&amp;nbsp;he has also undertaken a review of all the research – more than 50 provocation studies – and&amp;nbsp;found no evidence of sensitivity to telecoms radiation. He says, "The suffering is very real – I&amp;nbsp;don't doubt that – and I take it very seriously. But&amp;nbsp;we've spent millions on the research and the&amp;nbsp;time comes when you have to say, in the future the money would be better spent on looking for effective treatments, rather than chasing a&amp;nbsp;cause."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Andrew Marino is less sceptical. "When people say they feel unwell and trace that&amp;nbsp;to a Wi-Fi signal or a phone, that is a kind of&amp;nbsp;experiment. It may not be well designed, they&amp;nbsp;may not understand blinds and double blinds, but if they are reasonable people, carefully&amp;nbsp;noting what they are suffering, we should take a look at that."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marino was a first-year postgraduate in 1964 when he began working with Dr Robert Becker. Once he and Becker began campaigning against electricity pylons, their funding disappeared. Becker retired at the relatively young age of 56. Today, Andrew Marino will not look to industry for research funds. He has reviewed many of the same 50 papers on EHS as Rubin, concluding, "It's easy to find nothing." The common denominator he identified in the papers casting doubt on EHS is that they were funded by the telecommunications industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EHS sufferers have criticised Rubin's research because it is funded jointly by mobile phone companies and government. They believe this shows direct bias. Marino's criticism is different.&amp;nbsp;He recognises Rubin's money was placed in a&amp;nbsp;fund and administered by scientists separate from the industry. Yet, he argues, the industry approves funding because statistical modelling of&amp;nbsp;large-scale studies averages out experiences and produces no clear-cut results. Big business is&amp;nbsp;happy to back risk studies, but they favour projects that minimise risk: "You&amp;nbsp;look&amp;nbsp;at the&amp;nbsp;statistics and see the way they design the&amp;nbsp;experiments and they have no ability&amp;nbsp;to find&amp;nbsp;anything."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rubin's research is statistic-driven. If Rubin is&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;pollster, then Marino is a canvasser. He believes vast overviews hide the way people really feel. Marino chose to focus on a single sufferer, a&amp;nbsp;female doctor. His two-week study began by first discovering which wavelengths affected her. Once her symptoms had subsided, Marino and his team began again, using provocation studies of real and fake signals. Their results were published as &lt;a href="http://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=2&amp;ved=0CEwQFjAB&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fandrewamarino.com%2FPDFs%2F165-IntJNeurosci2011.pdf&amp;ei=f1RMUdXtGsmJOMWUgZgD&amp;usg=AFQjCNGctqGQgTbV-XYekjuv3Oo6qhXyag&amp;bvm=bv.44158598,d.ZWU" title=""&gt;Electromagnetic Hypersensitivity: Evidence For A Novel Neurological Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marino and Rubin have exchanged a series of letters about the study in the &lt;a href="http://www.jneurosci.org/" title=""&gt;Journal Of Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;. If the research stands up, Marino's syndrome is novel because it is unlike other kinds of hypersensitivity. In truth, it depends upon singularity. Marino speaks urgently: "I'm not interested in measuring the prevalence of the syndrome. I want to establish its existence." In his view, humans – complex living organisms – are all different. In the economy of our bodies, Marino says, "causes becomes effects and effects becomes causes which become effects, and so on". It is an endless and unpredictable cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So should we all make radical lifestyle changes, like cutting down our mobile phone use or getting rid of our Wi-Fi?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Why?" Marino sounds perplexed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Because we might get sick."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marino dismisses the idea. He may disagree vehemently with Rubin, but he views EHS sufferers as outliers, far removed from the average human experience and with few lessons for the rest of us. "Listen, I use an ear bud with my phone, and I minimise use. I don't know if you'd call it radical but I don't have acute reactions to anything. So there's nothing for me to worry about."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/health"&gt;Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/health-and-wellbeing"&gt;Health &amp; wellbeing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/mobilephones"&gt;Mobile phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/telecoms"&gt;Telecoms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/energy"&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science/psychology"&gt;Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/nicholasblincoe"&gt;Nicholas Blincoe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/2a244ac6/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/YMkAi2NbAAU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Energy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science">Psychology</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Health</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle">Health &amp; wellbeing</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Technology</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Telecoms</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology">Mobile phones</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle">Life and style</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science">Science</category><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/electrosensitivity-is-technology-killing-us</guid><dc:creator>Nicholas Blincoe</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-29T19:00:01Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406321472</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Health, Society, Health &amp; wellbeing, Life and style, Mobile phones, Telecoms, Technology, Energy, Environment, Psychology, Science</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/27/1364386512723/Tim-Hallam-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Thomas Ball</media:credit><media:description>Tim Hallam, 36, sleeps in a custom-made silver-coated sleeping bag that helps block out electromagnetic fields. Photograph: Thomas Ball</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/27/1364386519563/Tim-Hallam-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Thomas Ball</media:credit><media:description>Tim Hallam, 36, sleeps in a custom-made silver-coated sleeping bag that helps block out electromagnetic fields. Photograph: Thomas Ball</media:description></media:content><media:content height="550" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="457" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/27/1364386507569/Tim-Hallam-001.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Thomas Ball</media:credit><media:description>Photograph: Thomas Ball</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/27/1364387251519/Michelle-Berriedale-Johns-006.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Thomas Ball</media:credit><media:description>Michelle Berriedale-Johnson, 65, is wearing a jacket made from a silver-coated material that reduces the strength of electromagnetic fields. Photograph: Thomas Ball</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/29/electrosensitivity-is-technology-killing-us</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
