<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>The Guardian World News</title><link>http://www.guardian.co.uk</link><description>Latest news and features from guardian.co.uk, the world's leading liberal voice</description><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. 2013</copyright><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:20:55 GMT</pubDate><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:20:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><ttl>5</ttl><image><title>The Guardian World News</title><url>http://image.guardian.co.uk/sitecrumbs/Guardian.gif</url><link>http://www.guardian.co.uk</link></image><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/theguardian/rss" /><feedburner:info uri="theguardian/rss" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item><title>The Book of Mormon – review</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/cWkB8crIe6Q/the-book-of-mormon-review</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/81083?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Athe-book-of-mormon-review%3A1883922&amp;ch=Stage&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Theatre%2CStage%2CCulture%2CUK+news%2CMormonism%2CReligion+%28News%29%2CChristianity+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CTheatre&amp;c6=Michael+Billington&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+11%3A00&amp;c8=1883922&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Review&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=The+Book+of+Mormon++%E2%80%93+review&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FStage%2FTheatre" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Prince of Wales, London&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strip away all &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/2013/mar/12/the-book-of-mormon-london" title=""&gt;the hype surrounding this hit Broadway import&lt;/a&gt; and what do you find? A mildly amusing musical, with some knowingly parodic songs, that takes a few pot shots at religious credulity without ever questioning the need for belief. I had a perfectly pleasant time, but the idea that the show, which won nine Tony awards, is either daringly offensive or a Broadway breakthrough is pure codswallop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Book, music and lyrics are jointly assigned to &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/2013/jan/04/book-of-mormon-stone-parker" title=""&gt;Trey Parker and Matt Stone&lt;/a&gt; (of South Park fame) and Robert Lopez (co-creator of Avenue Q); and they are undeniably sharp guys. Realising that a host of American musicals (South Pacific, The King and I, Pacific Overtures) are about a collision of cultures, they show two naive Mormon missionaries, the narcissistic Elder Price and the nerdy Elder Cunningham, being dispatched from Salt Lake City to northern Uganda. There they encounter a world of poverty, Aids, genital mutilation and terror, all overseen by a general known as Butt Fucking Naked. Through a mixture of Cunningham's harebrained storytelling and Price's reckless courage, goodness finally prevails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the show actually saying? In part, that religion is a human invention. Passing reference is made to the Mormon founder, Joseph Smith, and his supposed discovery of sacred tablets on a hillside in New York state in 1827. We see Cunningham concocting a new faith in which Mormonism is merged with bits of Star Wars and The Lord of the Rings. Yet, as satire, this is pretty toothless compared with &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/theatreblog/2009/nov/09/the-making-of-moo-nigel-dennis" title=""&gt;Nigel Dennis's 1957 Royal Court play, The Making of Moo&lt;/a&gt;. Dennis devastatingly showed that it is easy enough to invent a new religion, but that it will inexorably lead to sacrifice and ritual slaughter before achieving respectability. The Book of Mormon takes the exact opposite line, suggesting a made-up faith may be a remedy for violence and bloodshed. For all its rude words, this is essentially a safe, conservative show for middle America.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's not to say it doesn't have its pleasures; and part of the fun lies in playing spot-the-source for the numerous songs. The opening number, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vmp-xmguqh4" title=""&gt;Hello, in which trainee missionaries press doorbells&lt;/a&gt;, has echoes of the telephone song in Bye Bye Birdie. A cheery African anthem, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NhRwxCm7bV8" title=""&gt;Hasa Diga Eebowai&lt;/a&gt;, is clearly a foul-mouthed parody of a similar number in The Lion King. And, when the Ugandans stage their own muddied version of Mormon faith, one is reminded of the Uncle Tom's Cabin scene from The King and I. But my own favourite number was &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nKEdVAaKQo4" title=""&gt;Baptize Me&lt;/a&gt;, in which the virginal Nabulungi seeks total immersion from the clueless Cunningham, in what is clearly a form of surrogate sex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If that number is funny and touching, it is because of the two performers. Jared Gertner is stubbily endearing as the klutzy Cunningham, who starts out as a total jerk and ends up as a local saviour. What Gertner essentially captures is the puppy-like innocence of a character who, having arrived in Africa as a closet racist, still never manages to get his tongue round Nabulungi's name. Conversely Alexia Khadime, as Nabulungi, constantly suggests a sharp intelligence behind the caricatured showbiz image of African naivete. And, completing the trio of lead roles, Gavin Creel as Elder Price wittily conveys the implacable self-regard and gleaming teeth of the door-to-door religious salesman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should add that the show is efficently directed by Casey Nicholaw and Trey Parker, and offers a perfectly decent night out. What it lacks, though, is the courage of its own convictions. Having decided to spoof the implicit colonialism of the missionary position and the palpable fabrications of sacred texts, it then endorses the idea that humans have a built-in bias towards belief. That may well be true. But you can't be Swift and Pollyanna at the same time. And, while the show has a few sardonic things to say about our capacity for credulity, the biggest myth of all is that it's somehow a landmark American musical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;South Park: in rude health&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the first South Parks, by Trey Parker and Matt Stone, was an unaired short featuring a fight between &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eSQczYEeB2w" title=""&gt;Santa and Jesus Christ&lt;/a&gt;, which could have offended Jews, Christians, obese people and anybody who objected to profuse swearing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 98th episode, Krazy Kripples, featured two disabled boys joining LA's&amp;nbsp;Crips gang and &lt;a href="http://www.southparkstudios.com/clips/153901/what-an-inspiration" title=""&gt;Christopher Reeve (then still alive) sucking the blood out of unborn foetuses in order to walk again&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 150th episode was aired six weeks after the death of Australian crocodile hunter Steve Irwin, who is featured turning up to a party organised by Satan with a stingray through his chest. Even the devil was surprised at the joke so soon after his death – "It's too soon, you know?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parker and Stone met at Colorado University and their big break came when Comedy Central happened upon the Jesus vs Santa short and asked them to develop a series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sixteen series and 237 episodes later South Park is still going. There has been a South Park movie and the film Team America: World Police which features members of the Film Actors Guild (FAG) – Alec Baldwin and Matt Damon among others – conspiring with North Korea's Kim Jong-il, who gives a moving rendition of &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UEaKX9YYHiQ" title=""&gt;I'm So Ronery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fans of South Park would argue that the show has a genuine humanity and can be incredibly sweet. They might also concede that it can be puerile and in the most appalling taste. That may even be why they watch it. &lt;strong&gt;Mark Brown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="rating"&gt;Rating: 3/5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/theatre"&gt;Theatre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/mormonism"&gt;Mormonism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/religion"&gt;Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/christianity"&gt;Christianity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/michaelbillington"&gt;Michael Billington&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d8be2f/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393912366/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8be2f/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393912366/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8be2f/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393912366/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8be2f/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/cWkB8crIe6Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Mormonism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Reviews</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage">Stage</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage">Theatre</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Christianity</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Religion</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:00:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/2013/mar/21/the-book-of-mormon-review</guid><dc:creator>Michael Billington</dc:creator><dc:subject>Stage</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T23:00:02Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406021624</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Theatre, Stage, Culture, UK news, Mormonism, Religion, Christianity, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363887718627/The-Book-of-Mormon-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Johan Persson</media:credit><media:description>The Book of Mormon at the Prince of Wales theatre in London. Photograph: Johan Persson</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363887726322/The-Book-of-Mormon-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Johan Persson</media:credit><media:description>The Book of Mormon at the Prince of Wales theatre in London. Photograph: Johan Persson</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/2013/mar/21/the-book-of-mormon-review</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Gas price warning as cold March leads to short supplies</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/L0A8u-Xj-Hs/gas-price-warning-short-supplies</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/87973?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Agas-price-warning-short-supplies%3A1884037&amp;ch=Business&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Gas+%28business%29%2CGas+%28environment%29%2CUtilities+sector+%28Business+sector%29%2CBusiness%2CEnergy+%28Environment%29%2CFossil+fuels+%28Environment%29%2CEnvironment%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CBusiness+Markets%2CEnergy%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=Fiona+Harvey&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+10%3A26&amp;c8=1884037&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Gas+price+warning+as+cold+March+leads+to+short+supplies&amp;c66=Business&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FBusiness%2FBusiness%2FGas" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Forecasts suggest that gas supplies will be exhausted by 8 April, requiring Britain to import from Norway and Russia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cold snap in March could lead to Britain's gas supplies running out next month, forcing the nation to pay higher prices for fuel from elsewhere. Forecasts suggest that gas supplies in the UK will be exhausted by 8 April, requiring Britain to turn to imports from Norway and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The warning came on the day Scottish and Southern Energy, one of the UK's biggest power suppliers, warned that there could be electricity blackouts in the country within three years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lack of gas storage facilities, and rapid depletion at the UK's North Sea gas fields, has led to the UK having as little as two days' supply of the fuel in reserve. Demand spiked during the coldest March in 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though experts have warned of the problem for years, and the government has championed a "dash for gas" that would see a massive rise in demand for the fuel, little has been done to increase storage facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ian Marchant, chief executive of SSE, said there was a "very real risk of the lights going out" within the next three years. SSE intends shutting down power plants, enough to have supplied 2m homes, as the stations are either uneconomic or coming to the end of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other firms are also planning to take power stations out of service, including the UK's fleet of ageing nuclear reactors, increasing the risk that demand for electricity will exceed the available supply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marchant said: "It appears the government is significantly underestimating the scale of the capacity crunch facing the UK in the next three years and there is a very real risk of the lights going out as a result."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His comments follow warnings by Alistair Buchanan, the departing chief of Ofgem, that power shortages will be many times more likely in the next five years. Government estimates suggest that energy bills could rise by £100 a year this winter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The warnings are a particular blow to George Osborne, the chancellor, who has championed a new "dash for gas" in the UK, that would see gas take over as the dominant fuel in the UK's power generation market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much of the generating capacity that SSE plans to retire consists of gas-fired power stations, though the recent budget has given tax breaks for shale gas extraction in the UK and heralded what could be the biggest expansion of UK gas-fired power in a generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SSE said gas-fired power was uneconomic because of the fuel's high price compared with coal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move by SSE highlights the disputes over energy policy and energy generation, following upheavals in the international markets for fossil fuels. It also brings into question whether targets to cut carbon dioxide can be met.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrew Pendleton, head of campaigns at Friends of the Earth, said energy firms were trying to hold the government to ransom by threatening power outages that would help them extract concessions to get financial benefits. The UK has only six big energy suppliers to households, which campaigners say reduces competition and raises prices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coal has become much cheaper because of the use of fossil fuel in the US in the past five years, where a massive increase in the supply of cheap gas is attributed to fracking, the controversial method of blasting dense rocks apart under high pressure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The coal that would have been burned in the US is now available on international markets at cut-price, and has now become "the preferred fuel", according to SSE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is the opposite of what the government, and the EU intended by their energy policies in the past decade. Coal was supposed to become more expensive than gas, because of the EU's emissions trading scheme, which puts a price on carbon emissions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That has not happened, because flaws within the system mean the price of carbon is near an all-time low, meaning coal-fired power stations are not penalised for their effect on the climate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marchant urged the government to bring forward reforms favouring gas. "The government can reduce this risk [of power cuts] very easily, by taking swift action to provide much greater clarity on its electricity market reforms."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An energy bill is under discussion by parliament at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SSE's warnings were dismissed by green campaigners as "an attempt to force the government's hand".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pendleton said: "The risk is that these companies are holding us to ransom, in order to make the environment more favourable to their forms of generation. There is a lot at stake here. Basing our energy strategy on gas rather than clean forms of energy such as renewables means we could be held to ransom more and more in the future in this way. It could do a huge amount of harm."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government rebuffed the claims from SSE. John Hayes, minister for energy, said: "We're alive to the challenge facing us. The bill before parliament will set the conditions for the investment needed to keep Britain's lights on in the long-term. The amount of spare power available today is currently comfortable. As old infrastructure closes over the coming years we expect this margin to reduce but we will make sure it stays manageable."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the UK's nuclear power plants are slated for closure by 2022, and many coal-fired stations must be closed or run at reduced capacity within the next few years because of EU rules on pollution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts have warned for years of a looming "energy gap" between demand and supply. The building of wind farms and other forms of renewable energy, which were supposed to fill the gap, has been below expectations, in part due to planning laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hayes said: "We are not complacent about this... We are confident in our approach and in the responsiveness of the market in providing secure power supplies."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joss Garman, political director of Greenpeace, said: "Not content with the profits they're making from sky-high energy bills the gas industry now seems to be trying to hold everybody to ransom – 'give us even more of your cash or we'll turn out the lights'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Cheap coal and the collapse of the carbon price have made gas burning less profitable, but that's a reason to ban unabated coal burning and reform the carbon market, not to give hand-outs to the big six energy companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Gas-fired generation should only be a last-ditch backup for renewable energy sources, and [ministers] should prioritise support for interconnectors, storage, and combined heat and power stations that would compliment renewables and guarantee we have secure power."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/gas"&gt;Gas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/gas"&gt;Gas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/utilities"&gt;Utilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/energy"&gt;Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/fossil-fuels"&gt;Fossil fuels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/fiona-harvey"&gt;Fiona Harvey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d8b8b5/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393911793/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8b8b5/kg/350-355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393911793/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8b8b5/kg/350-355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393911793/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8b8b5/kg/350-355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/L0A8u-Xj-Hs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Energy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Fossil fuels</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Utilities</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Gas</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 22:26:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/mar/21/gas-price-warning-short-supplies</guid><dc:creator>Fiona Harvey</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T22:26:22Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406038453</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Gas, Gas, Utilities, Business, Energy, Fossil fuels, Environment, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363904723984/Gas-hobs-on-a-cooker-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Anthony Devlin/PA</media:credit><media:description>The cold snap in March could lead to gas supplies running out, forcing Britain to pay higher prices for fuel from elsewhere. Photograph: Anthony Devlin/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363904730199/Gas-hobs-on-a-cooker-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Anthony Devlin/PA</media:credit><media:description>The cold snap in March could lead to gas supplies running out, forcing Britain to pay higher prices for fuel from elsewhere. Photograph: Anthony Devlin/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/mar/21/gas-price-warning-short-supplies</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Jobcentre was set targets for benefit sanctions</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/zEWFmO7jfG0/jobcentre-set-targets-benefit-sanctions</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/79516?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ajobcentre-set-targets-benefit-sanctions%3A1884029&amp;ch=Society&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Benefits+%28Society%29%2CUnemployment+%28Society%29%2CSociety%2CPolitics%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Patrick+Wintour&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+09%3A37&amp;c8=1884029&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Jobcentre+was+set+targets+for+benefit+sanctions&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FSociety%2FBenefits" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;• Inquiry launched after league tables revealed&lt;br /&gt;• Leak shows pressure on staff to refer claimants&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has launched an inquiry after it was forced to admit that jobcentres have been setting targets and league tables to sanction benefit claimants despite assurances to parliament this week that no such targets were being set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A leaked email shows staff being warned by managers that they will be disciplined unless they increase the number of claimants referred to a tougher benefit regime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruth King, a jobcentre adviser manager, discloses in the email that she has received "the stricter benefit regime" figures for her area, adding: "As you can see Walthamstow are 95th in the league table out of only 109" – the number of jobcentres in London and the home counties. The employment minister, Mark Hoban, had assured MPs on Tuesday: "There are no league tables in place. We do not set targets for sanctions. I have made that point in previous discussions."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The league table could only have been drawn up through information provided by senior managers in the Department for Work and Pensions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hoban had told MPs that decisions on sanctioning claimants "need to be based on whether people have breached the agreements they have set out with the jobcentre, and there are no targets in place".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Faced with the email, the DWP said: "We are urgently investigating what happened in this case. If a manager has set a local target for applying sanctions this is against DWP policy and we will be taking steps to ensure these targets are removed immediately."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;King says in her email: "Our district manager is not pleased … because senior managers are under pressure to improve our office output and move up the league he has to apply some pressure downwards." She continues: "Guys, we really need to up the game here. The 5% target is one thing – the fact that we are seeing over 300 people a week and only submitting six of them for possible doubts is simply not quite credible."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The email reveals that along with other area team managers King had until 15 February to show an improvement, adding that if she does not do so she will be subject to a performance improvement plan, the first stage of disciplinary action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She says if she is threatened with disciplinary action to improve performance, she will have to threaten her own staff in the same way. She writes: "Obviously if I am on a PIP [performance improvement plan] to improve my team's Stricter Benefit Regime referral rate I will not have a choice but to consider implementing PIPs for those individuals who are clearly not delivering SBR within the team."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She also discloses that the jobcentre customers manager is looking for about 25 referrals a week. "We made six last week and so far this week have made four. There is a shortfall here."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shadow work and pensions secretary, Liam Byrne, is due to raise the matter in parliament on Friday. He said: "This explosive letter lays bare the climate of fear in jobcentres as league tables and threats of disciplinary action are used to perpetrate a culture of sanctioning innocent people to hit targets. That is just plain wrong and must be stopped now. Either ministers have no grip on their department or they misled parliament. Either way they must now face the consequences."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Labour MP for Walthamstow, Stella Creasy, said: "We have to get to the bottom of this. It is quite horrible that jobcentre staff feel they have to set people up to fail."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DWP maintained that this was an isolated case. Hoban said: "I'm clear there should be no chasing of targets because I believe we should be making the right and fair decisions."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the email King sets out ways jobcentre staff can catch out claimants, saying: "You should consider every doubt – if you are unsure then please conference with me." Her advice includes: "Do not accept the same job search every week, do not accept 'I dropped off CV to shops like Asda or Sainsbury's', listen for telltale phrases 'I pick up the kids', 'I look after my neighbours children/my grandchildren' or just 'I am busy' – all of which suggest that the customer may not be fully available for work, even cases where a parent shares custody can be considered."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She says someone can be deemed not to be actively seeking employment, and therefore subject to sanction "if someone is going away from home, but is not willing to return to take up employment, not willing to leave details of how they can be contacted should a job become available or not looking for work whilst away".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/benefits"&gt;Benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/unemployment"&gt;Unemployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/patrickwintour"&gt;Patrick Wintour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d8255b/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393910677/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8255b/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393910677/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8255b/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393910677/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d8255b/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/zEWFmO7jfG0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Unemployment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Benefits</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 21:37:55 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/21/jobcentre-set-targets-benefit-sanctions</guid><dc:creator>Patrick Wintour</dc:creator><dc:subject>Society</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T21:37:55Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406036411</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Benefits, Unemployment, Society, Politics, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363901665473/Job-Centre-Plus-sign-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Rui Vieira/PA</media:credit><media:description>A manager at a jobcentre has leaked an email revealing the existence of a league table in her region for referrals to the stricter benefits regimes. Photograph: Rui Vieira/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363901671359/Job-Centre-Plus-sign-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Rui Vieira/PA</media:credit><media:description>A manager at a jobcentre has leaked an email revealing the existence of a league table in her region for referrals to the stricter benefits regimes. Photograph: Rui Vieira/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/2013/mar/21/jobcentre-set-targets-benefit-sanctions</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Budget 2013: IFS warns of £9bn tax rises after election</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/jn5evJBKnIs/budget-2013-ifs-9bn-tax-rises-election</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/41358?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abudget-2013-ifs-9bn-tax-rises-election%3A1884026&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Budget+2013%2CBudget+deficit%2CUK+news%2CBudget%2CCredit+rating+agencies+%28Business%29%2CGeorge+Osborne%2CPolitics%2COffice+for+Budget+Responsibility%2CEconomics+%28Business%29%2CEconomic+policy%2CGovernment+borrowing%2CBusiness%2CPublic+sector+cuts+%28Society%29%2CPublic+finance+%28Society%29%2CSociety&amp;c5=Society+Weekly%2CUnclassified%2CCredit+Crunch%2CPolicy+Society%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CBudget&amp;c6=Phillip+Inman&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+09%3A19&amp;c8=1884026&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Budget+2013%3A+IFS+warns+of+%C2%A39bn+tax+rises+after+election&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FBudget+2013" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;George Osborne's spending cuts will leave huge gap in government finances, says the Institute for Fiscal Studies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tax rises of up to £9bn – equal to a 2p increase in the basic rate of income tax – could be imposed after the next general election to limit further cuts in public spending, experts warned on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scale of the spending cuts scheduled for 2015 in George Osborne's budget will be so difficult to implement an incoming government would have little alternative but to raise taxes or borrow more, the Institute for Fiscal Studies said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IFS, which produces a keenly watched analysis of the chancellor's budget, gave its warning after the Treasury's independent forecaster, the Office for Budget Responsibility, warned that growth would halve this year to 0.6% and the recovery would be weaker than predicted only in December.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was speculation in the City following the poor figures that the UK could face its second credit downgrade as soon as the weekend. Ratings agencies Standard &amp; Poor's and Fitch have the UK on negative watch and both have warned that a weakening of the recovery could lead to their stripping Britain of its AAA status. Osborne would face a second humiliation after Moody's issued a downgrade notice last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a budget that kept the coalition tied to its austerity theme, Osborne was forced to admit that the UK would take two years longer to push the annual deficit below 3%. A rise in the personal income tax threshold to £10,000 next year, together with a 1p cut in beer duty and the abolition of a planned fuel duty rise in the autumn, were offset by a further tightening of Whitehall budgets to leave what the IFS described as a fiscally neutral budget that masked a further deterioration in the government's finances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Osborne plans to keep spending at its current level until 2015 before a second wave of steep cuts takes effect up to 2018. The IFS said the government was delaying some austerity measures until after 2015, leaving the next government to bridge a large gap in Whitehall's finances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rowena Crawford of the IFS said politicians were likely to prefer tax rises to avoid making further spending cuts. "That is after an election and it is much more possible that a future government will prefer to increase taxes instead," she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tony Travers, a director of research at the London School of Economics and an expert on local government finance, told Public Finance magazine: "You wouldn't know it from the headline figures, but local government, along with some other unprotected and unloved public services, looks likely to face at least 50% spending cuts between 2011-12 and 2017-2018."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spending figures until 2018 show the debt bill has risen by £70bn since forecasts in the autumn statement and by almost £250bn since the coalition took office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IFS criticised Osborne for devoting senior civil servants' time to manipulating public spending figures to meet a pledge that the deficit would fall in successive years. The chancellor grabbed £10.9bn in underspends by Whitehall departments to squeak this year's debt bill under last year's £120bn deficit by £100m. More than £2bn came from an underspend in the NHS while a further £3bn came from defence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also delayed payments to bodies such as the World Bank and the European Union and brought forward a planned cut in a long-standing national insurance benefit to final salary pension schemes to reduce the annual bill. Some budget spending commitments were also delayed until after the election – including a £3bn infrastructure programme championed by the business secretary, Vince Cable, and £1bn for social care – which will not take effect until after April 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IFS said a ringfence around the NHS, schools, international development and defence equipment to protect them from cuts left further reductions in departmental spending limits to fall disproportionately on the remaining services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under pressure from backbench Tory MPs to sweeten the pill of welfare cuts already scheduled to hit this year, Osborne chose to let borrowing rise higher over the next two years than the government planned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul Johnson, the IFS director, said: "Year-on-year real cuts in departmental spending have effectively come to an end for the period of this parliament." Tax cuts in the budget entailed a "modest loosening" in the next two years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He pointed to a Treasury note in the budget documents saying bridging the gap between lower than expected tax receipts and spending commitments would need to be addressed by tax changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/budget-2013"&gt;Budget 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/budget-deficit"&gt;Budget deficit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/budget"&gt;Budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/rating-agencies"&gt;Rating agencies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/georgeosborne"&gt;George Osborne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/office-for-budget-responsibility"&gt;Office for Budget Responsibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/economics"&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/economy"&gt;Economic policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/government-borrowing"&gt;Government borrowing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/public-sector-cuts"&gt;Public sector cuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society/public-finance"&gt;Public finance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/phillipinman"&gt;Phillip Inman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d84354/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393674251/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d84354/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393674251/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d84354/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393674251/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d84354/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/jn5evJBKnIs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Budget deficit</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">George Osborne</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Rating agencies</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Budget</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Office for Budget Responsibility</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Economics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Society</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Public sector cuts</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Budget 2013</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Government borrowing</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Economic policy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/society">Public finance</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 21:19:09 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/budget-2013-ifs-9bn-tax-rises-election</guid><dc:creator>Phillip Inman</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T22:01:52Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406036052</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Budget 2013, Budget deficit, UK news, Budget, Rating agencies, George Osborne, Politics, Office for Budget Responsibility, Economics, Economic policy, Government borrowing, Business, Public sector cuts, Public finance, Society</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363900443682/George-Osborne-arrives-at-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Olivia Harris/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>George Osborne’s budget will be so difficult to implement an incoming government would have to raise taxes, the IFS said. Photograph: Olivia Harris/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363900451039/George-Osborne-arrives-at-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Olivia Harris/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>George Osborne’s budget will be so difficult to implement an incoming government would have to raise taxes, the IFS said. Photograph: Olivia Harris/Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/budget-2013-ifs-9bn-tax-rises-election</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Guantánamo hunger strike much bigger than reported, rights group claims</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/GTfEptBeaAA/guantanamo-bay-inmates-hunger-strike</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/47483?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aguantanamo-bay-inmates-hunger-strike%3A1884000&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Guantanamo+Bay+%28News%29%2CUS+foreign+policy%2CCuba+%28News%29%2CUS+military+%28News%29%2CHuman+rights&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Paul+Harris&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+08%3A09&amp;c8=1884000&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Guant%C3%A1namo+hunger+strike+much+bigger+than+reported%2C+rights+group+claims&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FGuant%C3%A1namo+Bay" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Pentagon accused of 'not admitting scale and scope' of strike, with reports of 130 inmates protesting mistreatment of Qu'rans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A campaign group representing some of the inmates at Guantánamo Bay said on Thursday that a mass hunger strike currently taking place at the controversial prison camp is far larger than US military authorities have admitted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, General John Kelly told a congressional committee that 24 Guantánamo prisoners were on "hunger strike light" and eating "a bit, but not a lot" as a way of protesting against allegations that the Qu'ran had been mishandled by military staff, and also to highlight their continuing detention without trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But Omar Farah, who works on Guantánamo issues for the New York-based Center for Constitutional Rights, said that one of his seven clients at the base, Yemeni inmate Fahad Ghazy, had recently told him that the strike involved many more inmates. "They [the Pentagon] are not admitting the scale and scope of the hunger strike," Farah said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On March 14, Farah said, Ghazy had told him in a phone call that all but two inmates in Guantánamo's Camp Six were on hunger strike, and that that likely represented almost 130 people. Ghazy had added that some detainees at Camp Five were also on hunger strike. There are about 166 inmates at Guantánamo, of whom about half have been cleared for transfer or release. Nearly all inmates have been held without charge – some for as long as 11 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Farah warned that if the hunger strike continued, some inmates could die. "We are afraid for some of the mens' lives. If someone persists with not eating food they can suffer severe physical damage and may die," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kelly, who vociferously denied any charge that Qu'rans had been mishandled, did admit that eight detainees had lost enough weight that they were now being force fed via tubes. But he insisted there was no crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"[They] present themselves daily, calmly, in a totally co-operative way, to be fed through a tube," he said, adding that he believed those prisoners were also eating by themselves when they were in their cells.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The clashing versions of events are the latest in a long line of controversies that have dogged the Guántanamo prison since it was set up to house suspects caught up in the so-called "war on terror". The process of detaining terror suspects has outraged civil liberties groups in the US and abroad, especially as dealing with the suspects legally has been painfully slow or non-existent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Obama vowed to shut the camp in his first year of office, but his efforts were stymied by Congress and have apparently been shelved. Earlier this year, the State Department office meant to deal with resettling Guantánamo prisoners was closed down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even Kelley admitted that the inmates' morale was extremely poor. "They had great optimism that Guantánamo would be closed. They were devastated, apparently, when the president backed off," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, those advocating prisoners' rights have also criticised a recent announcement that will end the only civilian flight that goes to the base. Earlier this week Florida firm IBC Travel said it had been ordered to stop flying to the base from May 1 at the latest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That will mean lawyers, journalists and human rights workers will only be able to get to the base aboard a military flight – something that requires permission from the Pentagon. "It will certainly make it a lot more difficult to get there at a time when we all need increased access," said Farah.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only major trial to emerge from Guantanamo Bay has been a military tribunal held for alleged 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Muhammed and four others, which began last year. By contrast, Osama bin Laden's son-in-law Sulaiman Abu Ghaith, who was captured earlier this month, will be prosecuted in a criminal court in New York on charges of conspiring to kill Americans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/guantanamo-bay"&gt;Guantánamo Bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usforeignpolicy"&gt;US foreign policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/cuba"&gt;Cuba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/us-military"&gt;US military&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/human-rights"&gt;Human rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/paulharris"&gt;Paul Harris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d76447/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393728497/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76447/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393728497/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76447/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393728497/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76447/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/GTfEptBeaAA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Cuba</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US foreign policy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US military</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Guantánamo Bay</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Editorial</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Human rights</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:09:24 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/guantanamo-bay-inmates-hunger-strike</guid><dc:creator>Paul Harris</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T20:09:24Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406032423</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Guantánamo Bay, US foreign policy, Cuba, US military, Human rights</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2012/1/11/1326280477441/A-group-of-detainees-knee-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">John Moore/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>A group of detainees kneels during prayers at Guantanamo Bay. Photograph: John Moore/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/audio/video/2012/1/11/1326280481411/A-group-of-detainees-knee-007.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">John Moore/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Campaigners have warned that if the hunger strike continued, some inmates could die. Photograph: John Moore/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/guantanamo-bay-inmates-hunger-strike</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Obama tells Israelis: 'peace with Palestinians is possible' – live updates</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/dSo1mDhw0HI/barack-obama-visits-west-bank-live</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Follow live updates as Barack Obama condemns Israeli settlement activity and the latest rocket attacks by Hamas militants&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/matthewweaver"&gt;Matthew Weaver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/jim-newell"&gt;Jim Newell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d15fd7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393843888/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d15fd7/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393843888/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d15fd7/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393843888/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d15fd7/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/dSo1mDhw0HI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Mahmoud Abbas</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Blogposts</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Middle East and North Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Barack Obama</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US foreign policy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Minute by minutes</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Israel</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Arab and Middle East unrest</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Palestinian territories</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Syria</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Jordan</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Refugees</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Binyamin Netanyahu</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:29:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/middle-east-live/2013/mar/21/barack-obama-visits-west-bank-live</guid><dc:creator>Matthew Weaver, Jim Newell</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T19:29:22Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>405972071</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Israel, Barack Obama, Palestinian territories, Mahmoud Abbas, US foreign policy, Binyamin Netanyahu, Middle East and North Africa, Arab and Middle East unrest, Syria, Jordan, Refugees, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363880675820/3f25c298-cdfc-4ead-bfd3-c9c89e22644f-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">SAUL LOEB/AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>US president Barack Obama waves after delivering a major speech at the Convention Center in Jerusalem. Photograph: SAUL LOEB/AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/middle-east-live/2013/mar/21/barack-obama-visits-west-bank-live</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Syria: suicide bomber kills top Sunni preacher in Damascus mosque</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/TexW0vXbuVM/syria-suicide-bomber-sunni-damascus-mosque</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/74298?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Asyria-suicide-bomber-sunni-damascus-mosque%3A1883963&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Syria+%28News%29%2CBashar+al-Assad%2CTerrorism+-+international&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Associated+Press+in+Damascus&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+07%3A26&amp;c8=1883963&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Syria%3A+suicide+bomber+kills+top+Sunni+preacher+in+Damascus+mosque&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FSyria" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Sheikh Mohammad Said Ramadan al-Buti, a supporter of Assad, was killed in an explosion during evening prayers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A suicide bomber has blown himself up during evening prayers inside a mosque in Damascus, killing a prominent Sunni Muslim preacher and longtime supporter of President Bashar Assad, state TV has reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The death removes one of the few remaining pillars of support of the Alawite leader within the minority sect that has risen up against him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sheikh Mohammad Said Ramadan al-Buti, an 84-year-old cleric known to all Syrians as a religious scholar who often appeared on TV, was killed in the explosion in the Eman mosque in the central Mazraa district.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Syrian TV did not give more details but said the explosion injured many people. It occurred at a time the mosque would have been packed with worshippers for Friday evening prayers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TV footage showed wounded people and bodies with severed limbs on the bloodstained floor of the mosque. Sirens echoed in the capital as ambulances went to the scene, which was sealed off by the military.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Al-Buti's death is a big blow to Syria's embattled leader, who is fighting mainly Sunni rebels seeking his downfall. Al-Buti has been a vocal supporter of the regime since the early days of Assad's father and predecessor, the late President Hafez Assad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent months Syrian TV had carried his sermon from mosques in Damascus live every week. He had a regular religious TV programme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/syria"&gt;Syria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/bashar-al-assad"&gt;Bashar al-Assad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/terrorism"&gt;Global terrorism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d84358/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/TexW0vXbuVM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Bashar al-Assad</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Global terrorism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Syria</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:26:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/syria-suicide-bomber-sunni-damascus-mosque</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T19:26:57Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406027197</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Syria, Bashar al-Assad, Global terrorism</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363893968731/Sheikh-Mohammad-Said-Rama-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Sana/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Mohammad Said Ramadan al-Buti a Sunni Muslim preacher and supporter of President Assad has been killed in a suicide bomb attack. Photograph: Sana/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363893975803/Sheikh-Mohammad-Said-Rama-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Sana/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Mohammad Said Ramadan al-Buti a Sunni Muslim preacher and supporter of President Assad has been killed in a suicide bomb attack. Photograph: Sana/Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/syria-suicide-bomber-sunni-damascus-mosque</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Justin Welby enthroned as new archbishop of Canterbury</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/h5dt9so85m8/justin-welby-archbishop-of-canterbury-enthroned</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/4323?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ajustin-welby-archbishop-of-canterbury-enthroned%3A1883981&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Justin+Welby%2CUK+news%2CAnglicanism+-+Church+of+England+%28News%29%2CReligion+%28News%29%2CChristianity+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Sam+Jones&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+07%3A02&amp;c8=1883981&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Justin+Welby+enthroned+as+new+archbishop+of+Canterbury&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FJustin+Welby" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;African dancers and Punjabi hymn greet new leader of world's Anglicans as he takes up his post at cathedral ceremony&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Justin Portal Welby's long and unlikely journey from young oil executive to leader of the world's 77 million Anglicans ended with three slow and echoing taps on the west door of Canterbury Cathedral on Thursday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The knocking of his pastoral staff was answered with a fanfare – and a self-inflicted inquisition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We greet you in the name of Christ," said Evangeline Kanagasooriam, a 17-year-old Anglican chosen to hail the new archbishop by putting to him a list of questions he himself had penned for the occasion. "Who are you and why do you request entry?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The archbishop replied: "I am Justin, a servant of Jesus Christ, and I come as one seeking the grace of God, to travel with you in this service together."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before a congregation of 2,000 people, among them the Prince of Wales, the Duchess of Cornwall, the prime minister and representatives of all the world's major religions, the 105th Archbishop of Canterbury explained, slowly and humbly, that he had come to proclaim the love of Christ, to worship him and to love him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I come knowing nothing except Jesus Christ and him crucified, and in weakness and fear and much in trembling," he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But if he was shaking inwardly at either the thought of his new responsibilities or the knowledge that the date of his enthronement coincided with the anniversaries of the deaths of both St Benedict and Thomas Cranmer, he gave no outward sign.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He followed a magnificent – if at times halting – procession of clerics from the Assyrian church of the East, the Oriental Orthodox churches, the Orthodox churches and the Roman Catholic church clad in purple, scarlet, black and white. But Welby seemed at ease in his green and gold robes and his new office.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After bowing his head to listen to Psalm 80, he smiled at the congregation as he made his way towards the cathedral altar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The enthronement ceremony itself was as eclectic and international as the guest list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first time in the church's history, the new archbishop was installed on his diocesan throne by a woman, the Venerable Sheila Watson, archdeacon of Canterbury.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the role falls to the archdeacon regardless of gender, the precedent will delight those Anglicans who, like Welby, remain in favour of the introduction of women bishops despite the General Synod's no-vote on the issue last November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the new archbishop had been installed on the marble chair of St Augustine, signalling his appointment as head of the Church of England and also representing his inauguration as spiritual leader of the global Anglican communion, C of E tradition gave way to a more personal and international celebration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of a Punjabi hymn, however, may have been a step too far for some of the worshippers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Confronted with the overwhelming otherness of its refrain of saranam, saranam, saranam – meaning my refuge – the congregation treated it as if it were an overly spiced dish: they picked at it gingerly, politely and, above all, Englishly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Appropriating other people's liturgies," whispered one wry cleric, "does bring certain difficulties."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the Punjabi melody was as nothing in comparison with the African dancers, whose booming drums, chanting and energetic dancing elicited a grin from the archbishop – a reminder, perhaps, of his time as a peace negotiator in the continent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gleefully aware of the disconnect between the sober surroundings and the vitality of the dancers, he kicked off his sermon with a joke. "It's got a good reverberation, this cathedral," he noted, to much laughter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rest of the sermon, though, was deliberately short on gags. As befitted the leader of the C of E, Welby insisted on the primacy of his church's position in the nation's past and its future – and its absolute right to have its say in an increasingly secular society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"For more than 1,000 years this country has to one degree or another sought to recognise that Jesus is the son of God; by the ordering of its society, by its laws, by its sense of community," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Sometimes we have done better, sometimes worse. When we do better we make space for our own courage to be liberated, for God to act among us and for human beings to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Slaves were freed, Factory Acts passed and the NHS and social care established through Christ-liberated courage."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was only through such courage, he added, that the economic, environmental and developmental challenges of the age could be faced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Repeated compound adjectives – "a Christ-heeding life" and a "Christ-heeding church" – were deployed, as was the peculiar blend of missionary zeal and corporate speak that one might expect from a man with the archbishop's unique CV and evangelical links with Holy Trinity, Brompton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Today we may properly differ on the degrees of state and private responsibility in a healthy society," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"But if we sever our roots in Christ we abandon the stability which enables good decision-making. There can be no final justice or security or love or hope in our society if it is not finally based on rootedness in Christ."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the creed and some Benjamin Britten, and a blessing and a long round of applause, the man charged with holding together the fractious global Anglican communion as it struggles with the vexed issues of women bishops and same-sex marriage processed out of the cathedral and into the bitterly cold spring afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/justin-welby"&gt;Justin Welby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/anglicanism"&gt;Anglicanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/religion"&gt;Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/christianity"&gt;Christianity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/samjones"&gt;Sam Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d76a46/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393907362/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76a46/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393907362/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76a46/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393907362/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76a46/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/h5dt9so85m8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Anglicanism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Justin Welby</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Christianity</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Religion</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:02:30 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/justin-welby-archbishop-of-canterbury-enthroned</guid><dc:creator>Sam Jones</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T19:02:30Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406029708</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Justin Welby, UK news, Anglicanism, Religion, Christianity, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/cartoons/2013/3/21/1363892279882/Archbishop-of-Canterbury--004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Chris Ison/PA</media:credit><media:description>The Archbishop of Canterbury, The Most Reverend Justin Welby, strikes three times on the West Door of Canterbury Cathedral with his pastoral staff prior to his Enthronement. PRESS ASSOCIATION Photo. Picture date: Thursday March 21, 2013. Photo credit should read: Chris Ison/PA Wire Photograph: Chris Ison/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/cartoons/2013/3/21/1363892287474/Archbishop-of-Canterbury--009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Chris Ison/PA</media:credit><media:description>Justin Welby strikes three times on the cathedral door with his pastoral staff. Photograph: Chris Ison/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/justin-welby-archbishop-of-canterbury-enthroned</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Christopher Walken: 'I'm a regular guy'</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/veDd6khVADU/christopher-walken-im-a-regular-guy</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/35317?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Achristopher-walken-im-a-regular-guy%3A1883866&amp;ch=Film&amp;c3=G2&amp;c4=Christopher+Walken%2CFilm%2CCulture&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Danny+Leigh&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+07%3A00&amp;c8=1883866&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=Feature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Christopher+Walken%3A+%27I%27m+a+regular+guy%27&amp;c66=Culture&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FCulture%2FFilm%2FChristopher+Walken" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Christopher Walken has made so many movies playing psychos and weirdos, he can't remember half of them. But in his latest film, A Late Quartet, he's been cast against type as a cellist with Parkinson's. He says why he'd be happier playing it straight&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/christopher-walken" title=""&gt;Christopher Walken&lt;/a&gt; will tell you what irritates him. "Quite often, I'll be sent a script for a movie," he says. "And I find that I like it, so I say I'll do it. But then they rewrite it for me. They make it &lt;em&gt;quirky&lt;/em&gt;. Odd. I find that rather annoying. I call it Walkenising."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He chuckles, then stops dead. There is silence. We are on the phone, so that when he speaks it is hard not to wonder what else he might be doing. "I'm in Connecticut," he says when I ask, at the rural home he shares with his wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The irony is that the film he's promoting, the elegant drama &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/movie/148757/late-quartet" title=""&gt;A Late Quartet&lt;/a&gt;, is his most un-Walkenised in years. Rather than, say, a neurotic hitman, he plays a gentle cellist whose diagnosis with Parkinson's disease causes schisms in a New York string quartet. The role clearly came as a relief. "Yes, it was different for me," he says. "I don't usually get to play fathers or grandfathers or uncles. Now that I'm older, maybe I can play people closer to myself. I'd like that."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 69, his manner is sometimes animated, more often businesslike. The diction, of course, is a marvel – the unlikely pauses and emphases so familiar from his films, put down to a childhood in the melting pot of Astoria, Queens. When I ask why he thinks he became so typecast, the answer in full goes: "Well, movies are so &lt;em&gt;expensive&lt;/em&gt; to make that ... if something &lt;em&gt;works&lt;/em&gt; you get asked to do it &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;. And when I &lt;em&gt;started&lt;/em&gt; I did well with these ... &lt;em&gt;eccentric&lt;/em&gt; people. &lt;em&gt;Troubled&lt;/em&gt;. Often &lt;em&gt;villains &lt;/em&gt;..." He gives a small cough. "And that's fine," he says, sadly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It sounds as if he wants to play regular guys. Does he feel like one?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Well, my life is really quite conservative. I've been married nearly 50 years. I don't have hobbies or children. I don't much care to travel. I've never had a big social life. I really just stay home, except when I go to work." A pause. "So in that sense I suppose I'm a regular guy."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His background, he admits, is not everyone's idea of regular. A child actor from the age of five, "there were schools for kids like me that also made it possible to work, and that's where I got my education".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 15, he joined a travelling circus, his duties including lion taming (he says he only worked with one lion, old and dog-like). Then came musical theatre. Cast as Riff in a touring production of West Side Story, the actor playing his girlfriend was called Georgianne Thon. He promptly married her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But still he sees himself as much removed from the skewed characters that made his name on screen – raving suicidally in &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/movie/36314/annie.hall" title=""&gt;Annie Hall&lt;/a&gt;, playing Russian roulette in &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/movie/36318/deer-hunter" title=""&gt;The Deer Hunter&lt;/a&gt;, stealing &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/movie/56612/pulp.fiction" title=""&gt;Pulp Fiction&lt;/a&gt; with a monologue about the bodily hiding place of a family heirloom. They may share his pallor, his vertical hair and strange inflections, but he is as much an observer of them as we are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I have one of those satellite things," he says. "On my television. And there are maybe 40 channels of movies. So once a day pretty much every day I'll surf those. I just go from one movie to another, watching 10 minutes of this, 10 minutes of that. And often there's something I'm in. And sometimes I'm quite good in it. And I'll sit and watch."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is, he says, "very educational". I ask him what he has learned. "That with every movie I make, there are some scenes where I'm good, and some where I'm not. With me, it's always hit and miss."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A keen reader of his own reviews, his approach to acting is self-sufficient. "I don't much like being directed," he says. "I enjoy being allowed to play." Naturally, in making more than a hundred films, there have been conflicts. "If somebody insists I do something, I have said: 'Please – don't insist I do that. I'm telling you, you're making a mistake.'" Again, he sounds heartbroken. "It's very rare, but it happens. It's just, as they say, the way the cookie crumbles."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work is rarely brought home, slavish research not generally his scene. While co-star &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/philipseymourhoffman" title=""&gt;Philip Seymour Hoffman&lt;/a&gt; learned the violin for A Late Quartet, Walken focused only on simulating playing the cello. The real thing held no appeal. "As a kid, I had piano and guitar lessons. I never got anywhere. I wasn't much interested. And physically, my hands ... they're rather large and clumsy. So it wasn't for me. I was a pretty good dancer though."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dancing and his life onstage come up a lot. By the time he made his first film – 1970 surveillance thriller The Anderson Tapes – he had been performing for more than 20 years. As a boy, still going by his real name Ronnie, he was thrust with his two brothers into theatre jobs and the live variety TV shows that broadcast nightly from the neon heart of 50s Manhattan. Was performing something he was drawn to? Comfortable with?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"No. Neither. As a child, you don't seek that out. My mother came to America as an adult. She came from Glasgow, in fact. She was smitten with movies, she read the movie magazines, and she wanted her kids to be in showbusiness. So I kind of just got put there."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sounds less than thrilled. "Oh no, I'm really very grateful. I can't imagine anything else I could have done that would have given me such a nice life."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The one shadow, of course, has been the death of Natalie Wood. &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jan/14/natalie-wood-death-reclassified-coroner" title=""&gt;In November 1981 the actor drowned off a Californian island&lt;/a&gt; while staying on a boat with Walken and her husband Robert Wagner. The case remains open. Walken, never a suspect, has chosen not to speak about it since 1997. You wonder how much of his reclusive bearing is a knowing shtick ("I wouldn't ever go into New York just for dinner or, you know, to visit someone") – and how much a response to having been so close to tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For all his showbusiness childhood, much of it was spent suffering from stage fright. Even now, six decades later, Walken is often called on to embody a certain tightly wound quality. Would he say he was a nervous person?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Not nervous exactly. But I'm very cautious. I worry. I tend to have contingency plans." About money? "Money and everything else. There has to be Plan B, and then Plan C. Always. It's just my nature. I know I might have a public persona of being a little wild, but I wouldn't have stuck around so long if that were the case."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He settles into the assured tone of the veteran actor rolling out an anecdote. "You know, I once sat next to Walter Matthau on an aeroplane. And for a very long time we didn't say anything. Then suddenly he turned to me and said: 'I know who you are! You're the guy who plays the crazy guys! You know, you got to have your feet on the ground to play crazy guys all the time.' And I said [... he leaves a beat, timing what will surely be a classic payoff] 'Yes – that's absolutely right.'"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, the crazy guys have taken care of the bills. For years, Walken's approach to employment has been that if you want him, you can probably have him. "I never planned my career," he says. "I just decided to work when I could. And you do that knowing sometimes it'll be good and sometimes it won't. Temperamentally I'm just that way, and it's worked out rather well."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Except in making so many films, a frightening number vanish into obscurity. "I know! And often they're the good ones!" It happens all the time, he says, reeling off movies he admits even he forgot until they turned up on his TV. He enthuses over a 1994 romance called &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109352/" title=""&gt;A Business Affair&lt;/a&gt;. I confess it passed me by. "It was made in London," he says meaningfully. "And I once made a movie in Wales that was really quite amusing. I don't think anyone saw that either. It's about rival undertakers. In Wales. It's called Plots With A View. A fun movie. It's not a very good title." (In Britain it was called &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0298504/" title=""&gt;Undertaking Betty&lt;/a&gt;, which may be worse.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But for Walken, there will always be another film. In this conversation at least, all roads lead back to work. In a week, he will turn 70. He is troubled by arthritis. But still, he exercises, watches his diet, tries to get enough sleep. The incentive? "So when the phone rings and someone says, 'Come do this job', I'll be as fit and ready as I can."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would his career have been possible had he had children? "Absolutely not. I'm sure many of the kids I knew as a child would have continued in showbusiness, but they had kids of their own, had to do something dependable. I didn't, so I could get by even in periods of unemployment."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet free time makes him uneasy. The usual diversions don't appeal. "A lot of my actor friends are passionate about golf or tennis," he says, as if they were passionate about dandruff. "Those things aren't for me." Is there anything he does that could be called a hobby? "I like to cook. You could call that a hobby. A hobby you can eat."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He says that last summer he made one of his rare trips to New York for a reading of Romeo and Juliet in Central Park. He played Mercutio. As a young man, he was Romeo on stage, but the reviews complained he made everything sound sarcastic. This time, the director told him he would make a fine Prospero in The Tempest. "So every day since I've spent a certain amount of time going over that part. Reading the lines. Thinking about them." Does he have a performance planned? "No, nobody's asked me yet. But someday they might."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sounds instantly energised: "People say you make your own opportunities. I've never known how to do that. But I squirrel away my nuts for when it comes. And when it does, well, I'm rather good at seizing it."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/christopher-walken"&gt;Christopher Walken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/dannyleigh"&gt;Danny Leigh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d76a4f/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393907361/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76a4f/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393907361/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76a4f/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393907361/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d76a4f/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/veDd6khVADU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film">Christopher Walken</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/culture">Culture</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film">Film</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/2013/mar/21/christopher-walken-im-a-regular-guy</guid><dc:creator>Danny Leigh</dc:creator><dc:subject>Film</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T19:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406016115</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Christopher Walken, Film, Culture</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885878683/-I-don-t-usually-get-to-p-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Canadian Press/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>'I don't usually get to play fathers or uncles' …Christopher Walken. Photograph: Canadian Press/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885884894/-I-don-t-usually-get-to-p-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Canadian Press/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>'I don't usually get to play fathers or uncles': Christopher Walken. Photograph: Canadian Press/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885527746/Christopher-Walken-in-A-L-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">PR</media:credit><media:description>Christopher Walken in A Late Quartet (2013).</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885365657/Walken-in-The-Deer-Hunter-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Moviestore Collection/Rex Feat</media:credit><media:description>Walken in The Deer Hunter (1978). Photograph: Moviestore Collection/Rex Feat</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885221445/Scene-stealer-Christopher-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Ronald Grant Archive</media:credit><media:description>Scene stealer: Christopher Walken in Pulp Fiction (1994). Photograph: Ronald Grant Archive</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885688492/Christopher-Walken-in-Sev-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Moviestore/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Christopher Walken in Seven Psychopaths (2012). Photograph: Moviestore/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/2013/mar/21/christopher-walken-im-a-regular-guy</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Alex Salmond announces Scottish independence referendum date</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/g9IcUsD7PwM/scottish-independence-referendum-date</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/64562?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ascottish-independence-referendum-date%3A1883457&amp;ch=Politics&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Scottish+independence%2CScottish+politics%2CAlex+Salmond%2CScotland+%28News%29%2CUK+news%2CPolitics&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Severin+Carrell&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+08%3A40&amp;c8=1883457&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Alex+Salmond+announces+Scottish+independence+referendum+date&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FPolitics%2FScottish+independence" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;First minister says 18 September 2014 will be seen as 'the day Scotland took a decisive step forward'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex Salmond has announced that Scotland's independence referendum will be held on 18 September next year, giving the independence movement 545 days to convince a largely sceptical population to say yes to leaving the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both the pro- and anti-independence campaigns launched online clocks counting down to referendum day, which the first minister had decided would come four weeks earlier than some expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around 4 million voters, set to include 16- and 17-year-olds for the first time in a major poll, will be asked a single six-word question: "Should Scotland become an independent country?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salmond said 18 September would be "a date which becomes etched in our nation's story as the day Scotland took a decisive step forward to a better, fairer future".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But opposition leaders said Salmond knew that independence was unpopular: a series of opinion polls has consistently shown that about a third of Scots back independence, with support for remaining in the UK commanding majority support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Willie Rennie, the Scottish Liberal Democrat leader, said it had taken Salmond some 700 days since he won a landslide in the Scottish elections to confirm the date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Johann Lamont, the Scottish Labour leader, said the further delay in staging the referendum meant Scotland would remain "on pause", delaying much needed action on poverty and economic recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Scottish government had repeatedly failed to set out in detail how an independent Scotland would function, what its tax, welfare and pensions policies would be or how it would improve health and education, Lamont said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"What I do not understand is that why, if leaving the United Kingdom is the key to Scotland's prosperity, why he wants Scotland to languish for another year and a half before we get the chance to vote on it," she said. "The truth is Alex Salmond knows if he held the referendum now he wouldn't just lose it he would be routed."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a direct appeal to unpersuaded voters, Salmond said the referendum was Scotland's chance to rid the country permanently of unpopular Conservative governments, and ensure it was not forced to accept deep cuts in welfare spending and London-led economic strategies which were failing to cut national debt or boost recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told the Scottish parliament Scotland "now faces two futures". While the UK was "an outdated political entity that ill-serves the interests of the people of Scotland", with independence, Scotland would "get a parliament that is both fully empowered and fully accountable to those whose lives are affected by its actions".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Voting yes in the referendum would allow Scotland to take direct control over its economy and welfare strategy. "Independence will be instrumental in bringing about that socially just and more prosperous Scotland that society wishes to see," Salmond said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His deputy, Nicola Sturgeon, who is tipped to take over the SNP leadership were Salmond to resign after losing the referendum, has downplayed the referendum as a nationalist cause. She argues independence is just a means of achieving greater social justice, to uphold "Scottish values of fairness and opportunity, promoting equality and social cohesion".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Harvie, the Scottish Green leader, and a senior figure in the Yes Scotland coalition, accused Salmond and his opponents of fixating on cutting taxes and enriching corporations rather than fighting for social justice. "Now we have the date for our diaries the effort to persuade those who are undecided must focus on the needs of real people and not just those with loud voices and deep pockets," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Salmond's original preferred date of Saturday 18 October 2014 was leaked to the launch edition of the Sun on Sunday newspaper last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Electoral Commission had warned that staging a vote on a Saturday would disadvantage some religious groups who would be prohibited from voting or object to votes being counted on a Sunday, and urged the Scottish government to choose the conventional voting day of Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two campaigns – the pro-independence Yes Scotland group, which includes the SNP, the Scottish Green party and two small socialist parties, and the pro-UK Better Together coalition of Labour, the Tories and Lib Dems – will be each allowed to spend £1.5m in the official 16-week campaign which will now start in May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total, those two campaigns, Scotland's political parties and allied groups such as trades unions and single-issue groups, will be able to spend at least £6m in that four-month period. It is likely to be the most intense period of campaigning in Scottish political history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SNP coffers have been boosted by about £2m in direct donations from the Euromillions winners Chris and Colin Weir, and a bequest from the former national poet Edwin Morgan. The Better Together campaign launched a fundraising drive this week, claiming that its supporters could not assume victory next year, despite the polls suggesting defeat for independence in the referendum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/scottish-independence"&gt;Scottish independence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/scotland"&gt;Scottish politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/alexsalmond"&gt;Alex Salmond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/scotland"&gt;Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/severincarrell"&gt;Severin Carrell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d1053b/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393885667/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d1053b/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393885667/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d1053b/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393885667/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d1053b/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/g9IcUsD7PwM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Scottish independence</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Scottish politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Scotland</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:55:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/21/scottish-independence-referendum-date</guid><dc:creator>Severin Carrell</dc:creator><dc:subject>Politics</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T18:55:32Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>405972468</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Scottish independence, Scottish politics, Alex Salmond, Scotland, UK news, Politics</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363855067568/First-Minister-Alex-Salmo-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Scottish parliament/Andrew Cowan</media:credit><media:description>First Minister, Alex Salmond, is to announce the date for the independence referendum at Holyrood. Photograph: Scottish parliament/Andrew Cowan</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363855074754/First-Minister-Alex-Salmo-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Scottish parliament/Andrew Cowan</media:credit><media:description>The Scottish first minister, Alex Salmond, announced the date of the independence referendum at Holyrood. Photograph: Scottish parliament/Andrew Cowan</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/2013/mar/21/scottish-independence-referendum-date</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Obama shows emotional and political intelligence with Jerusalem speech</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/5b0HUYsY0QE/obama-appeals-israeli-emotions-speech</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/51128?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aobama-appeals-israeli-emotions-speech%3A1883964&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Israel+%28News%29%2CBarack+Obama+%28News%29%2CPalestinian+territories+%28News%29%2CUS+foreign+policy%2CMiddle+East+and+North+Africa+%28News%29+MENA%2CUS+news%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CUS+Elections&amp;c6=Ian+Black&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+06%3A39&amp;c8=1883964&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News%2CAnalysis&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Obama+shows+emotional+and+political+intelligence+with+Jerusalem+speech&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FIsrael" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;US president appeals to Israeli emotions with talk of persecution and pioneers – but critics accuse him of lacking substance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Barack Obama pulled off quite a trick in his &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/obama-strong-call-israel-palestinian-peace" title=""&gt;Jerusalem speech&lt;/a&gt; – appealing to ordinary Israelis over the heads of their political leaders and cleverly borrowing a line from their national anthem to explain why Palestinians also deserve to be "free people in their own land".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the biggest moment of his &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/middle-east-live/2013/mar/21/barack-obama-visits-west-bank-live" title=""&gt;Middle East trip&lt;/a&gt; so far, the president displayed a smart combination of emotional and political intelligence in pressing the buttons that matter to mainstream Jewish opinion in Israel (and the US): he referenced Biblical heroes, pogroms, persecution, the Holocaust, Zionism and the old saw about pioneers "making the desert bloom" – all linked to the urgent prospect of making peace. The oratory was impressive; the politics less so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obama's &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/barack-obama-speech-jerusalem-text" title=""&gt;effusive pitch&lt;/a&gt; embraced every area of unqualified US support for Israel: military, political and economic aid. A quartet of common enemies – Hamas, Hezbollah, Syria and Iran – were vilified and there was praise for "the courage of the Israel Defence Forces, and a citizenry that is resilient in the face of terror" – though no mention of life in Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The president linked Tehran's nuclear programme to "living in a neighbourhood where many of your neighbours have rejected your right to exist" though he wisely avoided eliding it, like Binyamin Netanyahu, with the Nazi annihilation of six million Jews. Diplomacy remained the best way of dealing with Iran, but "all options" remained on the table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a warm bath of loving attention – all the more remarkable when compared to multiplying calls from Europe and elsewhere to boycott Israel and abandon the 45-year-old notion that a two-state solution to the world's most intractable conflict is achievable or even just.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israel, he declared to thunderous applause, was "not going anywhere", adding in passable Hebrew: "You are not alone." But he did also warn the country of the need to reverse "an undertow of isolation" at a time of fast-moving change in the wider Middle East. The tone was that of a candid, worried friend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hussein Ibish of the American Task Force on Palestine called it a "historic and brilliant speech". But Palestinian and Arab audiences were generally not impressed – not least because the president offered not a single practical proposal to advance the long-stalled peace process (though aides insisted that was never his intention). That Herculean labour will be up to John Kerry once the visit is over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, there is no obvious or easy way to translate the feelgood effect of the speech into practical politics and diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Are violins playing in the background while Obama speaks?" one Lebanese woman asked sarcastically. Others complained of eloquence without depth or substance. Ali Abunimah, an outspoken critic of the Palestinian president, Mahmoud Abbas, and a supporter of the one-state solution, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AliAbunimah/status/314761684692643840" title=""&gt;tweeted in anger&lt;/a&gt;: "Palestinians yearning for peace live in a tough neighborhood, surrounded by racist settlers and a murderous US-backed sectarian 'army.' Obama's 'history' of Israel is as delusional as his US history which still praises slave-owning, slave-raping founding fathers. This speech will drive liberal Zionists wild because it legitimizes their segregationist desires &amp; dresses them up as 'peace' &amp; 'democracy.'"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obama did speak of settler violence against Palestinians going unpunished. Otherwise direct criticism of Israel's government was extremely mild: illegal settlements – the core of his notoriously prickly relationship with Netanyahu – were "not constructive" and there was no call for a freeze, as Palestinians demand. But Abbas was explicitly urged to avoid "unilateral" steps such as appealing to the UN – a glimpse of double standards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rave reviews of this speech will probably outnumber the very bad ones. But what happens next matters much more than intelligent and honeyed words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/israel"&gt;Israel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/barack-obama"&gt;Barack Obama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/palestinian-territories"&gt;Palestinian territories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usforeignpolicy"&gt;US foreign policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/middleeast"&gt;Middle East and North Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/ianblack"&gt;Ian Black&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d788a0/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/5b0HUYsY0QE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Middle East and North Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Barack Obama</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US foreign policy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Analysis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Israel</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Palestinian territories</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:39:14 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/obama-appeals-israeli-emotions-speech</guid><dc:creator>Ian Black</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T18:51:55Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406027357</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Israel, Barack Obama, Palestinian territories, US foreign policy, Middle East and North Africa, United States, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363890964527/Barack-Obama-Jerusalem-sp-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Jim Hollander/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Barack Obama waves in front of Israeli and US flags after giving his speech in Jerusalem. Photograph: Jim Hollander/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363890972235/Barack-Obama-Jerusalem-sp-009.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Jim Hollander/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Barack Obama waves in front of Israeli and US flags after giving his speech in Jerusalem. Photograph: Jim Hollander/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/obama-appeals-israeli-emotions-speech</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Cyprus crisis: Government to create 'solidarity fund' after ECB issues Monday ultimatum - live</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/UJo-tQJQdf4/eurozone-crisis-cyprus-bailout-plan-b</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Party leaders in Cyprus are scrambling to find the funds to satisfy the IMF and the EU, after the European Central Bank threatened to turn off liquidity to its banks next week&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/graemewearden"&gt;Graeme Wearden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d0d9e2/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393884687/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d0d9e2/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393884687/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d0d9e2/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393884687/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d0d9e2/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/UJo-tQJQdf4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Blogposts</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Euro</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Minute by minutes</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">European Union</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Cyprus</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Eurozone crisis</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:31:52 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/mar/21/eurozone-crisis-cyprus-bailout-plan-b</guid><dc:creator>Graeme Wearden</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T18:31:54Z</dc:date><dc:type>Resource Content</dc:type><dc:identifier>405970798</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Eurozone crisis, Euro, Cyprus, World news, European Union</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363888191957/6aaad3ad-79ee-476e-b5dc-22d2efc8882c-140x84.jpeg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">YANNIS BEHRAKIS/REUTERS</media:credit><media:description>A protester shouts slogans during a rally by employees of Cyprus Popular Bank outside the parliament in Nicosia March 21, 2013. Photograph: YANNIS BEHRAKIS/REUTERS</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2013/mar/21/eurozone-crisis-cyprus-bailout-plan-b</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Cyprus crisis: politicians race to agree details of 'plan B'</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/kNouMsnjz3w/cyprus-crisis-race-agree-plan-b</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/94240?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Acyprus-crisis-race-agree-plan-b%3A1883955&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Cyprus+%28News%29%2CEurozone+crisis%2CEuropean+banks+%28business%29%2CBanking+%28Business+sector%29%2CWorld+news%2CEconomics+%28Business%29%2CFinancial+sector+%28business%29%2CEuro+%28Business%29%2CEurope+%28News%29%2CBusiness&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CCredit+Crunch%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CInvestments+%26+Savings&amp;c6=Graeme+Wearden%2CHoward+Amos&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+06%3A13&amp;c8=1883955&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Cyprus+crisis%3A+politicians+race+to+agree+details+of+%27plan+B%27&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FCyprus" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;ECB ratchets up pressure as party leaders met to agree a package that would satisfy its eurozone partners and the IMF&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cypriot politicians were racing to agree details of a "plan B" to rescue their economy on Thursday night, after the European Central Bank threatened to withdraw support for the country's banking sector if a bailout was not agreed by Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The country's second-largest bank, Laiki, is to be restructured as part of the plan. It will avert bankrupcy and protect savers with up to €100,000, according to the country's central bank governor, Panicos Demetriades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move came hours after the ECB ratcheted up the pressure on Nicosia as party leaders met to agree a package that would satisfy its eurozone partners and the International Monetary Fund. Tensions were rising on the streets, with crowds of bank workers demonstrating near the parliament building in Nicosia following reports that its second largest lender, Laiki, would be shut down and split into a good and bad bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday afternoon the president, Nicos Anastasiades, said parliament would receive a bill by the end of the night, outlining the creation of a state investment fund to meet the ECB's ultimatum to raise billions of euros or face the loss of the bailout money and the collapse of its banking sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another bill will pave the way for the imposition of capital controls - restrictions on taking money out of the country's banks - according to reports from Nicosia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ECB confirmed it would not provide emergency liquidity assistance to the island's banking sector beyond 25 March, unless a bailout had been agreed. Without its support, Cyprus's two largest banks, Bank of Cyprus and Laiki, could collapse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were lengthy queues at many Laiki cash machines on Thursday as banks and the domestic stock market remained closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eurogroup of finance ministers were scheduled to hold a conference call from 6pm GMT on Thursday to discuss the situation in Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cypriot political leaders were involved in emergency talks on Thursday morning to find a way to raise the €6bn (£5.1bn) demanded by the IMF and EU in return for a €10bn bailout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Averof Neophytou, the deputy leader of the ruling Disy party, confirmed the leaders had agreed to create the solidarity fund. Details of the scheme were not released, but it was believed the fund could use Cyprus's energy resources as collateral, or include state assets, pension funds or the property of the Church of Cyprus. A vote on the package could come as early as Thursday night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parliamentary speaker Yiannakis Omirou, who leads the small Edek socialist party, said the issue of taxing bank deposits had not been discussed during the meeting, suggesting a savings levy could be off the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/19/cyprus-rejects-eurozone-bailout-savings-tax" title=""&gt;the parliament rejected&lt;/a&gt; the plan for a 6.75% tax on savers with more than €20,000 in the bank, rising to 9.9% for those with more than €100,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ECB said a continuation of its emergency liquidity assistance "could only be considered if an EU/IMF programme is in place that would ensure the solvency of the concerned banks".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the ECB issued its ultimatum, Cyprus's central bank governor said he was confident the country would reach a deal in time. "We will have a programme of support for Cyprus by Monday," said Demetriades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cypriot finance minister, Michael Sarris, has been in Moscow since Tuesday in an attempt to secure a rescue package, but hopes for a Kremlin-brokered deal appeared to be fading, as negotiations between Sarris and his Russian counterpart looked set to enter a third day with no results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first time, Nicosia showed a public willingness to offer access to financial assets and gas deposits in the eastern Mediterranean as part of any agreement. "Understandably, if there is to be help, it has to be connected with a number of economic activities," said Sarris ahead of discussions with Russian finance minister Anton Siluanov.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian officials have sought to downplay talk of large amounts of corrupt cash flowing through Cyprus, but the Mediterranean island is thought to play a key role in Russian money laundering operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Russian prime minister, Dmitry Medevdev, has intensified his criticism of the idea of a compulsory levy on deposits in Cyprus, where Russian citizens are estimated to hold up to $19bn, and said the plan "looked like theft".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Medvedev interrupted a conference in Moscow to read the news from his iPad that the Cypriot parliament had decided to drop the compulsory tax proposal — and the announcement was met with applause and shouts of "hurrah!" from delegates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite alarm over possible expropriation, the Cypriot appeal to Moscow has given Russia an unprecedented opportunity to exert influence in an internal European Union matter. "It's an opportunity for the Russians to make a major play," said one western banker in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the parameters of any deal remain unclear. State-owned gas giant Gazprom is unlikely to be interested in operating Cypriot gas fields in the context of an over-supplied European market, according to Ildar Davletshin, an oil and gas analyst at Renaissance Capital in Moscow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia's three biggest state-owned banks — Sberbank, VTB and Gazprombank — have all denied they are interested in buying financial assets in Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cyprus has recently discovered significant offshore gas deposits, and major energy companies have shown an interest in tapping those resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the Monday deadline imposed by the ECB, time is running out for Cyprus to conclude an agreement with the Kremlin, according to Dmitry Polevoy, ING Bank's chief economist in Russia. "All these deals [involving energy or banking assets] require intensive due diligence processes … and usually require much more time than Cyprus has," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"But Russia is a country of surprises and nobody knows what is really at stake and whose money is at risk," he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Medvedev also sought to find more unorthodox benefits for Russia in Cyprus's crisis. The Kremlin should develop islands, including the Kurils and Sakhalin, off the country's far east Pacific coast as alternative offshore banking destinations, Medvedev said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian sovereignty of the Kuril Islands is disputed by Japan, while Sakhalin is the site of a former Tsarist penal colony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The implementation of such a plan would have "ruinous consequences for Russia's financial system," former finance minister Aleksei Kudrin wrote on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/cyprus"&gt;Cyprus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/debt-crisis"&gt;Eurozone crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/europeanbanks"&gt;European banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/banking"&gt;Banking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/economics"&gt;Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/financial-sector"&gt;Financial sector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/euro"&gt;Euro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/europe-news"&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/graemewearden"&gt;Graeme Wearden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/howard-amos"&gt;Howard Amos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d71f5c/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/kNouMsnjz3w" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Financial sector</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Euro</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Banking</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Economics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Cyprus</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Europe</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Eurozone crisis</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">European banks</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:13:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/cyprus-crisis-race-agree-plan-b</guid><dc:creator>Graeme Wearden, Howard Amos</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T19:38:49Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406025848</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Cyprus, Eurozone crisis, European banks, Banking, World news, Economics, Financial sector, Euro, Europe, Business</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363889611207/Tensions-are-rising-as-ba-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Andreas Manolis/REUTERS</media:credit><media:description>Tensions are rising as bank workers protest outside the parliament in Nicosia, Cyprus. Photograph: Andreas Manolis/REUTERS</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363889617345/Tensions-are-rising-as-ba-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Andreas Manolis/REUTERS</media:credit><media:description>Tensions are rising as bank workers protest outside the parliament in Nicosia, Cyprus. Photograph: Andreas Manolis/REUTERS</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/cyprus-crisis-race-agree-plan-b</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Lords plan parliamentary 'ping pong' to win battle over secret courts</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/5vfxUo4aaUw/lords-ping-pong-secret-courts</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/64861?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Alords-ping-pong-secret-courts%3A1883947&amp;ch=Law&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Justice+and+security+bill%2COpen+justice%2CHouse+of+Lords%2CPolitics%2CHuman+rights%2CLaw%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Nicholas+Watt&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+06%3A12&amp;c8=1883947&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Lords+plan+parliamentary+%27ping+pong%27+to+win+battle+over+secret+courts&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FLaw%2FJustice+and+security+bill" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Peers intend to change justice and security bill as it shuttles between houses of parliament, government is warned&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Campaigners against a new generation of secret courts are confident they will be able to introduce fundamental changes to the controversial measure next week by launching parliamentary guerrilla tactics dubbed "ping pong with grenades".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amid warnings that the government is planning to introduce Russian-style secret courts, the government is being warned that peers are prepared to exhaust a series of parliamentary devices when the bill sanctioning the changes reaches its final stage on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peers are planning to table amendments to the &lt;a href="http://services.parliament.uk/bills/2012-13/justiceandsecurity.html" title=""&gt;justice and security bill&lt;/a&gt; that would ensure judges are given complete discretion over the new system and the courts are used as a last resort. This will be done when the bill reaches "ping pong" stage, in which it shuttles between the two houses of parliament as MPs and peers haggle over last-minute amendments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The upper house usually avoids a prolonged fight with the Commons. But campaigners, who point out that the changes were not included in the coalition agreement, say peers are digging in for a long fight because the Commons cannot use its usual powers to force through a bill by invoking the Parliament Act. The Commons cannot do this with the justice and security bill because it originated in the upper house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Campaigners believe they have another weapon. They say that if no agreement is reached between the Lords and the Commons by the beginning of May, when parliament is prorogued before the Queen's speech on 8 May, it may die. This is because it may be too late to designate the bill as a "carry over" measure that should be allowed to continue into the next parliamentary session. The government would have to table a "carry over" amendment in the Lords, which it would struggle to win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One campaigner said: "The government have been caught napping on this. Next week we will see real ping pong with grenades."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andrew Tyrie, the Conservative MP for Chichester who has been one of the leading voices against the bill, told the Guardian: "We need to think of this as a massive experiment with the way justice has historically been done in Britain. The principle that you should be able to bust out what the other side are saying about your plea is so deeply entrenched in British and Anglo-Saxon justice it is amazing it is going more or less on the nod.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"You have only got to think about all those countries that do have secret courts to see why we don't really want to join their club. There are about 130 run by dictators – Russia has secret courts."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government plans to extend secret courts, known as closed material procedures, into the main civil courts in England and Wales. The bill would limit access to some sensitive intelligence to the judge and to special advocates cleared for security who would represent claimants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government introduced the bill after the public airing of evidence during litigation brought on behalf of Binyam Mohamed and other former Guantánamo Bay detainees. The court of appeal agreed to disclose CIA information which showed MI5 and MI6 knew that Mohamed, a UK resident, had been abused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Lords amendments are designed to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Guarantee full judicial discretion to ensure the new courts are only used as a last resort after all other avenues have been exhausted. The government is opposed to this because they want to avoid public immunity interest, which would give judges discretion to make some of the material public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Introduce a renewal clause to ensure the bill would have to be reviewed and approved in every parliament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has succeeded in overturning previous Lords amendments by whipping coalition MPs to overturn them. Tyrie and the Lib Dem president, Tim Farron, have rebelled against the government on the bill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tyrie said: "Everything hinges on the Lords sticking to their position. The judges should decide, not ministers. The government heavily qualified the judicial discretion which, rightly, the Lords put on the face of the bill. I very much hope the Lords back the spirit of their original amendments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This bill started in the Lords so they have a disproportionate say. This is a very important bill. It is ultimately about the type of country we want to live in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This bill has been introduced partly because parts of the executive didn't like the exposure given to Britain's complicity in rendition. We should be getting to the bottom of this – Britain's complicity in kidnap and torture – not closing down routes to exposing it."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tyrie said the government's arguments were weak. Ministers have said the courts are necessary to avoid large compensation payments which are being made at the moment because some sensitive intelligence material cannot be heard in open court and is therefore excluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sadiq Khan, the shadow justice secretary, said: "The decision on whether or not to have court hearings in secret should be decided by a judge, not a minister. We will be pushing to ensure all options that would maintain court hearings in the open are considered before a hearing becomes secret and also that a proper test is applied by a judge before opting for closed material proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We also want the bill to have to be renewed once by each parliament. We all want to see justice done in these very difficult cases, but without our changes being accepted this is unlikely to happen."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nick Clegg suffered a defeat at the recent Liberal Democrat spring conference when the party voted to reject the bill. Jo Shaw, a veteran Lib Dem who resigned from the party after moving the motion, confronted him on his LBC 97.3 radio phone-in on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shaw said: "Hello there. Nick, why are [you] whipping Lib Dem peers to support the justice and security bill next week when there is no evidence it is needed, it provides a toolkit for cover-ups of torture and kidnap and the entire Liberal Democrat party is united against it?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clegg defended the changes on the grounds that the special courts would be convened in "exceptional cases" to avoid the current situation in which large compensation payments were being made because some intelligence could not be heard in open court.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/justice-and-security"&gt;Justice and security bill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/open-justice"&gt;Open justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/lords"&gt;House of Lords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/human-rights"&gt;Human rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/nicholaswatt"&gt;Nicholas Watt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d7107b/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/5vfxUo4aaUw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Justice and security bill</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Law</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Open justice</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law">Human rights</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">House of Lords</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:12:12 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/2013/mar/21/lords-ping-pong-secret-courts</guid><dc:creator>Nicholas Watt</dc:creator><dc:subject>Law</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T18:12:12Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406024755</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Justice and security bill, Open justice, House of Lords, Politics, Human rights, Law, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363889478352/Andrew-Tyrie-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Felix Clay/Felix Clay</media:credit><media:description>Andrew Tyrie, the Tory MP who is a leading voice against secret courts. Photograph: Felix Clay</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363889487417/Andrew-Tyrie-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Felix Clay/Felix Clay</media:credit><media:description>Andrew Tyrie, the Tory MP who is a leading voice against secret courts. Photograph: Felix Clay</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/2013/mar/21/lords-ping-pong-secret-courts</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kurdish families separated by decades of conflict hold their breath for peace</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/QyO7dvIo6eE/kurdish-families-conflict-peace</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/91417?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Akurdish-families-conflict-peace%3A1883927&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Kurds+%28News%29%2CMiddle+East+and+North+Africa+%28News%29+MENA%2CWorld+news%2CTurkey+%28News%29&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Constanze+Letsch&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+05%3A43&amp;c8=1883927&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News%2CFeature&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Kurdish+families+separated+by+decades+of+conflict+hold+their+breath+for+peace&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FKurds" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Fatma watches historic ceasefire call she hopes will one day reunite her with the daughter she has not seen for 20 years&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Glued to the TV screen in her small Istanbul home, Fatma watches the Kurdish new year celebrations in faraway Diyarbakir, witnessing a historic ceasefire call that she hopes will one day reunite her with the daughter she has not seen for 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I am so excited," said the 56-year-old, who prefers not to use her real name, as she listened to a message from Abdullah Öcalan, the jailed Kurdish guerrilla leader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Fatma's daughter was 15 years old, the Kurdish teenager took to the hills to join Öcalan's Kurdistan Workers' party (PKK), enlisting in their 30-year guerrilla war against the Turkish state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I have not seen her since," Fatma said. "Sometimes we talk on the phone, sometimes her friends call me. I know that she is now a commander, that she trains fighters. But once the ceasefire is in place, once there is peace, I will go and visit her in the mountains. I will finally see my daughter again."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Kurdish politicians read a message from Öcalan, who has been held in solitary confinement for 14 years on a Turkish island prison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Öcalan's message proclaimed: "We are at a point today when the guns will fall silent and ideas will speak. It is time for armed fighters to move outside [Turkey's] borders. This is not an ending, but a new beginning." He talked of Turks and Kurds acting together after decades of human rights abuses, communal strife and violence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Turks and Kurds fought together in Çanakkale [during the first world war], and launched the Turkish parliament together in 1920," he said. "The basis of the new struggle consists of ideas, ideology and democratic politics."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the peace overture was read out in Diyarbakir, the main Kurdish city in southeast Turkey, Fatma and her two other daughters fell silent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I can hardly breathe," said Hatice, 25, clutching a scarf in red, yellow and green, the PKK colours. "I wish we could have gone to Diyarbakir too. Imagine what the atmosphere on that square must be like now."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Diyarbakir itself, hundreds of thousands thronged the streets to mark &lt;em&gt;Newroz&lt;/em&gt;, the new year, a celebration made more joyous by the possibility of peace after decades of conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The peace talks began gingerly last October, the first time a Turkish prime minister had openly engaged in dialogue with Öcalan, deemed the state's enemy No&amp;nbsp;1 by many Turks. And Thursday's ceasefire announcement was the biggest development yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Öcalan did not announce a timeframe, but, according to Turkish media reports, it is expected that all of the PKK's estimated 3,500 fighters based in Turkey will withdraw within five months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clad in a bright red &lt;em&gt;Newroz&lt;/em&gt; dress, Fatma's other daughter, Nilgün, listened intently to Öcalan's message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I wanted to join the PKK when I was 13," she said. "But they sent me home saying I was too young. I cried so much, but they did not let me join. My friend and I were caught on the road back to our village. I spent almost five years in jail."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The family moved to Istanbul 20 years ago, after Turkish security forces burned down their village as part of the scorched earth policy aimed at eradicating Kurdish rebel fighters. They lost their home and most of their belongings. Shortly after, Fatma's then 15-year-old daughter ran away from home and joined the PKK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of Kurdish families who share the same anxiety and the same joy. "Both my uncle and his son died fighting for the PKK. Almost every family here has someone in the mountains," said Nilgün.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ceasefire and the withdrawal of PKK fighters are the most critical moves yet in the peace talks. If they succeed, a settlement would end a bloody conflict that has cost more than 40,000 lives, seen thousands jailed and tortured, and displaced millions of Kurds from their homes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Koray Çalışkan, of the Istanbul Bosporus University, said the ball was now in Turkey's court: "The Turkish government will now likely carry out a number of legal reforms that will set free many of the people currently jailed under arbitrary Turkish terrorism laws."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 8,000 Kurdish politicians, journalists and activists are presently in jail, most of them for voicing their opinions peacefully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We all remember bad things happening in Turkey only months ago," Çalışkan added, referring to arbitrary arrests, the hawkish stance towards Öcalan and the Kurdish issue of Turkey's prime minister, Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, and a hunger strike by more than 700 Kurdish prisoners last year. "But now is not the time to remember. Now is the time to let peace happen. It has to work, we simply have no other choice."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hatice felt that Thursday was a milestone. "Millions of people have waited for this day. The war will end, and both Kurds and Turks will be better off." She hopes to finally meet the big sister she has never seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"She will be watching this with us in Qandil," said her mother, referring to the PKK mountain headquarters across the border in northern Iraq. "All the guerrilla fighters are watching this. And just like my daughter, they hope to be able to reunite with their families after all these years."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nilgün nodded. "Kurds want peace. We are tired. We have longed for peace for a very long time. We didn't have a childhood, we suffered so much. Kurds suffered so much. But it was all worth it when I hear this now."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 20 years of their separation, Fatma has caught sight of her fighter daughter only once – in a video clip on a Kurdish pro-PKK satellite channel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Every time that the names of martyrs were announced, my heart tightened with fear. But now the fighting will stop. I am so happy, so relieved."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The women's names have been changed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/kurds"&gt;Kurds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/middleeast"&gt;Middle East and North Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/turkey"&gt;Turkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/constanze-letsch"&gt;Constanze Letsch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d6e142/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/QyO7dvIo6eE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Middle East and North Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Kurds</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">Features</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Turkey</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:43:58 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/kurdish-families-conflict-peace</guid><dc:creator>Constanze Letsch</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T18:37:53Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406022113</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Kurds, Middle East and North Africa, World news, Turkey</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363887369029/PKK-Ocalan-declared-a-cea-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Sedat Suna/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Kurdish people cheer and hold pictures of PKK leader Abdullah Ocalan during new year celebrations in Diyarbakir, Turkey. Photograph: Sedat Suna/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363887376333/PKK-Ocalan-declared-a-cea-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Sedat Suna/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Kurds wave pictures of the PKK leader Abdullah Öcalan as they celebrate the Kurdish new year in Diyarbakir, Turkey. Photograph: Sedat Suna/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/kurdish-families-conflict-peace</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Sanjay Dutt ordered to finish jail sentence over 1993 Mumbai bombings</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/6Q430hacyag/sanjay-dutt-jail-mumbai-bombings</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/66180?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Asanjay-dutt-jail-mumbai-bombings%3A1883929&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=India+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CTerrorism+-+international%2CBollywood+%28Film+genre%29%2CFilm&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Maseeh+Rahman&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+05%3A43&amp;c8=1883929&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Sanjay+Dutt+ordered+to+finish+jail+sentence+over+1993+Mumbai+bombings&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FIndia" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Bollywood actor was convicted of possessing illegal firearms as part of case over serial attacks that killed 257 people&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;India's supreme court has ordered the Bollywood star Sanjay Dutt, the most high-profile of the 100 men and women who were convicted for the 1993 Mumbai serial bombings, to return to jail for a further three-and-a-half years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bombings on 12 March 1993 were engineered by a silver smuggler and gangster, Mushtaq "Tiger" Memon, widely seen as revenge for the destruction of the Mughal-era Babri Masjid, a hallowed Islamic site, by Hindu fanatics three months earlier. But the real mastermind behind the attacks was said to be the Muslim underworld kingpin Dawood Ibrahim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dutt had been out on parole since 2007, when he appealed against the original sentence by a lower court of six years imprisonment – not for the bomb conspiracy but for the lesser charge of possessing illegal weapons (an AK-56 rifle and a 9mm pistol) supplied by the same Mumbai gangsters who carried out the devastating serial bombings, which killed 257 people and injured 713.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dutt's defence was that he knew nothing about the bomb plot and that he asked for the guns to protect his family after receiving threats during sectarian riots in Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time, the bombings were the worst terrorist attack the world had seen, with 13 bombs set off over a two-hour period across Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The supreme court reduced the sentence for Dutt on Thursday to five years. Having already spent 18 months in jail, he will serve only the remainder of his sentence. He has been asked to surrender to prison authorities in a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amid a frenzy of support and sympathy for Dutt from Bollywood, the actor told NDTV: "I'm okay. I can't think straight now. I'm trying to come to terms with the verdict. I'm just trying to gather my thoughts."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the drawn-out trial in a special anti-terrorism court, which finally led to the sentencing of 100 men and women in 2007, there were accusations that Dutt was getting preferential treatment thanks to his high-profile status and his political connections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dutt is the son of two legendary Bollywood stars, one a Muslim and the other a Hindu, who fell in love on the sets of the 1957 blockbuster Mother India. His mother, Nargis, was close to India's first prime minister Jawaharlal Nehru. His father, Sunil Dutt, was an elected Congress party MP and the national sports minister. His sister Priya succeeded their father in parliament. Dutt himself has flirted with an opposition party, and also with Mumbai's militant Hindu radical Bal Thackeray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the trial court sentenced him in 2007, Dutt went to the supreme court and secured bail, since when he has re-established his successful film career, especially with the hit Munnabhai film trilogy, propagating "Gandhian values", and many action roles. He also remarried in 2008 and fathered twins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The supreme court also showed leniency by commuting the death sentences of 10 bombers to imprisonment for life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only one man will now go to the gallows – Yakub Memon, a chartered accountant who functioned as a financial manager in his brother Tiger's smuggling business. The court confirmed the death sentence against Yakub even though the accountant appeared to have only a peripheral involvement in the terror conspiracy. He provided the money for the vehicles that were later packed with explosives, and he arranged for plane tickets for Tiger's men to fly to Dubai – from where they were taken to Pakistan to be trained as bombers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this was Yakub's normal role as the money manager in his brother's silver-smuggling business.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hours before his bombs ripped apart Mumbai, Tiger fled to Dubai and then Pakistan with three generations of his extended family. Dawood is also said to have taken refuge there, though Islamabad denied it all. Prosecutors said that Pakistan's ISI agency had supplied the explosive and trained the bombers, a charge accepted by the supreme court. But Yakub created a sensation in 1994 by suddenly deciding to return to India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After his return, this correspondent met Yakub while he was in police custody in Delhi. He remained silent, but the police were exultant – Yakub had come back with video and audio evidence that showed Pakistani officials had showered the Memons with extraordinary hospitality, including a 20-room mansion in Karachi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Yakub's help, the Indian police also succeeded in bringing back several other Memons – his parents, three brothers, their wives and children. But the Memons ran into a double-cross – on their return they were all thrown into jail. Finally, two brothers (one with a brain tumour and the other with a mental disability), have been sentenced to life, along with a sister-in-law who had moved away from Mumbai six months before the bombings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mumbai mafia: Bollywood and the underworld&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, Bollywood and Mumbai's organised crime elements were locked in a deadly embrace. Gangsters not only financed producers but also had a finger in everything from screenplay writing and casting to the distribution of films.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The crime for which actor Sanjay Dutt, 53, was sentenced to five years imprisonment – accepting a gift of illegal weapons from his producers in early 1993 – dates from the heyday of Bollywood's romance with mobsters. It was only after cinema was designated as an "industry" by the government in 2001 – making bank finance possible – that the stranglehold of the underworld began to loosen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 3bn rupees (£35million) is said to be riding on Dutt's current film projects – a big chunk could be lost if he is jailed immediately. But the outpouring of support and sympathy from film celebrities for Dutt is not just a case of Bollywood putting its mouth where its money is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"There's genuine sympathy for Dutt," said Bollywood analyst Rauf Ahmed. "He is seen as a victim of the bad old days – he was foolish and immature, and could not resist the lure of an AK-56 rifle."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/india"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/terrorism"&gt;Global terrorism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/bollywood"&gt;Bollywood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/maseehrahman"&gt;Maseeh Rahman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d81c66/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/6Q430hacyag" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">The Guardian</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film">Bollywood</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">India</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Global terrorism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/film">Film</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:43:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/sanjay-dutt-jail-mumbai-bombings</guid><dc:creator>Maseeh Rahman</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T21:26:57Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406022114</dc:identifier><media:keywords>India, World news, Global terrorism, Bollywood, Film</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/21/1363887750555/Indian-Bollywood-actor-Sa-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Sanjay Dutt, pictured in 2012, has been ordered to serve the remaining three-and-a-half years of his sentence for possessing illegal firearms. Photograph: AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/21/1363887757011/Indian-Bollywood-actor-Sa-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Sanjay Dutt, pictured in 2012, has been ordered to serve the remaining three-and-a-half years of his sentence for possessing illegal firearms. Photograph: AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/21/1363888107071/Sanjay-Dutt-in-the-2011-f-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Everett Collection/Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Sanjay Dutt in the 2011 film Double Dhamaal, with Kangana Ranaut (l) and Mallika Sherawat. Photograph: Everett Collection/Rex Features</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/sanjay-dutt-jail-mumbai-bombings</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Hunt for runaway South African black mamba snake goes hi-tech</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/aM5shen0UaQ/hunt-south-african-black-mamba</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/56777?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ahunt-south-african-black-mamba%3A1883889&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=South+Africa+%28News%29%2CAnimals+%28News%29%2CAfrica+%28News%29%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CWildlife+Conservation%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Associated+Press+in+Johannesburg&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+05%3A03&amp;c8=1883889&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Hunt+for+runaway+South+African+black+mamba+snake+goes+hi-tech&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FSouth+Africa" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Pretoria zoo turns to infrared cameras in search for deadly 6.5ft reptile as public anxiety over potentially fatal attack grows&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pretoria zoo has resorted to using infrared cameras in the hunt for a 6.5ft snake that fled from its enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The black mamba is believed to be hiding in the roof of a service building behind its terrarium, said Craig Allenby, who works at the zoo in the South African capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However its lofty location has not stopped frightened callers to radio talk shows speculating over the nearly always fatal results of a bite from one of the world's fastest and most venomous snakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zookeepers realised last week that the mamba's enclosure was empty. They have been unable to search the roof where they suspect the animal is preparing to hibernate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hi-tech cameras can be used detect infrared radiation emitted by bodies and objects – even cold-blooded reptiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/southafrica"&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/animals"&gt;Animals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/africa"&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d660f4/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393903759/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d660f4/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393903759/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d660f4/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393903759/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d660f4/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/aM5shen0UaQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Animals</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">South Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Africa</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:03:02 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/hunt-south-african-black-mamba</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T17:03:02Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406018149</dc:identifier><media:keywords>South Africa, Animals, Africa, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885103881/Black-mamba-snake-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Joe Mcdonald/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>The runaway black mamba is believed to hiding in a nearby roof where it may be preparing to hibernate. The species is speedy and highly venomous. Photograph: Joe Mcdonald/Corbis</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363885110206/Black-mamba-snake-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Joe Mcdonald/Corbis</media:credit><media:description>The runaway black mamba snake is thought to hiding in a nearby roof where it may try to hibernate. The species is speedy and highly venomous. Photograph: Corbis</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/hunt-south-african-black-mamba</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Help to Buy questions linger as government dithers over second homes</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/_gq_HQRnpcw/help-to-buy-questions-homes</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/9684?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ahelp-to-buy-questions-homes%3A1883887&amp;ch=Money&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Help+to+Buy+scheme%2CProperty+%28Money+-+UK+consumer%29%2CFirst-time+buyers%2CMortgages+%28Money+-+UK+consumer%29%2CMoney%2CBudget+2013%2CBudget%2CUK+news%2CHousing+market+%28Business%29%2CReal+estate+industry+%28Business+sector%29%2CBusiness%2CPolitics%2CGeorge+Osborne&amp;c5=Personal+Finance%2CUnclassified%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CProperty+Mortgages+and+Interest+Rates%2CBudget&amp;c6=Juliette+Jowit&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+04%3A56&amp;c8=1883887&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Help+to+Buy+questions+linger+as+government+dithers+over+second+homes&amp;c66=Money&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FMoney%2FMoney%2FHelp+to+Buy+scheme" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Confusion as ministers fail to clarify if scheme to help first-time buyers could be exploited by those wanting more properties&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministers have been forced to try to reassure critics that their flagship scheme to help people pay their mortgages will not be used by people wanting to buy second homes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In what has become the &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/2013/mar/21/help-to-buy-scheme-exploited-second-homeowners" title=""&gt;most controversial post-budget story&lt;/a&gt;, confusion surrounded the details of the Help to Buy scheme, which was one of the biggest announcement's in the chancellor's speech on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the proposals, people buying new homes up to a value of £600,000 can get an interest-free loan for five years for 20% of the value in return for the government taking a stake in the equity, and homebuyers wanting to buy other properties will be able to take out higher value mortgages under a separate scheme under which the exchequer will help guarantee the risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However critics immediately seized on the initiative, claiming buyers could use it to purchase second homes – while at the same time, the government is gearing up to force people living in social housing to forfeit some housing benefit if they are judged to have more rooms than necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ed Balls, the shadow chancellor, said: "From what I can see, the government is basically saying that if you've got a spare room in a social home you will be paying a bedroom tax. But if you want a spare home and you can afford it, we'll help you buy one."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government's confusion over how to react began when George Osborne gave his traditional post-budget interview on BBC Radio 4's Today programme on Thursday. The chancellor said he said he did not want the mortgage guarantee scheme to help people buy second homes, but he refused to say people buying second homes would be banned from using it. "The mortgage market is an extremely complex thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The intention of the scheme is absolutely clear, which is that it is for people who want to get their first home or have a home and want to move to a bigger home, because perhaps they have got a bigger family. We are working with the industry to get a scheme that works."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, the prime minister's official spokesman also appeared not to be able to promise that such abuses could be ruled out, saying only that was not the intention and there was a consultation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The line hardened when Vince Cable, the business secretary, told MPs the equity loan scheme for new homes could not be used for second homes, and suggested a consultation on details of the mortgage guarantee initiative - the other half of the Help to Buy announcement – would look for a way to also stop people doing that. "I am quite sure these imagined horrors are not going to materialise," he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strongest denial came at lunchtime from Mark Prisk, the housing minister. "We do have the details in there about making sure there's a legal declaration through a solicitor before someone could take on a purchase, that they've got rid of their existing property and so on," Prisk told Radio 4's World at One programme. "This is about family homes, not about second homes."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was also criticism that the scheme could push up what many believe are already overvalued house prices – one of the key reasons given for banks demanding the high deposits of 20-30% which the chancellor said he wanted to help home buyers to afford.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The normally loyal Conservative backbencher Kwasi Kwarteng said while he generally welcomed the budget: "My worry is that having a system where you are giving mortgages without increasing the supply will lead to asset price inflation, because obviously if the amount of supply remains the same and you are making credit easier, the tendency would be for the prices to go up."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prisk dismissed this also, insisting that the budget also contained measures to encourage more housebuilding, including plans for 150,000 affordable homes and an increase in funds for developers building properties to rent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/help-to-buy-scheme"&gt;Help to Buy scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/property"&gt;Property&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/firsttimebuyers"&gt;First-time buyers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/mortgages"&gt;Mortgages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/budget-2013"&gt;Budget 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/budget"&gt;Budget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/housingmarket"&gt;Housing market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/realestate"&gt;Real estate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/georgeosborne"&gt;George Osborne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/juliettejowit"&gt;Juliette Jowit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d660e7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393903758/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d660e7/kg/355/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393903758/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d660e7/kg/355/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393903758/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d660e7/kg/355/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/_gq_HQRnpcw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">George Osborne</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money">Mortgages</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money">Property</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Budget</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Housing market</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Real estate</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Budget 2013</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money">Money</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money">Help to Buy scheme</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Politics</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/money">First-time buyers</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:56:32 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/2013/mar/21/help-to-buy-questions-homes</guid><dc:creator>Juliette Jowit</dc:creator><dc:subject>Money</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T16:56:32Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406017734</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Help to Buy scheme, Property, First-time buyers, Mortgages, Money, Budget 2013, Budget, UK news, Housing market, Real estate, Business, Politics, George Osborne</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/21/1363884943270/Critics-claim-the-Help-to-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Critics claim the Help to Buy scheme could be used by wealthy buyers looking for second properties. Photograph: Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/21/1363884951191/Critics-claim-the-Help-to-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Critics claim the Help to Buy scheme could be used by wealthy buyers looking for second properties. Photograph: Facundo Arrizabalaga/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/money/2013/mar/21/help-to-buy-questions-homes</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Police investigate publications found in Abu Qatada's home</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/OSa4Zivb0FQ/abu-qatada-police-investigate-publications</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/67973?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aabu-qatada-police-investigate-publications%3A1883706&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=Abu+Qatada+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CTheresa+May%2CPolitics%2CTerrorism+-+UK%2CUK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Sandra+Laville&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+02%3A41&amp;c8=1883706&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Police+investigate+publications+found+in+Abu+Qatada%27s+home&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FAbu+Qatada" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Anti-terror police examine whether radical cleric - whom home secretary wants deported ‑ is trying to spread extremism&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anti-terrorist police are carrying out a new investigation into the radical cleric Abu Qatada after uncovering evidence that may show he could be spreading extremism across the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detectives from the counter terrorism command of the Metropolitan police have seized a vast amount of material – including internet and traditional publications – from Qatada's home in north London, it was revealed on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deputy assistant commissioner Stuart Osborne – who is senior national coordinator for counter terrorism in the UK — said officers were going through the material, which was in several languages. He said it included many different publications and was a large mass of material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investigation is examining whether it crosses the criminal threshold to enable a prosecution to be brought against Qatada in Britain for the first time since he was detained in the UK 10years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Osborne said: "These publications may or may not be attributed to him. There are a range of sources. There is an awful lot of media that needs to be looked through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"These include publications on the internet which obviously would go across the whole world. We are investigating where these are sourced from, they are in a range of different languages and probably being translated from one language to another."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investigation will examine whether Qatada was the author of the material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qatada – who in 1999 was convicted in his absence of terrorism charges in Jordan – has fought attempts to deport him for 10 years since he was first detained. Once described by a Spanish judge as Osama bin Laden's right hand man in Europe, he was recently labelled still "truly dangerous," by the home secretary, Theresa May, and the British courts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May came closest to deporting him last year but three judges from the special immigration appeals commission (Siac) ruled he could not lawfully be deported to Jordan and he was released from Long Lartin jail to his home in north London with strict bail conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the conditions he is not permitted to publish or permit to be published any document or statement without the prior approval of the home secretary and cannot make any statements that he has reason to believe are likely to be published. He is under a 16-hour curfew and banned from using any mobile communication device, a landline phone or the internet. He also had to wear an electronic tag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qatada was arrested this month after police carried out raids at his home, another house and a business as part of a continuing investigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officers say they discovered several mobile phones and the publications. Qatada was arrested by the UK border agency for allegedly breaching his Siac bail conditions. He remains in custody. His arrest came shortly before the Home Secretary was due to make a fresh attempt to deport him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Details of the material seized from his home were revealed by police on Thursday — the same day a Siac bail hearing was due to be held which was expected to give details of the alleged breaches. The hearing was adjourned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May attempted to break the deadlock over Qatada last year by personally securing reassurances from the Jordanian authorities that he would not face trial based on evidence obtained by torture. Her attempts were thwarted when SIAC said that despite those assurances a real risk remained that he would face a trial based on such evidence. They said changes needed to be made to the Jordanian criminal code before they could be satisfied that the risk no longer existed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May took the case to the Court of Appeal and a judgement is awaited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abu Qatada, whose real name is Mohammed Othman, has waged a decade long battle against his deportation. He came to the UK seeking asylum more than 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the statements made against him he has never been prosecuted or charged with offences in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has been accused in Siac hearings of not only providing a "religious justification for acts of violence and terror", but also of being a "significant international terrorist, with extensive extremist contacts", engaging "in conduct which facilitates and give[s] encouragement to the commission, preparation and instigation of acts of terrorism", and "raising funds for terrorist groups".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MI5 has said in evidence to Siac that it has been difficult to prosecute Abu Qatada as he has been careful to disguise his support for terrorist attacks here and abroad, and that he is not "formally" a member of al-Qaida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/abu-qatada"&gt;Abu Qatada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics/theresamay"&gt;Theresa May&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/uksecurity"&gt;UK security and terrorism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/sandralaville"&gt;Sandra Laville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d4fc77/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393903106/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d4fc77/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393903106/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d4fc77/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393903106/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d4fc77/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/OSa4Zivb0FQ" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Abu Qatada</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Global terrorism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Terrorism policy</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK security and terrorism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/politics">Theresa May</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:55:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/abu-qatada-police-investigate-publications</guid><dc:creator>Sandra Laville</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T16:55:32Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406001300</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Abu Qatada, World news, Theresa May, Politics, UK security and terrorism, UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363875111258/Abu-Qatada-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Stefan Rousseau/PA</media:credit><media:description>Abu Qatada’s strict bail conditions imposed restrictions on his contact with the outside world. Photograph: Stefan Rousseau/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363875118302/Abu-Qatada-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Stefan Rousseau/PA</media:credit><media:description>Abu Qatada’s strict bail conditions imposed restrictions on his contact with the outside world. Photograph: Stefan Rousseau/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/abu-qatada-police-investigate-publications</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Justin Welby enthroned as archbishop of Canterbury</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/5c4hvXRZHcA/archbishop-canterbury-enthroned-by-woman</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/35223?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aarchbishop-canterbury-enthroned-by-woman%3A1883590&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Justin+Welby%2CAnglicanism+-+Church+of+England+%28News%29%2CChristianity+%28News%29%2CReligion+%28News%29%2CUK+news%2COrdination+of+women&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Sam+Jones&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+11%3A57&amp;c8=1883590&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Justin+Welby+enthroned+as+archbishop+of+Canterbury&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2FJustin+Welby" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Role of the Venerable Sheila Watson, archdeacon of Canterbury, in ceremony puts issue of female bishops back in spotlight&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 3pm amid African dancers and to the strains of Punjabi music, &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/theobserver/2013/jan/27/observer-profile-justin-welby-archbishop-canterbury" title=""&gt;Justin Portal Welby&lt;/a&gt; was formally enthroned as the 105th archbishop of Canterbury and leader of the world's 77 million Anglicans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Prince of Wales and the Duchess of Cornwall as well as the prime minister, David Cameron, were among about 2,000 people attending the ceremony at Canterbury cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The service drew on hundreds of years of ecclesiastical tradition, but the proceedings differed in one key respect: for the first time in the Church of England's history, its head was enthroned by a woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Venerable Sheila Watson, archdeacon of Canterbury, took a central role in the ceremony, which marks the beginning of Welby's public ministry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cleric, who was made the first female archdeacon of Canterbury in 2007, installed the archbishop on the diocesan throne in the cathedral, a historic moment symbolising his appointment as bishop of Canterbury – the first of three roles held by the Archbishop of Canterbury.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welby was then installed by the dean of Canterbury, the Very Rev Robert Willis, on the marble chair of St Augustine in the cathedral, marking his appointment as head of the Church of England and also representing his inauguration as spiritual leader of the global Anglican communion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Watson's role in the ceremony will inevitably put the issue of female bishops in the spotlight once again. Four months ago the General Synod voted against legislation to introduce female bishops. Like his predecessor, Rowan Williams, Welby voted in favour of their introduction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another female member of the Anglican communion, Evangeline Kanagasooriam, played an important part in the ceremony when she asked the archbishop formal questions about his role after he struck the west door of the cathedral three times with his staff at the start of the service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The African aspect of the ceremony was a nod to Welby's links with the continent in both his &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/justin-welby-spook-speculation" title=""&gt;previous career as an oil executive&lt;/a&gt; and as a conflict negotiator during his time at Coventry cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The archbishop of Burundi in central Africa, the Most Rev Bernard Ntahoturi, pronounced a blessing in French on the archbishop and African dancers performed before the gospel was read at the service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other personal touches included Welby's choice of robes for the service. He wore colourful vestments originally designed and made for the late bishop of Peterborough, the Most Rev Ian Cundy, who was his tutor at Cranmer Hall, Durham, where he trained in preparation for ordination between 1989 and 1992 after leaving the oil industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The archbishop was asked to make the declaration of assent outlining his loyalty to the Church of England by the archbishop of York, Dr John Sentamu. He was then asked by Willis to swear an oath of faithfulness on the Canterbury gospels, brought to Britain by St Augustine in 597.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The service featured a newly commissioned anthem using the opening words of the Rule of St Benedict set to music by the composer Michael Berkeley. The ceremony coincided with the feast day of St Benedict of Monte Cassino, a significant figure for both Canterbury cathedral, which was a Benedictine monastery 1,000 years ago, and Welby, who is an oblate of the Order of Benedict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the pomp and splendour concluded, the archbishop began the job of presiding over a communion that is greatly divided over the issue of female bishops and same-sex marriage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an interview with Channel 5 News that will have delighted proponents of women in the highest echelons of the church, the archbishop said he believed there would be a female archbishop one day, in spite of the Synod vote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pressed on the timing, he said: "Oh, I have no idea … when the right person turns up. But, yes, I think there certainly will."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday Welby &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/archbishop-canterbury-admits-gay-challenge" title=""&gt;addressed the question of same-sex marriage&lt;/a&gt;, saying that some gay couples had loving and monogamous relationships of "stunning quality".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said he backed the church's traditional view of marriage as the union of one man and one woman, but he had witnessed the strength and profundity of same-sex love in the relationships of some of his friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"You see gay relationships that are just stunning in the quality of the relationship," he &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-21860447" title=""&gt;told the BBC&lt;/a&gt;, adding that he had "particular friends where I recognise that and am deeply challenged by it".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It emerged that Welby sent a letter on Wednesday night to the human rights campaigner Peter Tatchell, offering to meet him face to face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The invitation was in response to an open letter in which Tatchell accused Welby of being homophobic by opposing gay marriage and said some local Anglicans had colluded in persecution of gay people in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In his response, the Times reported, Welby thanked Tatchell for his "very thoughtful" letter and said the points he had made were "powerful".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/justin-welby"&gt;Justin Welby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/anglicanism"&gt;Anglicanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/christianity"&gt;Christianity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/religion"&gt;Religion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/ordination-of-women"&gt;Ordination of women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/samjones"&gt;Sam Jones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d31cb4/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393850111/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d31cb4/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/161393850111/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d31cb4/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/161393850111/u/49/f/639023/c/34708/s/29d31cb4/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/5c4hvXRZHcA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Anglicanism</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Ordination of women</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">Justin Welby</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Christianity</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Religion</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/archbishop-canterbury-enthroned-by-woman</guid><dc:creator>Sam Jones</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T16:39:04Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>405989087</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Justin Welby, Anglicanism, Christianity, Religion, UK news, Ordination of women</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363866982838/Justin-Welby-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:credit><media:description>Justin Welby has said he believes there will be a female archbishop one day. Photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363866988444/Justin-Welby-008.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:credit><media:description>Justin Welby has said he believes there will be a female archbishop one day. Photograph: Dominic Lipinski/PA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/archbishop-canterbury-enthroned-by-woman</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>North Korea threatens to attack US military bases in Pacific if provoked</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/WKIBhmInMQU/north-korea-threatens-attack-us</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/84532?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Anorth-korea-threatens-attack-us%3A1883847&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=North+Korea+%28News%29%2CSouth+Korea+%28News%29%2CUS+military+%28News%29%2CAsia+Pacific+%28News%29%2CUS+news%2CWorld+news&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CMotorsport&amp;c6=Reuters+in+Seoul&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+04%3A32&amp;c8=1883847&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=North+Korea+threatens+to+attack+US+military+bases+in+Pacific+if+provoked&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FNorth+Korea" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Kim Jong-un oversees mock drone strike as North Korea threatens military bases in Japan and on Guam&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;North Korea &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/video/2013/mar/21/north-korea-us-bases-japan-video" title=""&gt;has said it will attack US military bases&lt;/a&gt; on Japan and the Pacific island of Guam if provoked, a day after its leader, Kim Jong-un, oversaw a mock drone strike on South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The North also held an air raid drill on Thursday after accusing the United States of preparing a military strike using bombers that have overflown the Korean peninsula as part of drills between South Korean and US forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;North Korea has stepped up its rhetoric in response to what it calls "hostile" drills between South Korea and the United States. It has also been angered by the imposition of fresh UN sanctions that followed its nuclear test on 12 February.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Separately, South Korea said a hacking attack on the servers of local broadcasters and banks on Wednesday &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/south-korea-cyber-attack-chinese" title=""&gt;originated from an IP address in China&lt;/a&gt;, raising suspicions that the intrusion came from North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The United States is advised not to forget that our precision target tools have within their range the Anderson air force base on Guam where the B-52 takes off, as well as the Japanese mainland where nuclear powered submarines are deployed and the navy bases on Okinawa," the North's supreme military command spokesman was quoted as saying by the KCNA news agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Japan and US Pacific bases are in range of Pyongyang's medium-range missiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is not known if North Korea possesses drones, although a report on South Korea's Yonhap news agency last year said it had obtained 1970s-era US target drones from Syria to develop into attack drones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The [drone] planes were assigned the flight route and time with the targets in South Korea in mind, Kim Jong-un said, adding with great satisfaction that they were proved to be able to mount [a] super-precision attack on any enemy targets," KCNA reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is extremely rare for KCNA to specify the day on which Kim attended a drill. It also said a rocket defence unit had successfully shot down a target that mimicked an "enemy" Tomahawk cruise missile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;North Korea has said it has abrogated an armistice that ended the 1950-53 Korean war and threatened a nuclear attack on the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although North Korea lacks the technology to carry out such an attack, Washington said it would deploy more anti-missile batteries in Alaska to counter any threat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hacking attack brought down the servers of the South Korean broadcasters YTN, MBC and KBS as well as two major commercial banks, Shinhan Bank and NongHyup Bank. South Korean communications regulators said the attack originated from an IP address based in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An unnamed official from South Korea's presidential office was quoted by the Yonhap news agency as saying the discovery of the Chinese IP address indicated Pyongyang was responsible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Investigations of past hacking incidents on South Korean organisations have been traced to Pyongyang's large army of computer engineers trained to infiltrate the South's computer networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least one previous attack was traced to a Chinese IP address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;South Korea's defence ministry said it was too early to blame the North but said such a cyber capability was a key part of its arsenal. Experts say thousands of North Korean engineers may have been recruited for the purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Throughout the world, states that create cyberwarfare and engage in those types of activities are precisely the same countries that develop nuclear weapons," the defence ministry spokesman Kim Min-seok said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"North Korea has strongly stepped up development of asymmetrical strategy with nuclear development and many types of ballistic missiles as well as special forces 200,000 strong."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/north-korea"&gt;North Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/south-korea"&gt;South Korea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/us-military"&gt;US military&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/asia-pacific"&gt;Asia Pacific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d6738c/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/WKIBhmInMQU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Asia Pacific</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">South Korea</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">US military</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">North Korea</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:32:33 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/north-korea-threatens-attack-us</guid><dc:creator /><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T20:13:28Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406014563</dc:identifier><media:keywords>North Korea, South Korea, US military, Asia Pacific, United States, World news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363882976807/Kim-Jong-un-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">KCNA/EPA</media:credit><media:description>Kim Jong-un inspects a missile-firing drill in North Korea on Wednesday. Photograph: KCNA/EPA</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/north-korea-threatens-attack-us</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Shell accused of benefiting from South African apartheid-era land law</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/2gf0jElHTuc/shell-south-africa-apartheid-land</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/34421?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Ashell-south-africa-apartheid-land%3A1882706&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=Guardian&amp;c4=South+Africa+%28News%29%2CShell+%28business%29%2COil+%28business%29%2COil+and+gas+companies+%28Business%29%2CBusiness%2CAfrica+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CLand+rights+%28environment%29%2CGlobal+development%2CEnvironment&amp;c5=Environment+Conservation%2CUnclassified%2CCredit+Crunch%2CBusiness+Markets%2CNot+commercially+useful%2CEthical+Living&amp;c6=David+Smith+%28Africa+correspondent%29&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+04%3A21&amp;c8=1882706&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Shell+accused+of+benefiting+from+South+African+apartheid-era+land+law&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FSouth+Africa" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Campaigners say oil company is paying just 192 rand (£13.75) annual rent for two filling stations in impoverished KwaZulu-Natal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remote and unspoiled, &lt;a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionskzn/umgababa.php" title=""&gt;Umgababa&lt;/a&gt; is a small but aspirational South African beach resort washed by the warm Indian ocean. Tourists who veer off the beaten track to get there might feel somewhat isolated, but for the reassuring presence of two Shell service stations along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The oil giant is not so welcome, however, to a community where land ownership remains a highly inflammatory subject. Shell stands accused of paying rent of just 192 rand (£13.75) a year for each of the two stations – barely enough to buy enough petrol for a 100km journey. The company strongly denies the claim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dispute comes against the backdrop of widespread poverty in KwaZulu-Natal province and the imminent centenary of the &lt;a href="http://www.ruraldevelopment.gov.za/1913-land-act-centenary" title=""&gt;1913 Natives' Land Act,&lt;/a&gt; which resulted in the systematic dispossession of black South Africans. Even under democracy, millions of hectares of state-owned land have still not been transferred to those who live on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Shell anomaly is being investigated by South Africa's parliamentary oversight committee on rural development and land reform. Stone Sizani, its chairman, said: "It's a huge unfairness on the part of Shell to the community there. They're making huge sums of money from those filling stations and what they're paying is the equivalent of an indigent family for a piece of land."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added: "Nobody can explain how Shell got such a piece of land. Even if it was done during apartheid, Shell should be feeling ashamed."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shell obtained permission to occupy (PTO) during the apartheid era, when black people were not permitted to obtain title deeds to land. A PTO holder once paid a token rent to the government; now it pays it to the Ingonyama Trust Board, which administers about 2.8m hectares of land in KwaZulu-Natal. The board says the agreement legally cannot be changed, despite the stations' profitability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shell denies the 192-rand claim, saying that when it signed a 50-year contract with a body called the Ithala Development Finance Corporation, it was required to pay a significant sum upfront. "Shell paid total costs of approximately 29m rand [£2m] by 2000," spokeswoman Jackie Maitland said on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Umnini tribal land is now administered by the Ingonyama Trust, who are deemed to be the landlord of these sites. The PTO remains held by Ithala, who Shell signed the lease agreement with in 1988. All rentals have been paid in full for the duration of the 50-year lease."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She added: "We are aware that nominal amounts can be paid on an annual basis by individuals to local chiefs for permission to occupy land. This process does not apply to Shell, as we entered a prepaid rental agreement with Ithala."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Informed of Shell's response, Sizani stuck to his guns, saying he had asked the Ingonyama Trust board to check its records and "the outcome is still the same". His message to Shell was: "Are you aware that, in South Africa, old age pensioners get 1,000-plus rand per month individually? What can 192 rand per year for the whole community do?"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The way the land was assigned also highlights a tension between longstanding traditions in rural areas, where a local chief still wields power, and the letter of the law in a 21st century constitutional democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.da.org.za/our_people.htm?action=view-page&amp;category=provincial-leaders&amp;person=699" title=""&gt;Athol Trollip&lt;/a&gt;, shadow minister of rural development and land reform, who has visited one of the stations, said: "The problem with these Shell filling stations is that this land would have been granted through a traditional leader."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He added: "It is a crazy situation because they have this arbitrariness in the way they allocate land. There's no lease held, there's no formal transfer of ownership."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The South African government recently claimed it has completed an audit of state-owned land, but Trollip and others are sceptical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Johan Kruger, director of the &lt;a href="http://ccrjustice.org" title=""&gt;Centre for Constitutional Rights,&lt;/a&gt; said: "One of the biggest concerns is that we just don't know what's out there. We don't know how much the government owns and how much has been redistributed or on a long lease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It is a responsibility the government has not fulfilled yet. There is a huge amount of land in government hands that could be transferred to black ownership."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An annual rental fee of 192 rand "can't be right", he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/southafrica"&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/royaldutchshell"&gt;Royal Dutch Shell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/oil"&gt;Oil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/oilandgascompanies"&gt;Oil and gas companies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/africa"&gt;Africa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/land-rights"&gt;Land rights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/davidsmith"&gt;David Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d6738d/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/2gf0jElHTuc" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Land rights</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Oil and gas companies</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Royal Dutch Shell</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Oil</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">South Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment">Environment</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Africa</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business">Business</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:21:41 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/shell-south-africa-apartheid-land</guid><dc:creator>David Smith</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T17:51:49Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>405874250</dc:identifier><media:keywords>South Africa, Royal Dutch Shell, Oil, Oil and gas companies, Business, Africa, World news, Land rights, Global development, Environment</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/19/1363720609457/Shell-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Toby Melville/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Shell denies the 48 rand claim, saying it paid a substantial sum upfront when it signed a 50-year contract for the sites Photograph: Toby Melville/Reuters</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/About/General/2013/3/19/1363720615203/Shell-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">Toby Melville/Reuters</media:credit><media:description>Shell says it paid a substantial sum upfront when it signed a 50-year contract for the sites. Photograph: Toby Melville/Reuters</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/shell-south-africa-apartheid-land</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Hot yoga's Bikram Choudhury accused of sexual harassment by protege</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/o3uhFsJQcHM/bikram-choudhury-hot-yoga-sexual-harassment</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/6940?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Abikram-choudhury-hot-yoga-sexual-harassment%3A1883814&amp;ch=Life+and+style&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Yoga%2CUS+news%2CLife+and+style&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful%2CHealth&amp;c6=Dominic+Rushe&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+04%3A18&amp;c8=1883814&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Hot+yoga%27s+Bikram+Choudhury+accused+of+sexual+harassment+by+protege&amp;c66=Life+and+style&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FLife+and+style%2FLife+and+style%2FYoga" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Bikram yoga founder's former student alleges the yogi prevented her from teaching because she refused his sexual advances&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The founder of "hot yoga", Bikram Choudhury, has been accused of sexual harassment and discrimination by one of his top students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 67-year-old founder of the international Bikram yoga studio is alleged to have pursued protege Sarah Baughn, 29, for years, claiming they were connected in a past life and his wife didn't understand him. Eventually his pursuit turned physical, she claims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to a suit filed in Los Angeles' superior court, Choudury denied Baughn an international championship title she had been awarded and has prevented her from teaching "because of her past and continuing refusal to have sex with her guru."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The multi-millionaire founder of the international chain claims to have taught yoga to presidents Nixon, Reagan and Clinton. Celebrities such as Madonna, David Beckham, George Clooney, Jennifer Anniston and Lady Gaga have all practiced the yoga system, which consists of 26 sequential poses and takes place in rooms heated to over 100F (37.8C).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choudhury claims to have a fleet of Rolls Royces, has compared himself to Jesus and Elvis and claims to have the biggest pool in Beverly Hills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choudhury and his wife Rajashree control the Bikram yoga empire from their home in Beverly Hills, California and &lt;a href="http://www.villagevoice.com/2012-07-18/news/the-hot-yoga-war/"&gt;have clashed in court with other yoga studios over what they claim is their patent on "hot yoga&lt;/a&gt;." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the suit, Choudhury told Baughn: "My wife is such a bitch, you have no idea." He told Baughn: "I am so lonely. I am dying. I can feel myself dying. I will not be alive if someone doesn't save me."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Baughn's suit describes how she began practising Bikram while a student studying creative writing in 2004. She said that, encouraged by her yoga teachers, she dropped out of college at age 20 to dedicate herself full time to yoga. She paid Choudhury $7,500 to attend a "gruelling" nine-week training course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Very early in training, Sarah Baughn noticed that Bikram Choudhury's relationship with young women yoga students was different," the suit says. Young women were chosen to brush the pony-tailed guru's hair and give him massages, it alleges. On the third night of training Choudhury had one of his students hand Baughn his diamond-studded Rolex watch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choudhury insisted that he had known Baughn in a past life and the connection was "so strong and meaningful that he still remembered it". The suit alleges that Baughn complained to other members of the studio and was told Bikram was "not a good man" but a "good teacher".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In one class, Baughn alleges, Bikram "pushed her down towards the floor after pulling her leg apart and opening her body". The suit alleges that he then pressed his body against her and "began whispering sexual things to her until she collapsed in sobs".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choudhury did not return a call and email for comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/yoga"&gt;Yoga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/usa"&gt;United States&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/dominic-rushe"&gt;Dominic Rushe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d66779/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/o3uhFsJQcHM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">United States</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle">Yoga</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle">Life and style</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 16:18:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2013/mar/21/bikram-choudhury-hot-yoga-sexual-harassment</guid><dc:creator>Dominic Rushe</dc:creator><dc:subject>Life and style</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T20:21:22Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406010862</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Yoga, United States, Life and style</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363881516019/Bikram-Choudhury-003.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">KPA/Zuma / Rex Features/KPA/Zuma / Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Bikram Choudhury and his wife Rajashree Choudhury pose with some of the yoga competitors 7th Annual International Yoga Asana Championships, Los Angeles, America - 12 Feb 2010 The 7th Annual International Yoga Asana Championships produced by the flamboyant yoga entrepreneur Bikram Choudhury Photograph: KPA/Zuma / Rex Features</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363881518158/Bikram-Choudhury-004.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">KPA/Zuma / Rex Features/KPA/Zuma / Rex Features</media:credit><media:description>Bikram Choudhury and his wife Rajashree pose with yoga competitors at 2010's International Yoga Asana Championships. Photograph: KPA/Zuma / Rex Features</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2013/mar/21/bikram-choudhury-hot-yoga-sexual-harassment</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Artist Graham Ovenden denies abusing young models</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/-vfAYUjCR08/artist-graham-ovenden-young-models</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/79344?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aartist-graham-ovenden-young-models%3A1883752&amp;ch=UK+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=UK+news&amp;c5=Not+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Steven+Morris&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+03%3A13&amp;c8=1883752&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Artist+Graham+Ovenden+denies+abusing+young+models&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FUK+news%2F" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Painter says children he photographed naked were in 'state of grace' and he was not sexually attracted to them&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A celebrated artist best known for his candid images of children, often unclothed, has denied in court that he abused any of his young models and passionately defended his right to create such paintings and photographs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graham Ovenden, 70, whose work has hung in Tate Britain and great galleries across Europe, rejected allegations that he blindfolded the girls before forcing them to take part in oral sex or explicit games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked if he found children sexually attractive, Ovenden replied: "No."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asked why he had described children as "sensual creatures" during a police interview, he said everything from a child to the bark of a tree had sensuality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ovenden, who denies offences of indecency relating to four children – now all adults – dating back several decades, told the court of his own idyllic childhood growing up in Hampshire. The poet John Betjeman was a family friend and by the age of 14 Ovenden said he was a "very serious" painter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After school he went to the Royal College of Art, where he studied under Sir Peter Blake. He told the jury his work had been exhibited in major galleries in the UK – and could still be seen on Tate Online – as well as famous museums in Paris and Vienna.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ovenden said his main interest was English landscapes. But he also took photographs and made paintings of young girls. He told the jury he had created a series based on Nabokov's character Lolita and had worked with Blake on a project around Lewis Carroll's Alice books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The artist, bespectacled and white-bearded, said he married and had two children. He and his wife Annie, also a talented artist, lived in west London until 1973 when the family moved to a 22-acre estate called Barley Splatt on the edge of Bodmin Moor in Cornwall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ovenden said the estate was a "paradise, a garden of Eden" with beech woods and a "tumbling" stream often visited by other artists, writers and musicians. Families with children stayed there and youngsters tended to discard their clothes "pretty regularly".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He told the jury he took photographs of girls, sometimes clothed, sometimes in Victorian dress and at other times semi or totally naked. Often these were studies for paintings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ovenden said the point of the nude images was to show children in a "state of grace". He claimed he had a "moral obligation" to take such images. The idea of pictures of naked children being obscene was "abhorrent", he said, and criticised what he saw as a "witch-hunt" over them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the witness box, Ovenden was asked about one photograph in which an alleged victim is posing when she was a girl – naked on a rock at Barley Splatt. Asked why he took the image, Ovenden said: "The child in its state of grace is something of wondrous beauty."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grabbing the collar of his own jacket he said clothes were a "mask", adding: "What one is is underneath. One of the great qualities of art is to go back to the point of innocence."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He explained that an image of the same alleged victim blindfolded was a reference to the Catholic practice of covering the eyes of believers about to be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Questioned about an image of a girl on a stool with her legs parted, he said it was the natural way to pose when sitting on such a piece of furniture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said photographs were "infinitely more complicated than what you are seeing".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ovenden was asked about another victim whom he had photographed clothed and naked from the age of three to around 11. He denied having once got into a bath with her and asking her to wash his penis. Had he put his thumb or penis into her mouth? "Absolutely not," he replied. Had he taken hold of her breasts? "Certainly not."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trial continues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/stevenmorris"&gt;Steven Morris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d5d4c1/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/-vfAYUjCR08" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk">UK news</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:13:15 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/artist-graham-ovenden-young-models</guid><dc:creator>Steven Morris</dc:creator><dc:subject>UK news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T15:28:16Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406006926</dc:identifier><media:keywords>UK news</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363878439324/Graham-Ovenden-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">SWNS.com/SWNS.com</media:credit><media:description>Graham Ovenden, pictured outside Truro crown court, said the idea of pictures of naked children being obscene was 'abhorrent'. Photograph: SWNS.com</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363878446939/Graham-Ovenden-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">SWNS.com/SWNS.com</media:credit><media:description>Graham Ovenden, pictured outside Truro crown court, said the idea of pictures of naked children being obscene was 'abhorrent'. Photograph: SWNS.com</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2013/mar/21/artist-graham-ovenden-young-models</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Australian prime minister Julia Gillard survives damaging leadership battle</title><link>http://feeds.guardian.co.uk/~r/theguardian/rss/~3/D-0CMSe-V64/australian-julia-gillard-survives-leadership</link><description>&lt;div class="track"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://hits.guardian.co.uk/b/ss/guardiangu-feeds/1/H.25.3/40695?ns=guardian&amp;pageName=GUK%3AArticle%3Aaustralian-julia-gillard-survives-leadership%3A1883743&amp;ch=World+news&amp;c3=GU.co.uk&amp;c4=Australia+%28News%29%2CAsia+Pacific+%28News%29%2CWorld+news%2CJulia+Gillard&amp;c5=Unclassified%2CNot+commercially+useful&amp;c6=Alison+Rourke&amp;c7=2013%2F03%2F21+02%3A53&amp;c8=1883743&amp;c9=Article&amp;c10=News&amp;c13=&amp;c19=GUK&amp;c47=UK&amp;c65=Australian+prime+minister+Julia+Gillard+survives+damaging+leadership+battle&amp;c66=News&amp;c72=&amp;c73=&amp;c74=&amp;c75=&amp;h2=GU%2FNews%2FWorld+news%2FAustralia" width="1" height="1" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class="standfirst"&gt;Labor leader is forced by senior members of government to throw job open to contest but is re-elected unopposed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian prime minister, Julia Gillard, survived a damaging leadership battle on Thursday to retain the reins of a divided Labor party heading towards almost certain defeat in elections in September.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drama began when one of the most senior members of her government called for Gillard to be replaced by Kevin Rudd, the man she controversially ousted from the job three years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Less than an hour later, Gillard declared her leadership of the party, and in effect her job as prime minister, vacant – inviting rivals to nominate themselves for the role. But, when the ballot took place two and a half hours later, Rudd refused to put himself forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the second time Gillard's leadership has been challenged in just over a year. She defeated Rudd by 71 votes to 31 in a divisive party leadership ballot last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The challenge followed two opinion polls that suggested Labor would lose heavily in September if Gillard remained prime minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The party's share of the vote is down to 31%, compared with 47% for the conservative Liberal/National coalition opposition. This comes after a chaotic week in which Gillard's standing was further damaged when her government failed to force through a controversial media bill that would have introduced a statutory regulator for newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning Simon Crean, a former Labor party leader, called on both figures to "break the deadlock" in the "interest of the Labor party and the nation". He urged Gillard to call for a vote and for Rudd, whom he said he would back, to contest it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gillard responded by announcing a "spill" – declaring her position open. Few could have predicted what followed next.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just minutes before the leadership contest, Rudd declared he would not stand, and Gillard was re-elected unanimously and unopposed, prompting questions about what the damaging party spat had been all about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rudd said the only circumstances in which he would consider a return to the leadership were "if there was an overwhelming majority of the parliamentary party requesting such a return – drafting me to return – and the position was vacant. I am here to inform you that those circumstances do not exist".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analysts speculated that Rudd simply did not have the numbers to win Thursday's ballot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leadership speculation has come to symbolise the Labor party's woes in the first national hung parliament in 80 years. Throughout her term in office, Gillard has had to rely on the support of independents, and, until recently, the Green party, to stay in power. The conservative opposition has repeatedly cast her as untrustworthy because of the way she toppled Rudd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But after Thursday's drama, Gillard declared the leadership question over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Today the leadership of our political party, the Labor party, has been settled, and settled in the most conclusive fashion possible. The whole business is completely at an end. It has ended now," she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day of intense political theatre was a gift to the opposition leader, Tony Abbott, who was the target of Gillard's now famous sexism and misogyny speech last October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The civil war [in the Labor party] will continue as long as Kevin Rudd and Julia Gillard are in parliament. The only way to give our country the good government that we so badly need right now is to have an election," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Thursday night, at least two Rudd backers had resigned their party posts to go to the backbenches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crean, a veteran of Labor politics, said he was surprised that Kevin Rudd did not stand but had no regrets about his role in the party's airing of its dirty linen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said Rudd "should have run", adding: "I think that itself would have been an important cleansing for the party."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="related" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/australia"&gt;Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/asia-pacific"&gt;Asia Pacific&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/julia-gillard"&gt;Julia Gillard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="author"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/profile/alison-rourke"&gt;Alison Rourke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;div class="terms"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk"&gt;guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; &amp;copy; 2013 Guardian News and Media Limited or its affiliated companies. All rights reserved. | Use of this content is subject to our &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/terms-of-service"&gt;Terms &amp; Conditions&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/help/feeds"&gt;More Feeds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="clear:both" /&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://guardian.co.uk.feedsportal.com/c/34708/f/639023/s/29d56a99/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/theguardian/rss/~4/D-0CMSe-V64" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Asia Pacific</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">World news</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/tone">News</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/publication">guardian.co.uk</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Julia Gillard</category><category domain="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world">Australia</category><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:53:11 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/australian-julia-gillard-survives-leadership</guid><dc:creator>Alison Rourke</dc:creator><dc:subject>World news</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-03-21T15:31:10Z</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>406005440</dc:identifier><media:keywords>Australia, Asia Pacific, World news, Julia Gillard</media:keywords><media:content height="84" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="140" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363877388262/-Julia-Gillard-005.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Julia Gillard, who emerged victorious from a party vote after former leader Kevin Rudd made a last-minute decision not to run. Photograph: AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><media:content height="276" lang="" type="image/jpeg" width="460" url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2013/3/21/1363877394401/-Julia-Gillard-010.jpg"><media:credit scheme="urn:ebu">AFP/Getty Images</media:credit><media:description>Julia Gillard, who emerged victorious from a party vote after former leader Kevin Rudd made a last-minute decision not to run. Photograph: AFP/Getty Images</media:description></media:content><feedburner:origLink>http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/mar/21/australian-julia-gillard-survives-leadership</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
