<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'
      xmlns:thr='http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0'
      xml:base='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/ongoing.atom'
      xml:lang='en-us'>
 <title>ongoing by Tim Bray</title>
 <link rel='hub' href='http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/</id>
 <link href='./' />
 <link rel='self' href='' />
 <link rel='replies'       thr:count='101'       href='/home/tbray.org/www/html/ongoing/comments.atom' />
 <logo>rsslogo.jpg</logo>
 <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
 <updated>2013-04-14T18:22:02-07:00</updated>
 <author><name>Tim Bray</name></author>
 <subtitle>ongoing fragmented essay by Tim Bray</subtitle>
 <rights>All content written by Tim Bray and photos by Tim Bray Copyright Tim Bray, some rights reserved, see /ongoing/misc/Copyright</rights>
 <generator uri='/misc/Colophon'>Generated from XML source code using Perl, Expat, Emacs, Mysql, Ruby, Java, and ImageMagick.  Industrial-strength technology, baby.</generator>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/14/'>
 <title>HP4 &#x2014; Botanicals</title>
 <link href='Hawaii-Botanicals' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='2'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Hawaii-Botanicals#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/14/Hawaii-Botanicals</id>
 <published>2013-04-14T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-14T08:48:46-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Hawaii' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Hawaii' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Botanical gardens are A Good Thing. If you haven&#x2019;t been to any, you should rectify that soonest. If you get to Hawaii&#x2019;s Big Island, you should definitely drive north from Hilo and visit the <a href='http://www.htbg.com/'>Hawaii Tropical Botanical Garden</a>. In this entry, the <b>H</b>awaii-<b>P</b>roblem you-gotta-see-these-pix monotony is relieved by sex.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Botanical gardens are A Good Thing. If you haven’t been to any,
you should rectify that soonest. If you get to Hawaii’s Big Island, you should
definitely drive north from Hilo and visit the
<a href="http://www.htbg.com/">Hawaii Tropical Botanical Garden</a>.
In this entry, the <b>H</b>awaii-<b>P</b>roblem you-gotta-see-these-pix monotony
is relieved by sex.</p>
<p>Even if you’re not a botanical-garden sort of person, you might want to
take Route 19 north from Hilo anyhow, because it’s beautiful, lush, country.
Along the way, it’s worth stopping at Alae cemetery, which has one of the most
remarkable trees anywhere.  Then you turn off on Old Mamalahoa Highway, and
the scenery suddenly gets even more intense.</p>
<p>The botanical garden, a non-profit, isn’t cheap to get into, but I think
it’s good value. Take along a picnic and have it at the tables down by the
beach.</p>
<p>I’m not sufficiently botanically erudite to know what most of them are, and
didn’t bother to record the info off the helpful little signs.</p>
<img src="DSCF3092.png" alt="Big apricot-colored palm frond" />
<img src="DSCF3100.png" alt="Ferns" />
<p>I promised you some sex.  See what I mean?</p>
<img src="DSCF3111.png" alt="Wet pink orchid" />
<p>Yes, they really were these colors.  Credit for this one to my son, who
said “Dad, you <em>gotta</em> take a picture of that.”</p>
<img src="DSCF3114.png" alt="Lurid orchid blossoms and berries" />
<p>Leaves behind leaves behind leaves, and plenty of sun to light things up
even under all of them.  That’s the windward side of the Big Island.</p>
<img src="DSCF3117.png" alt="Shadows on palm leaves" />
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/13/'>
 <title>HP3 &#x2014; More Hot Lava!</title>
 <link href='More-Hot-Lava' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='More-Hot-Lava#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/13/More-Hot-Lava</id>
 <published>2013-04-13T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-13T10:16:34-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Hawaii' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Hawaii' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I wrote about <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth'>hiking across hard lava to poke a stick into hot lava</a>, and the pictures were groovy, but I had more than I could squeeze in there, so here are the rest that are worthwhile. Those who don&#x2019;t sympathize with my <b>H</b>awaii <b>P</b>roblem (the urge to force recent-vacation pictures down the world&#x2019;s throat) will be happy to hear that there are only a couple more instalments after today.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I wrote about
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth">hiking
across hard lava to poke a stick into hot lava</a>, and the pictures were
groovy, but I had more than I could squeeze in there, so here are the rest
that are worthwhile.
Those who don’t sympathize with my <b>H</b>awaii <b>P</b>roblem (the
urge to force recent-vacation pictures down the world’s throat) will be happy
to hear that there are only a couple more instalments after today.</p>
<p>Here are the pictures.  I really have nothing to add to what I
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth">wrote
before</a>.  Well, once again: Go see this if you get a chance.</p>
<img src="DSCF2938.png" alt="Hot 2013 lava near Kalapana, Big Island" />
<img src="DSCF2944.png" alt="Hot 2013 lava near Kalapana, Big Island" />
<img src="DSCF2956.png" alt="Hot 2013 lava near Kalapana, Big Island" />
<img src="DSCF2957.png" alt="Hot 2013 lava near Kalapana, Big Island" />
<p>This last picture is blurry and less dramatic, but gives a human-scale feel
for the size and shape of a reasonably-typical live lava flow.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/12/'>
 <title>HP2 &#x2014; The Last Palms</title>
 <link href='The-Last-Palms' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='The-Last-Palms#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/12/The-Last-Palms</id>
 <published>2013-04-12T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-12T12:49:36-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Hawaii' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Hawaii' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The <b>H</b>awaii <b>P</b>roblem is when you come back from there with an irresistible urge to show off your pictures.  Today, some lonely palm trees.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The <b>H</b>awaii <b>P</b>roblem is when you come back from there with an
irresistible urge to show off your pictures.  Today, some lonely palm
trees.</p>
<p>Highway 130 heads south and west across the bottom right corner of the Big
Island, then along the south coast. Chain of Craters Road heads down from
Volcano National Park to the south coast and eventually meets 130.
Except for starting in 1986, the lava flowed down the mountain and
<a href="http://www.hawaiihighways.com/photos-Lava-Closures.htm">broke the
link</a>.</p>
<p>The eastern end of the breakage is where you park your car and start hiking
if you want to
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth">poke a
stick into live flowing lava</a>.
From the Western edge of breakage, you can see this.</p>
<img src="DSCF3006.png" alt="South coast of the Big Island of Hawaii" />
<p>It’s pretty well a lava wasteland all the way across; but in that picture
you can see a little grove of palms, all by itself, right up against the edge
of the cliff.  It was off the normal walking route, but it called out to me
and we paid it a visit.</p>
<img src="DSCF3057.png" alt="Lonely palm trees in the lava" />
<p>It’s amazing that it survived; the lava flows surround it and
some went right through the middle, somehow managing to miss most of the
trees.</p>
<p>It’s an eerie place, not like anywhere else I’ve been in the whole world.
Once we were there I didn’t
want to leave, but the family had lunch in mind, so we did.</p>
<p>I was pretty pleased with the little Fuji X-E1’s handling of all the
textures these scenes.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/10/'>
 <title>HP1 &#x2014; Sea Turtles</title>
 <link href='Hawaii-Problem-1-Turtles' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='1'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Hawaii-Problem-1-Turtles#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/10/Hawaii-Problem-1-Turtles</id>
 <published>2013-04-10T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-11T00:27:03-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Wildlife' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Wildlife' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Hawaii' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Hawaii' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>HP stands for &#x201c;Hawaii Problem&#x201d;, which is what happens when your friends  come back from it and insist on showing you their pictures.  Except for since this is the Internet, nobody can <em>insist</em> you look at anything. Anyhow, I have a few more I feel the urge to share, starting with sea turtles.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>HP stands for “Hawaii Problem”, which is what happens when your friends 
come back from it and insist on showing you their pictures.  Except
for since this is the Internet, nobody can <em>insist</em> you look at
anything. Anyhow, I have a few more I feel the urge to share, starting with
sea turtles.</p>
<p>They’re easy to see on the Big Island and my favorite thing that’s not an
erupting volcano.  This guy was grazing the tidal pools at 
<a href="http://www.nps.gov/puho/index.htm">Pu`uhonua O Hōnaunau</a> National
Park, also known as City of Refuge, a really nice spot to visit.</p>
<img src="DSCF2722.png" alt="Sea turtle grazing in tidal pool" />
<p>Our next sea-turtle is at the famous 
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Punaluu,_Hawaii">Punaluu</a> black-sand beach, where 
they often swim and rest.  I went there last millennium in another life,
and wrote in another place:</p> 
<blockquote><p>At Punaluʻu harbor, I saw the giant turtles fly. They graze,
moving cowlike, with precise minimal wingstrokes, root piglike among the
bottom-stones. They are nervous of being chased — when pressed, beat wings 
rapid as gulls’ and rocket into green obscurity.  Their eyes are
not quite snakes’, not quite cows’, not quite wise, not quite sad.
I learned to drift with the flow, float up to them, and
finally stroked a passing shell.  It was thickly coated with dusty
outgrowth (a small fish danced attendence on each turtle) and my hand
left a track across it.</p></blockquote>
<p>There are all these strict signs about how you have to give the turtles
lots of space, which these days seem genially ignored.</p>
<img src="DSCF2831.png" alt="Children playing on black-sand beach near sea
			     turtle" />
<p>You might want to enlarge that one, it has stories.</p>
<p>I have to say that the turtles seem totally cool with the primates sharing the
beach.  Millennial primates, raised on a diet of 
Discovery-channel video, are correspondingly cool with the beasts, neither
pestering them nor worrying too much about it.</p>
<p><i>And I think to myself... what a wonderful world.</i></p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/09/'>
 <title>I Bought Some BitCoins</title>
 <link href='I-bought-some-BitCoins' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='7'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='I-bought-some-BitCoins#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/09/I-bought-some-BitCoins</id>
 <published>2013-04-09T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-10T08:01:35-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Internet' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Internet' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Software' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Software' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>On Tuesday evening I gave an envelope full of hundred-dollar bills to a friendly long-haired young man I&#x2019;d never met in an undistinguished coffee-shop in an undistinguished neighborhood.  By the time I got home, the BitCoins I&#x2019;d bought were worth noticeably less than I paid.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>On Tuesday evening I gave an envelope full of hundred-dollar bills to a
friendly long-haired young man I’d never met in an undistinguished coffee-shop
in an undistinguished neighborhood.  By the time I got home, the BitCoins I’d
bought were worth noticeably less than I
paid.</p> 
<p><i>[Update: By morning, the wild gyrations in BitCoins price had
swung me back and forth between profit and loss several times.]</i></p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Why I Did This</h2>
<p>Two reasons; both seem good to me.</p>
<p>First, I’ve been working for a long time and have built up some savings.
Like they say, “diversify your portfolio”.</p>
<p>Second, it’s a new (where by “new” I mean “four years old”) thing on the
Internet.  I feel both desire and duty to experience such things.
My new job has enhanced my appreciation of the power of modern cryptography;
I suspect that if I’d been doing this in 2009, I would have piled into
BitCoins earlier.</p> 
<h2 id='p-2'>How I Did This</h2>
<p>First, I poked around on the Internet and there are exchanges where
you can sign up to buy/sell, but they seemed slow and bureaucratic and
overloaded, plus they wanted
full-color copies of identity documents.</p>
<p>Next,  I griped on Twitter and a
<a href="http://vancouver.hackspace.ca/wp/">Vancouver Hack Space</a>
acquaintance advised me to ask that crowd.</p>
<p>Next, asking VHS yielded a link to the Vancouver BitCoin site,
which as I write this is off the air.</p>
<p>Next, I picked a BitCoins merchant in my neighborhood from the site and
sent him email. He answered, wasn’t comfortable with what I was up to, but
referred me to
<a href="http://adamsoltys.com/">Adam Soltys</a> AKA
<a href="https://twitter.com/adamsoltys">@adamsoltys</a>.</p>
<p>Next, Adam and I shot emails back and forth and agreed on Tuesday night at
the
<a href="http://www.sweettoothcafe.ca/">Sweet Tooth Café</a>.  
Adam has a day job, does BitCoins on the side, is thinking of how he might
make it a career.</p>
<p>We talked for a
while, then I gave him some money and he sent me some BitCoins.  
Yes, the transaction had a bit of 
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sprawl_trilogy">Sprawl-trilogy</a> 
flavor, but if you recognize the reference you’ll probably find that pleasing.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Advice On Doing This</h2>
<p>First, find someone like Mr
Soltys who will advise you on what software to use and so on.
Second, don’t put in any money you can’t afford to lose.</p>
<p>For advice on the larger questions of whether the BitCoin mechanism is
sound, and what they might end up being worth, and whether they are an
anarchist tool for Sticking It To The Man or a libertarian escape-route from
the tyranny of pettifogging regulation or just a Shiny Geek Toy: Go
elsewhere.  I hope to report back with opinions on these topics, once they’re
informed by experience and I can figure out how not to be perceived as
offering investment advice.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/09/'>
 <title>Polyglot</title>
 <link href='Polygot' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Polygot#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/09/Polygot</id>
 <published>2013-04-09T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-09T12:30:08-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Vancouver' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Vancouver' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Software' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Software' />
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Or in full, the
<a href="http://polyglotconf.com/">Vancouver Polyglot {un} Conference</a>.  I
saw it coming, thought it looked cool and that I’d go, then I got copied on an
internal conversation where someone suggested we should sponsor it.  D’oh,
good idea, why didn’t I think of it? So we are. So I’ll not only go, I’ll
suggest an unconference session on my current Identity obsessions.  It’s a
cool location and they look like cool people; come on down!</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/06/'>
 <title>Card Update Degree of Difficulty</title>
 <link href='CC-Update-Degree-of-Difficulty' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='4'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='CC-Update-Degree-of-Difficulty#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/06/CC-Update-Degree-of-Difficulty</id>
 <published>2013-04-06T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-06T14:53:18-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business/Internet' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Business' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Internet' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>In Hawai&#x2019;i I left my credit card behind where we ate lunch on the way to the airport. Called &#x2019;em from the departure lounge and told &#x2019;em to cut it up and throw it out. Called Visa and told &#x2019;em to send me a new one.  Really pretty easy. Then there&#x2019;s switching over all the pre-authorized payments.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>In Hawai’i I left my credit card behind where we ate lunch on the way to
the airport. Called ’em from the departure lounge and told ’em to cut it up
and throw it out. Called Visa and told ’em to send me a new one.  Really
pretty easy. Then there’s switching over all the
pre-authorized payments.</p>
<p>I have seven; how many do you have?  Here is a list, in decreasing order of
degree of difficulty, of the difficulty of upgrading your credit card
details.</p> 
<h2 id='p-1'>Stupid Website — Extreme Pain</h2>
<p>Example: My cable/Internet provider. Various kinds of obstacles and
roadblocks, just generally horribly bad UX.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Bad Call Center — Considerable Pain</h2>
<p>This is when you get put on hold for a long time and then talk over a
staticky echoey line to a
heavily-accented individual who can’t understand the numbers you say over the
phone.  Example: Another telephone company.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>OK Websites — Moderate Pain</h2>
<p>I’m just not sure anyone’s figured out how to set up a website to make a 
non-trivial transaction like this easy, when you hardly ever visit it and thus
aren’t going to know its rhythms or share its assumptions.  It always seems
harder than it should be.</p>
<p>Example: One telephone company. Also, Google, which was perfectly fine,
once I’d given up on poking around my account and found the right place by
typing “google wallet” into Google.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Intelligent Human — Slight boredom</h2>
<p>These are provided, generally, only by organizations to whom you pay
significant amounts of money.  In my case, my government health insurance.
Read ’em off an account number and they get you set right up.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Mobile Phone Responder — Minimum Pain</h2>
<p>This one caught me by surprise. For still another phone company (yes, I
deal with three, it’s a long story) I couldn’t find my account on their Web
site, so I dialed 611 on that phone, and in about 3 clicks they’d pulled up
the account linked to the phone, proactively noticed that my credit card had
gone bad, and asked me if I wanted to type in the new number.</p>
<p>There’s a lesson in that.</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Oh, and All Those Web Sites</h2>
<p>It would have been a case of severe pain everywhere if I didn’t use a
password manager with a browser plug-in so I could look up the account details
for each of them and get the login stuff out of the way.</p>
<p>Yeah, I think about Identity all the time these days.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/04/'>
 <title>On ID Tokens</title>
 <link href='ID-Tokens' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='5'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='ID-Tokens#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/04/ID-Tokens</id>
 <published>2013-04-04T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-04T15:56:09-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology/Identity' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Technology' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Identity' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>These are a product of the <a href='http://openid.net/connect/'>OpenID Connect</a> work, and I think they&#x2019;re going be super-useful; in fact I keep getting ideas for nifty things you could do with them.  So here&#x2019;s a walk-through on what they are and how they work; maybe you&#x2019;ll have some ideas too.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>These are a product of the
<a href="http://openid.net/connect/">OpenID Connect</a> work, and I think
they’re going be super-useful; in fact I keep getting ideas for
nifty things you could do with them.  So here’s a walk-through on what they
are and how they work; maybe you’ll have some ideas too.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>What They Are</h2>
<p>ID Tokens are little chunks of text which
claim that some particular person wants to tell some particular party out
there that they’re signed in and authenticated by the Identity Provider that
issued the token.</p>
<p>There are some more goodies in there, but that’s the big deal.
ID Tokens are easy to understand and cheap for programmers to process.  And
if you follow the rules for handling them, they offer first-rate security.</p>
<p>It seems painfully obvious to me that these things are a key weapon in our
fight against passwords on the Internet.  Now let’s drill down.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>History</h2>
<p>A hundred or so years ago 
<a href="http://scripting.com/davenet/2001/07/17/distributedMembershipAndPr.html#4">Dave Winer said</a>
the Web needed a “You Know Me” button.  I’ve liked that idea ever since.
ID Tokens are the machinery behind that; and
when you’re sending them from a mobile device you don’t even need the button,
because <em>of course</em> the phone knows who you are and can tell anyone you
want it to.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Standards Wonkery</h2>
<p>ID Tokens are defined in
<a href="http://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-messages-1_0.html#id_token">OpenID Connect Messages 1.0</a>,
currently in Draft 17 and (in my opinion) very close to completion.  They work
well enough that Google is deploying them in production.</p>
<p>If you look there, you’ll discover that they weren’t invented from whole
cloth, they’re actually
<a href="http://openid.net/specs/draft-jones-json-web-token-07.html">JSON Web
Tokens</a> (JWT for short, pronounced “jot”, another OpenID spec) which are
based on some IETF work, chiefly
<a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-jones-json-web-signature">JSON Web
Signatures</a>. </p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Where Do They Come From?</h2>
<p>OpenID Connect (OIDC for short) is a spec for doing Authentication
(login or sign-in) 
using OAuth 2.0.  It has nice clean instructions for
redirecting a browser back and forth between an “RP” (relying party)
and “OP” (OpenID Provider) to authenticate a user, then communicate that
authentication (using an ID Token) to the RP. </p>
<p>OIDC is fine as far as it goes, but kind of browser-centric;
we all spend more and more of our time in mobile apps, and they
don’t do that redirect stuff.  And furthermore, when you take your
phone out of your pocket and type your PIN or whatever, you’re pretty
effectively authenticated to the phone, no Web roundtrips needed.</p>
<p>And I’m an Internet-protocols
guy not a user-interface guy.
So I think this tool for communicating
authentication status is way more interesting than the process of
authentication, which I expect to change all the time as we get smarter and
learn new lessons.</p>
<p>On an Android device, you can get an ID Token by calling
<a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/com/google/android/gms/auth/GoogleAuthUtil.html#getToken(android.content.Context, java.lang.String, java.lang.String)">GoogleAuthUtil.getToken()</a>
with a particular value for the “scope” argument; you can read the details in
<a href="http://android-developers.blogspot.ca/2013/01/verifying-back-end-calls-from-android.html">Verifying Back-End Calls from Android Apps</a>.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Inside an ID Token</h2>
<p>Want to look at one?  Drop by the
<a href="https://developers.google.com/oauthplayground/">Google OAuth 2.0
Playground</a>, ignore all the APIs, type “openid email” into the “input your
own scopes” window, press the “Authorize APIs” button, tell Google it’s OK to
make the token, and then press the “Exchange authorization code for tokens”
button on the next screen.</p>
<p>I just did that, and here’s the ID Token I got (broken up to fit into the
relatively narrow columns here at <span class='o'>ongoing</span>).</p>
<pre><code>eyJhbGciOiJSUzI1NiIsImtpZCI6IjQ4OWRmMzE3YzIyYzY3NTZkOTUyMTVk
YjQ1NTA5MjY0N2RmNWIxNmEifQ<span style="color: red;">.</span>eyJpc3MiOiJhY2NvdW50cy5nb29nbGUuY
29tIiwiZW1haWwiOiJ0aW1icmF5QGdtYWlsLmNvbSIsImVtYWlsX3Zlcmlma
WVkIjoidHJ1ZSIsInN1YiI6IjEwNzYwNjcwMzU1ODE2MTUwNzk0NiIsImF1Z
CI6IjQwNzQwODcxODE5Mi5hcHBzLmdvb2dsZXVzZXJjb250ZW50LmNvbSIsI
mF0X2hhc2giOiJyTC1jVml3OTJtYW5EUU1MdU1tTEt3IiwiYXpwIjoiNDA3N
DA4NzE4MTkyLmFwcHMuZ29vZ2xldXNlcmNvbnRlbnQuY29tIiwiaWF0IjoxM
zY1MDk5MTUxLCJleHAiOjEzNjUxMDMwNTF9<span style="color: red;">.</span>GeqJOTJSMaQjo33wxM-3f5k5
FIEADqxd3K4zS0pWgWjtqwDldbpGgmxwTytgvtXKjFu7dtZx6TUXPnDhLBti
MjtkTyPGZbm65RwG0arSLqH-iDelceDR5HDABhOBqXjsi19rdnC3TAWf5Dpe
QYZt9uSSgPseGW2wh6OO5izat48</code></pre>
<p>That’s not supposed to be human-readable, but do take a moment to
notice that the token is separated into three chunks by two dots, which I’ve
colored red to make them a little easier to see.</p>
<p>Want a look inside that token?  Google has a service for that (you have to
paste in the whole token, but I’m only showing the first few characters to
keep things readable):</p>
<pre><code>>> curl https://www.googleapis.com/oauth2/v1/tokeninfo?id_token=eyJhb...
{
 "issuer": "accounts.google.com",
 "issued_to": "407408718192.apps.googleusercontent.com",
 "audience": "407408718192.apps.googleusercontent.com",
 "user_id": "10315112535234507946",
 "expires_in": 3089,
 "issued_at": 1365099151,
 "email": "example@gmail.com",
 "email_verified": true
}</code></pre>
<p>You can try this yourself, but not with that token, which will have expired
by the time you’re reading this. So go over to the
playground and make your own ID Token and give it a whirl.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Let’s Unpack It Ourselves</h2>
<p>It turns out that if you’re a programmer and you get an ID Token,
you don’t have to have a conversation with Google to unpack it. Here’s how.</p>
<p>Earlier, I pointed out that these things have three .-separated parts.  It
turns out that the first two are just base64-encoded JSON.  Let’s decode them
(I use the command-line <code>base64 -D</code> on my Mac, but there are a lot
of ways to do this).</p>
<p>First segment (with line breaks for readability):</p>
<pre><code>{
 "alg":"RS256",
 "kid":"489df317c22c6756d95215db455092647df5b16a"
}</code></pre>
<p>Second (somewhat anonymized):</p>
<pre><code>{
 "iss":"accounts.google.com",
 "email":"example@gmail.com",
 "email_verified":"true",
 "sub":"10315112535234507946",
 "aud":"407408718192.apps.googleusercontent.com",
 "at_hash":"rL-cViw92manDQMLuMmLKw",
 "azp":"407408718192.apps.googleusercontent.com",
 "iat":1365099151,
 "exp":1365103051
}</code></pre>
<p>(Alert observers will have noticed that the fields in the second don’t have
the same names as reported by the “tokeninfo” endpoint above. I think that’s
wrong and have filed a bug; will report back.)</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Be Careful</h2>
<p>First of all, note that the token isn’t encrypted; which means you have to
be careful that the wrong people don’t see it.  In practical purposes, this
means whenever you send it anywhere, you have to use TLS, i.e HTTPS not HTTP.
Which is just good practice anyhow.</p>
<p>That said, let’s look at the fields inside the ID Tok<b>BZZZZZZZZZZT! 
WRONG!</b></p>
<p>Oops.  It turns out you must <em>never</em> use the info in an ID Token
unless you’ve validated it, or Evil Internet People Will Come To Your House And
Strangle Your Puppy. OK, I’m kidding about the puppy, but seriously, there are
a lot of bad things that can happen if you don’t do this right;
which, fortunately, is pretty easy.</p>
<p>(By the way, the tokeninfo endpoint I used above with “curl” takes care 
of the base64 parsing, the validation, and the unpacking all at once).</p>
<p>The third piece of the token (after the second dot) is the cryptographic
signature. The first part (before the first, unpacked above) tells you which
key and crypto algorithm was used to make it.</p>
<p>Fortunately, you don’t need to understand that crypto stuff. Most languages
have signature verifiers and the ones I’ve been working with recently come
with JWT libraries, you can just pass in the raw token and get back a
nicely-validated and unpacked hash or dictionary or whatever...</p>
<p>... well, sort of.  You also need to pass in the key, which can get a
little complicated. It turns out that if you know the ID Token was signed by
Google, you can tell the library to fetch our keys from
<a href="https://www.googleapis.com/oauth2/v1/certs">www.googleapis.com/oauth2/v1/certs</a>
(go ahead, click and have a look).</p>
<p>This can be automated.  If you know the email address
you’re authenticating, you can use
<a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-appsawg-webfinger">WebFinger</a> to figure out which IDP to use,
and then use
<a href="http://openid.net/specs/openid-connect-discovery-1_0.html">OpenID Connect Discovery</a>
to figure out the URI pointing to the
IDP’s keys, then go get them.  Or you could start from the “issuer” field in
the token, if you’ve whitelisted it.</p>
<p>All of which, of course, would be a <em>lot</em> of Web round-trips, but 
in practice you’d almost never have to; these things
are all very stable and cacheable.</p>
<p>In most cases you’re not going to have to even fetch the keys.  We at Google
only rotate ours on the order of once per day. So the library code I’ve seen
caches them, and if a token fails to validate, they go re-fetch the keys and
try again, on the assumption that the token was issued since they rolled
over.  So in almost every case, validating an ID Token is a couple of calls
into a crypto library.</p>
<h2 id='p-9'>More Carefulness</h2>
<p>Once you’ve validated and believe that the ID Token was really signed by
an issuer you’re prepared to trust, you still have to do a little more work.
Most importantly, you need to look at the value of the “aud” (for audience)
field.  This represents who the issuer and user thought this token was
intended for.  It’d better be you.  You’re identified by “Client ID”,
a string you get from the IDP (issuer, “iss” In the ID Token) when you
register with them.  If the value of 
“aud” isn’t yours, something has gone gravely astray and you really shouldn’t
use the token.</p>
<h2 id='p-10'>The Payload</h2>
<p>Having practiced good hygiene, we can now talk about what was inside that
ID Token.  It turns out that it’s flexible enough to allow for all sorts of
different fields, but here are the standard ones that deliver the real
value.</p>
<p><b>iss</b> is the Issuer.  Many apps will want to whitelist the
issuers they’ll accept ID Tokens from, but I can imagine some apps where you’d
be less sensitive.</p>
<p><b>email</b> is self-explanatory, the person the ID Token claims to have authenticated.</p>
<p><b>email_verified</b> means that the
token issuer really took pains to check that this is that person.</p>
<p><b>sub</b> (for subject) is interesting.  It’s the real unique identifier
for the person whose “email” was provided.  The combination of
“issuer” and “sub” is globally unique.  For example, you can change the
email address on a Google account, but the “sub” won’t change. So
if you’re building a user database, the right key for “example@gmail.com”
would be the combination of 
”accounts.google.com” and 10315112535234507946.</p>
<p><b>aud</b> is the app which is expected to receive this ID Token. For
example, 
on an Android device, when the app asks for an ID Token, the user would be
prompted if it were OK to share her identity with the app (identified by name
and graphic) which had registered with Google and been given this Client
ID.</p>
<p><b>at_hash</b> is used in the case where you get both an ID Token and an
Access Token, to verify the linkage. It’s an interesting use-case, but not
what I’m discussing today.</p>
<p><b>azp</b> identifies the party authorized to send the ID Token, in the
same way that “aud” identifies the one expected to receive it. In the case
where the ID Token was generated on Android, it’ll identify the Android app
that requested it.</p>
<p><b>iat</b> and <b>exp</b> are timestamps for when the token was issued and
when it expires. If we apply that advanced algorithm known as “subtraction”,
we can deduce that this particular token was good for 65 minutes.</p>
<h2 id='p-11'>There You Have It</h2>
<p>Lightweight, suitable for including in a URL or sending in an HTTP header,
easily verified, easily unpacked, and (assuming you validate properly) just as
trustworthy as you think its issuer is.</p>
<p>A very damn useful little piece of technology.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/04/02/'>
 <title>Hem</title>
 <link href='Hem' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Hem#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/04/02/Hem</id>
 <published>2013-04-02T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-04-02T23:32:36-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Music' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Music' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>Currently listening to: <cite>Departure and Farewell</cite> by <a href='http://www.hemmusic.com/'>Hem</a>; there was a <a href='http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2013/04/video-hems-seven-angels.html'>plug in the <cite>New Yorker</cite></a> with a nice video sample so I checked out the site and there was the album for sale, lossless format, fair price; why wouldn&#x2019;t I just buy it instantly?</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>Currently listening to: <cite>Departure and Farewell</cite> by
<a href="http://www.hemmusic.com/">Hem</a>; there was a
<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/culture/2013/04/video-hems-seven-angels.html">plug
in the <cite>New Yorker</cite></a> with a nice video sample so I checked out
the site and there was the album for sale, lossless format, fair price;
why wouldn’t I just buy it instantly?</p>
<p>Now, not every band is gonna get noticed in the <cite>New Yorker</cite>;
but if you get noticed somewhere, and you have a nice sample, and your site
will sell me the music, uncompressed, with a couple of clicks, I’m probably
gonna buy it right there.  And I don’t think I’m <em>that</em> eccentric.</p>
<p>The songs are very pretty and Sally Ellyson’s singing has got to touch your
heart if you have one.  The playing and arrangements have an effortlessly
light touch, the kind it takes serious effort to achieve, 
something I appreciate more and more with the passing decades.</p>
<p>One gripe on the production: Instruments and voices
well-captured, but emerging here and there from black silence, no sense of an
enclosing
room or live ensemble, a band leaning forward and back into the flow of the
song.</p>
<p>More producers ought to go and listen to what their counterparts did
in the Fifties and Sixties by putting bands in a room and pointing a
high-quality microphone at them.  Or, to the Cowboy Junkies.</p>
<p>I put an LP from way back then on the turntable and it creates the illusion
that the musicians are at the other end of the room, and I know perfectly well
it’s not the ineffable wonderfulness of vinyl, it’s because the musicians were
actually there and the producer was capturing the track, not constructing it
<i>ex post facto</i>.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/03/30/'>
 <title>Ingress Tourism</title>
 <link href='Ingress' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Ingress#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/30/Ingress</id>
 <published>2013-03-30T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-03-31T11:05:14-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Life Online' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>The game still feels like a big story to me, and still under-reported; so herewith Ingress coverage, featuring tourism, community cancer, client controversy, and tactical tips. With pictures of places Ingress players see.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>The game still feels like a big story to me, and still under-reported; so
herewith Ingress coverage, featuring tourism, community
cancer, client controversy, and tactical tips. With pictures of places
Ingress players see.</p> 
<p>Previously in this series:
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/02/06/Improving-Ingress">Ingress Weekly</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/01/29/Ingress-Month-3">Ingress, Month 3</a>,
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/01/09/Things-about-Ingress">Things About
Ingress</a>, and
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2012/12/08/Ingress">Ingress</a>.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Tourism</h2>
<p>I’m still not a serious player; you can’t be one of those with a job and 
family and so on.  But I travel a lot.</p>
<p>Last time out, I mentioned the fun I’d had playing Ingress in London.
Ditto for Tokyo, ditto ditto for the Big Island.  I guess if there’s an
Ingress-photography genre, it’s gonna be mostly cellphone photos. But not
here.</p>
<img src="DSCF2587.png" alt="Ingress portal location, Tokyo" />
<div class="caption"><p>There’s a portal nearby.</p></div>
<p>Whatever Ingress’ virtues and problems, it absolutely
makes travel more interesting. You go places you wouldn’t have gone, you meet
people you wouldn’t have met, you photograph things you wouldn’t have
seen.</p>
<p>Also, for weeks afterwards, you get Ingress emails about how
portals you set up back there have been attacked; a nice bit of short-term
nostalgia.</p>
<img src="portal-at-my-desk.png" alt="Portal at my desk" class="inline" />
<h2 id='p-1'>General State of Play</h2>
<p>It’s not bad. The early-2013 problem, where one side or the other took total
control of an area then locked out the other, seems to have been pretty well
resolved; most maps I look at have a sane mixture of blue and green.</p>
<p>One thing that’s helped a whole lot has been the injection of many
new portals.  People have figured out that they can submit 
loads of candidates near where they are, and some get accepted.
So on the walking route from my office to the craft-beer store to 
my house there are
now five portals (not all my submissions).  I’m totally changing from
six-packs to individual bottles.</p>
<p>And (heh-heh) check the screenshot to the right; the little blue triangle
is me, <em>sitting at my desk</em>.</p>
<p>Finally, on March 29th every player level 6 and up got an
invitation 
to pass on to anyone; so I suspect Niantic thinks they’re ready for some
serious scaling.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Community Problems</h2>
<p>I suppose it will surprise exactly nobody to hear that in an unmoderated
game-focused online community, bad behavior has occurred.  This includes but
isn’t limited to: bullying, bigoted name-calling, outing players’ real-world
identities, and various forms of cheating — most commonly one person playing
multiple accounts.</p>
<img src="DSCF2828.png" alt="Southernmost bar in the United States" />
<div class="caption"><p>There are a couple of portals here, down by the
southernmost bar in the United States, in
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naalehu,_Hawaii">Naalehu</a>.
Unclaimed!  But I didn’t notice till 
after we’d driven away. Sob.</p></div>
<p>It got pretty bad here in Vancouver, but a combination of community
pressure and one intervention from Niantic — a notorious potty-mouth got banned
for a while — seems to have brought things mostly under control.</p>
<p>It totally defeats me why, when a person is called out for unacceptable
behavior, they think it makes any difference to say “I was just doing it for
the lulz” or “Only trolling”.  The Internet is <em>real life</em>. If you say
things on the Internet that only an asswipe would say, you’re an
asswipe. That’s all there is to it.</p> 
<h2 id='p-3'>Client Controversy</h2>
<p>There’s a Web view of the state of the game; called the “Intel
map”, it uses gobs of JavaScript to give players the big picture of what’s
going on.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, someone reverse-engineered the protocol, pulled together
some different gobs of JavaScript, and published “Ingress Intel Total
Conversion”; it presents a different view which many people have said is more
useful.</p> 
<img src="DSCF3165.png" alt="View across False Creek from Science World" />
<img src="DSCF3166.png" alt="BC Place from Science World at night" />
<div class="caption"><p>Multiple portals at (and lots more in the
view<br/>from) Vancouver’s
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science_World_(Vancouver)">Science
World</a>.</p></div>
<p>This may or may not be against the
<a href="http://www.ingress.com/terms">Ingress Terms of Service</a>; I don’t
have an opinion.  Surprisingly, IITC’s author wrote to Niantic asking
if what he was doing was OK.  Unsurprisingly, he didn’t like the answer he
got.
Nobody can possibly complain, this is a free service being offered by Niantic
and if you don’t like the terms you shouldn’t play.</p>
<p>So now everyone’s still using IITC, but from one of a bunch of Github forks
and guerilla sites.</p>
<p>Me, I can’t figure the rights and wrongs of this situation. Obviously,
Niantic has to try to make sure the game stays fair, that the clients don’t
hit the servers so hard that they ruin performance, that nobody’s privacy is 
compromised, and so on.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it’s not obvious to me that it’s technically feasible to
keep people from building alternate JavaScript clients.  And, given a
reasonable regulatory framework, it might be a good thing to have an ecosystem
of clients for this new server offering.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Public Servants</h2>
<p>I went out to play a bit of Ingress in Kona and the portal was in the weeds
behind
<a href="http://goo.gl/maps/JjzBK">the fire station</a>; I was picking my way
past when a fireman popped out and asked “Can I help you?” I explained; he was
a bit baffled, but OK with me fighting through his underbrush.</p>
<p>And just recently, because even though I don’t play that much any more, I’m
<em>very</em> near Level 8 (weeks and weeks after all the guys I was playing
with in January got there) and thus motivated to get out and grind a bit; so I 
was cruising through Vancouver’s Old Chinatown and wandered into the notorious
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Downtown_Eastside">Downtown
Eastside</a>. There I was among various flavors of drug victim, and of course
drug-victim suppliers.  This friendly cop came along and said “You know where you
are, right?  I’d hate to see you lose that nice tablet.”  I find the DTES sad
not scary, but I guess he had a point, so I knocked off and came home.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Tactical Tips</h2>
<p><i>[Probably unintelligible to non-players.]</i> When you get to L7 or L8,
you’re probably furiously farming L6 and L7 portals to get your ammo and
resos. And for every portal you take on your own you need either 3 (L7) or 2
(L8) sub-L5 resos to fill it up.  It’s real easy to run real low on those.</p>
<p>So here are things you can do:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Go farm some L3 portals (boring).</p></li>
<li><p>When you’re smashing enemy portals, hack ’em as you’re taking them
down when they’re at L3 or so, then pause for reflection and hack ’em again as
you’re deploying when they’re at L3 or so (slows you down).</p></li>
<li><p>Play with a high-level friend. Problem solved. (Neither boring nor
slow.)</p></li>
</ul>
<h2 id='p-4'>A New Thing in the World</h2>
<p>That’s what Ingress is.  I’m enjoying watching its trajectory as much as
I’ve enjoyed watching any New Net Thing in recent years.  Stay tuned.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/03/28/'>
 <title>Tropical Mirrorless Research</title>
 <link href='Tropical-Mirrorless-Research' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Tropical-Mirrorless-Research#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/28/Tropical-Mirrorless-Research</id>
 <published>2013-03-28T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-03-29T14:17:06-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos/Cameras' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Cameras' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Hawaii' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Hawaii' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I claim that watching people photograph the Big Island is effective camera-futures research; and camera futures are interesting now. So here&#x2019;s some research. Oh, and Big Island photos.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I claim that watching people photograph the Big Island
is effective camera-futures research; and camera futures are
interesting now. So here’s some research. Oh, and Big Island photos.</p>
<p>Those camera futures became interesting with the arrival, this
past few years, of “mirrorless” and other compact-format high-quality
cameras (overview
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/06/Fuji-X-E1-in-Tokyo#p-1">here</a>).  Check out
<a href="http://www.sansmirror.com/newsviews/ive-got-good-news-ive-got.html">I've Got Good News, I've Got Bad News</a>
for some data on sales trends; it suggests SLRs are doing well but
compacts aren’t much of a factor.</p>
<img src="DSCF2725.png" alt="Old Hawaiian wood-carving" />
<div class="caption"><p>At the
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pu%CA%BBuhonua_o_H%C5%8Dnaunau_National_Historical_Park">Puʻuhonua o Hōnaunau
(City of Refuge)<br/>park</a>, a must-see on the Big Island.</p></div>
<h2 id='p-1'>Why Hawaii?</h2>
<p>People go to the Big Island to see things. (This probably applies to Kauai
too).  If you just want to lie on the
beach, Maui’s the place. For civilized funk and surfing, Oahu. But the Big
Island is all about lava and canyons and Saddle Roads and botanical
gardens and coffee plantations and paniolos; most people would want to come
home with pictures.  In fact, I suspect a Big Island vacation is a common
factor motivating new-camera purchases. And since it's not a particularly
cheap place to go or stay, a lot of those purchases will be high-end, thus a
useful indicator of which way the market’s heading.</p>
<img src="DSCF2742.png" alt="Hawaiian vegetation, partially sunlit" />
<h2 id='p-2'>What I Saw</h2>
<p>This is uncontrolled anecdotal scavenging, not real data collection. But still:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Astonishingly few point-&amp;-shoots.</p></li>
<li><p>A huge number of iPhones and Androids (more of the former, but plenty
of both).</p></li>
<li><p>Unsurprisingly many big honking CaNikon SLRs.</p></li>
<li><p>Surprisingly, a waterproof compact or two at most pools and beaches.</p></li>
<li><p>Memorably, a few iPads, held up to shoot Mom &amp; Sis in front of the 
waterfall or whatever. The photographer looks dorky but I don’t think cares
because you preview and shoot at the same time, if it weren’t that awkward
it’d sweep the planet, but it is that awkward.</p></li>
<li><p>And then, in the places where photos matter, compacts.  Lots of
compacts; maybe as many as SLRs. Panasonics and Sonys mostly; I had the only
Fujifilm I saw but it got called out by savvy-seeming photogs carrying way
heavier metal.  I kept having to say “No, it’s not an X100.”</p></li>
</ul>
<img src="DSCF2786.png" alt="A stone personage in the waves" />
<div class="caption"><p>Look closely, there’s a creature in that stone.</p></div>
<h2 id='p-3'>Instinct Call</h2>
<p>I can’t encourage you, honestly, to trust mine. But it’s shouting in my
ear, saying the future is electronic viewfinders and small bodies.</p>
<p>SLRs are really hard to shrink
because of their lens legacy and prism-size requirements, neither of which get
help from Moore’s Law.  
The mirrorlesses are doing all sorts of innovation in sensors and lenses
and ergonomics, and their viewfinder systems are going to improve every year
because they <em>are</em> in Moore’s-Law territory.</p>
<p>And also, once again <em>size matters</em>. The whole point of a camera is
that, to be useful, it has to go with you.  The lighter and smaller it is, the
more likely it is to be there.</p>
<p>The corollary, of course, is that more and more photography is going to
happen through mobile phones because they’re the most likely to be there.  So
cameras have to find the sweet spot, where they take significantly better
pictures than phones, but aren’t so bulky they get left behind.</p>
<p>Is my new Fujifilm X-E1 a complete replacement for the Pentax SLRs I’ve been
carrying around for years?  Not entirely, because I don’t have a lens longer
than 55mm, and really no urge to get one, because once you get up into the big
lenses, you’re kind of trading off portability anyhow.</p>
<p>But for tourism, particularly if there’s some
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth">serious
walking</a> involved, the Fuji trumps the Pentax, big-time; the image quality
is about as good, the ergonomics are mostly better, and the size decides
it.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Just Getting into Photography?</h2>
<p>Go mirrorless. Don’t even think about an SLR.  It’s a no-brainer.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/03/26/'>
 <title>Finite Surface Integral of the Earth</title>
 <link href='Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='3'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Finite-Integral-of-the-Earth</id>
 <published>2013-03-26T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-03-27T16:11:49-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Hawaii' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Hawaii' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I have watched the piecewise creation of the world; new pieces  burn gold-red, creep into place like honey, lethally  hot in the ocean-moist air.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I have watched the piecewise creation of the world; new pieces 
burn gold-red, creep into place like honey, lethally 
hot in the ocean-moist air.</p>
<p>And of course took lots of pictures.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Back Story</h2>
<p>I owe this experience to one of the many photographers on Google+, who posted on
<a href="https://plus.google.com/115105647022907007398/posts/ctcmKPBMK3g">shooting lava</a>.  Since we’d planned a
vacation to the Big Island you can bet this caught my attention.  I’d visited
the island and the volcano a couple of times, but live lava
always seemed something that you had to be an extreme-hiking fanatic, and
prepared to die in the attempt, to see. Or, rich enough to rent a
helicopter. 
Well, it turns out that there are walking tours
from a place you can drive to and park at.</p>
<p>The one that caught my attention was 
<a href="http://lavarefuge.com/poke-a-stick-guided-lava-tours/">Poke-A-Stick</a>, so called
because that’s what they promise; poke it into molten rock, they mean.
<a href="http://www.laurenwood.org/anyway/">Lauren</a> and I
signed up, hiked across the lava to the lava, and sticks were poked.
More on the tour operation later, but first the experience.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>The Walk</h2>
<p>It’s five or so miles (around 8km) from car-park to lava and back, all
tough going, over lava formations that are irregular, sometimes
crumbling, often sharp.</p>
<img src="DSCF2903.png" alt="Walking across cold lava to hot lava" />
<p>There isn’t a single minute of the hour it takes to get there that your
eyes aren’t being grabbed by one lava formation or another: Twisted, folded,
woven, broken, wrapped, interpenetrated.</p>
<img src="DSCF2893.png" alt="Cold lava formations" />
<img src="DSCF2896.png" alt="Cold lava formations" />
<p>Both those pictures are full-color not B&amp;W, by the way.</p>
<p>I’d thought the biggest lava flow had been 1992; so I asked our guide
whether we were 
walking on 1992 lava, and he said “no, this is from 2010.”  It had little
sprigs of fern here and there; and then, a few minutes later, where there were
no plants, that was 2011 lava. Sobering.</p>
<img src="DSCF2888.png" alt="Ferns growing in 2010 lava flow" />
<p>There’s another story visible in that picture above, if you enlarge it.
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kalapana,_Hawaii">Kalapana</a> is the
town most completely erased by the volcano. But its people still own
their now-lava-covered lots, and a few have put houses back up,
some perched on naked rock; look at the top right of the picture. Our
guide told us that property taxes are low.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Fear</h2>
<p>There wasn’t much, to be honest. The operator seemed competent,
the online reviews were good, there were other groups in the distance
headed in the same general direction, I was confident I could manage three or
four hours of rough ground.</p>
<p>Well, except for once, when it was obvious we were approaching the live
lava. Wisps of steam here and there, and I noticed the ground we were walking
over was hot, and then the heat was everywhere, coming from below and rocks
all around.
(But that was an anomaly.  Mostly, the rocks underfoot weren’t hot, even
right up next to the outflow.)</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Live Lava!</h2>
<p>We scrambled over a little heap of coiled grey rock and there it was, 
unsubtly yellow in the afternoon light. And <em>moving</em>.</p>
<img src="DSCF2931.png" alt="Live lava!" />
<p>We spent maybe
half an hour there and three times as long wouldn’t have been boring. It was
like water finding its random way over irregular ground, only honey-slow not
water-fast; then the heat and the colors.</p>
<p>One hump on the right in the picture above piled up just before we got
there; look close and you can 
see a crack across the top.  Then with a lurch it pushed open and the hot glow
was oozing away left and right.</p>
<img src="DSCF2934.png" alt="Live lava outburst" />
<p>There are these curved-fold formations you see in any lava field, and
here’s how they get made: A tongue of lava spreads out, flattens, gets
pushed from behind as it cools and stiffens; hey-presto, bent ripples of stone!</p>
<img src="DSCF2937.png" alt="Where lava ripples come from" />
<p>It’s never fast, even when a flow goes over an edge and has air underneath
to fall into. So you can do things like stand right in front of an
advancing flow for that good camera angle, and not worry too much.</p>
<img src="DSCF2952.png" alt="Standing in front of an advancing lava flow" />
<p>There’s no noise to speak of; a little rustling, no more.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Poking Sticks</h2>
<p>I admit to having thought this notion a little gimmicky, maybe
disrespectful even. If I believed in any gods at all I might worry
about 
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pele_(deity)">Madam Pele’s</a> feelings.
But what can be the harm
in it?  Your marks are gonna be overrun, whether within ten minutes or
in next year’s flow; which should teach useful respect for the evanescence of
anyone’s impact on the world, even when inscribed in stone.</p>
<img src="DSCF2963.png" alt="Sticks being poked" />
<p>Man, that stuff is <em>hot</em>.  By the time you get close enough to poke,
your face is burning, your lungs are stressed, and those of us who are
shooting little 35mm Fujifilm primes as opposed to huge 70-200mm CaNikon zooms
are wondering about their camera’s temperature tolerances.</p>
<p>When you poke the stick in, usually there’s a little rush of flame. The
stick doesn’t instantly vaporize or even ignite.  But you can make it burn,
you can even hoist a bit of lava on it. One family brought marshmallows
for gleeful toasting.</p>
<p>It sets fast; within a minute, a bright-glowing edge that’s soft to the
touch has skinned over and trying to poke it is, well, hitting rock with a
wooden stick; feels silly.</p>
<h2 id='p-4'>Steam</h2>
<p>As dusk gathered, we hiked from the live lava down to the cliff edge 
over the shelf where it enters the sea.  You
can’t actually see molten rock hit water; but the glow in the evening
light is stark, and often there are bright fragments rolling
back and forth on the beach.  And from time to time, something impacts
something and bright gouts of lava arc up and away from the
entry-point. It was a good place to sit down, get a sandwich out of your backpack, and
contemplate.</p>
<img src="DSCF2984.png" alt="Lava enters the sea" />
<img src="DSCF2991.png" alt="Lava enters the sea" />
<h2 id='p-5'>Hiking Back</h2>
<p>Really arduous; in deep dark, single-filed behind
the guide and his GPS, everyone with a little flashlight to make the next few
steps safe. For the best part of two hours.  With a crunch-crunch-crunch 
like walking through  a certain class of thick Eastern-timezone snow; 
recent-lava surface is brittle.</p>
<p>This particular lava is nearly half silicon, which means it sparkles wetly
when you light it up at night.  So
I’m trudging through the huge dark with my little flashlight beam showing me 
ropy, shattered, twisted, wet-looking black shapes, and I’m thinking
“This is totally Ridley Scott.”  Which I said out loud but nobody seemed
to relate. Mind you, I’d watched <cite>Prometheus</cite> on the plane down to
Hawai’i.</p> 
<p>It was tough and after a while my feet were killing me, but the real
danger was wandering attention. I
found myself thinking about volcanoes and people and islands and how to photograph
them and write about them and more than once suddenly realized I’d dropped
back, leaving a maybe-dangerous gap in the single file.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Logistics</h2>
<p>Normally, when you visit a Hawai’i tourist attraction, the show
begins with a glowing introduction about the kozmick wonderfulness of the
islands’ birth in fire out of water.
But on this
trip to actually watch the birthing, it was pretty well just “You all ready?
Let’s head out.”</p>
<p>Cheryl Adler, who runs Poke-a-Stick as part of her
<a href="http://lavarefuge.com/">Lava Refuge</a>
operation, isn’t a geologist or a volcanologist, she just happened to own a
palm-tree farm that got cut off by the 1989 flow and is a really great
jumping-off spot for lava walks.</p>
<p>The land you’re walking across is still privately owned (some by Cheryl)
even if it is under a few feet of lava.  They trade for some access rights and
pay for others.   So anyhow, you’ll get a hell of an experience, but
you’re not going to get much mysticism. Which is OK by me.</p>
<p>In our party of a dozen or so, half were from Vancouver, a few from
Spokane, and there was a young seeing-the-world Norwegian couple.</p>
<h2 id='p-7'>Should You?</h2>
<p>Hell yes!  If you’ve got reasonably good legs and no big cardiovascular
issues. There was a kid in the party, maybe nine or ten, and while his Dad
had to carry both backpacks sometimes, he made it both ways
fine. It’s forty years since I’ve been a kid and I did OK too.</p>
<p>Well, to be honest, my feet and ankles were seriously sore the next day; Lauren
stumbled and cut her hand on that sharp silicon-rich rock, and got 
probably-permanent lava stains on nice walking pants.</p>
<p>But how often do you get to watch the creation of the earth?</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/03/26/'>
 <title>Being Google</title>
 <link href='Googleversary' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='12'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Googleversary#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/26/Googleversary</id>
 <published>2013-03-26T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-03-27T10:38:29-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Google' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Google' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>This month saw my 3-year anniversary here, and I feel like one of my missions is to be a guide on this Magical Mystery Tour. So, here are some things about Google; without asking anyone first, because not asking first is best.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>This month saw my 3-year anniversary here, and I feel like one of my
missions is to be a guide on this Magical Mystery Tour.
So, here are some things about Google; without asking anyone
first, because not asking first is best.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Being Careful</h2>
<p>Startups are all damn-the-torpedos and ship-it-now. Been there, done that,
loved it.  Inappropriate with a user count on the order of a billion.  My
first-ever push to Google’s webspace was a couple of paragraphs of
documentation; the compulsory review process ended up with four rewrites
involving input from three people. </p>
<p>Not management-driven cover-your-ass rewrites, either; topics of debate
included
“what is the actual failure mode?” and “Don’t talk abstractly about
‘developers’, say ‘You must...’”</p>
<p>Code reviews are way fiercer.  The world doesn’t see this process
but is in its debt; it occurs in every substantial engineering group not just
at Google. And most people don’t know that <em>caution</em> is at the core of
the engineering value system; nor 
<a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2004/08/18/Borked">why</a>.</p>
<p>Google tries to combine that value with insane risk-taking, as in Gmail or
Chrome or Google+.  That’s tricky.</p>
<h2 id='p-1'>Being Android</h2>
<p>It’s a <em>consumer</em> product, y’know, and that’s the most important
thing about it. Which means that it’s siloed and has to be; Microsoft proved
that back in 2007 when its heroic attempt to unsilo consumer platform development
squeezed out Vista, a day (by which I mean years) late and a dollar (by which
I mean billions) short.  If Android’s going to be great, Android has to care
about being Android.</p>
<p>And I care about Android, because it’s a really good way to have the
Internet in your pocket and as I
<a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2010/03/15/Joining-Google#p-5">said
before</a>: “freedom’s not just another word for anything, nor is it an
optional ingredient.”</p>
<p>But I care more about the Net. My adult life has had its share of
technical and ethical failures, but I’ve rarely failed to
advocate for the Internet.  Which is  bigger than Android or (by definition)
any other single software platform.
That’s why I’m happy working here at Google, and not just on Android.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Being Evil</h2>
<p>There’s no there there.  
Near as I can tell three years in, Google really wants you to be online all
the time (signed in if possible) and put everything in the cloud and use
our search engine and and enjoy those experiences and
not get hacked, and that’s about it.  The money we make
falls out of those things.</p> 
<p>The interesting question isn’t “Is Google evil?” (answer: not particularly)
but “What’s the downside
if Google suddenly becomes evil?” Because the chance is nonzero that when our
founders die or get bored, MBAs with desiccated souls will be in
command, and not really understand why it matters that people have decided, by
and large, to trust us.</p>
<p>Fortunately, there’s a firewall: the
<a href="http://www.dataliberation.org/">Data Liberation Front</a>, which
strongly limits the evil that an evil Google could do.  It’s simultaneously a
useful utility and the canary in the coalmine. People should pay attention to
it.</p>
<h2 id='p-5'>Being Fast</h2>
<p>I just can’t say how impressed I am when I hit Google with something like 
“Copenhagen weather” or
“Barca schedule” or “Oscar Winners” and the answer is <em>right there</em>,
no more clicks required.  Similarly, at the awesome efficiency, when I type
a search into Maps, of how it figures what address or neighborhood or business
I mean. I can’t remember the last time I actually completed a Maps
search and hit Enter.</p>
<p>This is the kind of engineering the Net needs more of.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Being Social</h2>
<p>Those of you who don’t use Google+ because you know for sure that it’s an
echoing wasteland can skip this section.  Personally, I spend quite a bit of
time there; here’s why:</p>
<ol>
<li><p>There are 29,000 people following me. I don’t know how much weight to
put on that number, but there are very few posts that don’t provoke reaction,
oftentimes intelligent.</p>
<p>I plug my blog pieces on G+ and it generates loads of traffic; comparable
to Twitter in that respect.</p></li>
<li><p>There are a lot of outstanding photographers posting great
pictures.</p></li>
<li><p>It’s where all the Ingress community happens.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>The short version: It’s not as efficient for spreading news as Twitter; but
it’s way better for having a conversation.</p>
<p>I’m still impressed that, starting in 2011, this company, emphatically not a
startup, turned on a dime and built a Google+ that is fairly
astonishing in its scale and energy.</p>
<p>Possibly you don’t agree with all the design decisions; I don’t.  But I
have to say the people doing it are pretty transparent in what they’re trying
to achieve and why they’re doing things the way they are.</p>
<p>Good luck to them.</p>
<h2 id='p-6'>Being Remote</h2>
<p>For an Internet-centric geek, Google’s obviously the best place in the
world to work.  If it weren’t for the remote-worker thing, I’d be pretty well
100% happy.</p>
<p>Speaking of which, I enjoyed the flurry of discussion on remoteness
kicked off by Ms Mayer over at Yahoo! I
recommend Scott Hanselman’s
<a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/BeingARemoteWorkerSucksLongLiveTheRemoteWorker.aspx">Being a Remote Worker Sucks - Long Live the Remote Worker</a>
for the most emotionally-honest coverage. If you want the contra
argument read Farhad Manjoo’s
<a href="http://mobile.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2013/02/yahoo_working_at_home_marissa_mayer_has_made_a_terrible_mistake_working.html">Marissa Mayer Has Made a Terrible Mistake</a>,
but he’s wrong.</p>
<p>Obviously, centralized works well for some companies like for example
Google; distributed works for others, for example 37 Signals.  I’m pretty sure
there’s not a hard-and-fast rule waiting to be laid down here.</p>
<p>Me, I’d rather work in an office than by myself, but Google doesn’t have one
where I choose to live, so there you go. Yeah, if I ran across another job and
it was in Vancouver and it was fulfilling, I’d think seriously about it even
if it weren’t Google-level fulfilling.</p>
<h2 id='p-2'>Being Boring</h2>
<p>Uh, Identity, the stuff I work on now.  I’ve had submissions to
conferences declined, something that hasn’t happened to me in
years. Nobody likes Identity, nobody thinks they’re gonna win the Web wars
because they do Identity better, nobody wants to own the Identity
subsystem.</p>
<p>I consciously picked this work because I thought it was the place to really
have an impact. And I still think it will.  But everyone’s looking the other
way. I can deal with that.</p>
<h2 id='p-3'>Being Happy</h2>
<p>I pretty much still am. I get to work with great people on things that
matter. Some year my luck will run out, but not yet.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/03/12/'>
 <title>X-E1@&#x6771;&#x4eac;: Still Water</title>
 <link href='Tokyo-X-E1-Still-Water' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='0'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Tokyo-X-E1-Still-Water#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/12/Tokyo-X-E1-Still-Water</id>
 <published>2013-03-12T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-03-12T17:08:26-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts/Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Arts' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Photos' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Places/Tokyo' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Places' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Tokyo' />
 <summary type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>I bought a ticket on the Tokyo airport bus leaving from near the Google office and thought my  fun with the <a href='/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/06/Fuji-X-E1-in-Tokyo'>new camera</a> was over; but I was wrong. A half-hour wait provoked a random stroll which brought me to a little teeny shrine down a little teeny alley.</div></summary>
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>I bought a ticket on the Tokyo airport bus leaving from near the Google office and
thought my 
fun with the <a href="/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/06/Fuji-X-E1-in-Tokyo">new
camera</a> was over; but I was wrong. A half-hour wait provoked a random
stroll which brought me to a little teeny shrine down a little teeny alley.</p>
<img src="DSCF2596.png" alt="A shrine in Roppongi Hills" />
<img src="DSCF2600.png" alt="A shrine in Roppongi Hills" />
<p>I guess I should conclude this series with some more reportage on the
camera, but hey, the most important thing isn’t that, because they’re all
pretty good these days.  What matters is finding something worth pointing it
at. Most times, all you really need is for the camera to get out of the
way.</p> 
<p>I didn’t feel there was anything between me and the water.
And that’s it for this series.</p>
</div></content></entry>

<entry xml:base='When/201x/2013/03/11/'>
 <title>Sex Education</title>
 <link href='Sex-Education' />
 <link rel='replies'        thr:count='5'        type='application/xhtml+xml'        href='Sex-Education#comments' />
 <id>https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/03/11/Sex-Education</id>
 <published>2013-03-11T12:00:00-07:00</published>
 <updated>2013-03-11T21:56:18-07:00</updated>
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World/Family' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='The World' />
 <category scheme='https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/' term='Family' />
<content type='xhtml'><div xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'>
<p>My turn in the carpool schedule. Girl and Boy in the back seat, my first-grade daughter
and her classmate who’s expecting a little sister any day now.
Girl: “Daddy, how do they know whether it’s a boy or a girl before it’s
born?” Me: <i>[Tries to explain about ultrasound (as if I understood it) and
how they can see a not-very-good picture of the baby, still in Mummy’s
tummy.]</i>  
<i>[Silence]</i> 
Girl: “But how do they know if it’s a boy or a girl?” 
Me:  “Well, they look to see if it has a penis!” 
<i>[Longer silence.]</i> 
Boy: “Did you know that when a baby’s born, it’s <em>naked</em>?” 
<i>[Still longer silence.]</i> 
Girl: “Daddy, please don’t talk about gross stuff like that.”
</p>
</div></content></entry>

</feed>
