<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Cutting edge science you can dice with</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 23:14:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='tallbloke.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Italian police seize $1.7b Mafia green energy assets</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/italian-police-seize-1-7b-mafia-green-energy-assets/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/italian-police-seize-1-7b-mafia-green-energy-assets/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tchannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12111</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A story in the MSM here reported by Aljazeera &#8220;Italy seizes Mafia-tied clean energy assets Police seize $1.7bn in assets which include 43 wind and solar energy companies, 98 properties and 66 bank accounts.&#8221; Elsewhere this is spinning more as windmill charging. I note Al J. using &#8220;clean&#8221; in the headline, even politics there. Well [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12111&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/news/europe/2013/04/20134373914609909.html" target="_blank"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-572.jpg?w=265&#038;h=285" width="265" height="285" align="left" /></a></p>
<p>A story in the MSM here reported by Aljazeera</p>
<p>&#8220;Italy seizes Mafia-tied clean energy assets</p>
<p>Police seize $1.7bn in assets which include 43 wind and solar energy companies, 98 properties and 66 bank accounts.&#8221;</p>
<p>Elsewhere this is spinning more as windmill charging.</p>
<p>I note Al J. using &#8220;clean&#8221; in the headline, even politics there.</p>
<p>Well it is Italy but many think the extent of fraud and embezzlement is endemic everywhere in the world where there is manipulation and money. Okay, that&#8217;s everywhere.</p>
<p><span id="more-12111"></span></p>
<p>Click the image or <a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/news/europe/2013/04/20134373914609909.html" target="_blank">link</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12111/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12111/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12111&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/italian-police-seize-1-7b-mafia-green-energy-assets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d21d6725f3925a85290ce54127b80d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-572.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Success - Afghanistan Joins The Kyoto Protocol</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/12107/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/12107/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/12107/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reblogged from Tory Aardvark: When this story first surfaced, the initial reaction was, April Fools day joke, how could a country with one of the lowest per capita emissions signing up to a treaty that expired on December 31st 2012 be hailed as a Green success story. The world's only treaty for fear of CO2, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12107&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="reblog-post"><p class="reblog-from"><img alt='' src='http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7dfbe74c9f5d37c3845d0351f215f346?s=25&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G' class='avatar avatar-25' height='25' width='25' /> <a href="http://toryaardvark.com/2013/04/04/green-success-afghanistan-joins-the-kyoto-protocol/">Reblogged from Tory Aardvark:</a></p><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt"><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt-content"><a href="http://toryaardvark.com/2013/04/04/green-success-afghanistan-joins-the-kyoto-protocol/" target="_self"><img src="http://toryardvaark.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/afghanistan_joins_kyoto.jpg?w=614" alt="Click to visit the original post" class="size-full" /></a>

<p>When this story first surfaced, the initial reaction was, April Fools day joke, how could a country with one of the lowest per capita emissions signing up to a treaty that expired on December 31st 2012 be hailed as a Green success story.</p>
<p>The world's only treaty for fear of CO2, the Kyoto Protocol ended along with 2012 on December 31st, attempts to keep it alive at COP18 failed, an attempt at a new&hellip;</p>
</div> <p class="read-more"><a href="http://toryaardvark.com/2013/04/04/green-success-afghanistan-joins-the-kyoto-protocol/" target="_self"><span>Read more&hellip;</span> 429 more words</a></p></div></div><div class="reblogger-note"><div class='reblogger-note-content'>
The insightful Tory Aardvark spots a potential windfarm location bonanza. Look, there's a portable one right there! Oh, hang on a minute...
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/12107/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tom Van Flandern: Was the planet Mercury once a moon of Venus?</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/tom-van-flandern-was-the-planet-mercury-once-a-moon-of-venus/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/tom-van-flandern-was-the-planet-mercury-once-a-moon-of-venus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astrophysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geomagnetism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gravity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mercury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moon formation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Van Flandern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[venus]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12102</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is an essay written some years ago by the late Tom Van Flandern  which was included in his book &#8216;Dark Matter, Missing Planets &#38; New Comets&#8217;. Tom, who worked for many years at the U.S. Naval Observatory, was an out of the box thinker who covered a wide range of astronomical topics, many of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12102&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is an essay written some years ago by the late Tom Van Flandern  which was included in his book &#8216;Dark Matter, Missing Planets &amp; New Comets&#8217;. Tom, who worked for many years at the U.S. Naval Observatory, was an out of the box thinker who covered a wide range of astronomical topics, many of them well outside the mainstream. His methodology was a bit similar to my old dad&#8217;s approach to cryptic crosswords. &#8220;The clue doesn&#8217;t give you the answer, but it helps confirm you got the right answer once you&#8217;ve got it&#8221;. Leif Svalgaard says he was a crank, which in my view means he&#8217;s well worth a read. I think this article, tied in with his other solar system formation concepts, deserves to be republished for the assessment and re-appraisal of the talkshop cogniscenti and the interested visitors here.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/mercury-300x300.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-4815" alt="mercury-300x300" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/mercury-300x300.jpg?w=614"   /></a>Let us examine in detail what the consequences would be of assuming that Mercury originated as a satellite of Venus. If that were so, we might presume that Mercury formed in close orbit about Venus, perhaps by fission<sup>a</sup>. But Mercury is four and a half times more massive than the Moon. So the interchange of energy through tidal friction between Venus and Mercury would have been enormous. Mercury&#8217;s original spin would have been halted fairly rapidly by Venus, leaving Mercury spinning once per revolution around Venus, always keeping the same face toward Venus, as for our Moon.<br />
<span id="more-12102"></span></p>
<p>We can also note that both planets would have been melted by tidal heating in the early stages following escape. Assuming this occurred before Venus differentiated (before the heavy elements sank to its core), this might explain both the high density and the magnetic field of Mercury, and the absence of an appreciable magnetic field for Venus<sup>b</sup>. Thus we have reason to believe that all three present-day planets with unusually high densities (Mercury, Venus and Earth) probably melted at one time from tidal heating. This melting is then the most probable cause of their high densities.</p>
<p>Tides raised by Mercury on Venus while Venus was still spinning rapidly would have caused great interior heating and out gassing, and probably a great deal of surface upheaval (mountain building). We already start to see the evolution of a planet very much like the Venus we know today: an unusually thick, dense atmosphere from outgassing to great depths below the surface; quite hot, with mountains as large as its gravity field will support; and robbed of most of its original spin. We know that 50-100 atmospheres worth of CO2 and other Venus-atmosphere constituents are trapped in carbonate rocks in the Earth&#8217;s crust, and might have been released from tidal grinding if the Earth&#8217;s Moon had been as massive as Mercury.<sup>c</sup></p>
<p>Tidal friction would take Mercury into higher and higher orbits, just as has been happening for billions of years with our own Moon. However, our Moon will not reach a distance at which it can escape from Earth. All the Earth&#8217;s spin energy will be transferred to the Moon, and the two will revolve while keeping the same side toward each other, some billions of years in the future. Mercury, however, is sufficiently massive that it takes all of Venus&#8217;s spin in the first half-billion years after formation; and Venus&#8217; orbit is close enough to the Sun that complete escape of Mercury will occur.<sup>d</sup></p>
<p>While Mercury is still a satellite of Venus, its shape will tend to become somewhat prolate (elongated toward Venus). Although that condition will relax somewhat after escape, the planet should still retain a slightly prolate shape. This turns out to be an important factor in understanding Mercury&#8217;s present-day odd spin state (3-to-2), as we shall see.</p>
<p><strong>Post-Escape Evolution</strong><br />
Calculations by Harrington show that escape would necessarily occur on the sunward side of Venus, and that the new orbit around the Sun which Mercury would then occupy is both stable and non intersecting with the orbit of Venus (important to avoid collisions or ejection from the solar system). The subsequent evolution of the orbit of Mercury takes it to higher orbital tilts and eccentricity (ellipticity)-indeed at times to the same values for those parameters which Mercury&#8217;s orbit has today, even though those values are higher than for any &#8220;true&#8221; planet.</p>
<p>Let us consider what forces might have been operative in the early solar system which could evolve Mercury&#8217;s orbit inward to its present distance from the Sun. One candidate is tides raised by Mercury on the Sun. Such tides are negligible today, for purposes of orbital evolution. However, these tides should be orders of magnitude larger than is usually assumed, as described in the chapter &#8220;sunspots and Planets&#8221;. And in the early solar system, the Sun is presumed to have been physically much larger in diameter than now, according to stellar evolution theory (its T Tauri contraction phase). There is no question that a Sun with ten times its present diameter would have produced major tidal evolution which could have separated the orbits of Mercury and Venus (assuming they already existed, and that Mercury had already escaped from Venus). Smaller solar sizes may well have accomplished the same feat, depending upon the rotation speed and extent of differential rotation of the early Sun.</p>
<p>Other forces which might have been operative, such as collisions or drag from leftover planetary formation material, would also operate in the direction of separating the orbits, taking Mercury closer to the Sun than Venus. It is often forgotten that some forces were likely operating to evolve the mean distances of the planets from the Sun; for if there were not, we would find leftover formation matter today in the vast number of stable orbits between the planets. In short, if the planets did not all evolve significantly in their mean distances from the Sun (changing their distances by at least a factor of two), the left-over solar system formation material would cause the solar system to more nearly resemble Saturn&#8217;s rings than discrete planets with empty space between. Even in the conventional model of solar system formation from the primeval solar nebula, the planets would have collided with masses totaling 100% of their own mass in the aggregate while they were undergoing their last doubling in mass during accretion. These aggregate collisions must have had a major effect on the mean distances of each of the planets from the Sun, which could therefore not have started at their present values even in the standard model.</p>
<p>We conclude that the orbit of Mercury would evolve into one with unusual eccentricity and inclination to the plane of the other planets, typical of what we see today; and that its mean distance from the Sun could have evolved to today&#8217;s values also. Venus would have lost most of its spin in the process, and its remaining slow spin could have become retrograde because of thermally-sustained high atmospheric winds being forced retrograde by tides from Mercury just prior to the satellite&#8217;s escape.</p>
<p>Further calculations by Harrington showed that Mercury would have had a revolution period (and therefore also spin period, since spin is locked to Venus up to escape) of somewhat over 40 days at the point of escape, which spin period it would then retain for a time in its new orbit around the Sun. Tides raised by the Sun on Mercury would gradually slow its spin. Under ordinary circumstances, this slowing would continue until it reached 88 days, Mercury&#8217;s orbital period, at which time the planet would always keep the same face toward the Sun. Instead Mercury slowed only until it reached its present 59-day, 3-spins-to-2-revolutions state. Why did its spin stabilize in that condition? Because (and I consider this the strongest argument for the correctness of the theory that Mercury was a satellite of Venus) following an escape with a 40-some-days period of spin, the next stable spin configuration for a Mercury-like body with a slightly prolate shape is the 3-to-2 spin condition. Mercury has the required prolateness (and no other planet does) to a necessary and sufficient degree. And this prolateness, which enables Mercury to lock into such an unusual spin configuration, is itself a predicted consequence of having been a satellite of a larger planet.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">In summary, something gave Venus a slow backwards spin, caused it to outgas a dense atmosphere and form high mountains, and to have no natural satellites today. Something caused Mercury&#8217;s satellite-like size and appearance, giving it a prolate shape, high density, and magnetic field, and put it into a 3-to-2 spin state. Up to now, astronomers have invented separate and ad hoc explanations for each of these anomalies. But we can instead invoke a single hypothesis, from which all these anomalies are natural, deductive consequences: that Mercury is an escaped satellite of Venus!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">________________________________________</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Footnotes</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><sup>a</sup> If Mercury fissioned from Venus due to overspin, as is suspected to be the case for the Earth&#8217;s Moon, then we would expect hemispheric asymmetry on Venus, with analogs to the Earth&#8217;s &#8220;Pacific basin&#8221; and &#8220;Atlantic ridges.&#8221; Since there are no oceans because of the heat, these might take the form of missing crust, replaced with mantle material, in one hemisphere, and perhaps a major rift or split in the other hemisphere. Or in view of Mercury&#8217;s greater mass, perhaps the entire original crust of the planet was stripped away in the fission.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><sup>b</sup> If Mercury is an escaped satellite of Venus, perhaps most of the original iron in Venus (which ultimately produces the magnetic field) was forced up into the crust by an excessively high spin rate. Venus may have then fissioned from overspin to form Mercury, with Mercury getting most of the iron. Subsequently both bodies would have melted each other from tidal friction, which would cause the heavy elements (such as iron) to sink to the core. Such a scenario could explain why Mercury&#8217;s magnetic field is stronger than that of Venus, since Mercury would get most of the iron during the original fissioning.</p>
<p>As for the Earth and its Moon, a similar scenario might apply, except that the Earth&#8217;s iron was not forced to the surface, perhaps because the Earth was not as hot and molten as Venus during that phase of its formation. Whether the iron and heavy elements rise or sink depends on the rate of spin and degree of melting of the planet. For the Earth, if these elements sank to the core before the Moon fissioned, the Moon would end up without its share of heavy elements. The sinking process increases the Spin of the Earth, and raises the likelihood of a fission to form the Moon.</p>
<p>Interestingly, for Venus, when the heavy elements rise to the surface, its spin slows. Yet a configuration with a heavy crust and light core becomes more likely to fission at lower spin speeds because it is unstable. If it does fission, the planet that remains behind will have lost a considerable portion of its angular momentum right at the outset.</p>
<p><sup>c</sup> We might also note that Venus and the Earth have the only two surfaces in the solar system with linear mountain ranges. In this model, these were presumably built during the crust fracturing process which led to the formation of a large Moon initially in orbit around each of these two planets, and no others.</p>
<p><sup>d</sup> It is interesting to follow closely what would happen to the spin of Venus as Mercury approaches tidal escape. For Venus or any planet that rotates faster than the mean speed of its atmospheric winds, mountains and other surface irregularities impart enough momentum to the atmosphere to ensure that it moves in the same general direction as the planet spins. But when the planet&#8217;s rotation slows to below the mean wind speed, as Mercury would cause Venus to do, then the situation reverses. Mean wind speed can push on mountain ranges and other surface inegularities, and ultimately determine which direction the planet will rotate.</p>
<p>As Mercury tidally evolves outward, it must necessarily produce rotational drag on Venus, tending to slow the rotation of Venus. But it must raise even bigger tides on Venus&#8217; atmosphere, causing the whole atmosphere to circulate in the retrograde direction. After billions of years, this may produce retrograde spin of the entire planet.</p>
<p>Today, the largest net torques on Venus&#8217; atmosphere are due to the Earth, since its tidal forces are stronger than either Mercury&#8217;s or Jupiter&#8217;s. The Sun produces stronger tidal forces than any planet, but with no net torque. So the Earth will ensure that the atmosphere of Venus continues to receive slight retrograde impulses at every inferior conjunction of the two planets. This may explain why the spin of Venus today lies close to a resonance with Earth, despite the seemingly negligible strength of the interaction between the two planets.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12102/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12102/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12102&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/tom-van-flandern-was-the-planet-mercury-once-a-moon-of-venus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/mercury-300x300.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mercury-300x300</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iceland earthquake swarm: 484 earthquakes in less than 48 hours</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/iceland-earthquake-swarm-484-earthquakes-in-less-than-48-hours/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/iceland-earthquake-swarm-484-earthquakes-in-less-than-48-hours/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 08:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncertainty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12094</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many thanks to Alan Bond for sending in details of this seismic activity. Tectonic plates pulling apart off the north Icelandic coast have produced a swarm of earthquakes, including a 5.5 rattler, felt across the north of the country. Monitoring website earthquake report has this: Update 10:49 UTC : The swarm continues and the most [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12094&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many thanks to Alan Bond for sending in details of this seismic activity. Tectonic plates pulling apart off the north Icelandic coast have produced a swarm of earthquakes, including a 5.5 rattler, felt across the north of the country. Monitoring website <a href="http://earthquake-report.com/2013/04/02/moderate-earthquake-iceland-region-on-april-2-2013-4/">earthquake report</a> has this:</p>
<p>Update 10:49 UTC : The swarm continues and the most recently listed earthquakes had a Magnitude of M4.3 and M4.2. The number of earthquakes during the last 48 hours has risen to 484 ! The hypocenter depth is mainly varying in 3 layers, one at only a few hundred meter, another at 1.1 km and the last one at 20 km.<br />
Most of the epicenters are located in an area of 15 to 30 km from Grimsey.<br />
There have been earthquakes cycles of a similar nature in 1969, 1974, 1980, 1986, 1994 and 2002. The cycles were all from a few days up to several weeks.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/grimsey-quakes.png"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-12095" alt="grimsey-quakes" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/grimsey-quakes.png?w=614&#038;h=371" width="614" height="371" /></a></p>
<p>This event follows a recent report that volcano Hekla in the south of Iceland is restless:</p>
<p><span id="more-12094"></span></p>
<p>Associated Press<br />
Published Tuesday, March 2, 2013 10:43AM EDT</p>
<p>LONDON &#8212; Icelandic police say seismic activity near the Hekla volcano has prompted them to declare an &#8220;uncertainty phase&#8221; &#8212; the lowest level of civil warning.</p>
<p>Monitoring of the area in southern Iceland has been increased. Police advise people not to hike in the area, though it is not forbidden.</p>
<p>Vidir Reynisson, the department manager for civil protection, said Tuesday that a swarm of earthquakes prompted the warning but are not necessarily a sign of pending eruption. Scientists worry that Hekla is overdue for an eruption; in recent decades it has erupted roughly every 10 years, most recently in 2000.</p>
<p>Concern about seismic activity in the north Atlantic nation has grown since April 2010, when ash from the Eyjafjallajokul volcano grounded flights across Europe for days, disrupting travel for 10 million people.</p>
<p>However the <a href="http://en.vedur.is/about-imo/news/nr/2681">Icelandic MET office</a> seems to e treating the Grimsey event as nothing unusual:</p>
<p>A M5.5 earthquake occurred at 00:59 on 2nd April 2013 about 15 km east of Grímsey island offshore North Iceland. The earthquake was felt at Grímsey, Húsavík, Raufarhöfn, Mývatnssveit, Akureyri and Sauðarkrókur. Several hundruds aftershocks have been detected following the mainshock. The source region is located on a fault system that reaching from Öxarfjörður to the north of Grímsey, the so called Grímsey lineament. Another M4.7 earthquake followed this morning at 08:56 and was located about 7.5km northwest of the night&#8217;s main event.</p>
<p>Both mainshocks are shown as black stars in the map, aftershocks that have been manually revised so far are shown as red dots. The M5.5 mainshock is located on a north-south striking left lateral strike-slip fault, see black lines in the map. The M4.7 event around 9 am was located on a normal fault to the north-west.</p>
<p>This cluster at about 7.5 km distance to the main cluster was most likely activated due to static stress changes induced by the M5.5 earthquake.</p>
<p>Earthquake sequences are common in this area. It is impossible to predict the further development of the seismic activity and how it might influence faults in its vicinity. Further large events can not be excluded.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12094/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12094/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12094&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/iceland-earthquake-swarm-484-earthquakes-in-less-than-48-hours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/grimsey-quakes.png?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grimsey-quakes</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dramatic pictures of west Scotland wildfires</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/dramatic-pictures-of-west-scotland-wildfires/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/dramatic-pictures-of-west-scotland-wildfires/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 23:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tchannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12086</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wildfires are burning in parts of western Scotland, partly blamed on unusually dry conditions in what is traditionally a very wet part of the UK. At this time of the year burning off dead heather and grass is common practice, helps to regenerate grazing. This year there has been a prolonged easterly airflow over the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12086&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="BBC website" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-highlands-islands-21999542" target="_blank"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-571.jpg?w=265&#038;h=367" width="265" height="367" align="right" /></a></p>
<p>Wildfires are burning in parts of western Scotland, partly blamed on unusually dry conditions in what is traditionally a very wet part of the UK.</p>
<p>At this time of the year burning off dead heather and grass is common practice, helps to regenerate grazing.</p>
<p>This year there has been a prolonged easterly airflow over the UK, originating as intensely cold are over Norway, picking up a little moisture over the North Sea before perhaps Fohn conditions if any snow fell over the central mountains. This would lead to drying of the air and also being in the rain shadow, no rain or snow.</p>
<p><span id="more-12086"></span></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know if this news in context Bing  link might work (couldn&#8217;t get Google to work at all)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bing.com/news/search?q=skye+%2bfires+news&amp;p1=%5bNewsVertical+SortByDate%3d%221%22%5d&amp;FORM=YGNR" target="_blank">Bing news on wildfires</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Post by Tim Channon</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12086/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12086/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12086&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/dramatic-pictures-of-west-scotland-wildfires/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d21d6725f3925a85290ce54127b80d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-571.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Possible conclusion on Arctic ice</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/possible-conclusion-on-arctic-ice/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/possible-conclusion-on-arctic-ice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 21:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tchannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Variation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sea ice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12076</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In response to an article yesterday about a possible amplitude variation in annual Arctic sea ice Roger Andrews wrote &#8220;Seems to me you could conclude a lot from a model like that.&#8221; Yes I was sitting on a wall not wanting to join what-might-be with the methodology. It&#8217;s easier for me to compose a new [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12076&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In response to an article yesterday about a possible amplitude variation in annual Arctic sea ice Roger Andrews wrote &#8220;Seems to me you could conclude a lot from a model like that.&#8221;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-186.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-186-small.png?w=550&#038;h=223" width="550" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 1</p></div>
<p>Yes I was sitting on a wall not wanting to join what-might-be with the methodology.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s easier for me to compose a new article with many images than put them together graphically. Taking some of the items <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/arctic-sea-ice-experimental-decode-of-modulation/">shown yesterday</a> here I put the sea ice back together again before I get accused of vandalism. I wonder what R<sup>2</sup> result there will be?</p>
<p><span id="more-12076"></span></p>
<p>The Y axis scaling which follows is carefully done to try and keep visual constancy.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-179.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-179-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 2</p></div>
<p align="center">now sum with the following</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-180.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-180-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 3</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">giving a result</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-181.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-181-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 4</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">Now below here is the original data as monthly</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-182.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-182-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 5</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">R<sup>2</sup> = 0.973</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">and difference the data and model</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-184.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-184-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 6</p></div>
<p>This is the residual but I have not included harmonics of 1 year, hence you can mainly see 0.5 year. A slight linear trend and offset is present but the model is incomplete.</p>
<p>Add in 0.5 year, details not shown.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-185.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-185-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 7</p></div>
<p>R<sup>2</sup> = 0.991 which traditionally implies accounting for 99% but in this case is misleading since there is a dominant regular component.  The proportion of unexplained is far greater.</p>
<p>More model detail could be included but with no material effect. Linear trend and offset is now negligible.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Commentary.</span></p>
<p>I am suspicious of the data, the result does not make sense because a very close to pure ~1ky sine is irrational as an underlying characteristic given this is the top  of the fragment. I&#8217;m assuming the modulation of the amplitude is encoding varous wiggles including something like this curve.</p>
<p>Repeating figure 1</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-187.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-187-small.png?w=550&#038;h=223" width="550" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 1</p></div>
<p>I don&#8217;t buy this as reasonable yet there is nothing in my software which could bias this nor did I do anything. Least squares fitted to daily data, except the parentage of the data is unknown.</p>
<p>Much the same result is produced by a straight processing of the data so I doubt it is to do with the envelope work.</p>
<p>So what is the explanation? I hope it is nothing to do with me.</p>
<p>Post by Tim Channon</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12076/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12076/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12076&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/possible-conclusion-on-arctic-ice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d21d6725f3925a85290ce54127b80d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-186-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-179-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-180-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-181-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-182-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-184-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-185-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/image-187-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ian Wilson: Could This Be The Climate Smoking Gun?</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ian-wilson-could-this-be-the-climate-smoking-gun/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ian-wilson-could-this-be-the-climate-smoking-gun/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 14:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cycles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dataset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Variation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tides]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12049</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here at the talkshop we have recognised from the get-go that with the demise of the pathetically myopic and wholly incorrect co2-driven-climate hypothesis, a better theory will be needed to take it&#8217;s place. Now we have some more exciting news from Astrophysicist Ian Wilson. He has discovered a very solid looking link between planetary motion, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12049&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Here at the talkshop we have recognised <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2009/11/29/planetary-solar-climate-connection-found/">from the get-go</a> that with the demise of the pathetically myopic and wholly incorrect co2-driven-climate hypothesis, a better theory will be needed to take it&#8217;s place. Now we have some more exciting news from Astrophysicist Ian Wilson. He has discovered a very solid looking link between planetary motion, solar variation, and Earth&#8217;s climate. The periods involved also tie in with the work going on in the background here on the Phi/Fibonacci thread. I believe we are getting closer to solving the solar system puzzle, and finding plausible explanations for cyclic climate changes on Earth which are evidenced by various proxy time series. Here, Ian uses the (in)famous bristlecone pine core data. Maybe this was the right proxy with the wrong approach all along. Just for the avoidance of doubt, that&#8217;s Prof. Michael Mann I&#8217;m alluding to. Excuse me while I spit the taste of his name out of my mouth.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Could This Be The Climate Smoking Gun?</strong><br />
<strong>Ian Wilson 2-4-2013</strong></p>
<p>In the paper:</p>
<p>Cyril RON, Yavor CHAPANOV and Jan VONDRÁK<br />
SOLAR EXCITATION OF BICENTENNIAL EARTH ROTATION OSCILLATIONS<br />
Acta Geodyn. Geomater., Vol. 9, No. 3 (167), 259–268, 2012</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/temperature.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-12050" alt="Temperature" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/temperature.jpg?w=614&#038;h=255" width="614" height="255" /></a></p>
<p>Figure 1 shows an amplitude spectrum of the North American temperature over a 2200 year period.</p>
<p><span id="more-12049"></span>The spectrum is based upon bristle-cone pine series obtained from:</p>
<p>MATTHEW W. SALZER and KURT F. KIPFMUELLER<br />
RECONSTRUCTED TEMPERATURE AND PRECIPITATION<br />
ON A MILLENNIAL TIMESCALE FROM TREE-RINGS<br />
IN THE SOUTHERN COLORADO PLATEAU, U.S.A.<br />
Climatic Change (2005) 70: 465–48</p>
<p>Given the controversial nature of the use of Bristle-cone as a proxy for temperature, I have quoted the section of this paper dealing with methods used in constructing the tree-ring chronology that reflects past temperature variability &#8211; see the Appendix at the end of this post. The important thing to note about figure 1 is that, for periods for less than or equal to 500 years, there are prominent spectral peaks at: 89 years, 104 years, ~ 150 years, 208 years, ~ 230 years, ~ 355 years and ~ 500 years. These periods (obtained from proxy temperature data) can be compared with a Fourier spectrum of solar activity qualified by the solar modulation potential and the Fourier spectrum of the planetary torque acting upon the Sun, published by: J. A. Abreu1, J. Beer, A. Ferriz-Mas, K. G. McCracken, and F. Steinhilber <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/10/25/j-a-abreu-et-al-is-there-a-planetary-influence-on-solar-activity/">Is there a planetary influence on solar activity?</a> A&amp;A 548, A88 (2012) These spectra are based upon a 9400 year time series of solar activity derived from observations of Be10 and C14.</p>
<p>Figure 2</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/solar.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12051" alt="Solar" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/solar.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<p>Amazingly, the solar activity spectrum shows peaks at:</p>
<p>89 years, 104 years, 150 years, 208 years, ~ 230 years, ~ 355 years and 506 years.</p>
<p>The planetary torque shows all of these peaks, except those at ~230 &amp; ~ 355 years.<br />
[See Ian Wilson's previous posts <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?s=ian+wilson">here</a> for more detail on his tidal-torque theory]</p>
<p>I believe that it is extremely unlikely that the spectral peaks for the North American temperatures are almost exactly the same as the spectral peaks for solar activity and planetary tidal torques acting upon the Sun by chance.</p>
<p>I claim that it indicates that the level of solar activity upon the Sun is modulated by planetary tidal-torquing acting upon the convective layer of the Sun and that it is these variations in the level of solar activity that have determined the mean temperatures of the North American continent over the last 2200 years.</p>
<p><strong>APPENDIX</strong><br />
Figure 1A</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/bristlecone.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-12052" alt="Bristlecone" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/bristlecone.jpg?w=614&#038;h=327" width="614" height="327" /></a></p>
<p><strong>quote:</strong><br />
To build a tree-ring chronology that reflects past temperature variability, upper-tree-line Bristlecone Pine (P. aristata), whose ring-width variability is a function of temperature, were sampled at timberline in the San Francisco Peaks (∼3,536 m), where temperature is most limiting to growth (Figure 2). Increment core and sawed samples were collected from living and dead Bristlecone Pine on both Agassiz Peak and Humphreys Peak. Long chronologies were constructed by cross-dating the deadwood samples with the living tree specimens. Prior to AD 659 the chronology is composed entirely from deadwood material. The individual growth rings of each sample were measured to the nearest 0.01 mm. The measured series were converted to standardized tree-ring indices by fitting a modified negative exponential curve, a straight line, or a negatively sloped line to the series.</p>
<p>This process removes the age/size related growth trend and transforms the ring-width measurement values into ring-width index values for each individual ring in each series (Fritts, 1976). Several statistics were calculated to gauge the reliability of the tree-ring series (Cook and Kairiukstis, 1990; Wigley et al., 1984) (Table I). Through conservative standardization techniques and the use of relatively long series, care was taken to preserve low-frequency information in the chronology (Cook et al., 1995). A regional curve standardization (RCS) approach (Briffa et al. 1992a), which has been used in some dendroclimatic studies to resolve multi-decadal to centennial trends, was considered but rejected. In general, RCS was devised for chronologies built from short series that use heavy detrending. The SFP chronology was built from relatively long segment lengths (Table I) and a conservative standardization process was employed. Additionally, we could not meet the necessary assumptions critical to successfully applying this technique: it was impossible to ascertain pith or near-pith dates from the deadwood material due to the irregular growth form of Bristlecone Pine, and we are not able to demonstrate that the age structure of the samples are evenly distributed.</p>
<p>To create the mean site chronology, the annual standardized indices of tree growth were averaged. A single chronology was developed from samples collected at two sites on Humphreys Peak and one site on Agassiz Peak. The SFP chronology extends from 663 BC–AD 1997. In total, 234 series (130 trees) are used. The period before 266 BC is considered less reliable than the rest of the chronology as six or fewer series cover this interval. The climate data used in the temperature reconstruction calibration are from the Fort Valley Experimental Research Station, which is part of the United States Historical Climatology Network. The station data, from an elevation of 2,239 m and approximately 4.5 km from the high elevation SFP tree-ring sites, span the period 1909–1994.<br />
<strong>end quote:</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12049/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12049/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12049&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/ian-wilson-could-this-be-the-climate-smoking-gun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/temperature.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Temperature</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/solar.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Solar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/bristlecone.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bristlecone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Arctic sea ice, experimental decode of modulation</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/arctic-sea-ice-experimental-decode-of-modulation/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/arctic-sea-ice-experimental-decode-of-modulation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tchannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sea ice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12026</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This article involves novel methodology so please act sensibly, I am risking ridicule by showing experimental analysis results. Maybe non-technical folks should skip this article, which offers no conclusion on sea ice. Posit: for many earth datasets the dynamics of earth act as a modulator encoding analogue change as modulation spectra. Modulation arises from earth [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12026&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This article involves novel methodology so please act sensibly, I am risking ridicule by showing experimental analysis results.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-174.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-174-small.png?w=550&#038;h=231" width="550" height="231" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 1</p></div>
<p><strong>Maybe non-technical folks should skip this article, which offers no conclusion on sea ice.</strong></p>
<p>Posit: for many earth datasets the dynamics of earth act as a modulator encoding analogue change as modulation spectra. Modulation arises from earth spin and orbit.</p>
<p><span id="more-12026"></span></p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-172.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-172-small.png?w=550&#038;h=158" width="550" height="158" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 2</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-173.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-173-small.png?w=550&#038;h=162" width="550" height="162" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 3</p></div>
<p>Figure 1 exhibits a poor Rsq but is I think convincing if short term variation is ignored. The intent of the cross check is confidence the modulation envelope is the same as the envelope produced from the data by bandpass filtering. None of these processes is perfect but neither is data noise free, nor can a model take into account noise. The whole thing is approximations.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">The dataset</span></p>
<p>Nothing is simple with this work. A little while ago someone emailed me pointing at a blog article about Arctic ice at Tamino&#8217;s, who I gather is really someone named Foster and works at an American university.</p>
<p>The only interest there for me was the use of an Arctic ice dataset which I had not come across before, which additionally seemed to be up to the current date.<br />
<a href="http://arctic.atmos.uiuc.edu/cryosphere/timeseries.anom.1979-2008">http://arctic.atmos.uiuc.edu/cryosphere/timeseries.anom.1979-2008</a><br />
I took a guess at column 3.</p>
<p>I know many of these datasets particularly well so daily data running from 1979 when I know there is no such daily data is a red flag.</p>
<p>Actual daily data? I don&#8217;t buy it. Provenance? When I back up from the data link given I came to a visually confusing web site, with little information. I failed to find any further information on the dataset. If you can handle the site and work it out, please tell.</p>
<p>The nearest to daily is NASA Stereo, a complicated work which starts with data every other day late 1978 eventually turning daily, publication ending 2007. (and a refusal to update further &#8212; private email with the authors)<br />
Nevertheless some time ago I produced an amalgamation with the geometrically different JAXA daily data until that dying satellite failed. At that point I gave up, if they can&#8217;t be bothered to do anything competently, walk away.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-175.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-175-small.png?w=550&#038;h=388" width="550" height="388" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 4</p></div>
<p>This image showing combined data is on disk here, dated 2010, the state of my knowledge then.</p>
<p>The upshot was I decided to take the newly indicated dataset at face value, see what if anything it had to tell.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">A second background</span></p>
<p>The fundamental law of Arctic ice variation is defined by earth polar inclination, earth orbit and a half sine from insolation variation. I have an incorrect blog article on this on my own blog <a href="http://daedalearth.wordpress.com/2011/04/30/how-polar-ice-is-modulated-by-the-sun/" target="_blank">How polar ice is modulated by the sun</a>. (I failed to point out inclination is involved)</p>
<p>All the time the earth is spinning once per day.</p>
<p>That little lot is a prime candidate for acting as a modulator mixing different things. The expected effect is amplitude modulation but I am not see DSB or anything clean. Perhaps this means the effect is not there, opinions welcome.</p>
<p>I am only trying to get across a gist.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Third background</span></p>
<p>Longstanding blog readers will know I use novel software to push past some of the conventional limitations in data analysis.</p>
<p>This software tries to precisely lock to items in a dataset.</p>
<p>A common idea is the annual cycle, and perhaps harmonics thereof, 0.5y, 0.25y etc. In most cases the fundamental and second harmonic is sufficient to account for ~99% of the annual cycle.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Into the mire</span></p>
<p>Is that all? I am coming to realise no it isn&#8217;t. I&#8217;ve often noticed this does not fully null out 1y and whilst I have sometimes looked this was mostly assumed to be mere annoyance of imperfection.</p>
<p>Devil in the detail, I&#8217;ve started looking very closely at these imperfections, all the alarm bells were ringing but I have chased around without seeing.</p>
<p>Many long datasets seem to show a variation in the amplitude of the annual cycle. Rather obviously if this is translated from the time domain into frequency domain it will appear as multiple spectral lines, perhaps a forest, or a spreading of pure lines, most very close in to the 1 year. (eg. 1.02 year equates to 100 year)</p>
<p>Unfortunately there are no tools or methods able to resolve this detail on available length data, the amplitudes are tiny. (don&#8217;t want to go into this now)</p>
<p>What I have now done is as best I can prise out the muddle of spectra to do with the annual cycle. Moreover this seems to be just as apt with many other datasets.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-176.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-176-small.png?w=550&#038;h=210" width="550" height="210" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 5</p></div>
<p>This shows just the annual but has a number of interfering terms with the effect the amplitude changes. (done as monthly to simply plotting)</p>
<p>The envelope as an rms level is shown in figure 1</p>
<p>A surprise for me was finding the infamous 2007 ice loss does not as I had assumed then produce an annual cycle regime change but is part of an ongoing gradual process. Figure 3 adds weight to this, 2007 shows as little more than short term isolated event.</p>
<p>Now since I have the model as a full transform it is time agnostic, I am already using this in the plots, daily input is being output monthly centred on month centres.</p>
<p>A question which arises is whether a model is sensibly stable outside of the data input time range. In this case yes and whilst caution is needed over validity the result suggests more data research is needed to find to evidence proving the posit is untrue, whether temperature variation of sea water / air are encoded and if so how.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-177.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-177-small.png?w=550&#038;h=135" width="550" height="135" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 6</p></div>
<p><strong>Please do not take figure 6 as more than illustrative of what might be the case if there was actual data, if it however as figure 1 and figure 5 over their time frame.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m afraid I haven&#8217;t finished yet, there is more.</p>
<p>Some kind of deduction can be made of how this variation is changing, the periodic terms if any. I have of course looked and have looked at other datasets. What appears are familiar long term numbers, ~67y, 23y, 45y, and so on. This is what suggests a modulation effect.</p>
<p>I could show DFT and what happens as items are subtracted out, part of a painstaking process. This adds little but here is ~70dB knocked out</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-178.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-178-small.png?w=550&#038;h=154" width="550" height="154" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Figure 7</p></div>
<p>I wish this was clearer but is the best I can do within the limitation of a short dataset, little more than 30 years.</p>
<p><strong>Note: for the purposes here I am ignoring other parts of the data and should not be taken as complete.</strong></p>
<p>Now how valid is that dataset?</p>
<p>At this stage I feel I know very little, neither is any of this confirmed, validated, safe so it must be taken as a curiosity for consideration.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure what is appropriate for supplied data. Maybe discuss, can always update the article.</p>
<p>Post by Tim Channon, co-moderator</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12026/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12026/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12026&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/arctic-sea-ice-experimental-decode-of-modulation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d21d6725f3925a85290ce54127b80d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-174-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-172-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-173-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-175-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-176-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-177-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-178-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The mystery of the vanishing cheap power source</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-mystery-of-the-vanishing-cheap-power-source/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-mystery-of-the-vanishing-cheap-power-source/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 12:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electro-magnetism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12037</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[20 years ago, I met two bright British engineers who had developed a superb piece of engineering technology. The setup was in two units about the size of steel lorry containers. One contained a fairly stock steam turbine and generator set, capable of producing around a Megawatt. The other unit contained their invention. It consisted [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12037&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tyres.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-12038" alt="tyres" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tyres.jpeg?w=614"   /></a>20 years ago, I met two bright British engineers who had developed a superb piece of engineering technology. The setup was in two units about the size of steel lorry containers. One contained a fairly stock steam turbine and generator set, capable of producing around a Megawatt. The other unit contained their invention. It consisted of a chain-link conveyor belt made from high quality chrome-vanadium steel, which ran through a chamber from which air was excluded. In this chamber, waste materials such as old car tyres were heated to very high temperatures without burning, due to the lack of oxygen.</p>
<p>Through the process of pyrolysis, the tyres would be reduced to their constituents, and the volatile combustible gases were transferred to a second chamber where they were combusted under very carefully controlled conditions. This enabled the combustion process to be very efficient.  The heat generated by the combustion was then run round the first chamber, generating the heat needed to perform the pyrolysis process on the following tyres, and from there to a heat exchanger where steam was developed to power the turbine, and spin the generating set to produce electricity.</p>
<p><span id="more-12037"></span>The real beauty of the system was that it not only generated electricity in useful quantities, but it did it with a waste product (worn out tyres) which are difficult to dispose of in other ways. The by product of the pyrolysis process was 93%pure carbon, for use in the printing industry, and high grade steel wire, which could be returned clean to the steelworks for reconversion into ingots or rolled stock. The conventional way of disposing of tyres is to guillotine them to pieces for landfill, an expensive and power hungry process. Rather than using electricity to dispose of tyres, the pyrocombustor generated a free Megawatt with 40 lorry tyres per hour.</p>
<p>The other big advantage of the adoption of their invention that the engineers foresaw, was that by spreading the systems countrywide, tyres could be disposed of locally, without high transport costs, and line transmission losses on the electricity grid would be minimised, because power was being generated close to where it is needed, rather than being transmitted from nuclear reactors at remote coastal locations or coal fired plant far up in the north of England miles out of the cities they serve.</p>
<p>It looked like a win-win proposition to me, and the engineers had got as far as negotiating contracts with Kwikfit, ATS and other tyre fitting services for the scrap tyres they were replacing on the country&#8217;s cars and lorries.</p>
<p>But there was a problem.</p>
<p>Although the emissions from the exhaust stack of the pyrocombustor were well within the standards set for small scale plant in force at the time, around 1984, new emissions regulations were in the pipeline from Brussels, due to fears about global warming and acid rain. Fears we sceptics have known to be overblown for many years. The pilot schemes the engineers had set up were subjected to endless delays, and eventually wrapped in so much red tape that they were driven out of business into bankruptcy.</p>
<p>Another company did lease their invention and set up a straw burning plant in Scotland, which was a lot less efficient, due to the much lower calorific value of the feedstock. I can&#8217;t find it on the web any more. The warm-mongers and nimbys successfully killed this promising process. Hunting around on the net today for snippets for this article, I found <a href="http://www.pyrolysisoil.net/">this Chinese company</a> building tyre pyrolising equipment for the recovery of oil. Yet another example of the way British innovation has been unnecessarily stifled while competitor nations move ahead with useful technology.</p>
<p>Of course, the big power companies and government dislike this sort of innovation, because it allows competition into the energy industry, and makes price fixing and hidden taxation more difficult. So it was in their interests to go along with the ridiculously stringent emissions targets set for newcomer technologies in the field, while they, as backbone established suppliers could be given free carbon credits for failing to meet those same standards, so long as they paid lip service by buying into the wind and photo-voltaic sectors.</p>
<p>I can feel some anglo-saxon phraseology welling up in me at this point so I&#8217;ll stop there.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12037/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12037/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12037&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-mystery-of-the-vanishing-cheap-power-source/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/tyres.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tyres</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Professor Roger Pielke Jr Snaps Marcott et al Hockeystick</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/professor-roger-pielke-jr-snaps-marcott-et-al-hockeystick/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/professor-roger-pielke-jr-snaps-marcott-et-al-hockeystick/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 07:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alarmism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Measurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marcott et al]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Mann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scientific misconduct]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12030</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hats off to Prof. Roger Pileke Jr, who has followed Steve McIntyre&#8217;s lead in standing up for science in the face of continued lies and scientific fraud. Here are some highlights from the post linked above: In 1991 the National Research Council proposed what has come to be a widely accepted definition of misconduct in science: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12030&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Hats off to Prof. Roger Pileke Jr, who has followed <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/">Steve McIntyre&#8217;s lead</a> in <a href="http://rogerpielkejr.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/fixing-marcott-mess-in-climate-science.html">standing up for science </a>in the face of continued lies and scientific fraud. Here are some highlights from the post linked above:</em></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/josh-paleo-rotten.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-12035" alt="josh-paleo-rotten" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/josh-paleo-rotten.jpg?w=614"   /></a>In 1991 the National Research Council proposed what has come to be a widely accepted definition of misconduct in science:<br />
Misconduct in science is defined as fabrication, falsification, or plagiarism, in proposing, performing, or reporting research. Misconduct in science does not include errors of judgment; errors in the recording, selection, or analysis of data; differences in opinions involving the interpretation of data; or misconduct unrelated to the research process.<br />
Arguments over data and methods are the lifeblood of science, and are not instances of misconduct.</p>
<p>However, here I document the gross misrepresentation of the findings of a recent scientific paper via press release which appears to skirt awfully close to crossing the line into research misconduct, as defined by the NRC. I recommend steps to fix this mess, saving face for all involved, and a chance for this small part of the climate community to take a step back toward unambiguous scientific integrity.</p>
<p><span id="more-12030"></span></p>
<p>The paper I refer to is by Marcott et al. 2013, published recently in Science. A press release issued by the National Science Foundation, which funded the research, explains the core methodology and key conclusion of the paper as follows (emphasis added):<br />
Peter Clark, an OSU paleoclimatologist and co-author of the Science paper, says that many previous temperature reconstructions were regional and not placed in a global context.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;When you just look at one part of the world, temperature history can be affected by regional climate processes like El Niño or monsoon variations,&#8221; says Clark.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;But when you combine data from sites around the world, you can average out those regional anomalies and get a clear sense of the Earth&#8217;s global temperature history.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>What that history shows, the researchers say, is that during the last 5,000 years, the Earth on average cooled about 1.3 degrees Fahrenheit&#8211;until the last 100 years, when it warmed about 1.3 degrees F.</strong><br />
The press release clearly explains that the paper (a) combines data from many sites around the world to create a &#8220;temperature reconstruction&#8221; which gives a &#8220;sense of the Earth&#8217;s temperature history,&#8221; and (b) &#8220;that history shows&#8221; a cooling over the past 5000 years, until the last 100 years when all of that cooling was reversed.</p>
<p>Here is Michael Lemonick at Climate Central:</p>
<blockquote><p>The study&#8230; confirms the now famous “hockey stick” graph that Michael Mann published more than a decade ago. That study showed a sharp upward temperature trend over the past century after more than a thousand years of relatively flat temperatures. . .<strong>“What’s striking,” said lead author Shaun Marcott of Oregon State University in an interview, “is that the records we use are completely independent, and produce the same result.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>In a belatedly-posted FAQ to the paper, which appeared on Real Climate earlier today, Marcott et al. make this startling admission:</p>
<blockquote><p>Q: What do paleotemperature reconstructions show about the temperature of the last 100 years?A: Our global paleotemperature reconstruction includes a so-called “uptick” in temperatures during the 20th-century. However, in the paper we make the point that this particular feature is of shorter duration than the inherent smoothing in our statistical averaging procedure, and that it is based on only a few available paleo-reconstructions of the type we used. Thus,<strong> the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Here are the steps that I recommend should be taken:</p>
<p>1) Science should issue a correction to the paper, and specially do the following:</p>
<p>(a) retract and replot all figures in the paper and SI eliminating from the graphs all data/results that fail to meet the paper&#8217;s criteria for &#8220;statistical robustness.&#8221;<br />
(b) include in the correction the explicit and unambiguous statement offered in the FAQ released today that the analysis is not &#8220;statistically robust&#8221; post-1900.</p>
<p>2) NSF should issue a correction to its press release, clarifying and correcting the statements of Peter Clark (a co-author, found above) and Candace Major, NSF program manager, who says in the release:<br />
&#8220;The last century stands out as the anomaly in this record of global temperature since the end of the last ice age,&#8221; says Candace Major, program director in the National Science Foundation&#8217;s (NSF) Division of Ocean Sciences.<br />
3) The New York Times (Gillis and Revkin, in particular), Nature and New Scientist as outlets that pride themselves in accurate reporting of science should update their stories with corrections. Grist and Climate Central should consider the same.</p>
<p>In comments, Professor Pielke says:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>I interact with climate scientists just about every day (being in CIRES, a leading global institute). There are an awful lot of people doing very good work.</strong></p>
<p><strong>There are a few bad eggs, with the Real Climate mafia being among them, who are exploiting climate science for personal and political gain. Makes the whole effort look bad.</strong></p>
<p><strong>That said, virtually all of the climate science battles are teapot/tempest affairs &#8212; climate politics and policy has moved on to issues involving economics and energy.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">________________________________________</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I have to disagree with Prof. Pielke on that last point. It is the tacit assumption that the paleoclimatology of institutions such as the Climate Research Unit at the University of East Anglia and Penn State University is inimpeachable that underpins the whole notion of &#8220;It&#8217;s unprecedented &#8211; we must act&#8221;, that has been pushed into the political and economic arena by activist groups such as Friends of the Earth and the World Wildlife Fund and Greenpeace. These organisations have infiltrated the IPCC, the civil service, the Department of Energy and Climate Change, the house of commons, and the house of lords.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">As Steve McIntyre notes in the post <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/">linked in the intro</a>, Marcott et al still haven&#8217;t &#8216;fessed up to the most egregious aspect of their paper, and are attempting to smoke screen the whole affair with a partial admission of the paper&#8217;s shortcomings.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The rot must be stopped, and chopped out before the disease spreads further.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12030/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12030/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12030&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/professor-roger-pielke-jr-snaps-marcott-et-al-hockeystick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/josh-paleo-rotten.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">josh-paleo-rotten</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
