<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Cutting edge science you can dice with</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:32:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='tallbloke.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Open Rights Group: Monday Deadline for UK Bloggers to Avert Internet Crackdown</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/open-rights-group-monday-deadline-for-uk-bloggers-to-avert-internet-crackdown/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/open-rights-group-monday-deadline-for-uk-bloggers-to-avert-internet-crackdown/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11774</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We need to act quickly. Please visit this website and sign up: http://www.openrightsgroup.org/campaigns/leveson Don&#8217;t clobber bloggers with Leveson Lord Leveson’s regulations are being applied to UK websites – in ways that could catch more or less anyone who publishes a blog. Ordinary bloggers could be threatened with exemplary damages and costs. If this happens, small website [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11774&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><em>We need to act quickly. Please visit this website and sign up:</em> <a href="http://www.openrightsgroup.org/campaigns/leveson">http://www.openrightsgroup.org/campaigns/leveson<br />
</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Don&#8217;t clobber bloggers with Leveson</strong></p>
<p>Lord Leveson’s regulations are being applied to UK websites – in ways that could catch more or less anyone who publishes a blog. Ordinary bloggers could be threatened with exemplary damages and costs. If this happens, small website publishers will face terrible risks, or burdensome regulation – and many may simply stop publishing.</p>
<p>We have until Monday to stop this happening.</p>
<p>Lord Leveson said he wanted to regulate print media. He proposed that judges be allowed to award exemplary damages and full costs against unregulated publishers. These are stringent and controversial measures, but he only envisaged them applying to large and powerful publishers. Not websites, unless they belonged to print publishers.</p>
<p>Last weekend, the proposals were agreed in a rush, without public consultation, and with no attention to the detail.</p>
<p>Outrageously, they have given the Lords until Monday to fix their mistakes.</p>
<p><span id="more-11774"></span></p>
<p>The result is that they apply to any size of web publisher – if there’s more than one author, the content is edited and there’s a business involved, then you must join a self regulator.</p>
<p>Most blogs like this aren’t powerful publishing houses. Even ORGZine would need to be regulated, or face punitive measures if it ended up in court.</p>
<p>The threat of websites being regulated like this was never the purpose of Lord Leveson’s recommendations. Websites weren’t involved in phone hacking. There is no evidence that they need to be forced into self-regulation like this.</p>
<p>We need you to email Nick Clegg, Harriet Harman, and David Cameron to ask them to back off and leave the Internet out of Leveson.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11774/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11774/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11774&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/open-rights-group-monday-deadline-for-uk-bloggers-to-avert-internet-crackdown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roy Martin: How do the planets affect the Sun &#8211; Updated</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/roy-martin-how-do-the-planets-affect-the-sun-updated/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/roy-martin-how-do-the-planets-affect-the-sun-updated/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 09:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cycles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tides]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11770</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My thanks again to Roy Martin who has done a substantial re-write of the paper he presented here a fortnight ago in response to the feedback he received here at the Talkshop.  How do the planets affect the Sun ? By Roy Martin Jan 5, 2013 Revised March 17, 2013 “Knowledge is about as durable as [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11770&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>My thanks again to Roy Martin who has done a substantial re-write of the <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/roy-martin-how-do-the-planets-affect-the-sun/">paper he presented here a fortnight ago</a> in response to the feedback he received here at the Talkshop. </em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>How do the planets affect the Sun ?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;" align="center">By Roy Martin Jan 5, 2013<br />
<em id="__mceDel">Revised March 17, 2013</em></p>
<p align="center"><i>“Knowledge is about as durable as green cheese.” </i>anon.<i></i></p>
<p> The barycentric motion of the Sun and the tidal forces acting on the Sun are both caused by the motion of the orbiting planets. This note was written to illustrate the differences between the combination of gravitational forces that cause the barycentric motion of the sun and the tidal forces believed to act principally on it&#8217;s surface layers. The first section was to be part of the introduction to a report about further work done on the tidal influence of the planets on solar activity, however it led to a few interesting, but quite unrelated observations about the synodic relationships between the planets and the José cycle, which would have been out of context there, so I have put them into this stand-alone note. As far as I know there is nothing fundamentally new here, just a somewhat different perspective on some older knowledge.</p>
<p>There is an intricate overlapping of features in the two phenomena, and yet they create distinctly different landscapes. This note aims to describe the differences and similarities relevant to my own studies, but they are possibly relevant to other on-going investigations and discussions surrounding the mechanisms by which the planets may effect both the solar cycle and the motion of the Sun about the barycentre.</p>
<p><span id="more-11770"></span>There is significant scope for confusion between the potential effects of the two causes. At least since the publication of José&#8217;s 1965 paper: &#8221;Sun&#8217;s Motion and Sunspots&#8221;, barycentric motion, or solar inertial motion (SIM), has been studied extensively. Many apparent correlations with events on earth and human activity have been identified, but most of those I have examined in any detail have failed to satisfy close scrutiny. The absence of any provable mechanism by which SIM caused by the planets can affect solar activity remains a major objection. SIM is fundamentally a whole-of-body effect, and as such none of the accelerations imposed on the Sun while orbiting the barycentre can differentially affect separate regions. Theories based on spin-orbit coupling appear to come up against the same objections.</p>
<p>During the same period, the possibility that tidal effects could affect solar activity was rejected and largely ignored, but in the last few years increased attention is being directed to this possibility. There is active reseach into suggested mechanisms, and in my own work I have identified close correlations between planetary induced tidal forces and the solar cycle. I now suspect that many of the correlations previously attributed to presumed SIM effects may be due to tidal effects occurring simultaneously.</p>
<p>We need to look at how each individual planet plays quite a different role in relation to SIM compared with tidal forces that may influence solar activity.</p>
<p>Figure 1. below is presented to show the relative effects of the major and minor planets, due to both the gravitational forces that cause barycentric motion, and the tidal effects which many are coming to believe are more likely to affect solar activity. The data plotted is from very simple physics, calculated using the basic formulae for gravitional and tidal forces. It is possible, even likely, that orbital eccentricity and inclination affect both to some extent, but are omitted from this analysis. I reason that if either gravitational or tidal effects are involved in modifying solar activity, it will first have to be shown and proved that the major primary forces due to one or the other are the principal cause. The individual bars represent the percentages of the total of the fully aligned planets.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig1_all_planets_combined_01.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11528" alt="Fig1_All_planets_combined_01" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig1_all_planets_combined_01.jpg?w=614&#038;h=380" width="614" height="380" /></a></p>
<p>Figure 1.</p>
<p>It can be seen from Fig.1 and Table 1. that the planets may be viewed as two overlapping groups:</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table1_planets_gravitational__tidal_groups.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11532" alt="Table1_Planets_gravitational_&amp;_tidal_groups" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table1_planets_gravitational__tidal_groups.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<p>Table 1.</p>
<p>The gravitational group includes Saturn but not Mercury. The tidal group includes Mercury but not Saturn.</p>
<p>The relative magnitudes show the basic differences between the two groups. Jupiter and Saturn dominate the gravitational group, and Jupiter alone accounts for 74% of the total. How these two combine with Uranus and Neptune to create SIM will be looked at a more closely further on. Mercury, Venus, Earth and Jupiter cause 97.8% of the tidal forces, but the component from Jupiter is only 34.7%, which is nearly matched by Venus at 33%. The relative role of Mercury changes from 2.3% to 14.6%, almost equal to that of Earth, and thus has the potential to be a significant influence on tidal effects. The tidal group will be studied in much more detail in another note.</p>
<p>We should observe here that the planets do not exist in isolation. It is far too easy to become fixated on one of them as the sole or principal cause of an observed phenomena. Jupiter is a prime candidate for such attention because the orbital period is so close to that of the solar cycle, and it does play a big part in both sets, but in real life it is “&#8230;just a player in a rock and roll band.”</p>
<p>But we need to look at the basic forces in conjunction with the synodic periods between the various planets. Table 2. lists the relevant relationships, and we are immediately confronted by the problem that the network of interconnections between the gravitational and tidal planets is so complex that it can lead to the illusion that one is the cause of observed effects, when it is really the other.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table2_synodic_periods_table_01.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11526" alt="Table2_Synodic_periods_table_01" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table2_synodic_periods_table_01.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<p>Table 2.</p>
<p>In the gravitational group, the dominant synodic period is between Jupiter and Saturn, with a period of 19.8650 years. The 19.8650 x 9 = 178.7853 year multiple is of primary importance, because it appears to be the nominal period underlying the José cycle. I have therefore used it as a base period for comparisons. As shown in the table, the synodic periods of the major planets are all harmonically connected to the nominal 178.8 year period, the consequences of which can lead to endless discussion. Note the small differences between the 178.785 year nominal José cycle length and the nearest multiples for J-V, J-E and V-E.</p>
<p>The gravitational forces from Mercury, Mars, Uranus and Neptune are relatively small, but are included to show that their orbits also appear to be harmonically linked to the José cycle.</p>
<p>I tend to scepticism when claims are made that because a value is &#8216;close to&#8217; another it implies justification for causation, but here the José cycle correlations for all of the significant planets except Uranus are within +/- 0.2%, and it seems to me this is too close to ignore.</p>
<p>Similarly, we need to be cautious about numbers like the multiples of the synodic periods, because a given number can often be factored in different ways. Should these numbers be accepted as meaningful at all? In this case the factors are all about primes and Fibonacci numbers. We have six of the early primes: 2;3;5;7;11;13, the sum of which is 41, and 2;3;5;13 are also Fibonacci numbers. The sum of the alternate primes 3;7;13 is 23. Within the solar system, such relationships are often observed, and support other observations of the exquisite mathematical balance between planetary orbitital periods. I believe they can be taken seriously.</p>
<p>(Note: The multiple for Mercury could also be taken as 452, with factors 113 x 2<sup>2</sup>, giving the product 178.902 years. Take your pick, the difference matters little here.)</p>
<p>The harmonics of the Venus and Earth synodics are found to form a cycle 22.38 years long, which is very close indeed to one eighth of the José cycle. The derivation of the 22.38 year cycle is shown in Table 3. which further extends the relationships between the synodic periods. These relationships appear as important in studies of the possible effects of planetary tidal forces on the Sun:-</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table3_synodics__22-38_year_cycle_01.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11527" alt="Table3_Synodics_&amp;_22.38_year_cycle_01" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table3_synodics__22-38_year_cycle_01.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<p>Table 3.</p>
<p>With regard to Ref.1.), by reference back to the multiples in Table 2., we find that for Jupiter-Venus, 276/8 = 34.5; for Jupiter-Earth, 164/8 = 20.5, and the difference between them is 14, the multiple for Venus-Earth. And just for the fun of it, from the set of factors: (3&#215;23)/2 = 34.5,  41/2 = 20.5,  and 34.5x(2/3) = 21.  The half cycle difference plus and minus from a Fibonnaci number emerges as relevant in the plots of tidal forces on the Sun.</p>
<p>With regard to Ref.2.), the multiple differs very slightly from 11.0. The small adjustment was necessary to reconcile the 12.0037 year cycle period with the value derived from two separate studies on tidal effects. (The precise period is 0.648846 x (37/2) = 12.00365.)</p>
<p>In the context of the orbit of the Sun around the barycentre, the most important observation is one of the simplest, that nine J-S synodic periods are the dominant cause of the variation of the radius, as can be seen clearly in a plot of radius vs. time in Fig.2. This type of plot is a rather flat-earth way of presenting solar motion, but it shows the longer term temporal relationships much better than multiple polar plots. The J-U and J-N synodics combine to modulate both the amplitude of the radius and the peak-to-peak timing of the nine waves within each José cycle of 178.8 years. The pattern is very close to an exact repeat within the two cycles plotted here, and the near repetition is also seen in the previous three full cycles.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig2_sun_radius_from_barycentre_1700_2100_01.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11529" alt="Fig2_Sun_radius_from_barycentre_1700_2100_01" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig2_sun_radius_from_barycentre_1700_2100_01.jpg?w=614&#038;h=356" width="614" height="356" /></a></p>
<p>Figure 2.</p>
<p>While Figure 1. illustrates the relative forces acting between each planet and the Sun, that does not reveal the actual effect each planet has on the movement of the Sun about the barycentre: The relationships in a simple two body system of rotating bodies in space is given by the expression: M<sub>p </sub>x R<sub>p</sub> = M <sub>s</sub>x R<sub>s</sub>, where M<sub>p</sub> &amp; M<sub>s</sub> are the masses of the planet and Sun, and R<sub>p</sub> &amp; R<sub>s</sub> are their respective radii from the common barycentre. As a means of illustrating the potential effect of each planet, the barycentric radius of the Sun has been calculated for each separate planet – Sun combination. These are shown in Figure 3.:</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig3_sun_barycentric_radius_-_separate_planets_01.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11771" alt="Fig3_Sun_barycentric_radius_-_Separate_planets_01" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig3_sun_barycentric_radius_-_separate_planets_01.jpg?w=614&#038;h=323" width="614" height="323" /></a><br />
Figure 3.</p>
<p>The dominant effect of Jupiter and Saturn is quite clear, but the effect of Uranus and Neptune is much greater than the gravitational forces acting would indicate. This is because of their very large orbital radii. The figures also show that the planets Venus, Earth, Mars, Pluto (and Mercury), can have only a very small effect on the barycentric motion of the Sun.</p>
<p>Figure 4. was drawn to illustrate the combining of three sine waves: the basic 19.865 year period J-S synodic cycle, plus the 13.813 year period J-U synodic cycle and the 12.783 year period J-N synodic cycle, phased as close as possible to the times of observed conjunctions, and scaled in approximately the same ratio as the separate planets barycentric radii shown above. This plot is disarmingly simple, yet it almost matches the plot of actual solar radii for the 1722 to 1901 period in Figure 2.above. Note that it is not possible to reproduce the plot exactly with simple sine waves because of the way the Sun actually orbits the barycentre.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig4_sun_radius_from_barycentre_9_13_14_02.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11772" alt="Fig4_Sun_radius_from_barycentre_9_13_14_02" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig4_sun_radius_from_barycentre_9_13_14_02.jpg?w=614&#038;h=479" width="614" height="479" /></a></p>
<p>Figure 4.</p>
<p>During the three cycles centred on the start and end dates at 1722 and 1901 the Sun traces successive orbits at a relatively large radius from the barycentre, then every second cycle during the middle six periods the Sun moves through tight loops passing close to the barycentre. The movement of the Sun during the middle six is thus somewhat different. The motion in tight loops causing the Sun to move almost radially to the barycentre, which is why the effect cannot be simulated with simple sine waves.</p>
<p>However, Figure 4. serves to emphasize the main point of this note; that there is a clear distinction between the effect on the Sun of the &#8216;gravitational&#8217; outer planets, and the &#8216;tidal&#8217; inner planets, Mercury, Venus, and Earth, noting however, that Jupiter plays a significant role in both.</p>
<p>To summarize: the synodic periods between the planets are shared between their gravitational and tidal influences on the Sun, but whereas the Jupiter-Saturn relationship dominates SIM, Venus-Earth-Jupiter relationships dominate the solar cycle scale tidal effects, with Mercury influencing some shorter term effects. Although some solar and terrestrial phenomena appear to correlate with SIM, the correlations are only partial and, to the best of my understanding, have no known physical connection.</p>
<p>I intend to cover the tidal influences more fully in later notes. They are proving to be a much more productive area of study. Suffice to say briefly in conclusion here; that tidal influences appear to correlate very closely with solar phenomena and with consequent effects on terrestrial phenomena.</p>
<p>As a footnote: In the work on the tidal theory there is a very significant cycle of 110.3 years. It is interesting to note that 110.3 x 1.61803(phi) = 178.48 years, within 0.31 years of the nominal José cycle period as derived above from the Jupiter – Saturn synodic.</p>
<p>It should also be mentioned that the work done in preparing the notes on the barycentric motion of the Sun may help us to clarify what rotates about what in the solar system.</p>
<p>__________________________________________________________________-</p>
<p>Credit: Figure 2.) was plotted using the ephemeris derived from JPL data by Carl Smith, available at <a href="http://landscheidt.wordpress.com/">http://landscheidt.wordpress.com/</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11770/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11770/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11770&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/roy-martin-how-do-the-planets-affect-the-sun-updated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig1_all_planets_combined_01.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fig1_All_planets_combined_01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table1_planets_gravitational__tidal_groups.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Table1_Planets_gravitational_&#38;_tidal_groups</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table2_synodic_periods_table_01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Table2_Synodic_periods_table_01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/table3_synodics__22-38_year_cycle_01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Table3_Synodics_&#38;_22.38_year_cycle_01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig2_sun_radius_from_barycentre_1700_2100_01.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fig2_Sun_radius_from_barycentre_1700_2100_01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig3_sun_barycentric_radius_-_separate_planets_01.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fig3_Sun_barycentric_radius_-_Separate_planets_01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fig4_sun_radius_from_barycentre_9_13_14_02.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fig4_Sun_radius_from_barycentre_9_13_14_02</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inventors Geim and Novoselov Hit the Big Time: Graphene Purifies Seawater</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/inventors-geim-and-novoselov-hit-the-big-time-graphene-purifies-seawater/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/inventors-geim-and-novoselov-hit-the-big-time-graphene-purifies-seawater/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 22:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11764</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Flashback to 2010: The prestigious 2010 Nobel Prize for Physics was announced today (October 5), with the prize going to Andre Geim and Konstantin Novoselov, both from the University of Manchester for their work on the development of graphene. Graphene is a sheet of carbon that is a single atom thick. It is the most [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11764&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><em><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/graphene.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11765" alt="graphene" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/graphene.jpeg?w=614"   /></a>Flashback to 2010:</em></p>
<p>The prestigious 2010 Nobel Prize for Physics was announced today (October 5), with the prize going to Andre Geim and Konstantin Novoselov, both from the University of Manchester for their work on the development of graphene.</p>
<p>Graphene is a sheet of carbon that is a single atom thick. It is the most efficient conductor of heat known and it conducts electricity as effectively as copper. It is completely transparent, but dense enough to trap helium.</p>
<p>So how did they do it? Gigantic particle accelerator? Interstellar observatory? Witchcraft? None of the above. They used a piece of sticky tape and a pencil to remove a flake of the carbon in the pencil that was one atom thick. Seriously.<br />
________________________________</p>
<p><em>Fastforward to 2013:</em><br />
(Reuters) &#8211; A defense contractor better known for building jet fighters and lethal missiles says it has found a way to slash the amount of energy needed to remove salt from seawater, potentially making it vastly cheaper to produce clean water at a time when scarcity has become a global security issue.</p>
<p>The process, officials and engineers at Lockheed Martin Corp say, would enable filter manufacturers to produce thin carbon membranes with regular holes about a nanometer in size that are large enough to allow water to pass through but small enough to block the molecules of salt in seawater. A nanometer is a billionth of a meter.</p>
<p>Because the sheets of pure carbon known as graphene are so thin &#8211; just one atom in thickness &#8211; it takes much less energy to push the seawater through the filter with the force required to separate the salt from the water, they said.</p>
<p><span id="more-11764"></span></p>
<p>The development could spare underdeveloped countries from having to build exotic, expensive pumping stations needed in plants that use a desalination process called reverse osmosis.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s 500 times thinner than the best filter on the market today and a thousand times stronger,&#8221; said John Stetson, the engineer who has been working on the idea. &#8220;The energy that&#8217;s required and the pressure that&#8217;s required to filter salt is approximately 100 times less.&#8221;</p>
<p>Access to clean drinking water is increasingly seen as a major global security issue. Competition for water is likely to lead to instability and potential state failure in countries important to the United States, according to a U.S. intelligence community report last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;Between now and 2040, fresh water availability will not keep up with demand absent more effective management of water resources,&#8221; the report said. &#8220;Water problems will hinder the ability of key countries to produce food and generate electricity.&#8221;</p>
<p>About 780 million people around the world do not have access to clean drinking water, the United Nations reported last year.</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the areas that we&#8217;re very concerned about in terms of global security is the access to clean and affordable drinking water,&#8221; said Tom Notaro, Lockheed business manager for advanced materials. &#8220;As more and more countries become more developed &#8230; access to that water for their daily lives is becoming more and more critical.&#8221;</p>
<p>PRODUCTION CHALLENGE</p>
<p>Lockheed still faces a number of challenges in moving to production of filters made of graphene, a substance similar to the lead in pencils. Working with the thin material without tearing it is difficult, as is ramping up production to the size and scale needed. Engineers are still refining the process for making the holes.</p>
<p>It is not known whether Lockheed faces commercial competition in this area. But it is not the only one working on the technology.</p>
<p>Jeffrey Grossman, an associate professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology who has done research on graphene membranes for filtration, said he was not familiar with details of Lockheed&#8217;s work. But he said finding a way to produce graphene sheets with nanometer-sized holes could produce a major advancement in desalination efficiency.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you can design a membrane that&#8217;s completely different than what we use today, then there&#8217;s a chance for more than two orders of magnitude (100 times) increase in the permeability of the membrane,&#8221; Grossman said.</p>
<p>Stetson, who began working on the issue in 2007, said if the new filter material, known as Perforene, was compared to the thickness of a piece of paper, the nearest comparable filter for extracting salt from seawater would be the thickness of three reams of paper &#8211; more than half a foot thick.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/13/us-usa-desalination-idUSBRE92C05720130313">Read the rest here.</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11764/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11764/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11764&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/inventors-geim-and-novoselov-hit-the-big-time-graphene-purifies-seawater/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/graphene.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">graphene</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chilbolton: unusual acoustic conditions</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/chilbolton-unusual-acoustic-conditions/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/chilbolton-unusual-acoustic-conditions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tchannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[atmosphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surfacestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11756</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chilbolton is about 30km from here and generally will share similar conditions. Report for 19th March. I went outside around 13 hrs, some clouds, maybe 4/8 and some sunshine. What struck me as very unusual was clear and quite loud sound from high flying jets, no contrails. Managed to spot a couple, high but not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11756&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;" align="center"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-556.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-556-small.jpg?w=550&#038;h=211" width="550" height="211" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.stfc.ac.uk/Chilbolton/weather/24987.aspx">Chilbolton</a> is about 30km from here and generally will share similar conditions.</p>
<p>Report for <strong>19th March</strong>.</p>
<p>I went outside around 13 hrs, some clouds, maybe 4/8 and some sunshine. What struck me as very unusual was clear and quite loud sound from high flying jets, no contrails. Managed to spot a couple, high but not very high.</p>
<p>Something unusual was going on with atmospheric layering / humidity. Otherwise a mixed weather day with rain late afternoon.</p>
<p><span id="more-11756"></span></p>
<p>Unfortunately Ch. radar was not operating but Lidar was, showing some unusual patterns.</p>
<p>Data archive for the 19th is <a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/chilbolton-2013-03-19.zip">here</a> (radar image is marked 18th, ignore)</p>
<p>Larkhill radiosonde was working, not at 12hrs though<br />
Skew-T PDF [1]  <a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sounding-1.pdf">here</a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-167.png"><img alt="Image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-167-small.png?w=550&#038;h=183" width="550" height="183" /></a></p>
<p>The pyrgeometer continues flapping dependent on cloud. (Lidar plot might need magnifying to see low level cover)</p>
<p>Bundled whole archive is <a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/chilbolton-16feb-19mar-2013.zip">here </a>(3.2M)</p>
<p>1. <a href="http://weather.uwyo.edu/upperair/sounding.html">http://weather.uwyo.edu/upperair/sounding.html</a><br />
Station 03743</p>
<hr />
<p>Post by Tim Channon</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11756/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11756/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11756&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/chilbolton-unusual-acoustic-conditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d21d6725f3925a85290ce54127b80d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-556-small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image-167-small.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>University of East Anglia Attempts to Put Frighteners on Tallbloke</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/university-of-east-anglia-attempts-to-put-frighteners-on-tallbloke/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/university-of-east-anglia-attempts-to-put-frighteners-on-tallbloke/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 20:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alarmism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11748</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve received an unsolicited email purporting to be from a legal firm claiming to represent the University of East Anglia. I&#8217;d be grateful if a lawyer with DPA experience, sympathetic to the public interest nature of the case, would get in touch here, with a view to forming a professional legal response to this communication [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11748&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>I&#8217;ve received an unsolicited email purporting to be from a legal firm claiming to represent the University of East Anglia. I&#8217;d be grateful if a lawyer with DPA experience, sympathetic to the public interest nature of the case, would get in touch here, with a view to forming a professional legal response to this communication &#8211; Thanks, TB.</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________</p>
<p>Dear Sir<br />
We act for the University of East Anglia and attach a response to your recent blog posts about a password supplied by &#8216;Mr FOIA&#8217;.<br />
&lt;&lt;Data Protection Act.pdf&gt;&gt;<br />
<strong>[Redacted]</strong><br />
Associate<br />
for Mills &amp; Reeve LLP</p>
<p>_____________________________________________________</p>
<p><em>The content of the attachment is reproduced below the break. Unusually, It has no header, no signature, no indication of provenance at all. My good lady and I have already been <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/12/14/tallbloke-towers-raided-many-computers-taken/">put through the wringer once</a>, and we don&#8217;t scare so easily anymore.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/tallbloke_towers_scr.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-3835" alt="tallbloke_towers_scr" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/tallbloke_towers_scr.jpg?w=614&#038;h=522" width="614" height="522" /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-11748"></span><br />
Dear Sir<br />
We understand from a blog post made by you on 12 March 2013 that you have either<br />
received an unsolicited email from someone going by the name of ‘Mr FOIA’ or that this has<br />
been forwarded to you. The email from Mr FOIA provides a password to access a<br />
substantial number of documents. It is our understanding from the blog postings which we<br />
have seen that the password does work and that the information can be accessed. We do<br />
not know what information has been made available in this way but have a very real concern<br />
that it may include ‘personal data’. This is data which, under the Data Protection Act 1998,<br />
might enable the identification of a living individual and which is strictly regulated under the<br />
provisions of the Act. Unlike previous releases, and from what we understand from the<br />
publication of Mr FOIA’s email, the information appears to have been left entirely unredacted<br />
or filtered in any way.<br />
The information contained in these document is likely to have been illegally obtained from<br />
the University’s servers in October 2009. The on-going dissemination of any ‘personal data’<br />
obtained in this way would amount to a further criminal offence. Given that the sharing of<br />
the password would enable any third party to access any of the documents there is a very<br />
real danger that personal data will be disclosed in breach of the Data Protection Act.<br />
The University has no desire to stifle debate around climate change but the University must<br />
take steps where information has been obtained illegally and to protect employees and<br />
students at the University as well as third parties from unnecessary harm arising from the<br />
unregulated and widespread disclosure of personal data.<br />
Accordingly, please confirm by return:<br />
• That you will not publish the password with which you have been provided nor the<br />
information it protects<br />
• That you will forward a copy of this notice to any person to whom you have supplied<br />
the password<br />
• That you will not publish any ‘personal data’.<br />
If you are in doubt about what is meant by ‘personal data’ then please follow the attached<br />
link to the Data Protection Act. Please note in particular the provisions of section 17, 21 and<br />
55. <a href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1998/29/contents">http://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1998/29/contents</a></p>
<p>______________________________________________________</p>
<p>Section 55 of the Data Protection Act states:</p>
<p>Unlawful obtaining etc. of personal data.</p>
<p>(1)<br />
A person must not knowingly or recklessly, without the consent of the data controller—</p>
<p>(a)<br />
obtain or disclose personal data or the information contained in personal data, or</p>
<p>(b)<br />
procure the disclosure to another person of the information contained in personal data.</p>
<p>(2)<br />
Subsection (1) does not apply to a person who shows—</p>
<p>(a)<br />
that the obtaining, disclosing or procuring—</p>
<p>(i)<br />
was necessary for the purpose of preventing or detecting crime, or</p>
<p>(ii)<br />
was required or authorised by or under any enactment, by any rule of law or by the order of a court,</p>
<p>(b)<br />
that he acted in the reasonable belief that he had in law the right to obtain or disclose the data or information or, as the case may be, to procure the disclosure of the information to the other person,</p>
<p>(c)<br />
that he acted in the reasonable belief that he would have had the consent of the data controller if the data controller had known of the obtaining, disclosing or procuring and the circumstances of it, or</p>
<p>(d)<br />
<strong>that in the particular circumstances the obtaining, disclosing or procuring was justified as being in the public interest.</strong></p>
<p>________________________________________________</p>
<p>I personally believe that disclosure of any relevant content of the material is justified in the public interest, given the billions of pounds of public money spent on the climate scare maintained since the start of the Climategate email chain. Early in that chain, Michael Mann&#8217;s paleoclimatology work, including the infamous &#8216;Hockey Stick&#8217; used to scare policy makers into great expense on the public&#8217;s behalf, is described as &#8216;crap&#8217; by other scientists who nonetheless did not speak up in public to allay the fears of impending climate doom it engendered. This is just one example of why the public has a right to know what went on behind the scenes at the heart of the Climate Research Unit and within the IPCC process.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll stand up for the public, because I know the public will stand up for me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11748/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11748/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11748&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/university-of-east-anglia-attempts-to-put-frighteners-on-tallbloke/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>107</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/tallbloke_towers_scr.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke_towers_scr</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indonesian Official Compares WWF to Thieves</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/11747/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/11747/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/11747/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reblogged from NoFrakkingConsensus: The behaviour of green NGOs in the developing word resembles foreign adventurism: arrogant, reckless, and exploitative. Just in time for Earth Hour this coming Saturday - that annual feel-good, accomplish-little World Wildlife Fund (WWF) event - a news story in the Jakarta Globe quotes Firman Subagyo, the head of the forestry commission [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11747&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="reblog-post"><p class="reblog-from"><img alt='' src='http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5a16d4fadc84f59117e93dae8c8e638d?s=25&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G' class='avatar avatar-25' height='25' width='25' /> <a href="http://nofrakkingconsensus.com/2013/03/19/indonesian-official-compares-wwf-to-thieves/">Reblogged from NoFrakkingConsensus:</a></p><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt"><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt-content"><p dir='auto'>
<a href="http://nofrakkingconsensus.com/2013/03/19/indonesian-official-compares-wwf-to-thieves/" target="_self"><img src="http://s0.wp.com/imgpress?url=http%3A%2F%2Fassets.wwf.org.uk%2Fimg%2Foriginal%2Fcarousel_001.jpg&w=614" alt="Click to visit the original post" class="size-full" /></a>
</p><p><em>The behaviour of green NGOs in the developing word resembles foreign adventurism: arrogant, reckless, and exploitative.</em></p>

<p>Just in time for Earth Hour this coming Saturday - that annual <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/health_and_science/project_syndicate/2013/03/earth_hour_is_all_wrong_we_need_more_electricity_not_less.html?google_editors_picks=true">feel-good, accomplish-little</a> World Wildlife Fund (WWF) event - a news story in the <a href="http://www.thejakartaglobe.com/nvironment/wwf-comes-under-fire-over-continued-riau-forest-clearing/580270"><em>Jakarta Globe</em></a> quotes Firman Subagyo, the head of the forestry commission for that country's House of Representatives:</p>
<blockquote><p>Foreign NGOs like the&hellip;</p></blockquote>

</div> <p class="read-more"><a href="http://nofrakkingconsensus.com/2013/03/19/indonesian-official-compares-wwf-to-thieves/" target="_self"><span>Read more&hellip;</span> 384 more words</a></p></div></div><div class="reblogger-note"><div class='reblogger-note-content'>
Donna Laframboise kicks over the rotting log of corruption hiding the big NGO's activities in poor countries.
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/11747/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking: EDF get go ahead for new nukes at Hinkley</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/breaking-edf-get-go-ahead-for-new-nuke-at-hinkley/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/breaking-edf-get-go-ahead-for-new-nuke-at-hinkley/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuclear power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That&#8217;ll please the no dash for gas protestors then&#8230; HT to Roger Harrabin for this tweet: Davey says 69% of DECC budget being spent on #nuclear clean-up. Promises that #Hinkley strike price will include clean-up costs. — roger harrabin (@RHarrabin) March 19, 2013 http://news.sky.com/story/1066793/hinkley-point-nuclear-plant-given-go-ahead A new  nuclear plant will be built at Hinkley Point in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11735&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>That&#8217;ll please the no dash for gas protestors then&#8230;<br />
HT to Roger Harrabin for this tweet:<br />
</em></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>Davey says 69% of DECC budget being spent on <a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23nuclear">#nuclear</a> clean-up. Promises that <a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23Hinkley">#Hinkley</a> strike price will include clean-up costs.</p>
<p>— roger harrabin (@RHarrabin) <a href="https://twitter.com/RHarrabin/status/314009837199560704">March 19, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nuke-power.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-6962" alt="nuke-power" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nuke-power.jpg?w=614"   /></a><a href="http://news.sky.com/story/1066793/hinkley-point-nuclear-plant-given-go-ahead" rel="nofollow">http://news.sky.com/story/1066793/hinkley-point-nuclear-plant-given-go-ahead</a></p>
<p>A new  nuclear plant will be built at Hinkley Point in Somerset after Energy Secretary Ed Davey granted planning permission.</p>
<p>The development of Hinkley Point C by French energy company EDF is a boost for the nuclear industry following a series of setbacks in plans to construct a new fleet of reactors in the UK, which ministers say are needed to cut carbon and keep the lights on.</p>
<p><span id="more-11735"></span>The permission for 3260MW of generation will be fulfilled with two European Pressurized Water Reactors. Hinkley is situated on the Severn Estuary in the southwest of England.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uk-nuke-map.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11745" alt="uk-nuke-map" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uk-nuke-map.jpg?w=614&#038;h=786" width="614" height="786" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11735/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11735/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11735&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/breaking-edf-get-go-ahead-for-new-nuke-at-hinkley/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nuke-power.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nuke-power</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uk-nuke-map.jpg?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">uk-nuke-map</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internet at risk: UK Govt. wants new press regulation to apply to bloggers too</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/internet-at-risk-uk-govt-wants-new-press-regulation-to-apply-to-bloggers-too/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/internet-at-risk-uk-govt-wants-new-press-regulation-to-apply-to-bloggers-too/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 23:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11727</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is much consternation about the outcome of the Levenson Report. Nick Cohen at the Spectator has a good article up on the subject: It’s not a press regulator, it’s a web regulator Nick Cohen &#8211; Spectator March 18 2013 Since the early 1990s, hundreds of millions of words have been produced about the Web. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11727&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>There is much consternation about the outcome of the Levenson Report. Nick Cohen at the Spectator has a good <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/nick-cohen/2013/03/its-not-a-press-regulator-its-a-web-regulator/">article</a> up on the subject:</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>It’s not a press regulator, it’s a web regulator<br />
</strong>Nick Cohen &#8211; Spectator March 18 2013</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong><br />
<a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gagging-orders.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11731" alt="gagging-orders" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gagging-orders.jpg?w=614"   /></a></strong>Since the early 1990s, hundreds of millions of words have been produced about the Web. Enthusiasts have told us that it is the greatest communications revolution since Guttenberg invented movable type, and they are probably right. Utopian fantasists have imagined that cyberspace would be beyond the reach of governments – those ‘weary giants of flesh and steel’, as one particularly giddy theorist put it – and they were certainly wrong.</p>
<p>Their libertarian dreams, as we can see tonight, were an illusion. Those ‘weary giants of flesh and steel’ are tougher than they look. They are more than capable of using the new technologies to their own advantage, while censoring what their citizens write online. In the past, I would have directed you to China, Iran or Belarus to see web censorship. But now we can get all that at home.</p>
<p><span id="more-11727"></span>Politicians and broadcasters are talking tonight as if those hundreds of millions of words had never been written, and we are still living in the pre-Berners-Lee age. They keep saying that the party leaders proposed “press regulation” today, when that was barely the start of it. The establishment – and when all three parties and the extra-parliamentary great and good come together, I think I can describe them as such – has emotional reasons for misleading themselves and the public. They see the excesses and alleged crimes of the tabloids and want to say that the legislation before Parliament will stop them. But there is also a strong element of propaganda. By focusing on the brutishness of the tabloids, they make public forget about attacks on fundamental principles and perhaps allow themselves to forget as well. For when people behave dreadfully they normally have to delude themselves before they can delude others.</p>
<p>I can see the propaganda’s appeal. Although I believe in freedom of the press in theory, I find the sanctimony, pornography and bullying of much of the press revolting. I don’t think the state has the right to control them, but if the tabloids closed tomorrow I wouldn’t shed a tear.</p>
<p>“Press regulation” as the BBC News was saying at Six and Channel 4 News is saying as I type, does not sound so bad, not even to me, if all it means is stopping the tabloids. The briefest study of the Royal Charter and the Crime and Courts Bill which carried Leveson proposals, however, shows that the first attempt at press licensing since 1695 does not confine itself to the press. In public, the establishment talks about “press regulation”, in the small print, its demands are much broader and very modern: it wants Web regulation.</p>
<p>The regulator will cover ‘relevant publishers’. If they do not pay for its services and submit to its fines and rulings, they could face exemplary damages in the courts. It is not just the old (and dying) newspapers, which the state defines as ‘relevant publishers’ but ‘website containing news-related material’.</p>
<p>As Index on Censorship says, ‘Bloggers could find themselves subject to exemplary damages in court, due to the fact that they were not part of a regulator that was not intended for them in the first place. This mess of legislation has been thrown together with alarming haste: there’s little doubt we’ll repent for a while to come.’</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/nick-cohen/2013/03/its-not-a-press-regulator-its-a-web-regulator/">Read the rest here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/censorship-infographic-header.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-11733" alt="Web" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/censorship-infographic-header.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11727/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11727/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11727&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/internet-at-risk-uk-govt-wants-new-press-regulation-to-apply-to-bloggers-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gagging-orders.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gagging-orders</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/censorship-infographic-header.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Web</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teacher training: What it all means – Climate Change</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/teacher-training-what-it-all-means-climate-change/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/teacher-training-what-it-all-means-climate-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 15:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alarmism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11720</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Following up yesterday&#8217;s post about &#8216;climate change&#8217; and sustainability&#8217; being removed from the compulsory aspect of the national curriculum for under 14&#8242;s. In response, Leo Hickman wrote an article published in the Guardian entitled: &#8216;Teachers should be given free reign to teach climate change in schools&#8217;.  I wondered what sort of information is fed to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11720&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr"><em>Following up yesterday&#8217;s post about &#8216;climate change&#8217; and sustainability&#8217; being removed from the compulsory aspect of the national curriculum for under 14&#8242;s. In response, Leo Hickman wrote an<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/blog/2013/mar/18/teachers-climate-change-schools-curriculum"> article published in the Guardian</a> entitled: &#8216;Teachers should be given free reign to teach climate change in schools&#8217;.  I wondered what sort of information is fed to the teachers who decide what to include in lessons such as Geography. The Notes re-produced below are on page 9 of <a href="http://www.derby.gov.uk/media/derbycitycouncil/contentassets/documents/brochuresandleaflets/DerbyCityCouncil-teacher-training-workshop-booklet.pdf">this publication</a> given to teachers by Derby City Council. It was produced by Resource Recovery Solutions (Derbyshire) Ltd, a UK registered limited company. Note that there is not a hint of any references to any external material.</em></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><strong><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brainwash.gif"><img class="alignright" alt="brainwash" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brainwash.gif?w=316&#038;h=400" width="316" height="400" /></a>What it all means – Climate Change</strong></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Below is a list of explanations that you will need to know in order to teach global warming and climate change.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><strong>Climate change</strong></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Climate change is a natural process, for millennia the earth has warmed and cooled in a regular cycle as evidenced by ice ages.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Now, man’s actions are accelerating the process at a phenomenal rate to the extent that the term climate change is now primarily used when referring to changes in the modern climate influenced by human activities or global warming.</div>
<div dir="ltr"><img title="More..." alt="" src="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/wp-includes/js/tinymce/plugins/wordpress/img/trans.gif" /></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">By this new definition climate change is changes to the earth’s climatic system that take place over decades or longer periods of time and is considered to be synonymous with global warming.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><strong>Global warming</strong></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Global warming is the increase in temperature of the oceans, land surface and near surface air of earth which has been increasing since the middle of the 20th century.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">The primary cause of this warming is an increase in greenhouse gases in the atmosphere due to human activity such as industrialisation, burning fossil fuels and deforestation.</div>
<div dir="ltr"><span id="more-11720"></span></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">The effects of global warming will be catastrophic, causing sea level rise, glacial retreat, floods, droughts and an increase in natural disasters such as mudslides and</div>
<div dir="ltr">hurricanes.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Global warming will also affect habitats and agriculture by changing the plants that are able to grow, the animals able to survive, the acidity of the oceans and the</div>
<div dir="ltr">amount of produce from crops.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Global warming is already believed to be affecting weather patterns resulting in greater extremes of weather and seasonal variations (e.g. hotter summers and colder</div>
<div dir="ltr">winters), this will only increase.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><strong>The greenhouse effect</strong></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">The greenhouse effect is the trapping of thermal radiation (the sun’s heat) between the atmosphere and the earth’s surface which warms the surface of the planet.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><strong>Greenhouse gas</strong></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">A greenhouse gas is a gas in the atmosphere that absorbs and emits thermal radiation (the sun’s heat) and contributes to the greenhouse effect.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Greenhouse gases aren’t all bad; without any greenhouse gases in our atmosphere the surface of the planet would be on average more than 30 degrees colder.</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div dir="ltr">The most common greenhouse gases are:</div>
<div dir="ltr">•</div>
<div dir="ltr">Water vapour</div>
<div dir="ltr">•</div>
<div dir="ltr">Carbon dioxide</div>
<div dir="ltr">•</div>
<div dir="ltr">Methane</div>
<div dir="ltr">•</div>
<div dir="ltr">Nitrous oxide</div>
<div dir="ltr">•</div>
<div dir="ltr">Ozone</div>
<div dir="ltr">•</div>
<div dir="ltr">Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs)</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">It is the rise in the concentrations of these gases in our atmosphere, since the middle</div>
<div dir="ltr">of the 20</div>
<div dir="ltr">th</div>
<div dir="ltr">century, which has caused global warming as the increase in greenhouse</div>
<div dir="ltr">gases reduces the amount of radiation that is able to pass back through the</div>
<p>atmosphere and out into space and as such is warming the planet</p>
</div>
<div dir="ltr"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gh.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11724" alt="gh" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gh.png?w=614"   /></a></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11720/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11720/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11720&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/teacher-training-what-it-all-means-climate-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brainwash.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brainwash</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/wp-includes/js/tinymce/plugins/wordpress/img/trans.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">More...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gh.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gh</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carbon tax the &#039;last straw&#039; for Aussie business</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/11712/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/11712/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 23:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/11712/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reblogged from Australian Climate Madness: Whilst Europe is paying about $4 a tonne (which is still $4 a tonne too much), Australian businesses are being slugged with $23 a tonne. Added to the raft of other anti-business legislation rolled out by Labor to keep the union vote sweet, this is finishing off businesses at a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11712&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="reblog-post"><p class="reblog-from"><img alt='' src='http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=25&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G' class='avatar avatar-25' height='25' width='25' /> <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/18/carbon-tax-the-last-straw-for-aussie-business/">Reblogged from Australian Climate Madness:</a></p><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt"><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt-content"><p dir='auto'>
<a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/18/carbon-tax-the-last-straw-for-aussie-business/" target="_self"><img src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2010/05/money_down_toilet1.jpg?w=614&h=150" alt="Click to visit the original post" class="size-full" /></a>

</p><p>Whilst Europe is paying about $4 a tonne (which is still $4 a tonne too much), Australian businesses are being slugged with $23 a tonne. Added to the raft of other anti-business legislation rolled out by Labor to keep the union vote sweet, this is finishing off businesses at a rate of one an hour:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>THE carbon tax is contributing to a record number of firms going to the wall with thousands of employees being laid off and companies forced to close factories that have stood for generations.</em></p></blockquote>

</div> <p class="read-more"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/18/carbon-tax-the-last-straw-for-aussie-business/" target="_self"><span>Read more&hellip;</span> 322 more words</a></p></div></div><div class="reblogger-note"><div class='reblogger-note-content'>
Sounds like things are getting pretty bad down under. Election promises broken, erosion of free speech, curtailment of autonomy. Hang in there friends, the end of climate madness is in sight. Legal challenge should soon be possible.
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/11712/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
