<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Cutting edge science you can dice with</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 15:47:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='tallbloke.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>A Personal Appeal to Britain&#8217;s Politicians: Wake-Up From Your Warm Dreams! Fuel Poverty is Killing People</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[atmosphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clouds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gravity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Variation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ocean dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shale gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tides]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are times when I find it hard to speak politely. I left school at sixteen and worked on the shop-floor of a large engineering works for ten years, gaining a higher national qualification in mechanical and production engineering along the way before getting the chance to study for a degree in the History and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11842&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11843" alt="tod_kaiser" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg?w=614"   /></a>There are times when I find it hard to speak politely. I left school at sixteen and worked on the shop-floor of a large engineering works for ten years, gaining a higher national qualification in mechanical and production engineering along the way before getting the chance to study for a degree in the History and Philosophy of Science. While I worked in heavy industry, I learned some choice ways of expressing myself which are basic, direct, and hurt the sensibilities of those who have spent their lives in polite company, although they got the job done effectively. So I sometimes struggle to find the right tone at those times when a message needs communicating forcefully to people in a position to influence policy, but without having them recoil and ignore things they don&#8217;t want to contemplate.</p>
<p>But the time for niceties has passed. Britain&#8217;s people face a looming disaster of epic proportion. Britain&#8217;s political class needs to act swiftly to minimise the damage which cannot be wholly averted at this late stage. Successive governments have set the stage for the impending denouement, so this is not a partisan rant, but a cross-party appeal to common sense. People are <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/government-protect-wintering-birds-but-not-pensioners/">dying by the thousand</a> as a direct result of <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-for-britains-insane-energy-policy/">botched energy policy</a> and we must act to save lives. Now.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s clear some of the undergrowth so we can see the shape of the problem. Firstly, we&#8217;ll deal with the climate scare.</p>
<p><span id="more-11842"></span><strong>The Climate Question</strong></p>
<p>There is no &#8216;enhanced greenhouse effect&#8217; from rising levels of co2 in the atmosphere. Carbon dioxide is an essential trace gas with little radiative effect compared with the enormous quantity of water vapour in the air. The hydrological cycle has massive redundant capacity to provide a negative feedback to any increase in radiative forcing from additional airborne co2. In any case it is <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/is-the-airborne-co2-fraction-temperature-dependent/">by no means certain</a> that the majority of the increase in airborne co2 is <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/04/18/uncertainty-the-origin-of-the-increase-in-atmospheric-co2/">of human origin</a>.</p>
<p>The real drivers of climatic change; the cyclically varying make-up of radiation from the Sun, the tidal effects on ocean circulation caused by the Moon&#8217;s declination cycle, and the Earth&#8217;s tectonic and seismic responses to the changing disposition of the rest of the solar system masses, induce near repeating <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/06/30/further-terrestrial-evidence-of-planetary-cycles-affecting-climate/">cyclic patterns</a> in Earth&#8217;s ever-changing climatic history. Through the decomposition of the complex signal into <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/tallbloke-and-tim-channon-a-cycles-analysis-approach-to-predicting-solar-activity/">simpler sinusoidal components</a>, we are able to better determine their origin, and predict future changes.</p>
<p>The indications are that the Sun is going into a phase of low activity levels. This is likely to increase cloudiness and reduce sunshine hours. That will induce surface cooling for several decades to come.</p>
<p><strong>The Energy Issue</strong></p>
<p>Supplying society&#8217;s need for high quality securely distributed energy is paramount to our well being. Clean water supply, food, health, education, and all of modern society&#8217;s benefits stem from our production of energy. Cleaner air is a desirable aspiration, but it cannot take priority over basic requirements on which peoples lives depend. The emissions from coal burning power stations are not particularly toxic at the levels they are ingested, and some of the by-products, such as sulphur are of direct benefit to agriculture. Acid rain destroying Scandinavian forest is a long debunked myth. Sulphur dioxide doesn&#8217;t make us ill. Hypothermia kills people, especially old people who have paid their dues to society and have the right to a warm home in retirement.</p>
<p><strong>The Engineer&#8217;s Solution</strong></p>
<p>Take a leaf out of Germany&#8217;s book and Commence building modern replacements for Britain&#8217;s aging coal fired generation capacity NOW, with whatever heavy industrial capacity we have left. Frack for gas NOW. Get the Americans in to do it if necessary, but don&#8217;t offer our tax money, we pay enough for gas as it is. Just cut the red tape and they will come to work willingly, without subsidy. Re-open any viable coal mines we still have, and start building some new ones.</p>
<p><strong>The Political Situation</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s time to force the British Government to grow a pair of balls and tell the unelected dick-heads in Brussels to FUCK OFF.  Then it won&#8217;t be able to use the excuse that the European Large Plant Directive prevents us from solving our URGENT energy crisis in the most time efficient and self reliant way. Use the money the European Union has been embezzling from us without providing audited accounts for the last two decades. Stop giving our tax money to thieves, NOW. If the British establishment doesn&#8217;t heed the warning, it will be brought down by cold, angry people voting for a populist party with no administrational experience. While it would be fun, it&#8217;s unlikely to solve the energy crisis which is upon us. The new Carbon Tax is an obvious ploy to steal more money from a cold population and will not be tolerated.</p>
<p>Nutshell message to British Government: Stop dicking around, the eyes of the people are upon you. If you don&#8217;t move fast to fix the mess you&#8217;ve created, their collective boot will be up your collective arse, and given that the Labour and Conservative parties are the two cheeks of the same arse, pointing the finger at each other in parliament won&#8217;t appease them.</p>
<p>There, I knew I couldn&#8217;t keep it up.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BGIIN8_CUAENRFb.jpg" width="600" height="399" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Queensbury West Yorkshire this morning. &#8220;Our children aren&#8217;t going to know what snow is&#8221; &#8211; Dr David Viner, Govt climate advisor 2002</p></div>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11842/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11842/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11842&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tod_kaiser</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BGIIN8_CUAENRFb.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Major UK Newspaper Calls for Repeal of Climate Change Act</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/major-uk-newspaper-calls-for-repeal-of-climate-change-act/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/major-uk-newspaper-calls-for-repeal-of-climate-change-act/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 09:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11840</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Via the GWPF: Too Much Green Energy Is Bad For Britain The Sunday Telegraph, 24 March 2013 It is time for the Coalition to tear up its energy policy before the lights go out. The first priority must be to repeal the Climate Change Act of 2008. With the worst snow conditions in the country [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11840&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Via the <a href="http://www.thegwpf.org/man-made-energy-crisis-sunday-telegraph-calls-repeal-climate-change-act/">GWPF</a>:</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Too Much Green Energy Is Bad For Britain</strong><br />
The Sunday Telegraph, 24 March 2013</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/solar-cartoon.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-8950" alt="solar-cartoon" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/solar-cartoon.jpg?w=614"   /></a>It is time for the Coalition to tear up its energy policy before the lights go out. The first priority must be to repeal the Climate Change Act of 2008.</p>
<p>With the worst snow conditions in the country since 1981, it’s worrying, to say the least, that gas supplies are running low. A month ago, The Sunday Telegraph warned in this column of the problems of an energy policy that puts expensive, inefficient green power before coal-fired and nuclear power. There have been a few signs that the Coalition is at last turning its attentions to the issue but, still, not nearly enough has been done.</p>
<p><span id="more-11840"></span>Now we are reaping the consequences. Because of a misguided faith in green energy, we have left ourselves far too dependent on foreign gas supplies, largely provided by Russian and Middle Eastern producers. Only 45 per cent of our gas consumption comes from domestic sources. All it takes is a spell of bad weather, and the closure of a gas pipeline from Belgium, to leave us dangerously exposed, and to send gas prices soaring. Talk of rationing may be exaggerated, but our energy policy is failing to deal with Britain’s fundamental incapacity to produce our own power.</p>
<p>Ed Davey, the Energy Secretary, may have granted planning permission this week to a new nuclear power station, Hinkley Point in Somerset. But one nuclear power station, with two new reactors, isn’t nearly enough. Moreover, it will take a decade to build and, even then, will only provide seven per cent of the country’s energy needs.</p>
<p>It is time for the Coalition to tear up its energy policy before the lights really do go out. The first priority must be to repeal the Climate Change Act of 2008, with its brutal, punishing targets: reducing carbon emissions by 80 per cent by 2050, and 26 per cent by 2020. These targets have already had a disastrous effect, forcing the closure of coal-fired power stations, and increasing tax-funded subsidies on wind power. Next month, electricity bills will soar even higher, thanks to a new tax on carbon dioxide produced by coal-fired and gas-fired power stations.</p>
<p>There are good intentions behind a green energy policy, and no one would wilfully want to damage the environment. But green technology – in its current incarnation, anyway – is just too inefficient and expensive to meet our energy needs. In some of the worst weather for more than 30 years, green power still only provides a tiny fraction of our energy needs. Solar power is of limited use in our cold, dark, northern climate. And wind power isn’t much better – cold weather doesn’t necessarily mean windy weather.</p>
<p>At last, the Coalition – or the Conservative part of it, anyway – is beginning to recognise these painfully obvious truths. In this week’s Budget, the Chancellor backed the policy of domestic fracking – the extraction of shale gas – with the promise of tax breaks for companies involved in the industry. He will know that American gas prices have plummeted, thanks to the US embracing the shale gas revolution. Britain must do the same. George Osborne also announced in the Budget that ceramics businesses would be exempt from the Climate Change Levy on energy costs. By making that exemption, he is acknowledging that green taxes are a significant drag on industry. He should make the exemption universal.</p>
<p>Our energy problems have been deepened by the greener-than-green Liberal Democrats, with their seeming stranglehold on the Cabinet post of Energy Secretary. When Chris Huhne took on the job in 2010, he swore Britain would become more independent of energy imports. Yet the country remains just as dependent, and Huhne’s Liberal Democrat colleague, Ed Davey, is still wedded to green power. Last year, he publicly slapped down his junior Tory energy minister, John Hayes, for calling for an end to more wind farms.</p>
<p>There is some good news, however. As we report today, government sources have said that wind power subsidies are to be cut again. This is a move in the right direction and we very much welcome it. It is to be hoped that there will be more such announcements, and concrete actions, from a government that has neglected a fundamental duty – to keep the lights on, energy affordable and our houses warm.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/comment/telegraph-view/9949595/Too-much-green-energy-is-bad-for-Britain.html">Read the original here</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11840/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11840/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11840&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/major-uk-newspaper-calls-for-repeal-of-climate-change-act/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/solar-cartoon.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">solar-cartoon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christopher Booker: It&#8217;s Payback Time for Britain&#8217;s Insane Energy Policy</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-for-britains-insane-energy-policy/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-for-britains-insane-energy-policy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alarmism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atmosphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11838</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another stinging column from Christopher Booker in the Telegraph, summarising several of the stories published recently at the Talkshop around taxation, energy policy, and the failure of a generation of politicians to get real about the needs of the British people who pay their comfortable salaries. Christopher Booker: It’s Payback Time For Britain’s Insane Energy Policy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11838&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Another <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/energy/windpower/9949571/Its-payback-time-for-our-insane-energy-policy.html">stinging column</a> from Christopher Booker in the Telegraph, summarising several of the stories published recently at the Talkshop around taxation, energy policy, and the failure of a generation of politicians to get real about the needs of the British people who pay their comfortable salaries</em>.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Christopher Booker: It’s Payback Time For Britain’s Insane Energy Policy</strong><br />
<strong> 23/03/13 Christopher Booker, The Daily Telegraph</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_11549" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/drax.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-11549" alt="Drax powerstation, generating 7% of Britains needs, is being forced to convert to imported woodchips." src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/drax.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Drax powerstation, generating 7% of Britains needs, is being forced to convert to imported woodchips.</p></div>
<p>An obsession with CO2 has left us dangerously short of power as coal-powered stations are forced to close</p>
<p>As the snow of the coldest March since 1963 continues to fall, we learn that we have barely 48 hours’ worth of stored gas left to keep us warm, and that the head of our second-largest electricity company, SSE, has warned that our generating capacity has fallen so low that we can expect power cuts to begin at any time. It seems the perfect storm is upon us.</p>
<p>The grotesque mishandling of Britain’s energy policy by the politicians of all parties, as they chase their childish chimeras of CO2-induced global warming and windmills, has been arguably the greatest act of political irresponsibility in our history.</p>
<p><span id="more-11838"></span>Three more events last week brought home again just what a mad bubble of make-believe these people are living in. Under the EU’s Large Combustion Plants Directive, we lost two more major coal-fired power stations, Didcot A and Cockenzie, capable of contributing no less than a tenth to our average electricity demands. We saw a French state-owned company, EDF, being given planning permission to spend £14 billion on two new nuclear reactors in Somerset, but which it says it will only build, for completion in 10 years’ time, if it is guaranteed a subsidy that will double the price of its electricity. Then, hidden in the small print of the Budget, were new figures for the fast-escalating tax the Government introduces next week on every ton of CO2 emitted by fossil-fuel-powered stations, which will soon be adding billions of pounds more to our electricity bills every year.</p>
<p>Within seven years this new tax will rise to £30 a ton, and by 2030 to £70 a ton, making it wholly uneconomical to generate any more electricity from the coal and gas-fired power stations that last week were still supplying two thirds of our electricity. Put all this together and we see more starkly than ever the game the Government is playing. It knows that no company would build wind farms unless it is given subsidies that, in effect, nearly double or treble the price of its electricity.</p>
<p>The Government will only get CO2-free nuclear power if it promises it an equal subsidy. And now the Coalition is also hell-bent on driving our much cheaper and more reliable coal and gas-fired plants out of business, by imposing a carbon tax that will not only eventually double the cost of their electricity, but also make it impossible for them to survive. So mad is this policy of “double-up all round” that it is driving even the largest and most efficient power station in the country, Drax, capable of supplying seven per cent of all the power we use, to switch from burning coal to wood chips, imported 3,000 miles across the Atlantic from the US. And how has the Government forced Drax to do this? By giving it a subsidy on wood chips that doubles the value of its electricity, while putting an increasingly prohibitive tax on coal.</p>
<p>This is all insane in so many ways that one scarcely knows where to begin, except to point out that, even if our rulers somehow managed to subsidise firms into spending £100 billion on all those wind farms they dream of, they will still need enough new gas-fired power stations to provide back-up for all the times when the wind isn’t blowing, at the very time when the carbon tax will soon make it uneconomical for anyone to build them.</p>
<p>So we are doomed to see Britain’s lights going out, all because the feather-headed lunatics in charge of our energy policy still believe that they’ve got to do something to save the planet from that CO2-induced global warming which this weekend has been covering much of the country up to a foot deep in snow. Meanwhile, the Indians are planning to build 455 new coal-fired power stations which will add more CO2 to the atmosphere of the planet every week than Britain emits in a year.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/energy/windpower/9949571/Its-payback-time-for-our-insane-energy-policy.html">Read the rest here</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11838/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11838/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11838&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-for-britains-insane-energy-policy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/drax.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Drax powerstation, generating 7% of Britains needs, is being forced to convert to imported woodchips.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Wind Turbine Blows Over: In a 50mph Wind</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/another-wind-turbine-blows-over-in-a-50mph-wind/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/another-wind-turbine-blows-over-in-a-50mph-wind/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 17:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gravity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basic mechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[numpetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resonance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11833</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After last week&#8217;s symbolic collapse of a wind turbine in Kyoto province, here&#8217;s news of another downed bird mincer in Donegal, Ireland. From the Donegal Daily: DD EXCLUSIVE: An investigation is underway after a 80 ft wind turbine came crashing to the ground in strong winds near Ardara. The windmill is one of nine located [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11833&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>After last week&#8217;s symbolic <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/photo-of-the-week-kyoto-wind-turbine-hits-the-deck/">collapse of a wind turbine </a>in Kyoto province, here&#8217;s news of another downed bird mincer in Donegal, Ireland. From the <a href="http://www.donegaldaily.com/2013/03/23/investigation-underway-after-massive-windmill-comes-down-in-gales/">Donegal Daily</a>:</em></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nowind.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-9800" alt="Nowind" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nowind.jpg?w=232&#038;h=300" width="232" height="300" /></a>DD EXCLUSIVE: An investigation is underway after a 80 ft wind turbine came crashing to the ground in strong winds near Ardara.</p>
<p>The windmill is one of nine located at Maas on the backroad near Ardara.</p>
<p>It is believed the wind turbine came down overnight when winds were gusting in the area to 80km/hr (50mph).</p>
<p>However the fact the turbine crashed in conditions it should otherwise have easily coped with has puzzled experts.</p>
<p><span id="more-11833"></span></p>
<p>Nobody was hurt during the incident.</p>
<p>The company which runs the windfarm, Vestas, has arrived on site and is carrying out a full investigation.</p>
<p>“These turbines aren’t supposed to fall down, the weather wasn’t that bad,” said one source in the company.</p>
<p>A gate at the entrance to the windfarm has been locked while engineers and investigators examine the cause of the accident.</p>
<p>Locals in the area have been traveling to see the toppled turbine.</p>
<p>The nine unit windfarm is the only one in the immediate area but there are plans for more windfarms nearby.</p>
<p>One eye-witness said the windmill has completely toppled over but that the winds in the area have since died down.</p>
<p>“There were strong winds in the area overnight so I presume that’s when it came down.</p>
<p>“I’m sure the company will have to examine the other turbines in the area to see if they are secure,” he said.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11833/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11833&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/another-wind-turbine-blows-over-in-a-50mph-wind/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nowind.jpg?w=232" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nowind</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Webcite is running out of money</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/11831/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/11831/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 08:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/11831/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reblogged from Shub Niggurath Climate: You know how every now and then, Wikipedia runs ads asking for funding to keep their website running. Sometimes I am not sure I want to give them money. At others, I feel they deserve to stay on. But here's a service that is definitely, one-hundred percent useful and deserving [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11831&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="reblog-post"><p class="reblog-from"><img alt='' src='http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/53dfb0cbbf5caa0b726cc8b116a070f2?s=25&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G' class='avatar avatar-25' height='25' width='25' /> <a href="http://nigguraths.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/webcite-is-running-out-of-money/">Reblogged from Shub Niggurath Climate:</a></p><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt"><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt-content"><a href="http://nigguraths.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/webcite-is-running-out-of-money/" target="_self"><img src="http://s0.wp.com/imgpress?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffarm8.staticflickr.com%2F7006%2F6647051213_ecb9f57612_z_d.jpg&w=614" alt="Click to visit the original post" class="size-full" /></a>

<p>You know how every now and then, Wikipedia runs ads asking for funding to keep their website running. Sometimes I am not sure I want to give them money. At others, I feel they deserve to stay on.</p>
<p>But here's a service that is definitely, one-hundred percent useful and deserving of Internet users' support: <a href="http://www.webcitation.org/">WebCite</a>.</p>
<p>WebCite is in <a href="https://fundrazr.com/campaigns/aQMp7">need of funds&hellip;</a></p>
</div> <p class="read-more"><a href="http://nigguraths.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/webcite-is-running-out-of-money/" target="_self"><span>Read more&hellip;</span> 19 more words</a></p></div></div><div class="reblogger-note"><div class='reblogger-note-content'>
A worthy recipient I have donated to. Webcite is a handy place to put those documants in danger of being 'disappeared' as the story unravels.
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/11831/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Big Meteor: This time over the U.S.</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/another-big-meteor-this-time-over-the-u-s/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/another-big-meteor-this-time-over-the-u-s/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 07:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shooting star]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11825</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Big Meteors are like London buses. You don&#8217;t see any for ages, then three roll up at once. There is an ongoing well informed and detailed discussion here at the talkshop about a possible connection between the Chelyabinsk meteor, which exploded over Russia last month, and a large asteroid which passed close to Earth on the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11825&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Big Meteors are like London buses. You don&#8217;t see any for ages, then three roll up at once. There is an ongoing <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/andrew-cooper-were-the-recent-asteroid-flyby-and-russian-meteor-strike-events-linked/">well informed and detailed discussion</a> here at the talkshop about a possible connection between the Chelyabinsk meteor, which exploded over Russia last month, and a large asteroid which passed close to Earth on the same day.</em></p>
<div id="attachment_11826" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shooting-star.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-11826" alt="Artists impression" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shooting-star.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Artists impression<em>a large asteroid passed near Earth. Now another big one has passed northeast-southwest over the U.S. with hundreds of  sightings ranging from New England to Florida.</em></p></div>
<p><em>Now another big meteor has entered Earth&#8217;s atmosphere, with sightings rangng from New England to Florida.</em></p>
<p>This from <a href="http://news.sky.com/story/1068697/nasa-confirms-meteor-after-fireball-reports">Sky News</a>:</p>
<p>The US space agency says reports of a flash in the sky along much of the US East Coast appeared to be a &#8220;single meteor event&#8221;.</p>
<p>Social media sites have been buzzing with reports of the flash that streaked across the sky.</p>
<p>It was spotted as far south as Florida and as far north as New England, reports said.</p>
<p>Bill Cooke of Nasa&#8217;s Meteoroid Environment Office said it &#8220;looks to be a fireball that moved roughly toward the southeast, going on visual reports.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Judging from the brightness, <strong>we&#8217;re dealing with something as bright as the full moon</strong>,&#8221; Mr Cooke said.<span id="more-11825"></span><br />
&#8220;We basically have [had&#8217;a boulder enter the atmosphere over the northeast.&#8221;</p>
<p>He says the meteor was widely seen, with more than 350 reports on the website of the American Meteor Society alone.</p>
<p>Robert Lunsford of the society told USA Today &#8220;it basically looked like a super bright shooting star&#8221;.</p>
<p>Derrick Pitts, chief astronomer at Philadelphia&#8217;s Franklin Institute, agrees that the sightings had all the hallmarks of a &#8220;fireball&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://news.sky.com/story/1068697/nasa-confirms-meteor-after-fireball-reports">Read the rest here.</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11825/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11825/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11825&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/another-big-meteor-this-time-over-the-u-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shooting-star.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Artists impression</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Usoskin et al: 775AD Cosmic Event was of Solar Origin</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/usoskin-et-al-775ad-cosmic-event-was-of-solar-origin/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/usoskin-et-al-775ad-cosmic-event-was-of-solar-origin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Astrophysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmic rays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11820</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A new paper just out at Astronomy and Astrophysics from Usoskin et al claims to show that the mysterious major cosmic event that took place in the 770&#8242;s AD was not of exotic origin, but solar: Abstract Aims. Miyake et al. (2012, Nature, 486, 240, henceforth M12) recently reported, based on 14C data, an extreme [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11820&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A <a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/usoskin2013a.pdf">new paper</a> just out at Astronomy and Astrophysics from Usoskin et al claims to show that the mysterious major cosmic event that took place in the 770&#8242;s AD was not of exotic origin, but solar:</p>
<p><strong>Abstract</strong></p>
<p>Aims. Miyake et al. (2012, Nature, 486, 240, henceforth M12) recently reported, based on 14C data, an extreme cosmic event in about AD775. Using a simple model, M12 claimed that the event was too strong to be caused by a solar flare within the standard theory. This implied a new paradigm of either an impossibly strong solar flare or a very strong cosmic ray event of unknown origin that occurred around AD775. However, as we show, the strength of the event was significantly overestimated by M12. Several subsequent works have attempted to find a possible exotic source for such an event, including a giant cometary impact upon the Sun or a gamma-ray burst, but they are all based on incorrect estimates by M12. We revisit this event with analysis of new datasets and consistent theoretical modelling.</p>
<p><span id="more-11820"></span><br />
Methods. We verified the experimental result for the AD775 cosmic ray event using independent datasets including 10Be series and newly measured 14C annual data. We surveyed available historical chronicles for astronomical observations for the period around the AD770s to identify potential sightings of aurorae borealis and supernovae. We interpreted the 14C measurements using an appropriate carbon cycle model.</p>
<p>Results. We show that: (1) The reality of the AD775 event is confirmed by new measurements of 14C in German oak; (2) by using an inappropriate carbon cycle model, M12 strongly overestimated the event’s strength; (3) the revised magnitude of the event (the global 14C production Q = (1.1 − 1.5) × 108 atoms/cm2) is consistent with different independent datasets (14C, 10Be, 36Cl) and can be associated with a strong, but not inexplicably strong, solar energetic particle event (or a sequence of events), and provides the first definite evidence for an event of this magnitude (the fluence &gt;30 MeV was about 4.5 × 1010 cm-2) in multiple datasets; (4) this interpretation is in agreement with increased auroral activity identified in historical chronicles.</p>
<p>Conclusions. The results point to the likely solar origin of the event, which is now identified as the greatest solar event on a multi-millennial time scale, placing a strong observational constraint on the theory of explosive energy releases on the Sun and cool stars.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11820/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11820&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/usoskin-et-al-775ad-cosmic-event-was-of-solar-origin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roger Helmer MEP: This is not a tax.  This is EU theft with a fancy name.</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/roger-helmer-mep-this-is-not-a-tax-this-is-eu-theft-with-a-fancy-name/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/roger-helmer-mep-this-is-not-a-tax-this-is-eu-theft-with-a-fancy-name/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 15:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11816</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Via Better Off Out: Roger Helmer MEP (UKIP) Tells Herman von Rompuy how it is: Mr. President, The report on last week’s Council calls for “differentiated growth-friendly fiscal consolidation” — a contradiction in terms. It wants to “restore normal lending”, to “promote growth and competitiveness”, to tackle unemployment and modernise public administration. If there were [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11816&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Via<a href="http://www.betteroffout.net/roger-helmer-mep-takes-on-herman-van-rompuy/"> Better Off Out</a>: Roger Helmer MEP (UKIP) Tells Herman von Rompuy how it is:</em></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roger-helmer.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-11817" alt="Roger-Helmer" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roger-helmer.jpg?w=226&#038;h=300" width="226" height="300" /></a>Mr. President, The report on last week’s Council calls for “differentiated growth-friendly fiscal consolidation” — a contradiction in terms.</p>
<p>It wants to “restore normal lending”, to “promote growth and competitiveness”, to tackle unemployment and modernise public administration.</p>
<p>If there were a prize for clichés and wishful thinking, gentlemen, you would win it. These objectives are motherhood and apple pie, but you have no idea how to deliver them.</p>
<p>You should take a leaf from Konrad Adenauer’s book, and have a bonfire of the regulations. You are drowning Europe in a sea of red tape.</p>
<p>You need to promote a low-tax, growth-friendly Europe.</p>
<p>And you need to dismantle the €uro. Again and again you declare the crisis over, but it comes back to bite you.</p>
<p>Now it’s Cyprus. You talk of a Europe of values, with the rule of law and property rights. Yet you planned to confiscate the funds of savers and pensioners, while protecting senior bondholders.<br />
<span id="more-11816"></span></p>
<p>You’re breaking the promise of your European Bank Deposit Guarantee scheme.</p>
<p>You try to evade your obligations by calling it a “tax”. But you have form in playing with words. You avoided further referendums on the European Constitution by calling it a Treaty. You broke your “no default” promise in Greece by calling it a haircut.</p>
<p>Now you break your deposit guarantee by pretending that confiscation is a tax. This is not a tax. This is EU theft with a fancy name. This is the very symbol and measure of your failure and breach of faith.</p>
<p>Former British Chancellor Lord Lawson described the €uro as “Possibly the most reckless political adventure of the post-war era”. And he was maybe under-stating the problem, at that.</p>
<p>You, Gentlemen, have presided over unemployment, and hardship, and poverty, and misery, in Southern Europe, on a scale we have not seen in my lifetime.</p>
<p>Yet you sit in your gilded offices, on your inflated salaries, and you fiddle while Rome burns. You have no answers to the problems of European citizens.</p>
<p>Let me quote a great Englishman, Oliver Cromwell:</p>
<p>“You have sat here too long for any good you have been doing. Depart, I say, and let us have done with you. In the name of God, go!”</p>
<p>The speech was recorded and is available <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8_V0D6oKZ6M">here.</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11816/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11816/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11816&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/roger-helmer-mep-this-is-not-a-tax-this-is-eu-theft-with-a-fancy-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roger-helmer.jpg?w=226" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Roger-Helmer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tamino loses the plot with new hockeystick</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/tamino-loses-the-plot-with-new-hockeystick/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/tamino-loses-the-plot-with-new-hockeystick/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 12:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alarmism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11803</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over at the &#8216;Open Mind&#8217; blog, Grant Foster, AKA &#8216;Tamino&#8217; has put up an entertainingly ludicrous post on long term temperature trends. It&#8217;s a Baron von Richthofen flying circus of mish-mashed paleoproxy data (with creatively re-engineered core top dates), Hadley/CRU &#8216;adjusted&#8217; instrumental data and climate model output for the next 90 years. The spliced up curve has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11803&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tamino-wheelchair.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-11805" alt="tamino-wheelchair" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tamino-wheelchair.png?w=300&#038;h=282" width="300" height="282" /></a>Over at the &#8216;Open Mind&#8217; blog, Grant Foster, AKA &#8216;Tamino&#8217; has put up an entertainingly <a href="http://tamino.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/global-temperature-change-the-big-picture/">ludicrous post</a> on long term temperature trends. It&#8217;s a Baron von Richthofen flying circus of mish-mashed paleoproxy data (with creatively <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/19/bent-their-core-tops-in/">re-engineered core top dates</a>), Hadley/CRU &#8216;adjusted&#8217; instrumental data and climate model output for the next 90 years. The spliced up curve has a distinctive shape which he dubs &#8216;the wheelchair&#8217;.</p>
<p>The Wheelchair?  Grant? Does it need one because it doesn&#8217;t have a leg to stand on?</p>
<p>To me it called something else to mind, so at the risk of him getting all upset about me reworking his graph, here&#8217;s my take:</p>
<p><span id="more-11803"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sharkjumper1.png"><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-11810" alt="sharkjumper" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sharkjumper1.png?w=614&#038;h=513" width="614" height="513" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11803/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11803/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11803&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/tamino-loses-the-plot-with-new-hockeystick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tamino-wheelchair.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tamino-wheelchair</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sharkjumper1.png?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sharkjumper</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ann Widdecombe: Climate orthodoxy  enforced with all the rigour of communism or fascism</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/ann-widdecombe-climate-orthodoxy-enforced-with-all-the-rigour-of-communism-or-fascism/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/ann-widdecombe-climate-orthodoxy-enforced-with-all-the-rigour-of-communism-or-fascism/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 09:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orthodoxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[widdecombe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11798</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently retired MP and former minister under the Major government Ann Widdecombe comes right out and says it like it is. And gets it printed in a daily. Is the UK print media &#8216;coming over the wall&#8217; in retaliation for Leveson? Even scientists are cooling on climate change Ann Widdecombe &#8211; Daily Express 22-3-2013 WHAT [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11798&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><em>Recently retired MP and former minister under the Major government Ann Widdecombe comes right out and says it like it is. <a href="http://www.express.co.uk/comment/columnists/ann-widdecombe/385446/Even-scientists-are-cooling-on-climate-change">And gets it printed</a> in a daily. Is the UK print media &#8216;coming over the wall&#8217; in retaliation for Leveson?</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/widdecombe.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11799" alt="Widdecombe" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/widdecombe.jpg?w=614"   /></a>Even scientists are cooling on climate change</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Ann Widdecombe &#8211; Daily Express 22-3-2013</p>
<p>WHAT do Peter Lilley, Andrew Tyrie, Philip Davies, Christopher Chope and I have in common? We were the only MPs to vote against the 2008 Climate Change Bill, which is to say we had by then considered all the evidence and found it wanting.</p>
<p>For years we have endured insults. Behind the scenes Fiona Bruce, normally the most courteous of broadcasters, called me a “flat-earther” to my face. Others branded us “deniers” as if we were disputing the holocaust. The Al Gore film was accorded the status of Holy Writ. David Bellamy lost his job. Doubting scientists were scorned. Nigel Lawson found it difficult to get his book An Appeal To Reason published.</p>
<p><span id="more-11798"></span></p>
<p>In short there was an orthodoxy which was enforced with all the rigour of communism or fascism or, for that matter, the Spanish Inquisition. Dissenters must not be heard and global warming became a religion. Well the dissenters have now been proved right. Heaven knows how many billions of pounds later the world is now being told that actually the warming is so far off predictions that all bets are off and indeed the world’s temperature is static or falling.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/comment/columnists/ann-widdecombe/385446/Even-scientists-are-cooling-on-climate-change">Read the rest here</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11798/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11798/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11798&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/ann-widdecombe-climate-orthodoxy-enforced-with-all-the-rigour-of-communism-or-fascism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/widdecombe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Widdecombe</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
