<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
	<atom:link href="https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Cutting edge science you can dice with</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:55:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='tallbloke.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>https://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Tallbloke&#039;s Talkshop" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Professor Roger Pielke Jr Snaps Marcott et al Hockeystick</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/professor-roger-pielke-jr-snaps-marcott-et-al-hockeystick/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/professor-roger-pielke-jr-snaps-marcott-et-al-hockeystick/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 07:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[alarmism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Measurement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[propaganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marcott et al]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Mann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scientific misconduct]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12030</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hats off to Prof. Roger Pileke Jr, who has followed Steve McIntyre&#8217;s lead in standing up for science in the face of continued lies and scientific fraud. Here are some highlights from the post linked above: In 1991 the National Research Council proposed what has come to be a widely accepted definition of misconduct in science: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12030&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Hats off to Prof. Roger Pileke Jr, who has followed <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/">Steve McIntyre&#8217;s lead</a> in <a href="http://rogerpielkejr.blogspot.co.uk/2013/03/fixing-marcott-mess-in-climate-science.html">standing up for science </a>in the face of continued lies and scientific fraud. Here are some highlights from the post linked above:</em></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/josh-paleo-rotten.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-12035" alt="josh-paleo-rotten" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/josh-paleo-rotten.jpg?w=614"   /></a>In 1991 the National Research Council proposed what has come to be a widely accepted definition of misconduct in science:<br />
Misconduct in science is defined as fabrication, falsification, or plagiarism, in proposing, performing, or reporting research. Misconduct in science does not include errors of judgment; errors in the recording, selection, or analysis of data; differences in opinions involving the interpretation of data; or misconduct unrelated to the research process.<br />
Arguments over data and methods are the lifeblood of science, and are not instances of misconduct.</p>
<p>However, here I document the gross misrepresentation of the findings of a recent scientific paper via press release which appears to skirt awfully close to crossing the line into research misconduct, as defined by the NRC. I recommend steps to fix this mess, saving face for all involved, and a chance for this small part of the climate community to take a step back toward unambiguous scientific integrity.</p>
<p><span id="more-12030"></span></p>
<p>The paper I refer to is by Marcott et al. 2013, published recently in Science. A press release issued by the National Science Foundation, which funded the research, explains the core methodology and key conclusion of the paper as follows (emphasis added):<br />
Peter Clark, an OSU paleoclimatologist and co-author of the Science paper, says that many previous temperature reconstructions were regional and not placed in a global context.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;When you just look at one part of the world, temperature history can be affected by regional climate processes like El Niño or monsoon variations,&#8221; says Clark.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;But when you combine data from sites around the world, you can average out those regional anomalies and get a clear sense of the Earth&#8217;s global temperature history.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>What that history shows, the researchers say, is that during the last 5,000 years, the Earth on average cooled about 1.3 degrees Fahrenheit&#8211;until the last 100 years, when it warmed about 1.3 degrees F.</strong><br />
The press release clearly explains that the paper (a) combines data from many sites around the world to create a &#8220;temperature reconstruction&#8221; which gives a &#8220;sense of the Earth&#8217;s temperature history,&#8221; and (b) &#8220;that history shows&#8221; a cooling over the past 5000 years, until the last 100 years when all of that cooling was reversed.</p>
<p>Here is Michael Lemonick at Climate Central:</p>
<blockquote><p>The study&#8230; confirms the now famous “hockey stick” graph that Michael Mann published more than a decade ago. That study showed a sharp upward temperature trend over the past century after more than a thousand years of relatively flat temperatures. . .<strong>“What’s striking,” said lead author Shaun Marcott of Oregon State University in an interview, “is that the records we use are completely independent, and produce the same result.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>In a belatedly-posted FAQ to the paper, which appeared on Real Climate earlier today, Marcott et al. make this startling admission:</p>
<blockquote><p>Q: What do paleotemperature reconstructions show about the temperature of the last 100 years?A: Our global paleotemperature reconstruction includes a so-called “uptick” in temperatures during the 20th-century. However, in the paper we make the point that this particular feature is of shorter duration than the inherent smoothing in our statistical averaging procedure, and that it is based on only a few available paleo-reconstructions of the type we used. Thus,<strong> the 20th century portion of our paleotemperature stack is not statistically robust, cannot be considered representative of global temperature changes, and therefore is not the basis of any of our conclusions.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Here are the steps that I recommend should be taken:</p>
<p>1) Science should issue a correction to the paper, and specially do the following:</p>
<p>(a) retract and replot all figures in the paper and SI eliminating from the graphs all data/results that fail to meet the paper&#8217;s criteria for &#8220;statistical robustness.&#8221;<br />
(b) include in the correction the explicit and unambiguous statement offered in the FAQ released today that the analysis is not &#8220;statistically robust&#8221; post-1900.</p>
<p>2) NSF should issue a correction to its press release, clarifying and correcting the statements of Peter Clark (a co-author, found above) and Candace Major, NSF program manager, who says in the release:<br />
&#8220;The last century stands out as the anomaly in this record of global temperature since the end of the last ice age,&#8221; says Candace Major, program director in the National Science Foundation&#8217;s (NSF) Division of Ocean Sciences.<br />
3) The New York Times (Gillis and Revkin, in particular), Nature and New Scientist as outlets that pride themselves in accurate reporting of science should update their stories with corrections. Grist and Climate Central should consider the same.</p>
<p>In comments, Professor Pielke says:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>I interact with climate scientists just about every day (being in CIRES, a leading global institute). There are an awful lot of people doing very good work.</strong></p>
<p><strong>There are a few bad eggs, with the Real Climate mafia being among them, who are exploiting climate science for personal and political gain. Makes the whole effort look bad.</strong></p>
<p><strong>That said, virtually all of the climate science battles are teapot/tempest affairs &#8212; climate politics and policy has moved on to issues involving economics and energy.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">________________________________________</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I have to disagree with Prof. Pielke on that last point. It is the tacit assumption that the paleoclimatology of institutions such as the Climate Research Unit at the University of East Anglia and Penn State University is inimpeachable that underpins the whole notion of &#8220;It&#8217;s unprecedented &#8211; we must act&#8221;, that has been pushed into the political and economic arena by activist groups such as Friends of the Earth and the World Wildlife Fund and Greenpeace. These organisations have infiltrated the IPCC, the civil service, the Department of Energy and Climate Change, the house of commons, and the house of lords.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">As Steve McIntyre notes in the post <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/31/the-marcott-filibuster/">linked in the intro</a>, Marcott et al still haven&#8217;t &#8216;fessed up to the most egregious aspect of their paper, and are attempting to smoke screen the whole affair with a partial admission of the paper&#8217;s shortcomings.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The rot must be stopped, and chopped out before the disease spreads further.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12030/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12030/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12030&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/professor-roger-pielke-jr-snaps-marcott-et-al-hockeystick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/josh-paleo-rotten.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">josh-paleo-rotten</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zhang et al: Consistent Long-term variation in the hemispheric asymmetry  of solar rotation</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/zhang-et-al-consistent-long-term-variation-in-the-hemispheric-asymmetry-of-solar-rotation/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/zhang-et-al-consistent-long-term-variation-in-the-hemispheric-asymmetry-of-solar-rotation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 20:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Astrophysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12008</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My thanks to Astrophysicist Ian Wilson for flagging up this new paper from Zhang, Mursula and Usoskin. This sheds some light on the periodic changes in the rate of rotation of the latitudinal bands on the solar surface, and the correlated changes in the number, size and hemispheric location of sunspots. It turns out there [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12008&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>My thanks to Astrophysicist Ian Wilson for flagging up this new paper from Zhang, Mursula and Usoskin. This sheds some light on the periodic changes in the rate of rotation of the latitudinal bands on the solar surface, and the correlated changes in the number, size and hemispheric location of sunspots. It turns out there is an anticorrelation between the two solar hemispheres. In other words, when rotation rates are high in the north, along with sunspot roduction, they are lower in the south, and vise versa. There are nuances that modify this relationship, and this leaves scope for further study. The periodicity is given as 80-90 years, and this frequency is potentially linked to planetary periods such as the Double inner solar system cycle, the half Jose cycle and Uranus&#8217; orbital period, which falls in the middle of the range</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/zhang-etal2013.png"><img class="size-large wp-image-12009 alignnone" alt="zhang-etal2013" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/zhang-etal2013.png?w=614&#038;h=539" width="614" height="539" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span id="more-12008"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Consistent Long-term variation in the hemispheric asymmetry of solar rotation</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong><br />
</strong>Context.<br />
Solar active longitudes and their rotation have been studied for a long time using various forms of solar activity. However, the results on the long-term evolution of rotation rates and the hemispheric asymmetry obtained by earlier authors differ significantly from each other. Aims. We aim to find a consistent result on the long-term migration of active longitudes of sunspots in 1877−2008 separately for the two hemispheres.<br />
Methods.<br />
We used a dynamic, differentially rotating reference system to determine the best-fit values of the differential rotation parameters of active longitudes for each year in 1877−2008. With these parameters we determined the momentary rotation rates at the reference latitude of 17◦and calculated the non-axisymmetries of active longitudes. We repeated this with five different fit intervals and two weighting methods and compared the results.<br />
Results.<br />
The evolution of solar surface rotation in each hemisphere suggests a quasi-periodicity of about 80−90 years. The long-term variations of solar rotation in the northern and southern hemisphere have a close anti-correlation, leading to a significant 80−90-year quasi-periodicity in the north-south asymmetry of solar rotation. The north-south asymmetry of solar rotation is found to have an inverse relationship with the area of large sunspots. The latitudinal contrast of differential rotation is also found to be anti-correlated with the sunspot area. Different fit and weight methods yield similar results.<br />
Conclusions.<br />
Our results give strong evidence for the anti-correlation of the rotation of the two solar hemispheres. The long-term oscillation of solar rotation suggests that a systematic interchange of angular momentum takes place between the two hemispheres at a period of about 80−90 years</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rotation_asymmetry_90_years.pdf">Full paper here</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12008/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12008/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12008&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/zhang-et-al-consistent-long-term-variation-in-the-hemispheric-asymmetry-of-solar-rotation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/zhang-etal2013.png?w=614" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zhang-etal2013</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mainstream Print Media Turns on Government and MET Office Climate Alarmists</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/mainstream-print-media-turns-on-government-and-met-office-climate-alarmists/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/mainstream-print-media-turns-on-government-and-met-office-climate-alarmists/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the last week, more articles critical of mainstream climate science alarmism, and the taxation and energy policies which  have been predicated on it have been published than have appeared in years. Undoubtedly this is partly because of the late snows and freezing temperatures endured by an increasingly climate-propaganda weary public. A couple of newspapers [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12004&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/leveson-media.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-12005" alt="leveson-media" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/leveson-media.jpeg?w=614"   /></a>Over the last week, more articles critical of mainstream climate science alarmism, and the taxation and energy policies which  have been predicated on it have been published than have appeared in years. Undoubtedly this is partly because of the late snows and freezing temperatures endured by an increasingly climate-propaganda weary public. A couple of newspapers which have always been in the vanguard of alarmist doomsaying, such as the Guardian have attempted to reverse the spin, but it is looking increasingly as if the majority of the UK press has had enough, and is coming over the wall to the sceptics position.</p>
<p>However, this may have as much to do with the late UK snow and revenge for the fallout from the Leveson enquiry as any genuine realisation of the shortcomings of the IPCC and the half-baked-one-side-only science it relies on. The impetus in the German media from their even colder spring may keep the ball rolling. Time will tell.</p>
<p><span id="more-12004"></span>Anyway, the fallout from this climate reporting shift could be spectacular. Once the dam wall starts to leak, the trickle soon becomes a torrent, and stories which the media has sat on for years will start coming out of the dusty intray pile. An example of this is the Daily Mail&#8217;s late Saturday night article &#8216;</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Leading the attack is committee member Sir Brian Hoskins, who is also director of the Grantham Institute for Climate Change at Imperial College, London. In a blog on the Committee on Climate Change’s website, Sir Brian insisted: ‘The scientific basis for significant long-term climate risks remains robust, despite the points raised .  .  . Early and deep cuts in emissions are still required.’</strong></p>
<p><strong>He also claimed our report ‘misunderstood’ the value of computer models. <em>Yet in an interview three years ago, Sir Brian conceded that when he started out as a climate scientist, the models were ‘pretty lousy, and they’re still pretty lousy, really</em>’</strong>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Expect more revelations of scientists admitting their work should never have been relied on for policy formation by politicians soon.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2301757/Governments-climate-watchdog-launches-astonishing-attack-Mail-Sunday--revealing-global-warming-science-wrong.html">Read more</a>:</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12004/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12004/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12004&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/mainstream-print-media-turns-on-government-and-met-office-climate-alarmists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/leveson-media.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leveson-media</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I think about climate change #4: Peter Ainsworth</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/what-i-think-about-climate-change-4-peter-ainsworth/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/what-i-think-about-climate-change-4-peter-ainsworth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 11:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=12001</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Peter Ainsworth is no longer an MP, he&#8217;s a founder member of the &#8216;Robertsridge Group&#8216;, an environmental and sustainability consultancy. He is chair of wild flora charity Plantlife. He&#8217;s also a board member of the environment agency, a government funded quango, which says of itself: We are an Executive Non-departmental Public Body responsible to the Secretary of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12001&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pa_crop.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-12002" alt="PA_crop" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pa_crop.jpg?w=614"   /></a>Peter Ainsworth is no longer an MP, he&#8217;s a founder member of the &#8216;<a href="http://www.robertsbridgegroup.com/who-we-are/peter-ainsworth/">Robertsridge Group</a>&#8216;, an environmental and sustainability consultancy. He is chair of wild flora charity Plantlife. He&#8217;s also a board member of the environment agency, a government funded quango, which <a href="http://www.environment-agency.gov.uk/aboutus/default.aspx">says of itself</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>We are an Executive Non-departmental Public Body responsible to the Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs and a Welsh Government Sponsored Body responsible to the Minister for Environment and Sustainable Development.</strong><br />
<strong>Our principal aims are to protect and improve the environment, and to promote sustainable development. We play a central role in delivering the environmental priorities of central government and the Welsh Government through our functions and roles.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>So his private consultancy is in a good position to benefit from his publicly paid for role with the EA.<br />
What was he saying about climate change as shadow environment minister back in 2006? Read on&#8230;</p>
<p><span id="more-12001"></span>Peter Ainsworth East Surrey, Conservative,<br />
Shadow Secretary of State for Environment</p>
<p>1: It is the greatest challenge facing our generation.</p>
<p>2: We must start by cutting our own emissions. A Climate Change Bill would help this. We need Government to lead by example, cutting its own energy use, converting to renewable energy sources, and using its enormous buying power to foster non-polluting technologies. Then we need long-term policies to create a framework for a shift to a low carbon economy. Only once we have put our own house in order, will we have the moral authority to lead an international effort to achieve a fair, robust, global system for tackling climate change. In the end, hard though it will be to secure, there must be a global agreement.</p>
<p>3: I have committed to cutting personal carbon emissions by 25% over 5 years; reducing car use, installing energy efficient light bulbs and other low carbon products, avoiding flying, switching off electrical appliances when not in use, converting to a renewable electricity supplier, recycling and composting waste.</p>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Ainsworth">Wiki says</a>:</p>
<p><em>Speaking in March 2006, Ainsworth set out the possible new direction for Conservative policy stating that &#8220;Achieving a sustainable world and combating the threat of climate change will require some really fresh ideas and radical thinking. We cannot expect to meet the challenges of this century by toying with the structures and technologies we have inherited from the past, and the concept of Decentralised Energy should to be taken seriously.&#8221;[5] Ainsworth was notable as the only member of the shadow cabinet to have voted against the war in Iraq.</em></p>
<p>I wonder how he got on with reducing his personal carbon emissions by 25% over 5 years.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12001/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/12001/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=12001&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/what-i-think-about-climate-change-4-peter-ainsworth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pa_crop.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PA_crop</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I think about Climate Change #3: Norman Baker MP</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/what-i-think-about-climate-change-3-norman-baker-mp/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/what-i-think-about-climate-change-3-norman-baker-mp/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 20:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11996</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another in our &#8220;what the MP&#8217;s were saying in 2006&#8243; series. This time it&#8217;s Norman Baker MP. These days he&#8217;s the Parliamentary Under Secretary for Transport. Norman Baker Lewes, Lib Dem; Chair, All-Party Environment Group 1: Climate change is a threat greater than any other faced by mankind and is therefore the most important political [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11996&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Another in our &#8220;what the MP&#8217;s were saying in 2006&#8243; series. This time it&#8217;s Norman Baker MP. These days he&#8217;s the Parliamentary Under Secretary for Transport.</em></p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11997" alt="norman-baker" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/norman-baker.jpeg?w=614"   />Norman Baker Lewes, Lib Dem;<br />
Chair, All-Party Environment Group</p>
<p>1: Climate change is a threat greater than any other faced by mankind and is therefore the most important political issue of our time. This means that we need to take urgent action on both the domestic and international stages. Climate change is a reality today, and is already having a huge impact on natural systems across the world, with ice-caps in retreat, coral reef bleaching, the extinction of numerous species, and increased frequency of extreme weather events. In the future, if insufficient action is taken, we face the prospect of catastrophic flooding in some countries alongside ruinous drought and famine in others. This will mean not only terrible human suffering, but economic disaster as well. I very much welcome the recent Stern Review, which may at last make those who somehow believe that the economy and environment are separate matters realize that, rather they are inextricably linked. If we want to stop the worst impacts of climate change, I believe it is vitally important that the average global temperature increases stay below 2°C from pre-industrial levels. Unfortunately, however, we are already much of the way there. Avoiding rises in temperature beyond 2ºC will therefore require dramatic and urgent reductions in emissions of greenhouses gases by all industrialised countries.</p>
<p><span id="more-11996"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2: Firstly, Britain needs to lead by example by putting its own house in order. The government has already admitted that the UK is going to miss the target of a 20% reduction in carbon emissions by 2010 and figures show that emissions of CO2 have actually been rising year on year. This is quite simply unacceptable. We therefore need radical and innovative measures to cut greenhouse gas emissions, backed up by a timetable of annual, binding targets. We need to make significant changes to the tax system to incorporate green taxes and market mechanisms that discourage environmentally unfriendly behaviour and, in turn, reward sustainable lifestyle choices. In particular we need to make significant progress on reducing emissions from aviation and make far- reaching changes to our energy policy to reduce demand, increase efficiency and develop the use of a wide variety of renewable energy sources. On the international stage, Britain should use its so-called &#8216;special relationship&#8217; with the US to push for action from the world&#8217;s biggest polluter, and more generally use our international status to promote a new, enforceable international agreement to reduce emissions to a sustainable level based on the so-called principles of contraction and convergence.</p>
<p>3: As I have become more aware of the dangers of climate change, my family and I have made a large number of changes to our lifestyle and consumption patterns over the years in order to reduce our carbon footprint. At home, we try to recycle as much as possible, and any kitchen or garden waste gets put in our compost bin. We make an effort to shop for food which is locally sourced and in season, thereby cutting food miles to a minimum, and I try to avoid food and other products with excess packaging. We are changing all my lights to energy saving bulbs as they expire, and we also make energy efficiency an important consideration when we buy any new domestic appliances. We have sourced our electricity from a green supplier. My role as an MP inevitably involves a lot of travelling, but we are now managing with just one car which we try to use a little as possible. Instead, I make the most of public transport always travelling by train between my constituency in Lewes and London and also increasingly around my constituency. If I have to travel within Europe, I can nearly always use the train rather than the plane, but when air travel is inevitable, I offset my carbon emissions. Over the years, both as the former Lib Dem Shadow Environment Secretary and current chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Environment group, I have made climate change my top priority, trying to raise awareness among fellow parliamentarians, constituents and members of the public. If all of us make small changes to our habits and lifestyles, then the cumulative effect will actually have a significant impact on our greenhouse gas emissions. We can all do something to help tackle climate change.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11996/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11996/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11996&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/what-i-think-about-climate-change-3-norman-baker-mp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/norman-baker.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">norman-baker</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quote of the week: Eurocrat Martin Schulz on Britain&#8217;s place in Europe</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/quote-of-the-week-eurocrat-martin-schulz-on-britains-place-in-europe/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/quote-of-the-week-eurocrat-martin-schulz-on-britains-place-in-europe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 20:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[flames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11993</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This one made me laugh. He&#8217;s probably right so far as it goes, if it were to be one of the failed main parties sorting out the mess. However, Mr Schulz little world, constrained and demarcated by red tape and rules as it is, could be in for a seismic shift if the political tide [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11993&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This one made me laugh. He&#8217;s probably right so far as it goes, if it were to be one of the failed main parties sorting out the mess. However, Mr Schulz little world, constrained and demarcated by red tape and rules as it is, could be in for a seismic shift if the political tide turns in the UK and ordinary folk get a say in the matter, like they&#8217;ve been promised on more than one occasion. Ordinary folk in the UK are a little freer than mainstream politicos with the old anglo-Saxon and might take exception to what Mr Schulz is telling them&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/schulz.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-11994" alt="schulz" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/schulz.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Any attempt by the UK government to repatriate powers to Westminster is likely to be a drawn out and cumbersome negotiation.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-11993"></span></p>
<p>I can&#8217;t be certain, but it may well be that the average Brit, on being told that there would have to be a drawn out and cumbersome negotiation before we were allowed to run our own country might result in advice being offered to Mr Schulz which would mainly involve sex and travel.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.express.co.uk/comment/columnists/macer-hall/387824/Eurocrat-rants-at-Cameron-You-will-break-up-the-EU">Full story here</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11993/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11993/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11993&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/quote-of-the-week-eurocrat-martin-schulz-on-britains-place-in-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/schulz.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">schulz</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apperley Bridge</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/apperley-bridge/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/apperley-bridge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 14:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11978</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A pleasant stroll in kinder weather. Happy Easter everybody.<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11978&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364652644420.jpg"><img title="wp-1364652644420.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364652644420.jpg?w=614" /></a></p>
<p>A pleasant stroll in kinder weather. Happy Easter everybody.</p>
<p><span id="more-11978"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364653726392.jpg"><img title="wp-1364653726392.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364653726392.jpg?w=614" /></a> </p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364653749998.jpg"><img title="wp-1364653749998.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364653749998.jpg?w=614" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-img_2521.jpg"><img title="IMG_2521.JPG" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-img_2521.jpg?w=614" /></a><br />
<a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-img_20130330_154421.jpg"><img title="IMG_20130330_154421.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-img_20130330_154421.jpg?w=614" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11978/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11978/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11978&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/apperley-bridge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364652644420.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wp-1364652644420.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364653726392.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wp-1364653726392.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-wp-1364653749998.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wp-1364653749998.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-img_2521.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2521.JPG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-img_20130330_154421.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_20130330_154421.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What I think about climate change #2: Nick Clegg MP</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/what-i-think-about-climate-chwhat-i-think-about-climate-change-2-nick-clegg-mpange-2/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/what-i-think-about-climate-chwhat-i-think-about-climate-change-2-nick-clegg-mpange-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 10:16:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11973</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nick Clegg MP Sheffield, Hallam, Liberal Democrat 1: I passionately believe that climate change is one of the greatest problems we face today. It is essential that politicians take rapid action to address this issue at local, national and international levels. As a Westminster MP I, along with my Liberal Democrat colleagues, support a Climate [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11973&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nick-clegg.jpeg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11974" alt="nick-clegg" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nick-clegg.jpeg?w=614"   /></a>Nick Clegg MP</p>
<p>Sheffield, Hallam, Liberal Democrat</p>
<p>1: I passionately believe that climate change is one of the greatest problems we face today. It is essential that politicians take rapid action to address this issue at local, national and international levels. As a Westminster MP I, along with my Liberal Democrat colleagues, support a Climate Change Bill which would set binding, independently monitored, annual targets for reducing emissions, but I also recognise the need for additional policy measures to make this happen. As a first step the Lib Dems are currently promoting a ‘Green Tax Switch’, which would introduce and increase green taxes on high emission vehicles and aircraft, whilst reducing income taxes elsewhere.</p>
<p>2: Britain should and can lead the way with regards to tackling climate change, using its unique influence in the many international organisations to which it is a member. However, to have any credibility in this respect we must first put our own house in order, cutting UK emissions which currently represent 2% of the global total. As with Kyoto the EU will have a major role to play and Britain should work constructively to support this.</p>
<p>3: I am installing energy saving light bulbs throughout my home and I try to use public transport as far as possible. I recycle recyclable waste at home, try to cut down on the unnecessary use of paper in the office, and unplug all unused electrical appliances. Energy consumption will certainly be a far greater consideration next time I look to purchase a new car or household appliances such as a fridge or kettle. I am also looking into switching to more environmentally responsible gas and electricity suppliers.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11973/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11973/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11973&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/what-i-think-about-climate-chwhat-i-think-about-climate-change-2-nick-clegg-mpange-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nick-clegg.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nick-clegg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Has Paul Hudson Put His Foot In It Again?</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/11971/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/11971/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 21:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/11971/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reblogged from NOT A LOT OF PEOPLE KNOW THAT: By Paul Homewood &#160; &#160; Paul Hudson works as a meteorologist with the BBC. He has earned the wrath of the Team previously, as the Climategate leaks revealed, when he dared to question some of their religious tenets. &#160; In the latest post on his BBC [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11971&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="reblog-post"><p class="reblog-from"><img alt='' src='https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6cb53b0c2439d15f5923b437211b662d?s=25&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G' class='avatar avatar-25' height='25' width='25' /> <a href="https://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/has-paul-hudson-put-his-foot-in-it-again/">Reblogged from NOT A LOT OF PEOPLE KNOW THAT:</a></p><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt"><div class="wpcom-enhanced-excerpt-content"><a href="https://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/has-paul-hudson-put-his-foot-in-it-again/" target="_self"><img src="https://s0.wp.com/imgpress?url=http%3A%2F%2Fstatic.bbc.co.uk%2Fprogrammeimages%2F320xn%2Fimages%2Fp014fdwb.jpg" alt="Click to visit the original post" class="size-full" /></a>
<p>By Paul Homewood</p>
<p>&#160;</p>

<p>&#160;</p>
<p>Paul Hudson works as a meteorologist with the BBC. He has earned the wrath of the Team previously, as the Climategate leaks revealed, when he <a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/damianthompson/100013173/the-bbcs-amazing-u-turn-on-climate-change/">dared to question</a> some of their religious tenets.</p>
<p>&#160;</p>
<p>In the latest post on his BBC blog, he has discussed the extreme cold weather we are currently getting. He finishes by commenting:-</p>
</div> <p class="read-more"><a href="https://notalotofpeopleknowthat.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/has-paul-hudson-put-his-foot-in-it-again/" target="_self"><span>Read more&hellip;</span> 85 more words</a></p></div></div><div class="reblogger-note"><div class='reblogger-note-content'>
Our favourite TV forecaster strikes again
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/11971/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BBC nags Met Office for horseracing form book</title>
		<link>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/bbc-nags-met-office-for-horseracing-form-book/</link>
		<comments>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/bbc-nags-met-office-for-horseracing-form-book/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 18:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tchannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forecasting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Variation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11960</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over on Talkshop Suggestions Gray quotes nicely so here it is By Roger Harrabin http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21967190 Last spring’s forecast has been obtained by BBC News under Freedom of Information. The Met Office three-monthly outlook at the end of March stated: “The forecast for average UK rainfall slightly favours drier than average conditions for April-May-June, and slightly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11960&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over on Talkshop <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/suggestions-3/comment-page-1/#comment-48706">Suggestions</a> Gray quotes nicely so here it is</p>
<p><a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rainy-race.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-11969" alt="rainy-race" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rainy-race.jpg?w=614"   /></a></p>
<blockquote><p>By Roger Harrabin</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21967190">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21967190</a></p>
<p>Last spring’s forecast has been obtained by BBC News under Freedom of Information.</p>
<p>The Met Office three-monthly outlook at the end of March stated: “The forecast for average UK rainfall slightly favours drier than average conditions for April-May-June, and slightly favours April being the driest of the three months.”</p>
<p>A soul-searching Met Office analysis later confessed: “Given that April was the wettest since detailed records began in 1910 and the April-May-June quarter was also the wettest, this advice was not helpful.”</p>
<p>In a note to the government chief scientist, the Met Office chief scientist Prof Julia Slingo explains the difficulty of constructing long-distance forecasts, given the UK’s position at the far edge of dominant world weather systems.</p>
<p>She says last year’s calculations were not actually wrong because they were probabilistic.</p>
<p>The Met Office explained it this way: “The probabilistic forecast can be considered as somewhat like a form guide for a horse race.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Something does not compute, the BBC using FOI with the end effect of mocking the Met Office?<br />
<span id="more-11960"></span></p>
<p>The story is covered various other places, <a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/29/met-office-or-bookies-office.html" target="_blank">Bishop Hill</a> being one worth a read.</p>
<p>In the same interview, Julia slingo came out with this gem:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>I think it was quite right that we looked at this particular forecast last year because in March we were facing really very serious pressures on water resources &#8211; a major drought that had been going on for nearly a couple of years &#8211; and I felt when I looked at the seasonal forecast at that time that I would be not being fair to the Government if I didn&#8217;t emphasise the fact that we did see a slightly enhanced risk of the drought continuing.</strong><br />
<strong> Likewise, I did also emphasise that there was also quite a chance that April would also be wetter than normal but in the context of where we were at that particular point as a country I felt it was right to emphasise the risk of dry conditions continuing as a <em>precautionary principle</em>.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Slingo&#8217;s wet phase.<br />
</strong>For goodness sake Slingo either scram or grow up although back to school might be a good idea, oh, school doesn&#8217;t get it yet either.</p>
<p>My take is that natural world physics is teaching an engineering lesson, that natural variability is much wider and operates on longer timescales than the likes of Slingo want to take on board. Low rainfall, high rainfall and every other shade of grey, sunshine, and snow white.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t answer for her brain but I can for the weather. Most of the weather and climate is not random as accepted and taught in statistics. This has been known for years. See <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/02/07/hurst-exponent-a-long-omitted-subject-from-the-talkshop/">here</a> and <a href="http://itia.ntua.gr/en/docinfo/537/">here</a> where there are many papers and links to investigate.</p>
<p>The name here is Hurst-Kolmogorov, the way the kind of random fluctuations show in weather. Koutsoyiannis has even derived a more correct statistical formula which not only give the gauss answer but are generalised if the Hurst exponent is not 0.5, which is the normal random case. (ranges from 0 which would be a completely cyclic behaviour to 1 which is highly random periodic)</p>
<p>Rainfall in the UK, temperature, probably most things have an exponent around 0.7, check the first of the &#8220;here&#8221; links, where I show this is the case with CET. This characteristic has the periodic behaviour such as spells of wet, dry, cold, hot, windy, calm, familiar to all Brits.</p>
<p>A twist though, came across a CSIRO tome which claimed indirectly Hurst does not apply, on what I spotted is flawed justification. I must drag that out and write it up. Recent floods in Oz. odd that, so they don&#8217;t get periods of dry and periods of wet? Except in politics.</p>
<p>This stuff seems to link in to log-log behaviour, maximum entropy and few other way out things which seem to be so but can&#8217;t be proven as such. I suppose that makes it deniable. No-one can actually know.</p>
<p>The AGW community are in strong denial of this, logical given that admission of there being much greater natural variation would make a mess of their doomsaying. FGS it&#8217;s weather, get on with it.</p>
<p>Rant by Tim Channon, co-mod<br />
(I usually don&#8217;t, looks bad, yet boy could I say some things including not so politely)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11960/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/tallbloke.wordpress.com/11960/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="https://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=tallbloke.wordpress.com&#038;blog=4307889&#038;post=11960&#038;subd=tallbloke&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/bbc-nags-met-office-for-horseracing-form-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d21d6725f3925a85290ce54127b80d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rainy-race.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rainy-race</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
