<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Marriage Confessions</title>
	
	<link>http://marriageconfessions.com</link>
	<description>Laugh.  Fight.  Stay Married.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 12:40:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MarriageConfessions" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="marriageconfessions" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item>
		<title>In the Silence</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/27/in-the-silence/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/27/in-the-silence/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage Confessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Understanding Katie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listening]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9219</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m in the middle of an eight-week small group Bible study at my church.  Our ministers asked a group of people to participate and go through this sort of training period, so that when they open small groups up to the congregation next fall, we will be the small group leaders.  I&#8217;m super excited about [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="3dcfe882ac67895bc1f627347da132a0 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8596880568/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8247/8596880568_687f2269e0_m.jpg" alt="3dcfe882ac67895bc1f627347da132a0" width="171" height="240" /></a><br />
I&#8217;m in the middle of an eight-week small group Bible study at my church.  Our ministers asked a group of people to participate and go through this sort of training period, so that when they open small groups up to the congregation next fall, we will be the small group leaders.  I&#8217;m super excited about it.  I love small groups when it comes to spiritual reflection.  I think I get more out of a group of 6-10 people than I do in any other form of worship.</p>
<p>The method of studying the Bible that we are learning is actually a monastic style of study.  It is based on principles of worship and reflection that monks have used for hundreds of years.  I love the ideas behind the practice, but, to be honest, it feels pretty foreign to me at this point.  We have been talking a lot about being versus doing in our faith, and we&#8217;ve concluded as a small group that it is much easier to DO than it is to BE.  To do gives you tasks and things to accomplish.  Tangible boxes to check and a sense of accomplishment when you finish.  Often, doing is led by others &#8211; a minister giving a sermon, an author writing a book, a small group leader directing the discussion.  But to BE is very different.  To be is to simply be in God&#8217;s presence.  To not ask for anything, to not give anything, to not focus on anything other than being in his presence and listening.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking and praying a lot lately about being and about listening.  As a pretty outgoing person, I tend to talk a lot.  I&#8217;m always telling stories or sharing my point of view.  As a blogger, my world revolves around my experiences and my challenges and my struggles.  If you were to put a label on me, you could call me noisy.  But lately, there have been huge indications that perhaps it is time that I listened for a while.  For one thing, this Bible study came right as I was pondering this issue for myself.  How strange (or divine?) that I would be thinking about this topic myself and then suddenly my small group at church is discussing it.  For another, I&#8217;ve been doing some writing on the side other than for this blog, and I just finished an article about silence last week that was not really related to my small group discussion, but ended up being exactly what our discussion was about last night.  I may be a little skeptical of burning bushes, but I know enough to recognize when God is trying to get my attention.</p>
<p><em>Message received, Lord.</em></p>
<p>But my thoughts about silence and listening have actually gone beyond my faith.  I think these might be principles that could serve anyone of any belief system.  The idea that sometimes we need to BE, instead of DO.  That sometimes we need to put it all down for a while &#8211; the phones, the tablets, the television, the jobs, and even the spouses and the children &#8211; and just be still.  For me, that might mean be still and know God more fully, but for others that might mean to be still and reconnect to ourselves, or hear the heartbeat of the universe around us.  For some it might mean to be still and clear our mind of clutter, doubts, fears, and anxieties.  And for others still, it might mean to be still and simply sit in peace.  Whatever it is that you hear, I&#8217;m pretty sure there are some things that we only hear in the silence.</p>
<p><a title="3dcfe882ac67895bc1f627347da132a0 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8596880568/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8247/8596880568_687f2269e0.jpg" alt="3dcfe882ac67895bc1f627347da132a0" width="357" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>A big focus for me in the past few weeks has been to be still and listen in my marriage.  Chris is such a laid back, gentle person, and it is usually me who drives our communication.  Normally, that&#8217;s not a bad thing.  Someone has to get us talking, and that task just usually falls on me.  I don&#8217;t mind because Chris always talks back.  He&#8217;s just generally not going to be the first one to bring it up.  But lately as I have sat in silence and thought about the importance of silence, I have wondered if maybe that&#8217;s not true.  Maybe Chris would bring things up.  Maybe he would speak first more, if only I was quiet enough to let him have a chance.  Maybe it&#8217;s not that he&#8217;s quiet.  Maybe it&#8217;s just that it takes him longer to prepare what he wants to say.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve focused this week, especially, on being quiet in my marriage.  On listening.  On asking questions about Chris and his day-to-day life.  I make sure to listen when he speaks, even if what he is saying seems small.  I heard someone caution one time that small does not mean insignificant, and I need to remember that when my husband speaks.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m working on finding silence in my life right now.  I&#8217;m learning how to quiet my head and listen with my heart, to both God and my husband.  Perhaps it was no coincidence that God gave us one mouth, but two ears.  It&#8217;s probably time I learned to use them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/27/in-the-silence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Potty Training, Step Three: Potty Camp 2013</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/27/potty-training-step-three-potty-camp-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/27/potty-training-step-three-potty-camp-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[About Gracie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gracie Girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Milestones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potty Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Romper Room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potty Camp 2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potty training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toddlers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9217</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are deep into Phase Three of potty training at our house.  Potty Camp 2013 has officially begun.  I&#8217;ve been chronicling the steps that we use in our house to potty train, so if you&#8217;re interested in Step One or Step Two, be sure to go back and read them.  This week we started Step [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_5202 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564944369/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8528/8564944369_5dd1fcc500_m.jpg" alt="IMG_5202" width="240" height="160" /></a><br />
We are deep into Phase Three of potty training at our house.  Potty Camp 2013 has officially begun.  I&#8217;ve been chronicling the steps that we use in our house to potty train, so if you&#8217;re interested in <a title="Gracie Update: Age 22 Months" href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/01/30/gracie-update-age-22-months/">Step One</a> or <a title="Potty Training, Step Two" href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/potty-training-step-two/">Step Two</a>, be sure to go back and read them.  This week we started Step Three &#8211; Potty Camp 2013!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5317 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591276898/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8252/8591276898_40fdf33e08.jpg" alt="IMG_5317" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Potty Camp is what I call the official, traditional, tied-to-a-potty-for-several-days potty training period.  Once Gracie first showed interested in going potty, we transitioned into practicing on the potty in Step Two.  Now that I have a full week off for Spring Break, we are using this long period of time at home for Potty Camp.  During this step, Gracie has started to wear panties instead of a diaper, has started using the potty regularly throughout the day, and is learning to tell me when she has to go before it happens.</p>
<p>Here are the key parts for our family:</p>
<p>1.  We get up in the morning and change Gracie out of her diaper and into panties.  She immediately goes to sit on the potty.</p>
<p>2.  I set our kitchen timer for 15 minutes.  Then, every time the timer goes off, we run to the potty to sit for a while.  After we&#8217;re through, I reset the timer for another 15 minutes.  If Gracie doesn&#8217;t go potty after 30-40 minutes of this routine, then I narrow the timer to 12 minutes, and finally down to 10.  What I&#8217;m trying to do is catch her on the potty when she has to go.  So, if I know it&#8217;s coming soon, we make more frequent visits to the potty to wait.</p>
<p>3.  I hung a big piece of butcher paper on the wall by the kids potty.  That&#8217;s our sticker chart.  They make actual charts, but neither of my kids could ever get the stickers in the right place on a chart, so I just use a big sheet of paper now.  She can put the sticker wherever she wants on the chart when she goes potty.  She also gets one Skittle or M&amp;M.  If she doesn&#8217;t actually use the bathroom, she doesn&#8217;t get a sticker or a candy, but I try to make it sound positive when she asks and I have to tell her no.  I say something like, &#8220;Oh, I know you wanted a sticker, but we didn&#8217;t go pee pee in the potty yet.  Maybe next time we will pee pee and then we can get a sticker and a treat!&#8221;</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5202 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564944369/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8528/8564944369_5dd1fcc500.jpg" alt="IMG_5202" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>4.  To keep Gracie sitting on the potty for as long as possible (to ensure that she has the largest window of opportunity for going pee pee in the potty), we use all kinds of tricks and games.  We sing songs, read books, play with mommy&#8217;s iPhone, play with baby dolls, play with bath toys, and watch movies on the iPad.  It also helps having Bean in the room because she&#8217;ll sit longer when he&#8217;s there, too.</p>
<p>5.  Throughout the day, I ask Gracie if she needs to go potty.  At this point (Day Two), she says yes every time, whether she needs to go or not.  But that&#8217;s okay.  She&#8217;s learning that if she tells me she has to go potty, we will go right to the potty.  Even if that is for false alarms right now, at least she is leaning how we get to the potty in the first place.  (&#8220;I tell Mommy, and she takes me.&#8221;)</p>
<p>6.  I stop potty training around 4:00 or 5:00 every day.  Usually, by this point, Gracie is tired of the ordeal and I don&#8217;t want to push her.  Also, I&#8217;ve noticed that she tends to have more accidents later in the day, and I think it&#8217;s just because she is over it.  So, I stop around 4:00 or 5:00 and put her back in a diaper for the evening and nighttime.  Then, we end on a positive note and can begin the next day on a positive note, too, because I haven&#8217;t pushed her too far.  As the week stretches on, I&#8217;ll probably lengthen that window and we&#8217;ll try making it to bath time and then bedtime without a diaper.</p>
<p>There are several goals of Potty Camp.  First, that Gracie learns that she has to tell me when she needs to go potty.  Second, that when she gets into the bathroom, she learns how to pull her panties up and down by herself.  Third, that she learns to wait on the potty until she actually goes to the bathroom.  Fourth, that Gracie learns what it feels like when she has to go potty.  And finally (and towards the end of the week), she learns to tell me BEFORE she goes potty that she needs to go.  It will take her probably all week to get to those last two steps.</p>
<p>A few things I have to remind myself throughout the week:</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>She is going to have accidents, and that is a good thing.  Having an accident is what often prompts kids to start wanting to go potty.  That&#8217;s the reason I prefer not to use trainer diapers or pull-ups.  I want her to feel the difference between going potty in her diaper and going potty in her panties.</li>
<li>After accidents, I never, ever scold her.  Ever.  Potty training should be fun and exciting.  I want Gracie to WANT to go sit on the potty.  So, if she has an accident, I say in my very best, over the top voice, &#8220;OH, NO!  Uh oh!  We had an accident.  That&#8217;s okay!  Let&#8217;s go to the potty and try again!&#8221;  And then we head immediately to the bathroom and sit on the potty again.  Just so she knows that when we have to use the bathroom, we sit on the potty.</li>
<li>We won&#8217;t be fully dressed for a couple of days.  Gracie has been running around in a t-shirt and panties this week.  Sometimes, I put leggings on her if she&#8217;s getting chilly, but mostly it&#8217;s just shirts and panties.  I thought maybe a little dress would be okay, but it was actually kind of hard for her to manage when she sat on the potty, so we left the dresses in the closet this week and are sticking to t-shirts.</li>
<li>It&#8217;s not a great idea to let a potty-training toddler sit on your unprotected furniture.  I took this picture all while thinking, &#8220;I should make her get down or else she&#8217;s going to pee on my couch.&#8221;  And 10 seconds later, she did.  Oops.</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<p><a title="IMG_5488 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8596788610/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8252/8596788610_4a03a76913.jpg" alt="IMG_5488" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5489 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8596789092/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8108/8596789092_d2d81dde1b.jpg" alt="IMG_5489" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5491 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8596789972/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8505/8596789972_464fd683f1.jpg" alt="IMG_5491" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>I try to be consistent during Potty Camp, and on the days or for the few hours when we aren&#8217;t consistent, I put Gracie back in a diaper.  I want her to be successful this week, not challenge her in new situations.  So, when we run to the grocery store or spent the day at my mom&#8217;s house, I put her back in a diaper.  I still took her on potty breaks, but she kept the diaper on so that if she had an accident it wasn&#8217;t such a big deal.  It will be a little time before I start taking her out of the house in only panties.  She&#8217;s got to master that concept first, and then we&#8217;ll try exploring.</li>
</ul>
<p>The best advice I can give a potty-training parent is to be patient and consistent, consistent, consistent.  Sometimes, Gracie doesn&#8217;t want to go sit on the potty when the timer dings.  It&#8217;s fun for the first part of the day, but by middle of the afternoon, she&#8217;s sort of over it.  But I still take her and gently encourage her to sit on the potty, even if it&#8217;s just for a minute or two.  The more consistent I am, the better chances of success she has.  And I want her to be successful, so she can be really proud of herself.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5200 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564943747/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8104/8564943747_bc3d86445a.jpg" alt="IMG_5200" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>So, that&#8217;s about all there is to report from the trenches right now.  Gracie is averaging about two accidents a day, and still thinks this is all super fun.  I&#8217;m hoping that tomorrow and Friday I can really get her to start being more aware of telling me when she needs to go, instead of me instigating it every time.  But you know what they say&#8230; plan to be surprised!  That is never more true than when potty training!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/27/potty-training-step-three-potty-camp-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes My Heart Melt</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/26/what-makes-my-heart-melt/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/26/what-makes-my-heart-melt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 17:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Siblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Romper Room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siblings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9214</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When Gracie was a baby, she was too small for Bean to play with.  He would occasionally bring his toys over and play next to her, but that was really the extent of their relationship.  That and sneaking her pieces of cheese when she was entirely too small to have chunks of cheese in her [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_5355 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591303202/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8086/8591303202_aebd7c0067_m.jpg" alt="IMG_5355" width="240" height="160" /></a><br />
When Gracie was a baby, she was too small for Bean to play with.  He would occasionally bring his toys over and play next to her, but that was really the extent of their relationship.  That and sneaking her pieces of cheese when she was entirely too small to have chunks of cheese in her mouth.  Almost gave me a heart attack several times.</p>
<p>About six months ago, they went through this very frustrating time when Bean realized that Gracie was now able to play with the toys, which meant he now had to share things.  That phase didn&#8217;t go over well with Bean.  There were frequent shouts of &#8220;mine!&#8221; in our house, until I banned the word to the naughty list.  Now, no one is allowed to say &#8220;mine&#8221; in our house.  Why?  Because everything is actually MINE.  I bought it, I simply ALLOW my children to play with it.  So, when they start claiming toys as untouchable for the other, I remind them that I have supreme authority over all the toys in the land.  It comes with my Mom crown.  Make sure you get yours before you leave the hospital when you have your baby.  They are quite handy.</p>
<p>Lately, though, the kids have been getting along so well.  So, so, so well.  I can send them upstairs to someone&#8217;s room to play, and I won&#8217;t hear a things from them for over an hour if I don&#8217;t go up there and check on them.  Now, there are times of the day when this works out better than others, but for the most part, all is quiet and docile in the sibling world at our house.</p>
<p>Which is why when things like these pictures below happen, Chris and I simply hide in a corner somewhere and take pictures on rapid shot.  Who knows how long this phase is going to last?  It might end tomorrow, for crying out loud.  We&#8217;re going to enjoy it while it&#8217;s here!</p>
<p>Chris took these pictures the afternoon of Gracie&#8217;s birthday party.  After all the guests had left, the two of them ended up on the kitchen floor together, just having a great time with a balloon.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5337 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591287934/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8377/8591287934_535c4909d8.jpg" alt="IMG_5337" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5336 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591286996/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8369/8591286996_59c3390308.jpg" alt="IMG_5336" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5335 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591285976/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8366/8591285976_e2a1e9ffe1.jpg" alt="IMG_5335" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5333 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591284146/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8370/8591284146_68eb64102b.jpg" alt="IMG_5333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5327 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590178785/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8248/8590178785_6d6dae5e32.jpg" alt="IMG_5327" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5331 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590181921/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8384/8590181921_e4977b7f7a.jpg" alt="IMG_5331" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5332 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590182571/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8365/8590182571_a28d7c7542.jpg" alt="IMG_5332" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5340 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591290332/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8525/8591290332_075a96c51b.jpg" alt="IMG_5340" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5342 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590191317/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8247/8590191317_991b6801e8.jpg" alt="IMG_5342" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5357 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590204095/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8237/8590204095_9595e20712.jpg" alt="IMG_5357" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5358 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591305844/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8097/8591305844_3c4b87891e.jpg" alt="IMG_5358" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5356 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591303972/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8238/8591303972_b3930044d5.jpg" alt="IMG_5356" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5355 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591303202/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8086/8591303202_aebd7c0067.jpg" alt="IMG_5355" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>And that, my friends, is why children make the world a better place.</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>Have you entered to win the $100 Visa gift card giveaway sponsored by <a id="js_7" href="http://www.facebook.com/buttpaste?group_id=0" data-hovercard="/ajax/hovercard/page.php?id=173232186057914&amp;extragetparams=%7B%22group_id%22%3A0%7D">Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste</a>??? Well, go on then! <a href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/look-what-i-found-butt-paste/"> Click here!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/26/what-makes-my-heart-melt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Happy, Happy Birthday</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/26/another-happy-happy-birthday/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/26/another-happy-happy-birthday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 17:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Changes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fun Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Just for Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage Confessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Out and About]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthdays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toddlers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9211</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gracie turned two yesterday, but we celebrated on Saturday with family.  It was a pretty low key celebration, which is just the kind of party that Gracie likes.  She&#8217;s not big on the crowds and action, so hanging out with grandparents, aunts, and uncles was perfect for her. But even the low number of people [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_5421 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591322512/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8511/8591322512_7dbfed24ef_m.jpg" alt="IMG_5421" width="240" height="160" /></a></p>
<p>Gracie turned two yesterday, but we celebrated on Saturday with family.  It was a pretty low key celebration, which is just the kind of party that Gracie likes.  She&#8217;s not big on the crowds and action, so hanging out with grandparents, aunts, and uncles was perfect for her.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5300 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590173423/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8532/8590173423_8e0091e319.jpg" alt="IMG_5300" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5301 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590174239/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8098/8590174239_1ec5b79468.jpg" alt="IMG_5301" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5294 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590170341/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8098/8590170341_fbb34880ac.jpg" alt="IMG_5294" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5274 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590163465/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8389/8590163465_2a117be5ee.jpg" alt="IMG_5274" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>But even the low number of people in attendance made our living room look like Christmas morning!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5245 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590155225/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8510/8590155225_cd4b476989.jpg" alt="IMG_5245" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5256 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591258186/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8387/8591258186_33ed84436e.jpg" alt="IMG_5256" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5258 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591259406/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8505/8591259406_2c88fe1edc.jpg" alt="IMG_5258" width="500" height="333" /></a><br />
Gracie wanted a Minnie Mouse themed party, so we had little Minnie Mouse decorations hanging from the ceiling in the kitchen (which I did not take any pictures of, sorry&#8230;). We also got Minnie Mouse balloons, along with pink and white balloons for our mailbox and scattered in bunches around the living room. There was also a Spiderman balloon that we snuck in there somewhere for Bean Man&#8230; And, of course, there was the Minnie Mouse birthday cake.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5287 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591269030/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8521/8591269030_6448b4be6c.jpg" alt="IMG_5287" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5291 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591269998/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8251/8591269998_101b8683a5.jpg" alt="IMG_5291" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>After opening presents and eating cake, we headed outside to play with Gracie&#8217;s two biggest gifts. Nana got her a new water table, and Grandmomma got her a sandbox. I think I am just as excited about this as both of the kids were. During the summer, we are outside all day long and these toys will be perfect!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5299 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590172455/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8521/8590172455_953b24c11b.jpg" alt="IMG_5299" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5297 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591272070/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8370/8591272070_420ee21efd.jpg" alt="IMG_5297" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5310 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591275946/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8252/8591275946_6d53d8ff32.jpg" alt="IMG_5310" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>Yesterday, on her actual birthday, Chris and I took the kids to the zoo to celebrate. It was a small zoo, but there was still a lot to do. It was gorgeous weather, and we stayed almost all day!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5363 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591306776/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8381/8591306776_ee3c27c114.jpg" alt="IMG_5363" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5394 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591319306/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8093/8591319306_df6d0b7b06.jpg" alt="IMG_5394" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5428 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590223459/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8238/8590223459_d6c45ce74f.jpg" alt="IMG_5428" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5425 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8590222201/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8382/8590222201_2ee7aa2bb9.jpg" alt="IMG_5425" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>When we first got to the zoo, Gracie flipped out at the very first exhibit. Chris and I were like, &#8220;Great. She&#8217;s afraid of animals and we brought her to a zoo on her birthday&#8230;&#8221; But, turns out, she&#8217;s just afraid of birds! And who can blame her? They kind of freak me out, too!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5368 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591307714/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8375/8591307714_65540fdc78.jpg" alt="IMG_5368" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>As the day went on, though, Gracie warmed up to the zoo. I think at first she was worried that something was going to jump out and get her. She was really jumpy. But Bean was a real life saver because the more he did, the more Gracie wanted to do, too!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5397 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591320234/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8248/8591320234_dc781f0dca.jpg" alt="IMG_5397" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Our favorite part was the giraffe exhibit. They had the spectator platforms built up really high so that we were literally face to face with the giraffes. They were really friendly, and you could feed them right out of your hand. Gracie liked them from afar, but Bean Man was right there in the middle of it!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5382 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591315392/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8380/8591315392_155aa4b9f4.jpg" alt="IMG_5382" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5380 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591313258/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8241/8591313258_0c4a63d159.jpg" alt="IMG_5380" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5377 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591312210/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8090/8591312210_06331e313d.jpg" alt="IMG_5377" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>It was a really great way to spend Gracie&#8217;s birthday, and we had fun together as a family, too. I can&#8217;t believe that sweet Gracie Girl is two! Where has the time gone????</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5418 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591321460/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8388/8591321460_9544818b24.jpg" alt="IMG_5418" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5421 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8591322512/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8511/8591322512_7dbfed24ef.jpg" alt="IMG_5421" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/26/another-happy-happy-birthday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy 2nd Birthday, Gracie Girl!</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/24/happy-2nd-birthday-gracie-girl/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/24/happy-2nd-birthday-gracie-girl/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 02:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flashbacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fun Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Just for Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage Confessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suburbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthdays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[two-year olds]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9201</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I should wait until tomorrow to post our annual birthday video for Gracie, but I just can&#8217;t do it! I can&#8217;t believe our sweet Gracie is two years old on Monday! Where has the time gone?!?! We love you so much, Gracie! You&#8217;re our little firecracker that keeps this family on its toes. You bring [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Untitled by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8431700336/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8045/8431700336_c07231d769_m.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="179" height="240" /></a><br />
I should wait until tomorrow to post our annual birthday video for Gracie, but I just can&#8217;t do it! I can&#8217;t believe our sweet Gracie is two years old on Monday! Where has the time gone?!?!</p>
<p>We love you so much, Gracie! You&#8217;re our little firecracker that keeps this family on its toes. You bring us sunshine and happiness every day, sweet girl. We love watching you grow, and can&#8217;t wait to see what the world has to offer you.</p>
<p>We love you to pieces,<br />
Mommy, Daddy, and Beanie</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Wp7jhLBbeJo?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe><br />
****<br />
<em>Music: &#8220;World on a String&#8221; by Michael Buble</em><br />
<em> Video made with: Animoto Pro</em><br />
****<br />
Want to see birthday videos from past years? Check these out:</p>
<p><a title="Happy Birthday, Gracie Girl!" href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2012/03/22/happy-birthday-gracie-girl/">Happy 1st Birthday, Gracie!</a><br />
<a title="Happy 3rd Birthday, Bean!" href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2012/05/31/happy-3rd-birthday-bean/">Happy 3rd Birthday, Bean!</a><br />
<a title="Happy 2nd Birthday, Bean!" href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2011/06/01/happy-2nd-birthday-bean/">Happy 2nd Birthday, Bean!</a><br />
<a title="Happy Birthday, Bean!" href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2010/06/01/happy-birthday-bean-2/">Happy 1st Birthday, Bean!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/24/happy-2nd-birthday-gracie-girl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Running Out of Time</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/running-out-of-time/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/running-out-of-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marriage Confessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, I casually mentioned in a blog post last week that I signed up for a 10k. And no one is freaking out about it, so I thought I would say it again to give people ample time to die laughing. I SIGNED UP TO RUN A 10K THIS WEEKEND. This is funny and terrifying [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_3592 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/7290066694/"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7229/7290066694_701bafdff4_m.jpg" alt="IMG_3592" width="240" height="160" /></a><br />
So, I casually mentioned in a blog post last week that I signed up for a 10k. And no one is freaking out about it, so I thought I would say it again to give people ample time to die laughing.</p>
<p>I SIGNED UP TO RUN A 10K THIS WEEKEND.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_3571 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/7289992180/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7082/7289992180_6925389510.jpg" alt="IMG_3571" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>This is funny and terrifying on several levels.</p>
<p>Level One &#8211; I have never run a 10k before. Ever. In fact, the farthest distance I have ever run was 8 miles. And that was at my peak last year.</p>
<p>Level Two &#8211; I haven&#8217;t run regularly since August. I get out maybe once or twice a week now.</p>
<p>Level Three &#8211; The farthest I have run in the past seven months has been 3.5 miles.</p>
<p>And so, CLEARLY, I am in the best position possible to run my farthest race yet.</p>
<p>(Go ahead and laugh now.)</p>
<p>(And while you&#8217;re at it, laugh at this picture. Especially Bean.)</p>
<p><a title="IMG_3592 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/7290066694/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7229/7290066694_701bafdff4.jpg" alt="IMG_3592" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>Seriously, I don&#8217;t know what happened. All I know is that I ran 3.5 miles last week (which is my favorite distance to run &#8211; just long enough to get the runner&#8217;s high, but short enough that I can still function for the rest of the day), came home, jumped on the computer, and signed up for the first race I found in my area.</p>
<p>This is what happens, people, when you make decisions while on a runner&#8217;s high. Or any kind of high, I would imagine. Things seem totally doable and fun and like the right thing to do. And then you wake up the next morning and think, &#8220;What the heck just happened?!?!&#8221;</p>
<p>The worst (or best?) part is that I immediately texted my friend, Dawn, and convinced her to sign up.</p>
<p>(That&#8217;s Dawn on the left of me in this picture. We sometimes run races together. And we sometimes run away from our problems together. That&#8217;s the best kind of friend to have.)</p>
<p><a title="IMG_3946 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/7509003094/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7115/7509003094_6b90a1efef.jpg" alt="IMG_3946" width="500" height="387" /></a></p>
<p>Then I emailed my mother-in-law, who will be in town this weekend, and got her to sign up, too. And then I texted my sister-in-law and convinced her to run, too. So, now, I couldn&#8217;t even back out if I wanted! I&#8217;ve got PEOPLE! I have a TEAM!</p>
<p>WHAT IS WRONG WITH ME, IMAGINARY FRIENDS????? WHY WEREN&#8217;T YOU ALL HERE TO STOP ME FROM MAKING NO GOOD, VERY BAD CHOICES?!?!?!?</p>
<p>You really dropped the ball on this one, imaginary friends. I&#8217;m very disappointed in you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/running-out-of-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Look What I Found! Butt Paste!</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/look-what-i-found-butt-paste/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/look-what-i-found-butt-paste/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Baby Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Romper Room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9106</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the first baby products I ever received was a big, giant tub of Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste. I remember it so well. Ahhh&#8230;memories&#8230; It was at my very first shower when I was pregnant with Michael, and a girlfriend gave it to me as a joke because it had &#8220;butt paste&#8221; in the name. [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Butt paste.  Cause you just never know. by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/3523699998/"><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3566/3523699998_3b40171a7e_m.jpg" alt="Butt paste.  Cause you just never know." width="240" height="180" /></a><br />
<script type="text/javascript" language="JavaScript1.1" src="http://oascentral.blogher.org/RealMedia/ads/adstream_jx.ads/ReviewBadge/OID3782_Butt_Paste_ReviewBadge_017/@x13"></script></p>
<p>One of the first baby products I ever received was a big, giant tub of <a href="http://goo.gl/epJOa" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste</a>. I remember it so well. Ahhh&#8230;memories&#8230; It was at my very first shower when I was pregnant with Michael, and a girlfriend gave it to me as a joke because it had &#8220;butt paste&#8221; in the name. (You know you&#8217;ve had children too young when phrases like &#8220;butt paste&#8221; make you explode in fits of giggles!)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="color: #0074bd;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/3523699998/"><img style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3566/3523699998_3b40171a7e.jpg" alt="" name="graphics2" width="503" height="378" align="BOTTOM" border="0" /></a></span></span></p>
<p>Michael hardly ever had diaper rash. Like, ever. In fact, I don&#8217;t think he had it once. And so my giant tub of Butt Paste sat unused in his closet. By the time Gracie was born, it had disappeared in one of our moves. Gracie was a completely different story when it came to diaper rash. That poor child hardly ever DOESN&#8217;T have diaper rash. One good diaper and her poor little bottom looks like a 17-year-old face with acne. Oh, it&#8217;s terrible! Big ol&#8217; welts all over! I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s a girl thing or a Gracie thing, but girlfriend has some issues! We tried several different methods of fighting diaper rash, but one of the most effective methods we have found is using diaper cream before diaper rash is a problem. We use it every night for Gracie, or any period of time when I know it might be a bit longer between regular diaper changes (ex. out running errands and on trips). This is preventative and helps us avoid the situation in the first place most of the time. I also use it any time there&#8217;s the slightest hint of red on her bum. My goal is to prevent the welts by using it before they show up. And that has worked really well.</p>
<p>The next step was figuring out which diaper cream to use. Since we use it so often, it has to be something that is gentle enough for her sensitive skin, but still really darn effective. That&#8217;s why we use Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste. You may think this is a product review, but I think of this post as more of a consumer report. Because we consume Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste. We consume much. I love that it comes in a tub, too. It fits in the drawer of Gracie&#8217;s changing table, and I can literally scoop out handfuls of the stuff to cover her toosh. More than the convenience, though, I love that it is actually what the silly name says. It is a BUTT PASTE, y&#8217;all. I&#8217;m talking full coverage, you-might-be-able-to-spackle-your-dining-room kind of coverage. That might sound too harsh for a baby, but if you&#8217;ve ever seen your child suffer from severe diaper rash, you know that that thick, creamy coverage is exactly what you want. <em>Ain&#8217;t nothin&#8217; gettin&#8217; through that Butt Paste</em>. Gracie&#8217;s tooshy stays dry and welt free, which is exactly what you want. While I found <a href="http://goo.gl/epJOa" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste</a> when I was a new mom, it really wasn&#8217;t until I was a more seasoned mom that I realized what a gold mine it was. We are hardly ever without it around my house. As their very entertaining video says, &#8220;Our butts are saved!!!&#8221; </span></p>
<p><iframe style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/V-Tw6Iw3qKA?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="560" height="315"></iframe></p>
<p>Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste and BlogHer are sponsoring a $100 Visa gift card giveaway on Marriage Confessions today! Enter to win by leaving a comment below telling me how you have &#8220;kicked some butt&#8221; while parenting. Be sure to especially share any good tips you have for treating or preventing diaper rash! You can also enter the giveaway a second time by posting a link to your Facebook, Twitter (be sure to use the hashtag #SweepstakesEntry), or blog post that either shares the funny video above or a link to this blog post. For more information about Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste, be sure to check out their <a href="http://goo.gl/epJOa" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Facebook page</a>. </p>
<p>Sweepstakes Rules:</p>
<p>No duplicate comments.</p>
<p>You may receive (2) total entries by selecting from the following entry methods:</p>
<p>a) Leave a comment in response to the sweepstakes prompt on this post</p>
<p>b) Tweet (public message) about this promotion and/or to share the above video; including exactly the following unique term in your tweet message: &#8220;#SweepstakesEntry&#8221;; and leave the URL to that tweet in a comment on this post</p>
<p>c) Blog about this promotion and/or the above video, including a disclosure that you are receiving a sweepstakes entry in exchange for writing the blog post, and leave the URL to that post in a comment on this post</p>
<p>d) For those with no Twitter or blog, read the official rules to learn about an alternate form of entry.</p>
<p>This giveaway is open to US Residents age 18 or older. Winners will be selected via random draw, and will be notified by e-mail. You have 72 hours to get back to me, otherwise a new winner will be selected.</p>
<p>The Official Rules are available <a href="http://www.blogher.com/new-mom-moments-official-sweepstakes-rules-group-3" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>This sweepstakes runs from 3/18/13 &#8211; 4/15/13</p>
<p>Be sure to visit the <a href="https://www.blogher.com/boudreauxs-butt-paste-reviews-sweepstakes" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Boudreaux&#8217;s Butt Paste brand page on BlogHer.com</a> where you can read other bloggers’ reviews and find more chances to win!</p>
<p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/19/look-what-i-found-butt-paste/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Cleaning Outside</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/spring-cleaning-outside/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/spring-cleaning-outside/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 21:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Around the House]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fun Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Just for Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage Confessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suburbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Little Tikes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spring cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Step2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9175</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This weekend has been another gorgeous central Florida day. Mid-seventies and not a cloud in the sky. I have crazy bad spring fever right now, and this weather isn&#8217;t helping at all! Luckily, I have spring break the week after next, so I&#8217;ll get a little taste of summer living soon, but it won&#8217;t be [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_5240 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566060000/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8096/8566060000_ec9af7eee9_m.jpg" alt="IMG_5240" width="240" height="160" /></a><br />
This weekend has been another gorgeous central Florida day. Mid-seventies and not a cloud in the sky. I have crazy bad spring fever right now, and this weather isn&#8217;t helping at all! Luckily, I have spring break the week after next, so I&#8217;ll get a little taste of summer living soon, but it won&#8217;t be enough. I&#8217;m ready for summer dresses, flip flops, bathing suits, beach bags, pool floats, and little drinks with umbrellas in them.</p>
<p>This afternoon, we decided to take full advantage of the weather by playing outside in our backyard. During the spring and summer, we live out back. We have a pool and lots of yard toys, so we pretty much wake up, put on bathing suits, and head outside. In the next month or two, Chris is going to be tearing down our back deck (which is horribly warped and falling apart) and building us a new deck that meets our family&#8217;s needs a little better. I&#8217;ll definitely blog about that process because it has been crazy cool to watching Chris design it. In preparation of that awesomeness that is coming, we decided to clean out our back yard while we were out there today.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5217 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564950985/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8232/8564950985_cc9762bf9f.jpg" alt="IMG_5217" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5219 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566049918/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8511/8566049918_7f8f1a4edd.jpg" alt="IMG_5219" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>As I said, we live outside in the spring and summer, but fall and winter we aren&#8217;t really out there too much. That means that our backyard quite literally goes to the dogs, who are the only inhabitants out there. At the first hint of spring every year, we head outback to survey the damage done all winter and set up for another year of summer fun.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5211 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566045430/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8510/8566045430_57b0f75b46.jpg" alt="IMG_5211" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5213 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566046410/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8112/8566046410_00c89f0db7.jpg" alt="IMG_5213" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5240 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566060000/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8096/8566060000_ec9af7eee9.jpg" alt="IMG_5240" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>The first thing we do is drag all the kids&#8217; outside toys into the yard and clean them off. We scrub them down with dish soap and water, and then spray them all off to get the cobwebs and bugs all cleared away. If the kids weren&#8217;t helping, I might put a little bleach in the water to help with that extra clean, but since they are old enough to want to help this year, I skipped this step.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5218 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566048930/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8104/8566048930_095fe2b7a5.jpg" alt="IMG_5218" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>While I was cleaning toys with the kids, Chris tackled the yard. He cut back the trees that hang over our playground area, picked up all the dog droppings, repaired part of the fence that was sagging, raked up leaves, picked up sticks, and then mowed. The grass hasn&#8217;t grown well this fall/winter because, quite frankly, we had other stuff going on and just didn&#8217;t care. But now that we&#8217;ve gotten all the dead leaves and junk off of it, we&#8217;ll start watering it regularly again and adding some fertilizer to help it grow. By summer, we&#8217;ll hopefully have a nice green cushion under the playground where the kids will be playing.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5205 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564945355/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8388/8564945355_7023d9a398.jpg" alt="IMG_5205" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5236 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566058988/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8247/8566058988_5ed8d880fc.jpg" alt="IMG_5236" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5223 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566053058/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8247/8566053058_b3653cae33.jpg" alt="IMG_5223" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>During our outdoor spring cleaning, we are usually able to salvage most of our big outdoor equipment. We bring most of it into the garage during the cooler months, and that helps. Plus, after a good bath, most of it seems to hold up really well all on it&#8217;s own, whether it&#8217;s in the garage or not. But, we spend this time accessing what needs to be thrown out, too. This year, we had to finally say goodbye to Bean&#8217;s water table. I love that thing, and so do the kids. But it accidentally got left out this fall/winter, and it was pretty rough when I cleaned it out today. Even after a good wash and several rinses, it was still full of residue and crap. Also, Gracie&#8217;s birthday is coming up and I hear a certain Nana is might be getting her a new water table of her very own.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5221 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8566050834/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8390/8566050834_a3c5b6855a.jpg" alt="IMG_5221" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a title="IMG_5222 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564954865/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8242/8564954865_e492b0d623.jpg" alt="IMG_5222" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>We also get rid of any pool and beach toys. These are fairly cheap, and worth the little expense of replacing every year. I tossed out old sand buckets, diving rings, and sand sculptors. I also threw out all of the kids balls. They were mildewy and gross and running out of air anyway. At only $2 or $3, I&#8217;ll happily replace those. This year, we tossed a couple beach chairs, too, because they were rusted. We usually only have to replace beach chairs about once every two years or so.</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5235 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564960903/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8248/8564960903_e1553a5981.jpg" alt="IMG_5235" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>In one short afternoon, our backyard is ready to play again. It is much easier to keep it up on a daily basis while the weather is warmer because we&#8217;re out there every day, so this will probably be one of the only all-day yard work days. But it was actually a lot of fun for all of us. The kids were super happy to be outside and use all their toys again. For Gracie, this is the first year she&#8217;ll be big enough to use some of these toys. It was great for Chris because we hung out with him while he did yard work, which he usually does by himself. And I was more than happy to clean and refresh while I dreamed about spending mornings at the splash part and nap time by the pool.</p>
<p>Hawaiian Tropic, take me away&#8230;</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5242 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564964641/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8524/8564964641_ebd0ab7a5c.jpg" alt="IMG_5242" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*******</p>
<p><em>For those who are interested, here are the toys we have in our backyard with my ratings out of 5 stars:</em></p>
<p><em></em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Lohasrus-Unfinished-Picnic-MM20301-Umbrella/dp/B001DDPSB4/ref=sr_1_31?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363544120&amp;sr=8-31&amp;keywords=kids+picnic+table+and+umbrella">Kids picnic table with umbrella</a> &#8211; 4 stars</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Little-Tikes-School-Bus-Activity/dp/B00328LR7W/ref=sr_1_cc_1?s=aps&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363544192&amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&amp;keywords=bus+and+slide+outdoor+toy">Little Tikes School Bus Activity Gym</a> &#8211; 5 stars</p>
<p>S<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Step2-Arctic-Splash-Water-Table/dp/B001JTE2KU/ref=sr_1_7?s=toys-and-games&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363544228&amp;sr=1-7&amp;keywords=water+table">tep2 Arctic Splash Water Table</a> &#8211; 5 stars</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Little-Tikes-Cozy-Coupe-Anniversary/dp/B001NQHN7S/ref=sr_1_1?s=toys-and-games&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363544273&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=cozy+coupe">Little Tikes Cozy Coupe</a> &#8211; 3 stars (great except neither of my kids ever figured out how to pedal with their feet!)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Little-Tikes-Home-Garden-Playhouse/dp/B00328322A/ref=sr_1_7?s=toys-and-games&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363544372&amp;sr=1-7&amp;keywords=little+tikes+play+house+for+outdoors">Little Tikes Home and Garden Playhouse</a> &#8211; 3 stars (my kids may not be old enough yet, but they haven&#8217;t been too interested in this one)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Step2-Kickback-Soccer-Goal-Pitch/dp/B004LLH8GS/ref=sr_1_2?s=toys-and-games&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363544505&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=little+tikes+soccer+goal+for+kids">Step2 Soccer Goal</a> &#8211; 2 stars (kind of flimsy and doesn&#8217;t stand up well when you&#8217;re playing with it)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/spring-cleaning-outside/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Potty Training, Step Two</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/potty-training-step-two/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/potty-training-step-two/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 21:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[About Gracie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daycare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gracie Girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Milestones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potty Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Romper Room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toddlerhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potty training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gracie has been showing signs of being ready for potty training for about a month now.  She can hold it for a while, sometimes even all night.  She tells us when she has to go potty, and she tells us when she needs a diaper change.  She loves panties, and has a healthy interest in [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_5200 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564943747/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8104/8564943747_bc3d86445a_m.jpg" alt="IMG_5200" width="240" height="160" /></a><br />
Gracie has been showing signs of being ready for potty training for about a month now.  She can hold it for a while, sometimes even all night.  She tells us when she has to go potty, and she tells us when she needs a diaper change.  She loves panties, and has a healthy interest in the potty happenings of all our family members.  She&#8217;s been interested, but any time I would actually put her on the potty, she wasn&#8217;t happy.  She&#8217;s squirm or cry, and so I would immediately take her down.  I didn&#8217;t want to force her to sit on the potty because I didn&#8217;t want her to be any more scared or unwilling than she already was.</p>
<p>In our house, we take potty training in a few long-term steps.  Step One has been happening for the last month.  We buy a potty seat (we use potty seats on the big potties and not little potty chairs just out of personal preference) in a favorite character and sit it on the potty.  We start reading books about going potty.  We start talking about going potty during diaper changes.  We buy a pair of underwear in a favorite character print.  Step One is all about getting them used to the idea of a potty, and beginning to associate potty with potty business.  In our house, this step can last a short while or a long while, and is completely led by the child.  Michael was in this phase for only a couple weeks.  Gracie has been in it for a little over a month.</p>
<p>With Gracie&#8217;s second birthday coming up on March 25 (WHAT!?!??!!??!??), we have slowly started entering Step Two.  Part of the reason we are entering this phase is because Gracie has started talking about going potty all by herself without us prompting her.  She takes her babydoll (named Baby Tut Tut after Cousin Tillman) into the bathroom a lot now and I can hear her telling Baby Tut Tut about going potty.  It sounds like this, &#8220;Baby Tut Tut (babble, babble, babble) potty (babble, babble, babble) big girl&#8230;(babbe, babble, babble).&#8221;  But we&#8217;ve also started Step Two because we are preparing for a big change coming up for Gracie in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>When they move into the two-year-old room at her daycare, they begin potty training.  It&#8217;s not that I&#8217;m opposed to letting someone else potty train my kids, but that time frame will line up really nicely with my spring break, so I figured I&#8217;d try to potty train her myself that week before sending her back to school into her new classroom.  She will probably have some regression (if it&#8217;s even called that this early on in the process), but at least she will have had one solid week of potty training at home with mommy.  So, spring break this year will be Potty Camp 2013 for our family, with the hope that Gracie will be ready to go by the time she&#8217;s back in school and heading into her new classroom.  Honestly, there is not a reason in the world for me to do this myself instead of just waiting for her daycare, except that I&#8217;m her mommy and I want to do it myself and my way.  I done birthed her, and I can teach her to pee pee in a potty, too.</p>
<p>Because Potty Camp 2013 will begin week after next, this interim week has been our Step 2.  In this phase, we start actually sitting routinely on the potty at specific times of the day.  I&#8217;m not actually expecting anything to happen in the potty, and if it does &#8211; great!  What this phase is for is to start getting used to being on the potty and connecting bodily functions with the potty itself.</p>
<p>So, this weekend, I&#8217;ve been taking Gracie to the potty whenever she wakes up, whenever I change her diaper, before she takes a nap, after she gets up from a nap, and before bath time and bedtime.  She&#8217;s getting really good at it now.  She likes to pull her stool up to the potty all by herself, and she always brings Baby Tut Tut with her each time.  And then &#8211; suddenly &#8211; this afternoon it happened!</p>
<p><a title="IMG_5200 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/8564943747/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8104/8564943747_bc3d86445a.jpg" alt="IMG_5200" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>I started squealing, Gracie started clapping, Bean and Chris came running &#8211; it was wonderful! She was so excited! She got her first Skittle (which we are using as potty treats because Gracie isn&#8217;t an M&amp;M fan) and got to put her first sticker up on her potty paper. She was so stinking proud of herself, and I was so proud of her!</p>
<p>GO, GRACIE, GO!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/17/potty-training-step-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Again and Again and Again</title>
		<link>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/14/again-and-again-and-again/</link>
		<comments>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/14/again-and-again-and-again/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 01:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage Confessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marriageconfessions.com/?p=9168</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh, imaginary friends!  What a week!  Am I still awake?  It&#8217;s quite possible that this week has exhausted me to the point that I am blogging with my eyes closed while I catch a few winks.  I have been busy with church obligations, school projects, requirements for my teaching certificate, and a couple big looming [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="IMG_5425_1 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/6336544421/"><img src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6033/6336544421_663fda4e66_m.jpg" alt="IMG_5425_1" width="160" height="240" /></a><br />
Oh, imaginary friends!  What a week!  Am I still awake?  It&#8217;s quite possible that this week has exhausted me to the point that I am blogging with my eyes closed while I catch a few winks.  I have been busy with church obligations, school projects, requirements for my teaching certificate, and a couple big looming deadlines at work.  In addition to these things on my mind, I&#8217;m in the middle of reading three books at the same time (&#8220;Bitterblue&#8221; by Kristin Cashore, &#8220;Raising Your Spirited Child&#8221; by Mary Sheedy Kurcinka, and &#8220;American Sniper&#8221; by Chris Kyle), and my two Bible study classes are overlapping a bit, so I&#8217;m actually participating in two devotionals at once this week.  And did I mention that I signed up today for a 10k race that is in (gulp) TWO WEEKS?  I feel like my brain is in 100 places at once!  Right now, I am the definition of spread too thin, but I&#8217;m loving it all!  Thank goodness we somehow make room for things we love.</p>
<p>Today I got ahead at school for the first time all week, which took a huge weight off my shoulders.  Last night I did a few loads of laundry, which took another weight off my shoulders.  And I finished one of my books this afternoon, which oddly took more weight off my shoulders.  (You know you are addicted to reading when books begin to weigh on you!)  Things are shaping up and I&#8217;m heading into the weekend ready to get some more things checked off my to do list.  I&#8217;m also making a to do list for Chris, which includes things like finish painting the last small side of our house and mowing our yard so that we don&#8217;t lose the kids in the grass when they are playing.</p>
<p>You know what is sitting the heaviest on my shoulders right now, though, Imaginary Friends?  Come close because I don&#8217;t want to say it too loudly.</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m working on my book.  With a publisher.  And have been for a couple months.  </em></p>
<p><em></em>Nothing is in stone yet.  Trust me, you&#8217;ll know as soon as I know.  In fact, no matter what corner of the world you are reading this blog from, I guarantee that you will hear me squeal and hoot and holler if a book deal is actually ever really signed.  But I have been talking with a publisher for a couple months now, and I&#8217;m in the middle of getting a few more sample chapters to them this week.</p>
<p>Almost a year ago, I wrote <a title="Meant To Be… Or Not To Be." href="http://marriageconfessions.com/2012/06/27/meant-to-be-or-not-to-be/">this blog post</a> about God shutting the door on my book.  I said that I thought sometimes God closed doors because it was what was best for you.  And I believe that.  But not very long after I wrote that post, I felt that tug again on my heart to write a book.  I just couldn&#8217;t get away from it.  Everywhere I went, book publishing was in my face.  It was what I literally dreamed about at night (one time I dreamed that my book came out and I was standing in Barnes and Noble, but wouldn&#8217;t let anyone pick it up off the bookshelf&#8230; ???).  And I prayed.  And I prayed.  And I prayed.  And I thought, &#8220;Lord, if this is your will, then put your hand on this book and I will be your servant.&#8221;</p>
<p>Not long after, my agent at the time called.  We had parted ways for a while after the first book deal fell through so I could go lick my wounds.  But several months had gone by and she wanted to check in to see if I was ready to try again.  And I was.  So, I wrote.  And I wrote.  And I wrote.  And publishers called and called and called.  I spoke with so many editors that I couldn&#8217;t keep them all straight.  My cup runneth over with publishers.</p>
<p>But not one of them worked out.  Every single deal I thought was in the bag passed me by.  And every time it broke my heart, but bolstered my spirit.  &#8220;I know your hand is on this, Lord, and I will wait for your perfect timing.&#8221;  Occasionally, my prayers were more like, &#8220;WHAT THE CRAP, GOD?!?!?!?&#8221; but more often than not, I was as patient as possible.  And still, no book deal.</p>
<p>This whole process has been going on for almost three years.</p>
<p>People have asked why I don&#8217;t self publish this sucker and get it over with.  I self publish every day on this blog.  Every day, I put my writing out there to be judged, criticized, embraced, laughed at, laughed with, shared, cultivated, and improved.  I don&#8217;t want to self publish because that&#8217;s an accomplishment I&#8217;ve already made.  I want something more.  I feel called to be something more.</p>
<p>Let me tell you, nothing has given me nerves of steel like trying to get a book published.  I&#8217;ve kept quiet about it because disappointment is so <em>disappointing</em> when it&#8217;s this personal.  When you want something this badly, the disappointment reaches all the way down to your toes and all the way to the core of your spirit.  And it can BREAK you.  It can break your heart into many, many pieces.  But every time it doesn&#8217;t work out, I learn to fill that broken heart with prayer and confidence that this has been put on my heart by a God who is big enough to fill that hole.</p>
<p>And so I am continuing to wait.  It might be this publisher.  It might not.  It might be this year.  It might be next.  It might be five years from now.  But I&#8217;ll be here, writing my heart out.  Pouring my heart out.  Because that&#8217;s the heart I&#8217;ve been given.<br />
<a title="IMG_5425_1 by marriageconfessions, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/marriageconfessions/6336544421/"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6033/6336544421_663fda4e66.jpg" alt="IMG_5425_1" width="333" height="500" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marriageconfessions.com/2013/03/14/again-and-again-and-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Database Caching using disk: basic
Object Caching 675/692 objects using disk: basic

Served from: marriageconfessions.com @ 2013-03-28 08:41:27 -->
