<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>back to her roots</title>
	
	<link>http://backtoherroots.com</link>
	<description>healthy eats + yummy treats</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 10:00:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<meta xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex,follow" />
	
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/backtoherroots" /><feedburner:info uri="backtoherroots" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://backtoherroots.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>backtoherroots</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>confessions…</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/MNrdgvognCk/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/16/confessions-43/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confessions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16408</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;d be remiss if I didn&#8217;t mention something about what happened yesterday in Boston before I post my trivial blather. I was once a runner. My sister is a marathoner. My brother is an ultra-marathoner. I like to consider myself part of the running community (even as just a spectator now), and this is just heart-wrenching. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/DSC06482.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6189" alt="13.1 race" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/DSC06482.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;d be remiss if I didn&#8217;t mention something about what happened yesterday in Boston before I post my trivial blather. I was once a runner. My sister is a marathoner. My brother is an ultra-marathoner. I like to consider myself part of the running community (even as just a spectator now), and this is just heart-wrenching. If you&#8217;ve ever been to the finish line of a marathon, you know that it&#8217;s completely joyous and triumphant. It&#8217;s full of smiles and hugs and happy tears and cheers. And yesterday, it was full of none of that. But even though it was horrific and terrifying, I like to try to peel away the terror and instead focus on the good. Focus on the people who help. Focus on the hugs that were given. Focus on the kindness and love that was transmitted. Focus on heart and soul of this country and the running community. Runners are a strong bunch (obviously, they run 26.2 miles just for funsies), and I have no doubt the community will end up even stronger and kinder than before.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16422" alt="red rogers" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/319939_550391681668361_710113943_n.jpg" width="570" height="618" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And now, onto something a little more light-hearted&#8230;</p>
<p>1. Every time I clean the kitchen, I turn on the *NSYNC Pandora station and dance while I clean. Unloading and loading the dishwasher is much more fun with the smooth five-part harmonies of the greatest boy band ever.</p>
<p><em id="__mceDel"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16419" alt="IMG_4286" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_42862.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></em></p>
<p>2. I love where I live for so many reasons, but I think my favorite is that while Indiana is typically considered in the Midwest—and we get all the awesome benefits of being Midwestern—here in Southern Indiana we live so close to the South that we get those cultural experiences, too (well, at least, the ones we want to adopt). I grew up eating grits and drinking sweet tea. I even have a touch of an accent (nerd alert: if you&#8217;re into that sort of thing, where I live is called the Hoosier Apex in linguistics, which is the Northernmost area in the U.S. where most residents have the Southern twang).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-5674" alt="Sun tea" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/IMG_9344.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></p>
<p>3. We call our hall bathroom &#8220;The Fish Bathroom&#8221; even though there isn&#8217;t a single fish in it. Growing up, my parents had that room decorated with fly fishing/lodge decor (if you&#8217;re new around here, last year, my husband and I bought the house I grew up in from my parents). And the name stuck. Even though there isn&#8217;t a rod, reel or creel to be found.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16410" alt="bathroom" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4288.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>4. I &#8216;ve been watching Dawson&#8217;s Creek lately, and I&#8217;m four seasons in, and I&#8217;m still not over the fact that they changed the theme song on Netflix. It&#8217;s not right. Or cool. Or okay.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16411" alt="dawson laptop" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4289.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>5. I don&#8217;t hate mowing as much as I remembered hating it when I was an angsty teenager growing up here. When I was 16, it was hours and hours of time away from The Real World marathons and my friends. But now, it&#8217;s hours and hours of uninterrupted time just sitting and thinking about life. Which, as a 16-year-old, is pretty much torture. But as an almost-30-year-old? Bliss.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16003" alt="tractor" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5608.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<h3 class="question">Do you have anything to confess?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=MNrdgvognCk:2Zk60L1_jMI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=MNrdgvognCk:2Zk60L1_jMI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/MNrdgvognCk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/16/confessions-43/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/16/confessions-43/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>this week’s menu</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/uGCT0M6ajb4/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/12/this-weeks-menu-5/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menu planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[this week's menu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16402</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Looking at this menu, and looking at the sunshiny day outside has got me thinking two things—1) we really need to get the gas tank filled on our grill and 2) I really need to put some more grill meals on the menu next week! I love grilling so much (if I&#8217;m being honest, it&#8217;s [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16403" alt="menu" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/menu.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>Looking at this menu, and looking at the sunshiny day outside has got me thinking two things—1) we really need to get the gas tank filled on our grill and 2) I really need to put some more grill meals on the menu next week! I love grilling so much (if I&#8217;m being honest, it&#8217;s mostly because I don&#8217;t have to clean up the kitchen afterward). So this is the last week of winter meals!</p>
<p>As always, if you’d like to refer to this post throughout the week, you can by clicking the big, honkin’ button in my sidebar for this week’s menu.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-16-at-8.40.38-AM.png"><img class="aligncenter" alt="menu button" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-16-at-8.40.38-AM.png" width="411" height="195" /></a></p>
<p>Onto this week&#8217;s eats&#8230;</p>
<h3>Breakfasts</h3>
<ul>
<li><a title="herbed egg, turkey and goat cheese cups" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/08/13/herbed-egg-turkey-and-goat-cheese-cups/">Turkey, Egg and Goat Cheese Cups</a></li>
<li><a title="overnight oats 101" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2011/05/11/overnight-oats-101/">Overnight Oats</a> (in a jar)</li>
<li>Oatmeal (with all the toppings)</li>
</ul>
<h3>Lunches</h3>
<ul>
<li>Tuna Salad on Rye Crisps</li>
<li><a title="salad-in-a-jar 101" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/salad-in-a-jar-101/">Salads in a Jar</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.peasandcrayons.com/2013/03/confetti-pasta-salad.html" target="_blank">Confetti Pasta Salad</a></li>
<li>Leftovers (whatever we have kicking around the fridge)</li>
<li>Veggies with Hummus</li>
<li>Fruit</li>
</ul>
<h3>Snacks</h3>
<ul>
<li><a title="peanut butter cookie date bites" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/08/30/peanut-butter-cookie-date-bites/" target="_blank">Peanut Butter Cookie Date Balls</a></li>
<li>Veggies with Hummus</li>
<li>Smoothies</li>
</ul>
<h3>Dinners</h3>
<ul>
<li>Red Beans and Rice, Cornbread</li>
<li><a title="shrimp and grits for one" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2011/10/24/shrimp-and-grits-for-one/">Shrimp and Grits</a></li>
<li><a title="chicken spinach alfredo pizza" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2011/10/28/chicken-spinach-alfredo-pizza/">Spinach Alfredo Pizza</a>, Salad</li>
<li>Salmon Fish Sticks (new recipe!), Roasted Potatoes</li>
<li><a href="http://www.healthytippingpoint.com/santa-fe-casserole" target="_blank">Sante Fe Casserole</a>, Salad</li>
<li>Hash</li>
<li>Leftovers</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="question">What&#8217;s on your menu for this week? Any new recipes you&#8217;re trying out?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=uGCT0M6ajb4:BHrpxn9_Znw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=uGCT0M6ajb4:BHrpxn9_Znw:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/uGCT0M6ajb4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/12/this-weeks-menu-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/12/this-weeks-menu-5/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>accountability update #10</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/dSzOD_5NWgA/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/12/accountability-update-10/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 12:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16389</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Friday, friends! I&#8217;m happy to report that this week went much better overall than last week. I have to be honest, the reason it&#8217;s going so well is because I am making it a&#160;priority&#160;to take care of myself. More on that below, but it&#8217;s changed my whole perspective. Everything seems to be going so [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday, friends!</p>
<p>I&#8217;m happy to report that this week went much better overall than last week. I have to be honest, the reason it&#8217;s going so well is because I am making it a&nbsp;priority&nbsp;to take care of myself. More on that below, but it&#8217;s changed my whole perspective. Everything seems to be going so much better when I focus on putting myself first.</p>
<h3>Food</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15331" alt="shabby slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/shabby.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p>Doing food prep this week was totally a game-changer! Having lots of healthy, fresh food waiting for me in the fridge is so key to eating healthfully for me. Even when I get snacky, it&#8217;s okay, because all the snacks that are easy to grab are healthy and nutritious!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16352" alt="salad jars" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4211.jpg" width="800" height="655" /></p>
<p>Interestingly enough, the one place I am struggling with this week is eating enough—especially on days when I&#8217;m working outside. I find myself losing track of time and skipping meals like crazy. And I&#8217;m so tired and worn out at the end of the day, it&#8217;s pretty much all I can do to flop down on the couch with a gin and tonic (which totally knocks me on my ass because of not eating). I started tracking my food again just to keep on top of it all. I need lots of calories when doing manual labor, and I gotta reformulate my brain to remember that.</p>
<p>Worth noting: food prep makes tracking calories super easy. I just calculate the calories for each item when I make it, and then input those into MyFitnessPal as a custom item. Then, when I eat one, all I have to do is add that item to my meal. No searching out ingredients or remembering amounts. Easy peasy!</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong>&nbsp;Plan out some easy-to-make dinners for days when I know we&#8217;re going to be working outside. The slow cooker will be great for this! Also, keep tracking my food for the week.</p>
<h3>Fitness</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="shabby slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/shabby.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p>The weather has been great this week (well, except yesterday, raaaaaiiiinnnnnn!) and it really helped me keep up with my fitness. We started off the week with an awesome hike at a nearby state forest. I know lots of folks think Indiana is flat and boring, well that&#8217;s just not entirely true. Southern Indiana is super hilly and we did a pretty intense hike.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16391" alt="me hike" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_695_size880.jpg" width="660" height="880" /></p>
<p>We basically started at the bottom of a big ridge and then hiked all the way back up it. We were on a horse trail, so it wasn&#8217;t the tidiest trail, which made it even more intense. I wish I would have worn my heart rate monitor just out of curiosity sake. I was sweating like crazy! On top of the ridge ,there is also a fire tower we hiked up. It&#8217;s like a stairclimber with an awesome prize at the end—a great view!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16392" alt="me firetower" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_669_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>The next day after the hike, we spent all day out the garden. Alllllll day. By the time the sun was setting, I was so sore and tired and stiff. Dude, gardening is a serious workout! And tilling is pretty much the best upper body workout on the planet. I was so sore the next day!</p>
<p>Because quite a few of you smart, smart people suggested it, I also started wearing a pedometer this week. I&#8217;m mostly just curious what a &#8220;normal&#8221; day for me is like activity-wise. Whenever I was figuring out how many calories I needed to eat in a day to lose weight in the past, I always checked the &#8220;sedentary&#8221; box for my activity level because I had a desk job. But I&#8217;m not so sure I&#8217;m so sedentary anymore. I&#8217;m averaging about 8,000 steps on most days, and a heck of a lot more on gardening/hiking/outside chore days. I think that&#8217;s pretty great! I remember wearing a pedometer back when I was working in an office, and it took everything I could do to get up to even 2,000 in a day. So I&#8217;m pretty happy with my active life, even if it isn&#8217;t full of cardio machines or dumbbells right now.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16336" alt="feet vibrams" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3606_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong>&nbsp;Keep on, keepin&#8217; on. Keep wearing my pedometer and try to hit 10,000 steps every day. It&#8217;s a fun little change of pace to focus on steps instead of beating myself up because I didn&#8217;t hop on the treadmill for 30 minutes.</p>
<h3>Self-Care</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15333" alt="awesome slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/awesome.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p>Like I said up top, I really tried to focus on this category this week. For me, taking care of myself this week meant setting some boundaries—especially on the work front. I quit my job so I could be the master of my own destiny, and honestly, I wasn&#8217;t acting like I had that power. I was letting people take advantage of me (from financial, time and respect standpoints) and the truth is, I don&#8217;t have to deal with that anymore. I&#8217;m my own boss, so I&#8217;m the one that has the final say on my life, my workload and my income. I said &#8220;no&#8221; this week more times than I probably ever have in my worklife before (I&#8217;m a people pleaser, &#8220;no&#8221; is a difficult word for me, and when you own your own business &#8220;no&#8221; is even scarier). But all those boundaries I set up help me have time to do the things that are really important to me—instead of just what is important to others. It meant that my morning posts were a little late this week. It meant that I ushered energy-sucking&nbsp;colleagues to the outskirts of my mind. It meant not saying &#8220;yes&#8221; to every single opportunity that crossed my desk. It meant putting my foot down when someone else&#8217;s lack of preparation turned into an emergency for me. It also meant that I pushed off some not-so-exciting projects to work on ones that really made me happy.</p>
<p>But it also meant I had time to finally plant my peas, potatoes and onions this week. And I had time to go on a hike with my husband and dog. And I was able to go out to lunch with my parents. And I got to work a little bit on a crazy exciting new adventure. I&#8217;m learning to care a lot more about uplifting the feelings of myself and those I care about than worrying so much about making someone who I don&#8217;t even really like be happy with me. It&#8217;s a struggle. For so long, I&#8217;ve been the &#8220;yes&#8221; girl. Yes, I can work on that insane deadline because no one else will. Yes, I can work on that annoying project because no one else will. Yes, I can work on that for less money because you can&#8217;t afford my standard rate. Yes, I can deal with your passive aggressive comments with a smile. And I&#8217;m changing that. I&#8217;m no longer going to let people walk all over me just because I don&#8217;t want to rock the boat. It&#8217;s not okay. And even worse than that, it&#8217;s effecting my mental and physical health.</p>
<p>So yeah, I&#8217;m feeling kinda empowered this week! Yay!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16390" alt="me hike view" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_666_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>Last week, I set a charge to not work after 8pm all week, and I did it—with one notable exception. I did work until 2am one night earlier in the week on one of those &#8220;emergency&#8221; situations. &nbsp;It was actually the catalyst for all these decisions to be more strong-willed with my boundaries. I allowed myself to make it okay for situations like that to get dropped on my lap, and I&#8217;m no longer giving permission to myself or others to let that happen. At least not on a regular basis.</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong>&nbsp;Stick to my guns and my boundaries. Do one item on <a title="50 self-care ideas" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/50-self-care-ideas/">my self-care list</a> everyday. Stop working at 8pm each night. Take one day completely off from work this week. That last one is going to be <em>really</em> hard—I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve taken a full day off from working (which I define as anything I do that makes money) since <a title="a week in paradise" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/03/27/a-week-in-paradise/">our vacation</a> last year. I&#8217;m a 100% card-carrying member of Workaholics Not-So-Anonymous. Always have been. And it&#8217;s not an admirable quality. There is life to live out there, and work (of any kind, even work I love) ain&#8217;t it.</p>
<h3>Weight</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15269" alt="slider prettygood" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/prettygood.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p><strong>Starting Weight:</strong>&nbsp;236.8 lbs<br />
<a title="accountability update #9" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/05/accountability-update-9/"><strong>Last Weigh In</strong></a>:&nbsp;228.5 lbs<br />
<strong>This Week’s Weight</strong>:&nbsp;227.4 lbs<br />
<strong>This Week’s Loss</strong>:&nbsp;-1.1 lbs<br />
<strong>Total Loss:</strong>&nbsp;-9.4 lbs.</p>
<p>I take care of myself nutritionally, physically and emotionally, and I lose weight. Go figure! This is not rocket science. I am getting a little sick of bouncing back and forth between the same five pounds or so, but hopefully, with the changes to my self-care routine, I&#8217;m on a steady path now. Since I&#8217;m starting to track my food again, that&#8217;ll also help tons! And my activity levels are increasing every single week thanks to the warm weather.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16393" alt="me feet stairs firetower" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3564_size880-e1365767208291.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>Weight is so strange, because when I was nearly 300 pounds, 10 pounds felt like nothing. I think I dropped 35 pounds before anyone ever even commented on my weight loss. But now? 10 pounds feels like everything. I feel so stuck in this land between 225-230, which is okay, if I land here forever, I won&#8217;t be reduced to a puddle of tears. But I know I feel happy and healthy at 215 (and maybe even below that, although, admittedly, I&#8217;ve never been there in my adult life). And 215 feels so close, yet so far away! It&#8217;s so crazy how much weight is about perspective. If you would have told me when I first starting losing weight that I&#8217;d struggle to lose 10 pounds for three years, I&#8217;d have laughed in your face. I could peel off 10 pounds in a couple of weeks.</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong>&nbsp;I&#8217;m going to keep tracking my food this week and see how things go. I still contend that by just living my life the way I do, weight comes off (as is evidenced by this week). So eventually, slowly I&#8217;ll get to the place my body is happy with.</p>
<h3 class="question">How did your week go? Was it healthy? Did you hit your goals?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=dSzOD_5NWgA:of58SKhU3CQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=dSzOD_5NWgA:of58SKhU3CQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/dSzOD_5NWgA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/12/accountability-update-10/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/12/accountability-update-10/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>50 self-care ideas</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/E1_MPdpzXdY/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/50-self-care-ideas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pampering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-care]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I mentioned last week that I want to start focusing more on trying to do a little something everyday to take care of myself emotionally. I focus a lot on taking care of myself nutritionally and through fitness, but I don&#8217;t talk a whole lot about the emotional side of living a healthy life. It [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16250" alt="me babyface lake" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3518_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>I mentioned last week that I want to start focusing more on trying to do a little something everyday to take care of myself emotionally. I focus a lot on taking care of myself nutritionally and through fitness, but I don&#8217;t talk a whole lot about the emotional side of living a healthy life. It isn&#8217;t just about eating kale and burning calories. There is an emotional component to wellness that I think gets overlooked too frequently. You can&#8217;t be the healthiest you until your diet, fitness and emotional state are all healthy. And I&#8217;m definitely guilty of neglecting the emotional component.</p>
<p>I tend to put myself at the very end of my priority list—especially when that list gets long. And even when I do take some time for just me, I struggle a lot with feeling guilty for neglecting my to-do list. Which is totally crazy. Taking a little bit of time out of the day is not selfish. It&#8217;s healthy! And not taking care of yourself only sets you up to eventually explode in an emotional puddle of stress and tears (or at least that&#8217;s what happens for me).</p>
<p>I <strong>have</strong> to take care of myself before I can take care of anyone or anything else. So what I&#8217;m trying to do is <em>make</em> it part of my to-do list. Sign up for at least a few minutes of me time each and everyday. Each. And. Every. Day. On most mornings, I get up and make a task list for the day. And right alongside things like &#8220;clean the kitchen&#8221; and &#8220;cook new recipe&#8221;, I&#8217;m going to slot in one of these ideas for self care. Everyday. And I&#8217;m vowing to check it off, everyday. Because I venture to say that taking care of myself is more important than having a clean kitchen, you know?</p>
<p>So here are my ideas for self-care. And I think everyone should make their own list of self-care ideas to pull from daily! My list isn&#8217;t one-size-fits-all. For example, I know a lot of folks might put &#8220;go for a run&#8221; or &#8220;go to the gym&#8221; on their self-care list, but those items just aren&#8217;t emotionally fulfilling for me, so I left them off. So feel free to add them to your own list. Join me and let&#8217;s focus on self-care just as much as we do nutrition and fitness!</p>
<p>Onto my list&#8230;.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h5>Give myself a pedicure.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Give myself a manicure.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Read for an hour.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Sit on the front porch. Just. Sit.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Take a bubble bath.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Pick a bouquet of fresh flowers.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Take a leisurely walk.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Put on a homemade face mask.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Watch a chick flick.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Take a nap.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Order in dinner.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Sew something.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Go to the library.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Color (yes, really).</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Watch funny YouTube videos.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Watch the clouds.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Look at the stars.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Dance.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Take a mental health day.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Burn a candle.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Sit in a coffee shop.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Go to the farmer&#8217;s market.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Find a new hobby.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Do yoga.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Sing at the top of my lungs (probably to the Dixie Chicks, if we&#8217;re being honest here).</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Listen to this week&#8217;s episode of This American Life.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Swing on our swingset.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Go swimming (for fun, not exercise).</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Plan out an extravagant vacation for fun.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Wear a dress that makes me feel great.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Declutter a room.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Bake something. Just for fun.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Watch the sunrise or set.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Have a picnic.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Read a magazine.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Go to bed early.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Sleep in.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Make myself a fancy coffee drink.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Learn something new.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Spend an hour on Pinterest.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Go to an art museum.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Have a beer at a bar.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Take a road trip.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Buy a fun treat at the grocery store.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Get a massage.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Do my hair in something that isn&#8217;t a bun, pigtails or a ponytail.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Make a batch of ice cream. And eat it.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Cook a fancy meal.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Catch up on blog reading.</h5>
</li>
<li>
<h5>Say &#8220;no&#8221; to someone.</h5>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 class="question">What&#8217;s your favorite way to take care of yourself? Are you good at pampering you? Or do you struggle with putting yourself at the end of your priority list?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=E1_MPdpzXdY:XlHhDGwDzWQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=E1_MPdpzXdY:XlHhDGwDzWQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/E1_MPdpzXdY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/50-self-care-ideas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/50-self-care-ideas/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>fudgy dark chocolate date frosting</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/3CNsGzYm7Xw/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/fudgy-dark-chocolate-date-frosting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16370</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, Craig and I watched Forks Over Knives. I&#8217;m kinda food documentary obsessed, so I was totally into it. Actually, whenever I find myself slipping with my healthy food lifestyle, I like to pop on one of the gazillion food documentaries on Hulu and it really helps reaffirm my whole foods lifestyle. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16372" alt="chocolate cupcake frosting" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4243.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<p>A few weeks ago, Craig and I watched Forks Over Knives. I&#8217;m kinda food documentary obsessed, so I was totally into it. Actually, whenever I find myself slipping with my healthy food lifestyle, I like to pop on one of the gazillion food documentaries on Hulu and it really helps reaffirm my whole foods lifestyle.</p>
<p>Now, of course, all of those documentaries are propaganda—not journalism—and should approached as such. I like to take them with a grain of salt and do my own research before I go and change my diet to 100% kale juice and tree bark just because some guy said so in a voice over some B-roll of a happy family playing in a field of daisies. But even though I&#8217;m decidedly&#8230;skeptical&#8230;about the things that are said in these documentaries, they do always get me thinking.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16374" alt="chocolate cupcake frosting" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4255.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t seen or heard of Forks Over Knives, it&#8217;s basically selling what they call a &#8220;plant-based diet&#8221; (AKA: veganism) as a great way to live a healthy life. Included are lots of stories about folks who were sick (mostly with cardiac issues, diabetes, high blood pressure, etc.) and when they transitioned to a whole foods, vegan diet, many of their diseases disappeared or at least diminished. Cool! Whatever works to get people healthier is totally awesome in my books.</p>
<p>But, personally, I still eat animal products, and don&#8217;t plan on changing that—even after watching FOK. That being said, what FOK did do for me is start to reevaluate some spots in my diet where I could maybe think about leaning more heavily on plants. If I&#8217;m being entirely honest, even though I&#8217;ve been trying to cut back on meat for years, I still use it (and other animal products) as the cornerstone of my meal planning. It takes a lot of effort and thought for me to make sure we have meatless meals in our menu each week. I guess that&#8217;s just engrained in my mind (and our culture here in the States). Sometimes, it&#8217;s still hard for me to feel like I&#8217;m eating a &#8220;real&#8221; meal when it&#8217;s meatless. And I&#8217;d much rather live a life where animal products are an accent in my diet rather than a main pillar. For me, when I eat that way, I feel my healthiest, strongest and my grocery budget is at its happiest.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16371" alt="chocolate cupcake frosting" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4238.jpg" width="800" height="1057" /></p>
<p>So what does this have to do with chocolate cupcakes? Well, I was perusing the Forks Over Knives website to get some creative recipe ideas and stumbled onto this little dose of genius—<a href="http://www.forksoverknives.com/double-chocolate-cupcakes/" target="_blank">Double Chocolate Cupcakes with Date Frosting</a>. I was totally in disbelief that you could make frosting out of dates. It was the same feeling I had the first time I heard about banana soft serve. Mind. Blown. Maybe this is something that is common knowledge in vegan communities, but for this carnivore, date-based frosting is pretty much the most insane and awesome discovery on the planet. What other crazy cool secrets are you vegans hiding over on the cheese-free side? Share your wealth of creative plant-based goodies with the rest of us!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16373" alt="chocolate cupcakes frosting" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4248.jpg" width="800" height="691" /></p>
<p>I changed up the method and ingredients a little bit, but the end result was still an incredible, fudgy, frosting masterpiece! All made without a drop of refined sugar or dairy. This is no buttercream (drool.yum.) but it is an awesome alternative to your normal cake shop frosting. If you&#8217;ve ever made a ganache before, it&#8217;s almost the same consistency as that, and the flavor is 100% chocolatey-goodness. Considering it&#8217;s made with dates, you&#8217;d think it&#8217;d be a little gritty, but it actually turns out incredibly smooth, spreadable and creamy. I&#8217;m pretty much in love with this stuff!</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<div class='et-box et-shadow'>
					<div class='et-box-content'><div class="hrecipe f2">
<h3>Fudgy Dark Chocolate Date Frosting</h3>
<p>by Cassie Johnston</p>
<p><strong>Prep Time: </strong>3 hours | <strong>Cook Time:</strong> None | <strong>Makes:</strong> About 2 cups of frosting</p>
<p><script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.write('<ifr'+'ame s'+'rc="ht'+'tp://www.recipage.com/new_pageCreator/media_bar.php?recipe_id=6045313" width="100%" height="50px" fr'+'ameborder="0" scrolling="no"></ifr'+'ame>');
// ]]&gt;</script></p>
<div id="ingredients">
<h4 id="ingr_header">Ingredients</h4>
<ul id="ingr">
<li>2 cups Medjool dates, pitted</li>
<li>1 cup boiling water</li>
<li>1/2 cup unsweetened cocoa powder</li>
<li>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</li>
<li>Pinch salt</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="instructions">
<h4 id="inst_header">Instructions</h4>
<ol>
<li>Place the dates in the basin of a blender, or in a tall, narrow container if using an immersion blender. Pour boiling water over dates and let sit for 10-15 minutes or until the dates are very soft.</li>
<li>Blend water and dates on high until very, very smooth. Add in the cocoa, salt and vanilla and blend until well-mixed.</li>
<li>Chill the frosting until completely cool (about 3 hours) before spreading on cupcakes.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Nutritional Info</h4>
<p><strong>Serving Size:</strong> About 2 tablespoons | <strong>Servings Per Recipe</strong>: About 16</p>
<p><span class="laveem-l" id="laveem-l-5311a303"> </span></p>
</div>
<div class="single_recipe_text" style="width: 100%; text-align: center; font-size: 10px; color: #000000;">Powered by <a class="single_recipe_header" style="text-decoration: none; color: #fb305f;" href="http://www.recipage.com/" target="_blank">Recipage</a></div>
</div></div></div>
<h3 class="question">Do you like food documentaries? Which one is your favorite?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=3CNsGzYm7Xw:PEb7nIM46AQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=3CNsGzYm7Xw:PEb7nIM46AQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/3CNsGzYm7Xw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/fudgy-dark-chocolate-date-frosting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/11/fudgy-dark-chocolate-date-frosting/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>salad-in-a-jar 101</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/1lMcO4LRgWM/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/salad-in-a-jar-101/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 16:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food prep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunch packing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16343</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, when I posted about my weekly food prep routine, I briefly mentioned that I like to make salads-in-a-jar each week. Apparently, you all are super interested in my jarred salads because I got so many comments and emails requesting more info! Now, let me note, I am in no-shape-way-or-from the originator [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16353" alt="salads in a jar" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4214.jpg" width="800" height="1044" /></p>
<p>A few weeks ago, when I posted about my weekly <a title="how i prep food for the week" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/">food prep routine</a>, I briefly mentioned that I like to make salads-in-a-jar each week. Apparently, you all are super interested in my jarred salads because I got so many comments and emails requesting more info!</p>
<p>Now, let me note, I am in no-shape-way-or-from the originator of this idea. I&#8217;ve seen it pinned from numerous sources in the holy land of Pinterest. I&#8217;m creative, but not nearly clever enough to come up with this one on my own. But I am smart enough to know a great idea when I see it and latch onto it! If any of you happen to know who the original genius behind these salad jars is, let me know, because I&#8217;d love to <del>bow down to them</del> give them the credit they deserve.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16095" alt="salad jars" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3890.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>I have four of my favorite combos to share with you guys today, but before I get to those recipes, I thought maybe I&#8217;d give you a quick primer on the things I&#8217;ve learned in my jar-making experience:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Most important rule: dressing at the bottom, greens at the top. Keep them as far away from one another as possible. If you do that, your greens will stay crispy and fresh, no problem.</span></li>
<li>Use the resting time to your advantage. Place items that&#8217;ll soak up and marinade in the dressing as the next layer for the best salad flavor. Cooked grains, tofu, meats, mushrooms—anything that is spongy and will suck up that yumminess as the jar sits in the fridge.</li>
<li>To make the salads a little more hearty and filling, try adding a protein like chicken, quinoa, beans or cubed tofu.</li>
<li>We&#8217;ve had these salads last as long as 10 days in the fridge without getting soggy, yucky or anything but delicious. We haven&#8217;t tried going longer than that because they are so yummy, they don&#8217;t last long in our house!</li>
<li>Really jam-pack the jars full. Not only does this give you the most veggies for your space, but it also helps keep things from shifting and moving around (which is particularly helpful if you are packing a jar in a lunch and it happens to tip over on its side). I shove so many greens in that I have to hold them down with one hand while I place the lid on with the other. It should be like a lettuce jack-in-the-box when you open that jar!</li>
<li>We use pint-sized canning jars and they end up making a nice-sized side salad—a pint Mason jar full of soup and a pint Mason jar full of salad would make for a perfect-sized, easy-to-pack workplace lunch (plus, you can just take the lid off the soup and microwave it right in the jar). If you want to go for a big, entree-sized salad, use quart-sized jars.</li>
<li>I try to keep the ratio of each jar about half-and-half—half toppings, dressing, grains, proteins and half greens.</li>
<li>There are two ways to eat these guys. You can either dump it all into a bowl—the dressing and toppings fall just beautifully over the greens when you dump—or, if you&#8217;re short a bowl, you can eat it directly out of the jar. Because they are so full, you might have to eat off a layer or two of greens, then replace the lid, shake the heck out of it to distribute the dressing, and then dig right in with a fork. It makes a super easy grab-and-go snack. I&#8217;ve been known to toss a salad jar in my purse when I go grocery shopping. What? Is that weird? Normal people don&#8217;t carry salads in their purses?</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16352" alt="salad jars" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4211.jpg" width="800" height="655" /></p>
<p>Below you&#8217;ll find four of my favorite combos, but it should be said that I&#8217;m much more apt to &#8220;freestyle&#8221; my salad jars each week. I mostly use whatever we have leftover in the fridge—it&#8217;s a great way to use up that 1/2 cup leftover quinoa from dinner three nights ago. They key is finding dressings that you really, really love, because that dressing will flavor everything in that jar. Experiment and figure out what works for you and your family.</p>
<p>Onto the combos&#8230;</p>
<h3>Strawberry Spinach Salad with Strawberry-Lime Vinaigrette</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16345" alt="strawberry spinach salad" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4184.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<p>This is one of my absolute favorite salads—in a jar or out. The sweet strawberries are a beautiful pairing with the creamy and tangy feta. I mixed up a super quick and easy strawberry-lime vinaigrette to flavor the whole thing. I used protein-packed quinoa and crunchy sunflower seeds, but you could easily sub in your favorite grain and seed.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16354" alt="salad jar ingredients" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_41801.jpg" width="800" height="738" /></p>
<p>To make this salad, in the jar, put items in this order:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/recipes/?recipe_id=6045233">Strawberry-Lime Vinaigrette</a> (I use about two tablespoons of dressing per pint-sized jar)</span></li>
<li>Cooked Quinoa</li>
<li>Sliced Strawberries</li>
<li>Sunflower Seeds</li>
<li>Sliced Green Onions</li>
<li>Crumbled Feta</li>
<li>Baby Spinach</li>
</ul>
<p>Depending on how juicy your strawberries are, you might want to put them down lower in the jar (before the quinoa) to keep them even further away from the spinach.</p>
<h3>Mexican Chickpea Salad with Chile-Lime Dressing</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16347" alt="mexican chickpea salad in a jar" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4192.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<p>Oh man, this one is so flavorful and delicious! The salsa really makes this salad shine, so make sure to use something you love. I really like the texture of chickpeas in this salad (and they hold up really well to the dressing) but you could easily sub in black beans, kidney beans or lentils and get the same kind of nutrition and flavor profile.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16355" alt="mexican chickpea salad jar ingredients" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_41891.jpg" width="800" height="656" /></p>
<p>To make this salad, in the jar, put items in this order:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/recipes/?recipe_id=6045235">Chile-Lime Dressing</a> (I use about two tablespoons of dressing per pint-sized jar)</li>
<li>Cooked Brown Rice</li>
<li>Cooked Chickpeas</li>
<li>Salsa</li>
<li>Red Onions</li>
<li>Halved Grape Tomatoes</li>
<li>Chopped Cilantro</li>
<li>Chopped Romaine</li>
</ul>
<p>Because of the tomatoes and salsa, this salad is a bit &#8220;wetter&#8221; than others and care should be taken not to tip it or turn it to avoid the romaine getting soggy.</p>
<h3>Tofu Living Salad with Sesame-Lemon Dressing</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16349" alt="living salad in a jar" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4200.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<p>You&#8217;ve seen the <a title="living salad with lemon-sesame dressing" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/26/living-salad-with-lemon-sesame-dressing/">big version of this salad</a> posted here before, but with a few tweaks and additions, it makes an awesome salad-in-a-jar. The flavors of this salad (and specifically, the dressing) are definite favorites in our house. Yum!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16356" alt="living salad ingredients" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_41951.jpg" width="800" height="779" /></p>
<p>To make this salad, in the jar, put items in this order:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/recipes/?recipe_id=6045236">Sesame-Lemon Dressing</a> (I use about two tablespoons of dressing per pint-sized jar)</li>
<li>Drained, Pressed and Cubed Extra Firm Tofu</li>
<li>Sliced Red Bell Pepper</li>
<li>Chopped Cucumbers</li>
<li><a title="how to sprout lentils" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/22/how-to-sprout-lentils/">Sprouted Lentils</a></li>
<li>Sunflower Seeds</li>
<li>Chopped Parsley</li>
<li>Chopped Romaine</li>
</ul>
<p>Small cubes of firm tofu act like little protein-packed sponges soaking up all the dressing goodness. Not into tofu? No problem. Shelled edamame would work great as a replacement.</p>
<h3>Sunshine Salad with Orange Marmalade Vinaigrette</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16351" alt="sunshine salad jar" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4209.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /><br />
The original Sunshine Salad recipe is one I made for my friends over at <a href="http://anytimehealth.com/blog/395204-spring-recipe-sunshine-salad" target="_blank">Anytime Fitness</a>, and I loved it so much that I decided to turn it into a salad-in-a-jar for everyday eating.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16357" alt="sunshine salad jar ingredients" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_42051.jpg" width="800" height="705" /></p>
<p>To make this salad, in the jar, put items in this order:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/recipes/?recipe_id=6045237">Orange Marmalade Vinaigrette</a> (I use about two tablespoons of dressing per pint-sized jar)</li>
<li>Cooked Quinoa</li>
<li>Clementine Wedges</li>
<li>Sliced Red Onions</li>
<li><a title="how to sprout lentils" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/22/how-to-sprout-lentils/" target="_blank">Sprouted Lentils</a></li>
<li>Pine Nuts</li>
<li>Chopped Romaine</li>
<li>Baby Spinach</li>
</ul>
<p>I use fresh clementine wedges, because I always seem to have them kicking around, but you can just as easily use canned mandarin slices—just make sure to drain them well before adding to the jar.</p>
<p>Like I said, these are just four of millions of possibilities! Let your imagination run wild. Just as long as you keep the wet layers away from the greens, your creation should be incredible! This might even be a fun way to get kids excited about eating their veggies. You can use smaller-sized jars (like jelly jars), set up a salad jar bar, and then let them assemble their own delicious, nutrient-packed creations.</p>
<p>Happy jar-making!</p>
<h3 class="question">What&#8217;s your favorite salad combo? Do you have any go-to dressing recipes to share for folks to try in their jars?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=1lMcO4LRgWM:lESdVEvwvFA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=1lMcO4LRgWM:lESdVEvwvFA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/1lMcO4LRgWM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/salad-in-a-jar-101/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/salad-in-a-jar-101/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>things i’m digging…</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/4Q9PZ2-ae0Y/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/things-im-digging-40/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[things i'm digging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16335</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1. Spring. Well, duh? Who isn&#8217;t digging this right now? It finally feels like spring has sprung here. I am so happy! We had such an awesome weekend enjoying the sunshine and warm weather. And it feels so incredible to turn the heat off and have all the windows open (well, at least until the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>1. Spring.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16337" alt="daffodils flowers stock" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3613_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>Well, duh? Who isn&#8217;t digging this right now? It finally feels like spring has sprung here. I am so happy! We had such an awesome weekend enjoying the sunshine and warm weather. And it feels so incredible to turn the heat off and have all the windows open (well, at least until the pollen takes over and I&#8217;m all about the A/C).</p>
<h3>2. My Vibrams.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16336" alt="feet vibrams" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3606_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>My awesome pink Vibrams have been safely tucked in my warm and cozy closet all winter, but it was finally warm enough to bring them out this weekend. I love these. I have such bad ankles and having barefoot shoes really help my feet wrap around obstacles and avoid another sprain. They are my favorite hiking shoe!</p>
<h3>3. Gin and Tonics.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16340" alt="gin and tonic" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Screen-shot-2013-04-08-at-1.02.28-PM.png" width="602" height="608" /></p>
<p>Spring means it&#8217;s gin and tonic season, friends! A gin and tonic is definitely my go-to cocktail. It&#8217;s so refreshing and delicious. And absolutely perfect after working out in the garden all day.</p>
<h3>4. Hart of Dixie.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16338" alt="fr_3638_size880" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3638_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>I started this show when it first came out, and I didn&#8217;t really get hooked. Recently I started watching it again from the beginning, and I&#8217;m definitely hooked this time around. It&#8217;s cute. And I like cute shows. It also helps that Summer Roberts and Jason Street are both in it. I&#8217;m such a TVaholic.</p>
<h3>5. Kombucha.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16339" alt="kombucha" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fr_3646_size880.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been kinda obsessed with kombucha lately. We make our own (well, actually, Craig does all the kombucha brewing) and I just love, love, love it! There are all kinds of reports about the health benefits of drinking kombucha, but I drink it because I love the taste of it. It makes me happy. I mix it with some chia seeds and cranberry juice to make it extra weird and gross looking. Ha! This is one of those things that I&#8217;d always get &#8220;What the hell are you drinking!?&#8221; comments in the office. Reason #3939 I&#8217;m happy to no longer working in an office: food judgement.</p>
<h3 class="question">What are you digging right now?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=4Q9PZ2-ae0Y:tCQInLJs-6I:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=4Q9PZ2-ae0Y:tCQInLJs-6I:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/4Q9PZ2-ae0Y" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/things-im-digging-40/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/09/things-im-digging-40/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>cheesy cauliflower and farro bake</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/v9JAWgQ4pA0/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/08/cheesy-cauliflower-and-farro-bake/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casseroles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cauliflower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[side dish]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Cauliflower is one of my favorite veggies. Whenever there is a veggie tray around, I always gravitate to those sweet, crunchy little trees of yumminess. Raw cauliflower is even one of my favorite road trip snacks. I tend to be a boredom snacker, and big bags of raw veggies (specifically raw cauliflower) are a great [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16328" alt="cauliflower and farro bake" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4231.jpg" width="800" height="1099" /></p>
<p>Cauliflower is one of my favorite veggies. Whenever there is a veggie tray around, I always gravitate to those sweet, crunchy little trees of yumminess. Raw cauliflower is even one of my favorite road trip snacks. I tend to be a boredom snacker, and big bags of raw veggies (specifically raw cauliflower) are a great way to munch on the road without eating thousands of calories worth of junk. In fact, I think I probably ate a whole head of cauliflower by myself on our drive down <a title="a week in paradise" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/03/27/a-week-in-paradise/">to Florida last year</a>. Yum!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16327" alt="cauliflower and farro bake" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4227.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>This dish is one of my favorite ways to use my favorite veggie! If you&#8217;re craving macaroni and cheese, but aren&#8217;t 100% ready to dive headfirst into a bucket of refined carbs, this casserole is a great substitute. Chewy, hearty, whole grain farro is mixed with tender cauliflower florets and then smothered in a gooey cheese sauce made with skim milk. The whole casserole is sprinkled with breadcrumbs and then baked until bubbly, browned and insanely delicious.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4222.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16326" alt="cauliflower and farro bake" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4222.jpg" width="800" height="547" /></a></p>
<p>You could serve this as a great side dish for Sunday dinner (or supper, if you prefer) or, if you&#8217;re really craving some comfort food, pile a big heap of this into a bowl, crawl up on the couch infront of your favorite movie and enjoy it as a main dish.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16329" alt="cauliflower and farro bake" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/IMG_4233.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re not into cauliflower (gasp! shock! awe! horror!), you can easily use the cheese sauce in this recipe for any kind of veggie yumminess. It&#8217;d be delicious over broccoli, and this is also the cheese sauce I use when I make scalloped potatoes. Yum!</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<div class='et-box et-shadow'>
					<div class='et-box-content'><div class="hrecipe f2">
<h3>Cheesy Cauliflower and Farro Bake</h3>
<p><span style="color: #000000; font-size: 15px;">by </span><span class="author" style="color: #000000; font-size: 15px;">Cassie Johnston</span></p>
<p><strong>Prep Time:</strong> 20 minutes | <strong>Cook Time:</strong> 30 minutes | <strong>Makes</strong>: 4 Servings</p>
<p><script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.write('<ifr'+'ame s'+'rc="ht'+'tp://www.recipage.com/new_pageCreator/media_bar.php?recipe_id=6045198" width="100%" height="50px" fr'+'ameborder="0" scrolling="no"></ifr'+'ame>');
// ]]&gt;</script></p>
<div id="ingredients">
<h4 id="ingr_header">Ingredients</h4>
<ul id="ingr">
<li>1 cup farro</li>
<li>2 cups vegetable broth</li>
<li>1 head cauliflower, cut into bite-sized pieces</li>
<li>2 tablespoons butter</li>
<li>1 small onion, diced</li>
<li>1 clove garlic, minced</li>
<li>2 tablespoons all-purpose flour</li>
<li>2 cups skim milk</li>
<li>1/2 cup freshly-shredded fontina cheese</li>
<li>1/2 cup freshly-shredded sharp cheddar cheese</li>
<li>Salt and pepper, to taste</li>
<li>1/2 cup panko breadcrumbs</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="instructions">
<h4 id="inst_header">Instructions</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 350°.</li>
<li>In a medium saucepan, combine the broth and farro over medium-high heat. Bring to a boil, reduce heat and simmer until the liquid is absorbed and the farro is tender, about 10 minutes. Set aside.</li>
<li>Meanwhile, bring a large pot full of water to a boil, add cauliflower florets and cook until fork tender, but not mushy, about 5 minutes. Drain and set aside.</li>
<li>While the farro and cauliflower are cooking, in a small saucepan melt the butter over medium heat. Add in the onion and garlic and cook until tender, about 5 minutes. Whisk in flour and continue to whisk constantly for 2 minutes. Slowly pour in the skim milk while whisking. Bring to a simmer and cook until thickened enough to coat the back of a spoon, about 7 minutes. Remove from heat and whisk in the cheeses, salt and pepper.</li>
<li>To assemble casserole stir together farro, cauliflower and cheese sauce until everything is well-coated. Pour into a casserole dish and then sprinkle top with breadcrumbs. Cover with aluminum foil.</li>
<li>Bake in preheated oven for 30 minutes, removing the foil during the last 10 minutes to brown the breadcrumbs.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Nutritional Info</h4>
<p><strong>Serving Size:</strong> About 1 cup |  <strong>Servings Per Recipe:</strong> About 4
<span class="laveem-l" id="laveem-l-4380b464"> </span></p>
</div>
<div class="single_recipe_text" style="width: 100%; text-align: center; font-size: 10px; color: #000000;">Powered by <a class="single_recipe_header" style="text-decoration: none; color: #fb305f;" href="http://www.recipage.com/" target="_blank">Recipage</a></div>
</div></div></div>
<h3 class="question">What&#8217;s your absolute favorite veggie?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=v9JAWgQ4pA0:4qm-NggbzGI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=v9JAWgQ4pA0:4qm-NggbzGI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/v9JAWgQ4pA0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/08/cheesy-cauliflower-and-farro-bake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/08/cheesy-cauliflower-and-farro-bake/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>monday motivation: sunshine</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/kaOJIEXkBrc/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/08/monday-motivation-sunshine/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monday motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quotes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16320</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What can you do today to stop looking at the negative and focus on the good things in your life?]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16321" alt="sunshine" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/sunshine.jpg" width="800" height="995" /></h3>
<h3 class="question">What can you do today to stop looking at the negative and focus on the good things in your life?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=kaOJIEXkBrc:30FnTDlqxeo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=kaOJIEXkBrc:30FnTDlqxeo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/kaOJIEXkBrc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/08/monday-motivation-sunshine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/08/monday-motivation-sunshine/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>friday freebie: $75 shabby apple gift card {CLOSED}</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/xl8I2ffF_R4/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/05/friday-freebie-75-shabby-apple-gift-card/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 17:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion & Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[giveaways]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This giveaway is now CLOSED! Thanks for entering! It&#8217;s been a while since I&#8217;ve done a giveaway around here, but I&#8217;ve got a really great one to make up for it this week! Instead of the normal food and fitness flair, the folks at Shabby Apple thought it might be fun to hand over to one lucky [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #ff0000;">This giveaway is now CLOSED!</span></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #ff0000;">Thanks for entering!</span></h2>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a style="font-size: 1.17em;" href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/shabby2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" alt="shabby2" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/shabby2.jpg" width="590" height="590" /></a></h2>
<p>It&#8217;s been a while since I&#8217;ve done a giveaway around here, but I&#8217;ve got a really great one to make up for it this week! Instead of the normal food and fitness flair, the folks at Shabby Apple thought it might be fun to hand over to one lucky reader a $75 gift card to snag some of their beautiful clothes, jewelry and accessories. There is so much pretty over at Shabby Apple, I seriously wish I could win this giveaway! I&#8217;m particularly in love with this <a href="http://www.shabbyapple.com/p-1307-honey-bee-necklace.aspx" target="_blank">darling little honey bee necklace </a>(because, as you know, I&#8217;m obsessed with all things bee-related!).</p>
<p>Not only does Shabby Apple have amazing products, but they&#8217;re also a pretty amazing company. They <a href="http://www.shabbyapple.com/t-helpingWomen.aspx" target="_blank">donate</a> 5% of all their sales to organizations that give micro-loans to women entrepreneurs in developing companies. Very cool!</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/shabby1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" alt="shabby1" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/shabby1.jpg" width="590" height="590" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>PRIZE: </strong>One $75 gift card to Shabby Apple</li>
<li><strong>TO ENTER:</strong> Like <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Shabby-Apple/56291792791)" target="_blank">Shabby Apple</a> on Facebook, then come back here and comment on this post and tell me which Shabby Apple product you are most excited to own.</li>
<li><strong>GIVEAWAY CLOSES:</strong> Tuesday, April 9th, 2013 at Noon (12pm) EST</li>
<li><strong>NUMBER OF WINNERS:</strong> One</li>
<li><strong>ELIGIBLE FOLKS: </strong>This giveaway is open to folks with a U.S. mailing address only. Sorry, international readers! I try to snag as many international give aways as I can. Maybe next time!</li>
<li><strong>WINNER ANNOUNCED:</strong> Wednesday, April 10th, 2013 on this here post!</li>
<li><strong>LEGALESE</strong>: To enter you must be 18 or older. Winner will be chosen by random drawing from the pool of comments on this post. To be considered for the prize, you must provide a valid email address. One entry per email address. Once a winner is notified and verified, Shabby Apple will be provided with the contact information of the winner and they will be responsible for  prize fulfillment. The number of eligible entries received determines the odds of winning. To enter, leave a comment on this post. No purchase necessary to win. Entries will close on Tuesday, April 9, 2013 at noon (EST). The winner will be contacted by email on or before Wednesday, April 10, 2013. If the winner does not claim the prize within seven days, the original winner forfeits the prize and a second random entry will be chosen from the pool. This contest is sponsored by Shabby Apple and is void where prohibited by law.</li>
<li><strong>DISCLOSURE</strong>: In exchange for this blog post, as well as posting this giveaway, I was in no way compensated.</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #ff0000;">We have a winner! Congratulations Valerie B.! Val loves the pearl dangle earrings. Happy shopping!</span></h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=xl8I2ffF_R4:InY2tDhV9Po:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=xl8I2ffF_R4:InY2tDhV9Po:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/xl8I2ffF_R4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/05/friday-freebie-75-shabby-apple-gift-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>85</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/04/05/friday-freebie-75-shabby-apple-gift-card/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.888 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-16 06:03:36 -->
