<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>back to her roots</title>
	
	<link>http://backtoherroots.com</link>
	<description>healthy eats + yummy treats</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 12:52:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
<meta xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex,follow" />
	
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/backtoherroots" /><feedburner:info uri="backtoherroots" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://backtoherroots.com/?pushpress=hub" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>backtoherroots</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>things i’m digging…</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/LjVnRXsUH3A/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/26/things-im-digging-39/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 12:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[things i'm digging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1. Our Office. We recently played a little musical chairs with some rooms in our house and flip-flopped the guest room with the office. Originally, our office was upstairs, which was great, in theory. But in practice, it turns out that being so far away from all the main living areas meant that we rarely [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>1. Our Office.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16146" alt="office" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_40012.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>We recently played a little musical chairs with some rooms in our house and flip-flopped the guest room with the office. Originally, our office was upstairs, which was great, in theory. But in practice, it turns out that being so far away from all the main living areas meant that we rarely used it. In fact, I pretty much never used it. I much preferred working on my tiny 13&#8243; Macbook screen on the couch downstairs. But now that we&#8217;ve switched it, I feel so much more connected the rest of the house when I&#8217;m working. And, it makes it easy to plug into the big monitor (which certainly makes designing websites easier). It&#8217;s so funny how you plan for certain spaces in a house and then, in reality, they just don&#8217;t work even though, on paper, they look perfect. Our office is now, easily, the most used room in the house. Granted, it&#8217;s chock full of hand-me-down furniture and needs a good makeover, but at least it&#8217;s functional!</p>
<h3>2. Keen Arcata Shoes.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15967" alt="me jeans feet keens" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3834.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>When <a href="http://www.zulily.com/invite/cjohnston392" target="_blank">Zulily</a> had their last Keen sale (knocking things down by 50-70%), Craig and I stocked up and purchased 16 pairs of shoes between the both of us (so not exaggerating). We both had a ton of cheap-o discount store shoes in our closet and figured it was time to become adults and spring for some nice, long-lasting options. Anywho, I love every single pair I ordered—Keen has never steered me wrong—but out of all of them, my<a href="http://www.zulily.com/p/black-arcata-sneaker-women-30014-1947711.html?s=1&amp;pos=2147483647" target="_blank"> black Arcatas</a> are my absolutely most worn. I wear them almost everyday. They are so comfortable and cute. I wish I would have picked them up in the other colors when the Zulily sale was still going on. Speaking of Zulily, for those fo you that were commenting on all my glass storage containers in my <a title="how i prep food for the week" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/" target="_blank">food prep post</a>, Zulily is having <a href="http://t.co/a8GenTXxQ8" target="_blank">a storage container sale </a>right now and they have quite a few nice glass ones.</p>
<h3>3. Being busy.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16145" alt="desk computer" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_40051.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>I have a tendency to bitch and moan and complain when I get overwhelmed, but the truth is, I thrive when I&#8217;m busy and right now, damn, am I busy. I knew being my own boss would be hard, but I didn&#8217;t quite realize it was going to be don&#8217;t-have-time-to-take-a-shower kinda hard. But even though it&#8217;s more work than I&#8217;ve ever done in my life, it is such a nice feeling to know that, even on my own, I can do my part to pay the mortgage. Yesterday, I clocked about 14 hours worth of work in front of the computer (surviving mostly on easy-to-grab yogurt and bananas). A little more healthy balance would be nice, but I&#8217;ll take this over working for the man any day. Eventually, I&#8217;m hoping to have enough business that I feel comfortable saying &#8220;no&#8221; or &#8220;not this month&#8221; to new clients, but right now, I&#8217;m taking on whoever wants to work with me. Hire me! I&#8217;m an award-winning graphic designer who loves doing anything from websites to wedding invitations! Oh, and sometimes I bake cupcakes for my clients. Just sayin&#8217;.</p>
<h3>4. Raisins.</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16074" alt="raisin clementine" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3897.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>Such a weird thing to be digging right? On a whim last week, I picked up a container of raisins (mostly because I wanted something sweet) and Craig and I plowed through them in three days. I forgot how yummy raisins are! I love how much they plump up in oatmeal. Yum.</p>
<h3>5.Portabella Mushrooms</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16147" alt="portabella mushrooms" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_4015.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>I used to hardly ever buy portabellas because the organic ones were so, crazy expensive at the grocery store I shopped at. But I changed stores when I moved here and, for some reason, they almost always have organic portabellas on sale, and even at regular price, they are crazy cheap. I buy 10-12 portabella caps every time I go grocery shopping. They are so versatile! We use them on pizza, in pastas and last night, Craig sautéed some to put as a baked potato topping. Yum!</p>
<h3 class="question">What are you digging right now?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=LjVnRXsUH3A:eXx20HSSR-k:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=LjVnRXsUH3A:eXx20HSSR-k:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/LjVnRXsUH3A" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/26/things-im-digging-39/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/26/things-im-digging-39/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>homemade protein powder (it’s cheap! it’s easy!)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/cAQKE6GxFng/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/25/homemade-protein-powder-its-cheap-its-easy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[add-ins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how tos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protein powder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tutorial]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16114</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have a love/hate relationship with protein powder. I love that it helps make my daily smoothie more filling and meal-like. I love that it&#8217;s a quick and easy way to get a nice dose of the recovery-helping macronutrient after a hard workout. But I hate the price. And I, more often than not, hate [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16130" alt="protein powder smoothie" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3984.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<p>I have a love/hate relationship with protein powder. I love that it helps make my daily smoothie more filling and meal-like. I love that it&#8217;s a quick and easy way to get a nice dose of the recovery-helping macronutrient after a hard workout.</p>
<p>But I hate the price. And I, more often than not, hate the ingredient list. There are definitely more natural protein powders out there, but the price is just so restrictively high! And the rare times I found a natural protein powder that wasn&#8217;t exorbitantly expensive, it was exorbitantly gritty, earthy, and generally not delicious.</p>
<p>We recently ran out of our giant tub of protein powder, and I&#8217;ve been meaning to buy another one. But every time I&#8217;ve gone grocery shopping, I&#8217;ve landed in the protein powder aisle, taken one look at the prices and turned my shopping cart right around. I have a seriously hard time justifying $20+ for some powder.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="protein powder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3962.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>But then it hit me, hey, I have stuff that has protein in it in my pantry. And I have a coffee grinder that does a dang good job of turning things into powder. So, uh, why not? So I did.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16124" alt="protein powder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3960.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>It took a little bit of experimentation to get something that didn&#8217;t overwhelm other flavors in smoothies. At first, I tried just straight ground dried lentils. Tons of protein, yes, but also tons of lentil-y flavor. Not recommended, unless you are one of those people who thinks a peanut butter-banana-lentil smoothie sounds delicious. So then I started to think about ways to cut the lentil flavor, but still add protein—enter steel cut oats and brown rice.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16122" alt="protein powder lentils, grains" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3955.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>Both the steel cut oats and the brown rice have protein, but more importantly in this little concoction they are pretty flavorless, which helps cut back on the earthy flavor of the lentils. I worked a little bit on the ratio, and soon enough, I had a nice protein-packed powder that just was pretty much flavorless in a smoothie. Win!</p>
<h3>Want to make your own? Here&#8217;s the break down:</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">1/3 cup steel cut oats</span></li>
<li>1/3 cup brown rice</li>
<li>1 cup dried green lentils</li>
</ul>
<p>I mixed all of that up in a bowl, and then ground it in my coffee grinder about 1/3 cup at a time (just because my grinder is small) until it was a very fine powder. I ended up with just shy of two cups total of protein powder.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16125" alt="protein powder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3962.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>The nutritional info isn&#8217;t quite as high in protein as your standard off-the-shelf protein powder, but it&#8217;s still pretty amazing, especially considering the low price tag and the low number of ingredients. Because of the carb-y nature of the oats and rice, it&#8217;s higher in carbs that store-bought powder, too, but I&#8217;m a big fan of whole grain, natural carbs, so I&#8217;m good with it! And, of course, you can play with the ratios to up the protein even more (more lentils) and reduce the carbs (less steel cut oats and rice).  You could also try other protein-tastic add-ins, like dried soybeans or dired black beans. I just always have lentils kicking around, so it was a good fit for our lifestyle.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the comparision between my homemade protein powder and my typical off-the-shelf protein powder.</p>
<h3>Homemade Protein Powder (per 1/4 cup of powder)</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">130 calories</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">8g protein</span></li>
<li>1g fat</li>
<li>24g carbs</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ingredients</strong>: Lentils, Brown Rice, Steel Cut Oats</p>
<h3>Store-Bought Protein Powder  (per 1/4 cup of powder)</h3>
<ul>
<li>80 calories</li>
<li>14g protein</li>
<li>0g fat</li>
<li>5g carbs</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ingredients</strong>: Proprietary non-GMO protein blend (rice protein, pea protein and soy [isolated soy protein and fermented soy]), di-calcium phosphate, FOS (fructooligosaccharides), curcumin (natural color), banana flavor, potassium citrate, guar gum, magnesium oxide, psyllium, natural vanilla flavor, oat bran, microcrystalline cellulose, spirulina, vitamin C, vitamin E (d-alpha tocopheryl acetate), choline bitartrate, inositol, apple pectin, bee pollen, niacinamide, vitamin A palmitate, zinc oxide, manganese sulfate, ferrous fumarate, calcium pantothenate, lecithin, lemon bioflavonoids, papaya, bromelain, chlorophyll, pyridoxine HCl, riboflavin, thiamine HCl, vitamin B-12, vitamin D, folic acid, biotin, potassium iodide, chromium chloride, sodium selenite, sodium molybdate</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16129" alt="smoothie protein powder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3980.jpg" width="800" height="1042" /></p>
<p>I know what some of you are saying—but I don&#8217;t have a coffee grinder! Well, I think it&#8217;s worth the cash to go out and buy one. My coffee grinder was a whopping $10 at Target a few years ago. A $10 coffee grinder, $1 bag of lentils, $1 bag of brown rice and $2 worth of steel cut oats will make you much more than $14 worth of all-natural, plant-based, vegan protein powder.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16131" alt="protein powder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3985.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;m a unflavored, unsweetened protein powder kind of girl, but I know that sometimes it can be really fun to mix it up with fun flavors, so I spent a little time creating four different flavor variations on the powder.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16128" alt="protein powder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3971.jpg" width="800" height="771" /></p>
<h3>Variations</h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><strong>Cappuccino</strong>: For each 1/3 cup of lentil/rice/oats mixture you blend in the coffee grinder, throw in 1 tablespoon of whole coffee beans and blend until a fine powder. To sweeten, add desired amount of stevia or sugar.</span></li>
<li><strong>Chocolate</strong>: For each 1/3 cup of lentil/rice/oats mixture you blend in the coffee grinder, throw in 1 tablespoon of unsweetened cocoa powder and blend until a fine powder. To sweeten, add desired amount of stevia or sugar.</li>
<li><strong>Vanilla</strong>: For each 1/3 cup of lentil/rice/oats mixture you blend in the coffee grinder, add in the insides of 1/2 of a vanilla bean or slice a whole vanilla bean in half lengthwise and stash in a jar with the whole batch of protein powder to flavor continuously. To sweeten, add desired amount of stevia or sugar.</li>
<li><strong>Pumpkin Spice</strong>: For each 1/3 cup of lentil/rice/oats mixture you blend in the coffee grinder, add in 1/4 teaspoon of ground ginger and ground cinnamon and 1/8 teaspoon of ground nutmeg and ground cloves. To sweeten, add desired amount of stevia or sugar.</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16127" alt="coffee grinder" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3965.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>Let me know if you guys try it out with any other ratios, flavors or ingredients! I&#8217;d love to hear what you guys come up with. Happy protein powder making!</p>
<h3 class="question">Does anyone else have a near panic-attack when they go to buy protein powder? Or am I just a cheapskate?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=cAQKE6GxFng:Lns_fP7aUxM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=cAQKE6GxFng:Lns_fP7aUxM:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/cAQKE6GxFng" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/25/homemade-protein-powder-its-cheap-its-easy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/25/homemade-protein-powder-its-cheap-its-easy/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>this week’s menu</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/Fc5GHy0vOOE/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/22/this-weeks-menu-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menu planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[this week's menu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16105</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For this week&#8217;s menu, I wanted to really focus on making our diet lean a little more toward the plant-based world. We&#8217;ve been steadily working our way through our stash of meat in the freezer (which has been awesome!) but I&#8217;d really like to be more cognizant of when we&#8217;re eating meat. If you look back at [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15905" alt="yogurt bowl" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3757.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>For this week&#8217;s menu, I wanted to really focus on making our diet lean a little more toward the plant-based world. We&#8217;ve been steadily working our way through our stash of meat in the freezer (which has been awesome!) but I&#8217;d really like to be more cognizant of when we&#8217;re eating meat. If you look back at the past few of my WIAWs, you&#8217;ll notice that I&#8217;ve been eating meat at most of my meals. And while, that&#8217;s cool if that&#8217;s you thing, I&#8217;ve found that I feel my best and get in my most fruits and veggies when I keep the meat to a minimum. So this week, we&#8217;re all about being strong with the plants!</p>
<p>As always, if you’d like to refer to this post throughout the week, you can by clicking the big, honkin’ button in my sidebar for this week’s menu.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-16-at-8.40.38-AM.png"><img class="aligncenter" alt="menu button" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-16-at-8.40.38-AM.png" width="411" height="195" /></a></p>
<p>Onto this week&#8217;s eats&#8230;</p>
<h3>Breakfasts</h3>
<p>I&#8217;ve been noticing that we&#8217;re focusing a lot more on quick breakfasts lately, so I figured I might as well go with that trend and put quick options on the docket for the week.</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Cereal with almond milk and <a href="http://instagram.com/p/XIVuvSw_NC/" target="_blank">a big selection of fruit</a></span></li>
<li>Banana and berry protein smoothies (with homemade protein powder—more on that soon)</li>
<li>Toast with peanut butter and fruit</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6299" alt="blueberry smoothie" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/IMG_01921.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></p>
<h3>Lunches</h3>
<p>Our fridge is actually still pretty packed from last weekend&#8217;s<a title="how i prep food for the week" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/" target="_blank"> food prep</a> (we ended up having more leftovers to eat on this week than I anticipated), so some of these are repeats, but there are a few new items in there, as well.</p>
<h4>Main Dishes</h4>
<ul>
<li><a title="cold greek quinoa salad" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/06/07/cold-greek-quinoa-salad/" target="_blank"><span style="line-height: 13px;">Greek Quinoa Salad</span></a></li>
<li>Salads in a Jar</li>
<li><a title="slamdunk black bean sliders with sriracha mayo" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/slamdunk-black-bean-sliders-with-sriracha-mayo/" target="_blank">Black Bean Burgers</a></li>
<li>Leftovers (whatever we have kicking around the fridge)</li>
</ul>
<h4>Side Dishes</h4>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;">Veggies with Hummus</span></li>
<li>Fruit</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16094" alt="veggies" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3881.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<h3>Snacks</h3>
<p>I&#8217;ve been finding myself snacking a lot less now that I&#8217;m home all the time. I think, when I was working in an office, I used &#8220;snack time&#8221; as a way to break up the day. Now, I don&#8217;t need that break! But just in case, here are the snacks I have planned:</p>
<ul>
<li><a title="peanut butter cookie date bites" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/08/30/peanut-butter-cookie-date-bites/" target="_blank"><span style="line-height: 13px;">Peanut Butter Cookie Date Balls</span></a></li>
<li>Veggies with hummus</li>
<li>Cereal with almond milk and fruit</li>
<li><a title="coconut-pistachio stuffed dates" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/01/16/coconut-pistachio-stuffed-dates/" target="_blank">Stuffed Dates</a></li>
<li>Cashews</li>
</ul>
<h3><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16107" alt="dates" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/dtaes1.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></h3>
<h3>Dinners</h3>
<p>A few folks asked me why I don&#8217;t do dinner prep when I do my <a title="how i prep food for the week" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/" target="_blank">weekly food prep routine</a>, that&#8217;s because I love cooking dinner! Usually, right around when time comes for me to start on dinner happens to be time I&#8217;m ready to quit working for the day. Heading to the kitchen is a nice change of pace after a few hours in front of the computer or out in the garden.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Friday</strong>: Roasted Veggie Pizza, <a title="living salad with lemon-sesame dressing" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/26/living-salad-with-lemon-sesame-dressing/" target="_blank">Living Salad</a></li>
<li><strong>Saturday:</strong> <a title="hard cider salmon and veggie packets with fresh peach salsa" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/06/13/hard-cider-salmon-and-veggie-packets-with-fresh-peach-salsa/" target="_blank">Grilled Salmon with Peach Salsa</a>, Green Beans</li>
<li><strong>Sunday:</strong> Portabella Fajitas (new recipe!)</li>
<li><strong>Monday</strong>: <a href="http://www.dailygarnish.com/2012/06/penne-with-creamy-vegan-sweet-potato-sauce.html" target="_blank">Penne with Creamy Sweet Potato Sauce</a>, Simple Kale Salad (new recipe!)</li>
<li><strong>Tuesday</strong>: <a title="baked falafel lettuce wraps with tahini sauce" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/05/17/baked-falafel-lettuce-wraps-with-tahini-sauce/" target="_blank">Baked Falafel Lettuce Wraps</a>, Tabbouleh</li>
<li><strong>Wednesday</strong>: <a href="http://www.pbs.org/food/fresh-tastes/stuffed-shells/" target="_blank">Stuffed Shells</a>, <a title="living salad with lemon-sesame dressing" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/26/living-salad-with-lemon-sesame-dressing/" target="_blank">Living Salad</a></li>
<li><strong>Thursday</strong>: Salmon Fish Sticks (new recipe!), Roasted Potatoes</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16110" alt="salmon" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/salmizzle.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<h3 class="question">What&#8217;s on your menu for this week? Any new recipes you&#8217;re trying out?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=Fc5GHy0vOOE:n8Tm72lsj5Y:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=Fc5GHy0vOOE:n8Tm72lsj5Y:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/Fc5GHy0vOOE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/22/this-weeks-menu-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/22/this-weeks-menu-3/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>accountability update #8</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/GPS62wtVcm0/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/22/accountability-update-8/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=15976</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Friday, everyone! I know I&#8217;ve skipped these accountability posts for the last few weeks, but I&#8217;m back this week with a vengeance! Food When it comes to the quality and quantity of foods, I feel like I&#8217;m doing really well. I&#8217;m also feeling incredibly inspired in the kitchen lately. I have so many ideas for [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday, everyone! I know I&#8217;ve skipped these accountability posts for the last few weeks, but I&#8217;m back this week with a vengeance!</p>
<h3>Food</h3>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/shabby.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15331" alt="shabby slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/shabby.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></a></p>
<p>When it comes to the quality and quantity of foods, I feel like I&#8217;m doing really well. I&#8217;m also feeling incredibly inspired in the kitchen lately. I have so many ideas for fresh recipes and clean food and healthy, delicious eats. Now that we are into spring (although, admittedly, it doesn&#8217;t feel like it outside), I find myself drifting toward a lot more of a plant-based diet. In the winter, I tend to crave dairy and meat and heavy carbs, but as soon as that sun starts shining and the snow stops, I want fresh greens, fruit, whole grains, and fish. I want lots of light and bright flavors, and that is great for my recipe inspiration and great for my health. I absolutely cannot wait until our garden is producing and my &#8220;grocery shopping&#8221; involves just walking out the door with a basket and a knife.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16095" alt="salad jars" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3890.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;m still 100% off the sugar. It&#8217;s been kinda remarkably easy for me, and has me really second-guessing the &#8220;need&#8221; for sugar in my life. Even though I swore I wasn&#8217;t going to, I started watching this season of the Biggest Loser the other day (no spoilers, I&#8217;m only a few episodes in) and one of the things that really resonated with me was the idea that your home should be your healthy food bubble. You can have cookies and brownies and cupcakes in a healthy lifestyle, but there is no reason to bring them into your bubble. There will be plenty of opportunities to eat those things outside of the bubble, so why would you add that temptation to your safety blanket? I really like the idea of keeping my bubble clean and green, and then getting my &#8220;fix&#8221; outside of the house. Get dessert with a dinner out at a restaurant. Eat a piece of birthday cake at a birthday party. Have a fancy coffee drink while out shopping. There is a certain nice black and white line about that &#8220;bubble&#8221; concept that really resonates with my all-or-nothing personality. I definitely still have a lot of thinking about how I&#8217;m going to go about reincorporating sugar back into my life now that Lent is coming to a close.</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong> I&#8217;d like to pick one day this upcoming week and track my food just to see how I&#8217;m doing with a typical day. As I&#8217;ve said before, my issue comes with portion control, and just as long as I keep an eye on it, I think I should be fine.</p>
<h3>Fitness</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15268" alt="slider okayish" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/okayish.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p>Fitness for the past few weeks has been a world of extremes. When it was nice out, I&#8217;d be working my buns off. I actually wore my heart rate monitor one day while I was out doing work around here and I burned about 900 calories in three hours. It&#8217;s not an extreme amount, but enough that I was tired and very, very sore the next day. And that was a short day.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15997" alt="shovel soil" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5598.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>Since the nice days are devoted 100% to working outside, I tend to be overcompensating on the not-so-nice days. I spend the cold and rainy days inside cleaning and working on the computer to make up for the neglect from the outside work. Which means, not a lot of activity on those days. If I were a more devoted person, I&#8217;d hop on the treadmill on those days, but the truth is, I&#8217;m not. And I&#8217;m working my arse off on outside days, so I&#8217;m mostly okay with that.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m still struggling with my mindset accepting that yes, indeed, three hours of shoveling is a workout and not feeling guilty for not using the treadmill in the last three weeks. The definition of an &#8220;active life&#8221; extends way beyond the gym, and I&#8217;m constantly reminding myself of that.</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong> Stop worrying about it so much. Just keep moving and just&#8230;be.</p>
<h3>Hydration</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15333" alt="awesome slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/awesome.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been a water rockstar for the past few weeks. Partially because it makes me feel so good, but also partially because I&#8217;m fighting off a UTI (TMI, right?). So to fight that off, I&#8217;m draaaaaankin&#8217; my weight in water and pucker-inducing 100% cranberry juice.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, when I&#8217;m in the house, at the desk and working, I drink a ton of water because my water bottle is right there. But when I&#8217;m outside working? I drink a lot less because I&#8217;m moving all around and my water bottle is never close. I&#8217;m actually considering wearing my CamelBak when I work outside. Especially once it starts to get warmer.</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong> Keep on, keepin&#8217; on.</p>
<h3>Weight</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="awesome slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/awesome.jpg" width="590" height="106" /></p>
<p><strong>Starting Weight:</strong> 236.8 lbs<br />
<a title="accountability update #7" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/01/accountability-update-7/"><strong>Last Weigh In</strong></a>: 229.1 lbs<br />
<strong>This Week’s Weight</strong>: 226.4 lbs<br />
<strong>This Week’s Loss</strong>: -2.7 lbs<br />
<strong>Total Loss:</strong> -10.4 lbs.</p>
<p>Woohoo! Down 10 pounds since January 20th! It certainly is coming off slow this time around (that 2.7 pounds took about three weeks to come off), but I&#8217;m moving in the right direction. I feel myself closing in on my &#8220;happy weight&#8221;. I know that sounds crazy that someone could be happy at 200+ pounds, but I honestly feel my best when I&#8217;m somewhere between 210-215ish, so we&#8217;re closing in.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15968" alt="me jeans" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3842.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>When I first started losing weight, back when I was close to 300 pounds, I thought I&#8217;d be my absolute happiest at 150 pounds. That was the magic number. But then I started to realize that your happy weight isn&#8217;t just about how you look and what size your jeans are, it&#8217;s also about what is maintainable with the lifestyle you want.</p>
<p>I could get down to 150 pounds. I could be a single-digit size. I know how. And maybe I&#8217;d even be crazy happy with my appearance at that weight. But that&#8217;d also mean I&#8217;d have to skip trying new beers at our local brewery. And only have dessert once a month. And count all my calories. And spend hours a week on the treadmill. My genetics just don&#8217;t make it easy to maintain that size, so it&#8217;d take some serious work to get there and stay there. And honestly, I&#8217;m just not willing to do that. Maybe that makes me lazy, but it&#8217;s the truth.</p>
<p>For me, finding my happy weight is a balance between health, appearance and lifestyle. At nearly 300 pounds, I wasn&#8217;t healthy, I didn&#8217;t like my appearance, but my lifestyle was certainly enjoyable. At my lowest weight, I was healthy, and I liked my appearance, but I hated my lifestyle of calorie-counting and dessert-skipping. At my &#8220;happy weight&#8221; I want to be healthy, like my appearance <strong>and</strong> get to enjoy my life. And I think that &#8220;magic&#8221; number is different for anyone (and certainly isn&#8217;t found on any height/weight or BMI chart). Anywho, I can feel myself closing in on that happy place, and that, well, makes me happy!</p>
<p><strong>How to improve next week:</strong> Just keep on eating fresh and staying active. If I keep both of those up, the scale will probably move. And if it doesn&#8217;t, it&#8217;s not supposed to.</p>
<h3 class="question">How did your week go? Was it healthy? Did you hit your goals?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=GPS62wtVcm0:cdqaY29ZP9M:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=GPS62wtVcm0:cdqaY29ZP9M:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/GPS62wtVcm0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/22/accountability-update-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/22/accountability-update-8/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>how i prep food for the week</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/JOCXNFAjC88/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food prep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preparing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve mentioned a few times on here how my food prep binges on the weekend really help me stay on track with nutrition throughout the week. I hadn&#8217;t really thought much about writing a post about it until I saw the awesome Lindsay over at the The Lean Green Bean do her weekly series on [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16097" alt="food prep" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3902.jpg" width="800" height="577" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve mentioned a few times on here how my food prep binges on the weekend really help me stay on track with nutrition throughout the week. I hadn&#8217;t really thought much about writing a post about it until I saw the awesome Lindsay over at the <a href="http://www.theleangreenbean.com/" target="_blank">The Lean Green Bean</a> do her weekly series on her food prep routine. I was so inspired by everyone else&#8217;s food prep, that I thought maybe I should give you guys a small peek into mine as well. So this past weekend, I snapped some photos while I set off one of my patented kitchen bombs.</p>
<p>The first step for my food prep is to make a list. This shouldn&#8217;t surprise you. I&#8217;m pretty much the queen of lists. Ha! I did a little pre-list when I made my menu and went grocery shopping for the week, but now that it&#8217;s time to actually do the work, I make a &#8220;real&#8221; list and make sure to put it in the order I want to work.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16091" alt="food prep list" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3876.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>After my list is made, I usually pull out all the ingredients I&#8217;ll need to get through the whole list. I&#8217;m lucky to have a giant island to spread out on. Having all the ingredients out and clumped together really saves me some time. Plus, I also like the visual of working my way through them. I put ingredients away as I&#8217;m finished with them, and as the counter starts to get empty, I know I&#8217;m closing in on the finish line.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16092" alt="food prep ingredients" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3878.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>To make the most out of my time, I try to start with the things that have an element of inactive work. Like making bread. I make a loaf of bread each week, and I get the dough together and rising first, before I do anything else. Bonus: because I&#8217;m working in the kitchen and have the stove and the oven on, it warms up and my dough rises better. Win!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16093" alt="dough bread" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3879.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>Next, I just start working through my list. I try to keep like things together so I can use the same kitchen utensils without washing. Like, for example, I chop all my veggies for snacking&#8230;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16094" alt="veggies" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3881.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>&#8230;and then right after, I start working on my salads-in-a-jar. I&#8217;m not sure who the first person to think of putting a salad in the jar, but man, it is genius. I was skeptical when I first tried it, but just as long as the lettuce is separate from the dressing, it all stays fresh and crisp for days. My lunchtime veggie intake has skyrocketed thanks to these little salad jars stashed in the fridge. I usually dump the whole thing into a bowl, but Craig just shakes it up and eats it right out of the jar. It&#8217;s a a perfectly portable healthy lunch. Love &#8216;em.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16095" alt="salad jars" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3890.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>Once I&#8217;ve made it through my whole list, I stash everything on the top shelf of the fridge. Not only does it make it easy to get to, but it&#8217;s also the first thing we see when we open up the fridge door. I&#8217;m a believer that if I&#8217;m visually assaulted with healthy foods, I&#8217;m much more likely to eat healthy foods.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16098" alt="fridge" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3909.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>Curious what I made this week? Here&#8217;s the whole lot of it:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16099" alt="food prep" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_38991.jpg" width="800" height="818" /></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height: 13px;"><a title="cold greek quinoa salad" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/06/07/cold-greek-quinoa-salad/" target="_blank">Cold Greek Quinoa Salad</a> (top left)</span></li>
<li><a title="slamdunk black bean sliders with sriracha mayo" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/slamdunk-black-bean-sliders-with-sriracha-mayo/" target="_blank">Black Bean Burgers</a></li>
<li><a title="herbed egg, turkey and goat cheese cups" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/08/13/herbed-egg-turkey-and-goat-cheese-cups/" target="_blank">Herbed Turkey and Egg Cups </a></li>
<li>Salads-in-a-jar: <a title="living salad with lemon-sesame dressing" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/26/living-salad-with-lemon-sesame-dressing/" target="_blank">lemon-sesame dressing</a>, quinoa, celery, red onion, <a title="how to sprout lentils" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/02/22/how-to-sprout-lentils/" target="_blank">lentil sprouts</a>, feta and romaine.</li>
<li>Cherry-chocolate smoothies (middle left)</li>
<li>Cherry tomatoes, carrot sticks, celery sticks and sweet pepper slices</li>
<li><a title="peanut butter cookie date bites" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/08/30/peanut-butter-cookie-date-bites/" target="_blank">Peanut Butter Cookie Date Balls</a> (with added bittersweet chocolate)</li>
<li><a title="kitchen 101: how to hard boil eggs" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/07/26/kitchen-101-how-to-hard-boil-eggs/" target="_blank">Hard-boiled eggs</a></li>
<li><a title="braided seed bread" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/06/braided-seed-bread/" target="_blank">Braided Seed Bread</a> (bottom left)</li>
<li>Grapes (washed and portioned out)</li>
<li><a title="coconut-pistachio stuffed dates" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/01/16/coconut-pistachio-stuffed-dates/" target="_blank">Pistachio-Stuffed Dates</a> (topped with chocolate)</li>
</ul>
<p>This, plus some other additions like cereal for breakfast or leftovers for lunch, will be enough food to get us through the week. It took me about three hours to get through all this cooking, but I know it saves so much more time than that during the week. It makes it so easy to grab breakfasts, lunches and snacks during the week. Honestly, the time and effort isn&#8217;t all that bad. The worst part about the whole thing? The pile of dishes afterward. Yeeeeesh.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16071" alt="kitchen dishes" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-19-at-5.30.14-PM.png" width="800" height="800" /></p>
<p>But thankfully, I have an awesome husband who doesn&#8217;t mind cleaning up after I spent hours cooking us healthy, yummy food for the whole week.</p>
<p>Each week, I try to make 2-3 options for lunches, 2-3 options for breakfast and a handful of options for snacks. It changes each week. Here&#8217;s another food prep I did a few weeks back. In this one, you&#8217;ll see other food prep frequenters like granola bars, <a title="overnight oats 101" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2011/05/11/overnight-oats-101/" target="_blank">overnight oats</a>, <a title="my favorite snacks : packable fruit and yogurt parfait" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2011/02/17/my-favorite-snacks-packable-fruit-and-yogurt-parfait/" target="_blank">fruit and yogurt parfaits</a>, and tuna salad. It all just depends on what we&#8217;re in the mood for.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-15733" alt="food prep" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_3450.jpg" width="800" height="675" /><br />
If it weren&#8217;t for food prepping each week, my diet would probably consist of some leftovers and whatever food was within reach in the pantry. I know having all these fresh fruits and veggies ready and waiting has definitely made me eat more goodies. Even Craig agrees! He says that without the weekly food prep, he probably wouldn&#8217;t even bother with packing fruits or vegetables in the lunch he takes to work, but with it all there and ready to go, it&#8217;s actually easier to just grab something healthy instead of doing the work to pack something not-as-healthy.</p>
<p>Food prepping takes a pretty big time commitment, but for us, it&#8217;s a system that works, so that time is worth it. If you&#8217;ve never tried it before, I highly recommend making your own list and setting off a kitchen bomb of your very own!</p>
<h3 class="question">Do you do food prep? What are you favorite dishes to prepare for eating throughout the week?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=JOCXNFAjC88:b72IrI63qZQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=JOCXNFAjC88:b72IrI63qZQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/JOCXNFAjC88" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/21/how-i-prep-food-for-the-week/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>bacon, beans and greens (for one!)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/sZaEDtoUhwo/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/20/bacon-beans-and-greens-for-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bacon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lunches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[side dishes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16081</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now that I&#8217;m working from home, I&#8217;m eating a lot of lunches on my own. Usually, I&#8217;m deep in the middle of some project, and don&#8217;t want to spend a lot of time pulling together a lunch. This means I&#8217;ll grab something quick and easy from the fridge. But sometimes, I feel like taking advantage [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16084" alt="beans and greens" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3923.jpg" width="800" height="1107" /></p>
<p>Now that I&#8217;m working from home, I&#8217;m eating a lot of lunches on my own. Usually, I&#8217;m deep in the middle of some project, and don&#8217;t want to spend a lot of time pulling together a lunch. This means I&#8217;ll grab something quick and easy from the fridge. But sometimes, I feel like taking advantage of the fact that I have my full kitchen at my disposal and work up a hot lunch.</p>
<p>I have quite a few hot lunch go-tos, but this one is one of my absolute favorites. It comes together in about 10 minutes, it&#8217;s packed with flavor, leafy greens, and healthy plant-based fiber and protein. And my favorite part—it&#8217;s perfectly portioned for one, filling lunch-sized serving.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16083" alt="bacon beans and greens" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3920.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>The truth is, this recipe is much less of a &#8220;recipe&#8221; and more like a suggestion of types of ingredients. I say that, because it&#8217;s so insanely adaptable. I like the combo of white beans and the crunch of lightly-sauteed pak choy, but you can use black beans and spinach or butter beans and chard&nbsp;or pinto beans and kale. Whatever you love (and have around) will work. Thanks to the flavorful base, it&#8217;s really hard to mess this one up. Really hard.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16082" alt="bacon beans and greens" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3917.jpg" width="800" height="916" /></p>
<p>I usually just pour everything into a bowl and eat it as an entrée, but this would also work as a healthy side dish for any dinner. And if you put a perfectly poached egg or two on top, you&#8217;ve got yourself a great breakfast to start your day.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<div class='et-box et-shadow'>
					<div class='et-box-content'><div class="hrecipe f2">
<h3>Bacon, Beans and Greens</h3>
<p class="single_recipe_text" id="author" style="font-size: 15px; color: #000000; padding: 0; margin: 5px 5px 5px 0px;">by <span class="author">Cassie Johnston</span></p>
<p class="single_recipe_text" style="color: #000000; font-size: 12px; padding: 0; margin: 8px 4px 4px 4px;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Prep Time:</span><span class="preptime"> 2 minutes</span></p>
<p class="single_recipe_text" style="color: #000000; font-size: 12px; padding: 0; margin: 4px;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Cook Time:</span><span class="cooktime"> 10 minutes</span></p>
<p class="single_recipe_text" style="color: #000000; font-size: 12px; padding: 0; margin: 4px;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Makes:</span> 1 serving</p>
<p><script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.write('<ifr'+'ame s'+'rc="ht'+'tp://www.recipage.com/new_pageCreator/media_bar.php?recipe_id=6044259" width="100%" height="50px" fr'+'ameborder="0" scrolling="no"></ifr'+'ame>');
// ]]&gt;</script></p>
<div id="ingredients">
<h4 id="ingr_header">Ingredients</h4>
<ul id="ingr">
<li>1 slice thick-cut bacon, cut into small pieces</li>
<li>1 clove garlic, minced</li>
<li>Pinch of red pepper flakes</li>
<li>1 small onion, diced</li>
<li>2 tablespoons water</li>
<li>2 cups greens, cut into bite-sized pieces (I used pak choy)</li>
<li>1-15 ounce can beans, drained and rinsed (I used cannellini beans)</li>
<li>Salt and pepper, to taste</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="instructions">
<h4 id="inst_header">Instructions</h4>
<ol>
<li>In a Dutch oven or a saute pan with a lid, saute the bacon, garlic, red pepper flakes and onion over medium-high heat until the bacon is crisp and the onion is tender, about five minutes.</li>
<li>Add in the water, and scrape the bottom of the pan to deglaze. Add in the greens, cover and let greens wilt for about 2 minutes.</li>
<li>Add in beans, salt and pepper and stir, cook for about another 90 seconds, or until the beans are warmed. Remove from heat and serve.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Nutrition Info</h4>
<p>Serving size: About 2-1/2 cups. Servings per recipe: 1.
<span class="laveem-l" id="laveem-l-1b767abe">&nbsp;</span></p>
</div>
<div class="single_recipe_text" style="width: 100%; text-align: center; font-size: 10px; color: #000000;">Powered by <a class="single_recipe_header" style="text-decoration: none; color: #fb305f;" href="http://www.recipage.com/" target="_blank">Recipage</a></div>
</div></div></div>
<h3 class="question">Do you have any go-to dishes that are perfectly portioned for one serving?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=sZaEDtoUhwo:DJdfIZ_ZzkY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=sZaEDtoUhwo:DJdfIZ_ZzkY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/sZaEDtoUhwo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/20/bacon-beans-and-greens-for-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/20/bacon-beans-and-greens-for-one/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>what i ate wednesday: leftovers</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/8I6cOQvysI4/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/20/what-i-ate-wednesday-leftovers-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what i ate wednesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16070</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are some days when I just cannot muster any energy beyond putting some leftovers on a plate and nuking them. This past Monday was one of those days. Craig had a surprise day off because of the nasty weather, and having that free day motivated both of us to kick some major buns on [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3786.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15904" alt="wiaw header" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3786.jpg" width="800" height="548" /></a></p>
<p>There are some days when I just cannot muster any energy beyond putting some leftovers on a plate and nuking them. This past Monday was one of those days. Craig had a surprise day off because of the nasty weather, and having that free day motivated both of us to kick some major buns on our to-do lists. We did a lot of spring organizing and I did an absolute ton of food prep for the week. As&nbsp;evidenced&nbsp;by this kitchen bomb I showed off on Instagram. And our sink is deep, so it&#8217;s even worse than it looks. Holy dishes, Batman.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-19-at-5.30.14-PM.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16071" alt="kitchen dishes" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-shot-2013-03-19-at-5.30.14-PM.png" width="612" height="611" /></a><br />
It was awesome that we got so much accomplished, but it meant that meals were all leftovers, all-the-time. It&#8217;s a good thing we both <del>like</del> love leftovers. Onto my eats&#8230;</p>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16072" alt="breakfast eggs bacon toast fruit" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3871.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p>Since we knew we were going to be working so hard, we decided to have a nice, big, hearty breakfast to fill us up. Scrambled eggs, bacon, toast and some fruit on the side. I like big breakfasts, and I cannot lie.</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16073" alt="pasta lunch" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3884.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p>By lunchtime, I was deep in the throes of cleaning out the fridge, which meant I had a pile of &#8220;we must eat these now!&#8221; leftovers to get through. I ended up heating up the last of my <a title="30 before 30 update: #14, #16, #19" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/14/30-before-30-update-14-16-19/">homemade pasta</a>, while Craig had another back-of-the-fridge special for his lunch.</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16074" alt="raisin clementine" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3897.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p>For an afternoon snack, I nibbled on some golden raisins and a clementine. We picked up the raisins on a whim at the grocery store last shopping trip, but I&#8217;m kinda obsessed with them. So sweet!</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16075" alt="salad casserole dinner" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3913.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p>Dinner was a leftover two-parter—leftover tuna casserole from a few nights back and a leftover garden salad. I tend to overdo it when I make salads for dinner, so I just keep adding the extras into a container in the fridge and then use them up as our veggie on leftover night. Yay for easy, healthy dinners!</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16076" alt="date tea" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3915.jpg" width="800" height="537" />
<p>For dessert, I had a date, stuffed with pistachio pieces and rolled in bittersweet chocolate (yum!) and a mug of tea.</p>
</div>
<p>As always, big thanks go out to Jenn at <a href="http://www.peasandcrayons.com/" target="_blank">Peas and Crayons </a>for hosting this fun food-filled party we have every week. If you guys haven&#8217;t clicked over to the main WIAW post yet, you should! There are so many fun eats and so many new blogs to discover. You could lose a handful of hours just discovering new friends and foods!</p>
<p><center><br />
<a href="http://www.peasandcrayons.com/" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="http://i48.photobucket.com/albums/f210/klutzycutie16/WIAWbutton.jpg" border="0" /></a></center></p>
<h3 class="question">What&#8217;s the best thing you&#8217;ve eaten so far this week?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=8I6cOQvysI4:gJSXWju5hVA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=8I6cOQvysI4:gJSXWju5hVA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/8I6cOQvysI4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/20/what-i-ate-wednesday-leftovers-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/20/what-i-ate-wednesday-leftovers-2/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>confessions…</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/R5Hg5iTHMfU/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/confessions-41/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confessions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16039</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am terrible about putting on sunscreen. I know I should put it on everyday, but I&#8217;ve just never gotten in the habit of it. This has to change. In related news, anyone have any natural sunscreen recommendations? I really like mayo. I think it&#8217;s yummy. And made with not-terrible-for-you stuff. I&#8217;ve never understood why [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16040" alt="me umbrella" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/me.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p><span class='et-dropcap' style="font-family: Sacramento; font-size: 70px; color: #65cbba; margin: 5px 15px 0px 0px;">1</span> I am terrible about putting on sunscreen. I know I should put it on everyday, but I&#8217;ve just never gotten in the habit of it. This has to change. In related news, anyone have any natural sunscreen recommendations?</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16029" alt="sliders" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3864.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p><span class='et-dropcap' style="font-family: Sacramento; font-size: 70px; color: #65cbba; margin: 5px 15px 0px 0px;">2</span> I really like mayo. I think it&#8217;s yummy. And made with not-terrible-for-you stuff. I&#8217;ve never understood why &#8220;mayo&#8221; is a four-letter word.</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16054" alt="me hair" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/fr_2677_size880.jpg" width="800" height="655" />
<p><span class='et-dropcap' style="font-family: Sacramento; font-size: 70px; color: #65cbba; margin: 5px 15px 0px 0px;">3</span> The best part about having bangs? I haven&#8217;t had to tweeze my eyebrows in over two months. Granted, I&#8217;ve trading tweezing for bang trimming, but I&#8217;ll take that over plucking pain any day.</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16056" alt="bed" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/fr_3252_size8801.jpg" width="800" height="600" />
<p><span class='et-dropcap' style="font-family: Sacramento; font-size: 70px; color: #65cbba; margin: 5px 15px 0px 0px;">4</span> I&#8217;m a recent covert to the world of bed-making. I now do it every morning. I&#8217;m so much more productive with a made bed. Weird, right?</p>
</div>
<div id="wiaw1"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16057" alt="clothes closet" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/clothes.jpg" width="800" height="533" />
<p><span class='et-dropcap' style="font-family: Sacramento; font-size: 70px; color: #65cbba; margin: 5px 15px 0px 0px;">5</span> 95% of the clothes in my closet go unworn now that I don&#8217;t work in an office. I think a major closet clean-out might be in my future. I have waaaay too many clothes anyway.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<h3 class="question">Do you have any confessions to share?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=R5Hg5iTHMfU:AbR2XeUmVQ0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=R5Hg5iTHMfU:AbR2XeUmVQ0:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/R5Hg5iTHMfU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/confessions-41/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/confessions-41/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>slamdunk black bean sliders with sriracha mayo</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/APLpeVd2pvI/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/slamdunk-black-bean-sliders-with-sriracha-mayo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black beans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burgers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandwiches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sliders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spicy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=16023</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you guys have been with me here for more that 10 seconds, you know that I am a huge, huge, huge sports fan. And the #1 sports love-of-my-life is college basketball. I went to my first college basketball game at five months old, and man, did that obsession ever stick. If you are a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3856.jpg"><img alt="sliders" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3856.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></a></p>
<p>If you guys have been with me here for more that 10 seconds, you know that I am a huge, huge, huge sports fan. And the #1 sports love-of-my-life is college basketball. I went to my first college basketball game at five months old, and man, did that obsession ever stick.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16029" alt="sliders" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3864.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></p>
<p>If you are a basketball fan, you know that today starts the NCAA tournament (aka: March Madness, The Big Dance, the most nerve-racking three weeks of the year). In this area of the country, pretty much everything revolves around the tournament. Basketball is religion in these parts. And March is our holiest of months.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3858.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16027" alt="sliders" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3858.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>My team doesn&#8217;t play until Friday afternoon, but the first few games of the tournament are today, and I can promise you, I&#8217;ll be tuning in. In fact, I pretty much rearranged my schedule this week to make sure I was inside, near a TV during game time.</p>
<p>March Madness isn&#8217;t necessarily about your specific team (although, of course, I&#8217;d love to see my Hoosiers win a sixth national championship). It&#8217;s about the love of the game. Even the years we didn&#8217;t make the tournament, I watched as many games as I could. I love March Madness. All of it. Every second of it. Magic happens during the tournament, my friends. Magic.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3852.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16024" alt="slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3852.jpg" width="800" height="1000" /></a></p>
<p>Of course, I had to pay homage to my favorite time of year with a perfect game time black bean sliders. I absolutely love sliders. And I think they are a perfect option for a game day party. Sure, there is something really nice about a big, juicy burger, but I love the control you have with sliders. Since they are so small, portable and easy-to-eat, you can really craft a perfect, flavorful bite. Plus, everything tastes better when it&#8217;s mini, right?</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3862.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16028" alt="sliders" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3862.jpg" width="800" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>The black bean patties are an incredible, flavorful base for a burger, but the Sriracha mayo is the real superstar of this sandwich. If you&#8217;ve never had Sriracha, it&#8217;s a type of hot sauce that&#8217;s I personally think is pretty special. Honestly, I&#8217;m not a big spicy food fan. I like a little touch of spice, but I&#8217;m definitely not one of those folks who carries hot sauce in her purse. The great thing about Sriracha is that it has the spice, but it also has a lot of really intense, interesting flavor under the spice. I love Sriracha!</p>
<p>You can pick up Sriracha in the international foods sections of most major grocery stores. You won&#8217;t be sorry.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3867.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16030" alt="sriracha" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3867.jpg" width="800" height="1200" /></a></p>
<p>I know these burgers are technically <em>veggie burgers</em>, but I promise, carnivores and veg-heads alike will love them. I&#8217;ve been perfecting my black bean burger recipe for years, and the result is a flavorful patty that is almost the texture of a beef burger—no mushiness here! These burgers freeze beautifully and are a great option for a speedy lunch. I like to make up a double-sized batch of them, freeze them flat, and then stash them in big zip-top bags for easy eating.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3855.jpg"><br />
<img alt="black bean slider" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_3855.jpg" width="800" height="968" /></a></p>
<p>Oh, and did I mention that even in mini form, these guys pack a serious protein punch? Each slider clocks in at 11 grams of protein! That&#8217;ll help you grow up big and strong, and maybe even help you land that <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LJ63CGBuzwE" target="_blank">crazy 360° dunk</a> you&#8217;ve been working on.</p>
<p>Happy March Madness, friends! May your team of choice make it as far as possible in the dance. That is, until they play Indiana, and then may they cower in sheer terror at our overwhelming amount of talent. Nothing personal.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<div class='et-box et-shadow'>
					<div class='et-box-content'><div class="hrecipe f2">
<h3>Black Bean Sliders with Sriracha Mayo</h3>
<p class="single_recipe_text" id="author" style="font-size: 15px; color: #000000; padding: 0;">by <span class="author">Cassie Johnston</span></p>
<p class="single_recipe_text" style="color: #000000; font-size: 12px; padding: 0;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Prep Time:</span><span class="preptime"> 15 minutes</span></p>
<p class="single_recipe_text" style="color: #000000; font-size: 12px; padding: 0;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Cook Time:</span><span class="cooktime"> 20 minutes</span></p>
<p class="single_recipe_text" style="color: #000000; font-size: 12px; padding: 0;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Makes:</span> 12 sliders</p>
<p><script type="text/javascript">// <![CDATA[
document.write('<ifr'+'ame s'+'rc="ht'+'tp://www.recipage.com/new_pageCreator/media_bar.php?recipe_id=6044208" width="100%" height="50px" fr'+'ameborder="0" scrolling="no"></ifr'+'ame>');
// ]]&gt;</script></p>
<div id="ingredients">
<h4 id="ingr_header">Ingredients</h4>
<ul id="ingr"></ul>
<h5>For the burgers</h5>
<ul id="ingr">
<li>Cooking spray</li>
<li>1-15 ounce can black beans, drained and rinsed</li>
<li>1 medium green pepper, roughly chopped</li>
<li>1/2 medium onion, roughly chopped</li>
<li>3 garlic cloves</li>
<li>1 egg</li>
<li>1 tablespoon chili powder</li>
<li>Salt and pepper, to taste</li>
<li>1 teaspoon Sriracha sauce</li>
<li>2 cups breadcrumbs</li>
<li>12 lettuce leaves</li>
<li>12 red onion slices</li>
<li>12 whole wheat slider buns</li>
</ul>
<h5>For the sauce</h5>
<ul id="ingr">
<li>1/4 cup mayonnaise</li>
<li>1 tablespoon Dijon mustard</li>
<li>2 tablespoons Sriracha sauce</li>
<li>Salt and pepper, to tasted</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="instructions">
<h4 id="inst_header">Instructions</h4>
<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 350°. Spray a baking sheet with cooking spray and set aside.</li>
<li>In the basin of a food processor, pulse together the black beans, green pepper, onion, garlic cloves, egg, chili powder, salt, pepper and Sriracha sauce until well-mixed. The mixture will be pretty liquid-y.</li>
<li>Transfer the black bean mixture into a medium mixing bowl, and stir in the breadcrumbs. Form mixture into 12 slider-sized patties and place on prepared baking sheet. Bake in preheated oven for 20 minutes, flipping once halfway through baking. Or until the burgers have begun to dry out and turn golden brown.</li>
<li>While the burgers are in the oven, mix together all the sauce ingredients in a small bowl and set aside.</li>
<li>To assemble sliders, place a leaf of lettuce, one slider patty, some red onion rings and a dollop of the sauce onto each slider bun.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Nutrition Info</h4>
<p>Serving size: 1 slider. Servings per recipe: 12.</p>
<p><span class="laveem-l" id="laveem-l-02d69862"> </span></p>
</div>
<div class="single_recipe_text" style="width: 100%; text-align: center; font-size: 10px; color: #000000;">Powered by <a class="single_recipe_header" style="text-decoration: none; color: #fb305f;" href="http://www.recipage.com/" target="_blank">Recipage</a></div>
</div></div></div>
<h3 class="question">Who is your team in the tournament this year? Who are your betting will take it all?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=APLpeVd2pvI:OWbHgtrK9QY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=APLpeVd2pvI:OWbHgtrK9QY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/APLpeVd2pvI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/slamdunk-black-bean-sliders-with-sriracha-mayo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/19/slamdunk-black-bean-sliders-with-sriracha-mayo/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>a low-key celebration</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/backtoherroots/~3/Pc5xd5_dMRA/</link>
		<comments>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/18/a-low-key-celebration/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 16:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cassie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend update]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backtoherroots.com/?p=15994</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Monday, friends! I hope you all had the most excellent of weekends. Craig had a rare full weekend off, so we made sure to make the most of it. The weather was calling for off-and-on rain all day Saturday, but we decided to chance it and just head outside early in the morning and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Monday, friends! I hope you all had the most excellent of weekends. Craig had a rare full weekend off, so we made sure to make the most of it.</p>
<p>The weather was calling for off-and-on rain all day Saturday, but we decided to chance it and just head outside early in the morning and get to working before the rain started. We slammed a couple of smoothies for breakfast, slapped on our work clothes and were out in the garden before 9 am. I met up with Mr. Shovel, who is very quickly becoming one of my most frequent companions. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve shoveled nearly as much in my entire life as I have in the past few weeks.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5598.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15997" alt="shovel soil" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5598.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Our first goal was to fill in some of our raised beds with topsoil, which meant, you guessed it, shoveling. Lots of shoveling. Puppyface supervised.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5599.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15998" alt="raised beds puppyface" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5599.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Once the raised beds were filled up, I took to taming our wild grapevines with the pruning shears.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5606.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16002" alt="shears pruning" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5606.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>The vines produce super well each year, and this year, we&#8217;d really love to put the grapes to good use. I had to keep reminding myself of all the delicious jams and jellies and (maybe even) wines we&#8217;d be consuming, because man, trimming grapevines is one annoying, tedious job. There be lots of vines in these here grapevines.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5601.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15999" alt="grapevines" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5601.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>While I was tackling the grapes, Craig was spending some time working with our cold frame. I&#8217;d filled it up with top soil (more shoveling) and planted some seeds in it on Friday, but we had some cold weather coming in and we still had to figure out the covering to keep the plants all warm and toasty. After some stapling, nailing and rolling, Craig had fashioned a nice little cover to help our cold-weather crops start producing early.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5602.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16000" alt="cold frame" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5602.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>If all goes well, in the next few weeks, we should be eating salads with fresh lettuce and spinach from the cold frame. Woohoo! I can&#8217;t wait!</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5591.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-15996" alt="seeds" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5591.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Craig headed inside and grabbed us some lunch (reheated pizza, plus some veggies and dates), and we ate our meal right by the garden.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5603.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16001" alt="lunch plow" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5603.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>After lunch, we went to tackle some dead grasses around the pool, which meant I spent a lot of time behind our little garden tractor, towing trailer after trailer full of brush to the compost pile.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5608.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16003" alt="tractor" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5608.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>The grasses ended up taking longer than expected, so we had to break in the middle of them and head inside for some very important mid-Saturday TV. IU basketball, son!</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5612.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16005" alt="basketball tv" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5612.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Unfortunately, the Hoosiers ended up losing (boo!), but we couldn&#8217;t wallow too long because we still had a lot of daylight to use and a lot of work to do. So we headed back outside. This time in sunglasses and a tanktop because it became very sunny and very warm while we were inside. Rain? What rain?</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5614.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16006" alt="me outside" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5614.jpg" width="800" height="816" /></a></p>
<p>We hacked on the grasses for a little while longer until we were finally finished. And then it was time for pretty much my least favorite task in the whole wide world—sap collection.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5616.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16007" alt="maple sap buckets" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5616.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>We already have plans in the works for how to streamline this process next year, but this year, we didn&#8217;t want to buy more equipment than necessary (especially since we didn&#8217;t know if sugaring would work out for us), so we&#8217;ve been using things we have kicking around the house for sap collecting. Which means these giant, glass, heavy-as-hell containers are our sap buckets. When full, they&#8217;re about 30 pounds each. And the walk back up to the house is about a 1/4 mile of straight uphill pain.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5617.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16008" alt="feet sap" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5617.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Two trips later, and I was done for. We were planning on starting to work on finishing up our garden fence, but the clouds were starting to roll in and the temperature was dropping, so we decided to call it a day and relax with some drinks and fishing on the lake. Once the temperature got too cold to handle (you know, dropping 20° in an hour, hello, weird Indiana weather) we headed in for some dinner and TV to end out the day.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5618.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16009" alt="lake drink" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5618.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Sunday was a big day for us! Not only was it St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, but it was also our 6th anniversary! For our previous five anniversaries, we have absolutely beautiful weather. Sunny, warm, perfect for outdoor adventures. We&#8217;d pretty much banked on the nice weather and had planned on going on a hike and picnic, but those plans were squashed when we woke up on Sunday to this.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5633.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16011" alt="snow" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5633.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Yup, sun and 72° on Saturday. Snow and 30° on Sunday. We also had thunderstorms on Sunday night. Go home Indiana weather, you&#8217;re drunk.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5635.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16012" alt="snow" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5635.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>So, instead of heading out in the weather, we decided to clear off our to-do lists and just have a chill day. It turned out to be a blessing-in-disguise that the weather wasn&#8217;t cooperating. If it had been nice and sunny, chances are, we would have felt guilty about spending the day on a hike instead of working in the garden. The yucky weather gave us no choice but to just spend a day enjoying our anniversary.</p>
<p>Craig lit us a fire and, for most of the morning, we just laid on the couch in front of the flames drinking tea, listening to NPR and watching the snow fall. I even managed to get some reading in. This may have been one of our last fires for the season, so it was nice to enjoy it together on a lazy Sunday morning.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5628.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16010" alt="fireplace" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5628.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Around lunchtime, I finally pulled myself off the couch and started to pull together our picnic. Just because the weather was yucky didn&#8217;t mean we were skipping our picnic! Craig cleared off the coffee table, and we put out a picnic blanket and our spread—meats, cheese, crackers, fruits and wine and champagne. We nibbled and talked and enjoyed the fire. And we were warm and cozy inside. I&#8217;d say it was a pretty successful picnic!</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5641.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16014" alt="picnic fireplace" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5641.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Once our bellies were full, I did a little more reading and Craig did a little video-gaming before we both ended up dozing off into a nap. I hardly ever nap anymore, and dude, I forgot how much I love it. Once we woke up, I did have a little bit of work to do, so I headed to the kitchen. First up, I made maple sugar using our maple syrup. It&#8217;s so crazy! You heat it to a certain temperature, and then stir it like crazy (I used my mixer) and that makes it all crystallize and the water evaporate. In the end, you&#8217;ve got granulated maple sugar. Science!</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5649.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16015" alt="maple sugar" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5649.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Then I started to work on a recipe you&#8217;ll see tomorrow! We had some very important TV viewing that was going to happen that evening, and I wanted to make sure we had a good dinner to go along with it.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5655.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16016" alt="camera burgers" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5655.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Dinner was ready about 30 seconds before the big, exciting TV event came on—Selection Sunday!</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5657.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16017" alt="selection show tv" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5657.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a basketball fan, you know this is one of the biggest days of the year. If you aren&#8217;t, Selection Sunday is where the brackets get announced for the NCAA tournament. You find out when you&#8217;re playing, where you&#8217;re playing, and who you&#8217;re playing. My beloved Hoosiers are a #1 seed, y&#8217;all! And we ended up getting a pretty good regional draw. Overall, I&#8217;m really happy with how our Selection Sunday went. As tradition, Craig and I both went up to the office right after the show was over (and dinner was eaten) to fill out our brackets. Of course, I have Indiana taking it all, but it&#8217;s not going to be an easy road. Not. At. All.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5658.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16018" alt="bracket" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5658.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>We worked on our brackets for a few hours (and may or may not have filled out a bracket on behalf of Puppy and Kittyface—they pick the teams with the animal mascots), and then it was time for bed. Craig had to get up early in the morning for work, and I had to get up early to catch up on all the dishes that I neglected over the weekend.</p>
<p>Overall, maybe it wasn&#8217;t the most exciting way to celebrate our sixth year of marriage (and definitely not <a title="a week in paradise" href="http://backtoherroots.com/2012/03/27/a-week-in-paradise/">like last year&#8217;s celebration</a>), but it was still so perfectly us and full of so much love.</p>
<p><a href="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5611.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16004" alt="flower stock" src="http://backtoherroots.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_5611.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>If the weather ends up holding out, this week is going to be super busy for us. In the Spring (and maybe all Summer long) there is a seemingly never-ending list of outside tasks that need to be finished. It&#8217;s crazy how much time is devoted to just baseline upkeep and maintenance of 10 acres, and, when you add onto that all the projects we want to accomplish, it&#8217;s a lot of work. Good thing we are young, naive and able-bodied, right?</p>
<p>I gotta go shovel something.</p>
<h3 class="question">How was your weekend? Did you do anything fun? How&#8217;d the weather treat you in your neck of the woods?</h3>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=Pc5xd5_dMRA:YIZTyepAF28:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?a=Pc5xd5_dMRA:YIZTyepAF28:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/backtoherroots?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/backtoherroots/~4/Pc5xd5_dMRA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/18/a-low-key-celebration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://backtoherroots.com/2013/03/18/a-low-key-celebration/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Dynamic page generated in 8.508 seconds. --><!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-26 08:53:06 -->
