<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>W3C News</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.w3.org/News/atom.xml" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2008-09-29://4</id>
    <updated>2013-04-18T13:42:27Z</updated>
    
    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type 4.34-en</generator>

<entry>
    <title>XML Digital Signatures for Widgets is a W3C Recommendation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9795" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9795</id>

    <published>2013-04-18T13:33:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T13:33:02Z</updated>

    <summary>The Web Applications Working Group has published a W3C Recommendation of XML Digital Signatures for Widgets. This document defines a profile of the XML Signature Syntax and Processing specification to allow a widget package to be digitally signed. Authors and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Home Page Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Services" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="XML Core Technologies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/webapps/">Web Applications Working Group</a> has published a W3C Recommendation of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/REC-widgets-digsig-20130418/">XML Digital Signatures for Widgets</a>. This document defines a profile of the XML Signature Syntax and Processing specification to allow a widget package to be digitally signed. Authors and distributors can digitally sign a widget as a mechanism to ensure continuity of authorship and distributorship. A user agent, or other validation system, can use a digital signature to verify the data integrity of the files within a widget package and to confirm the signing key(s). Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2006/rwc/">Rich Web Client Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>CSS Overflow Module Level 3 Draft Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9794" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9794</id>

    <published>2013-04-18T13:31:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T13:31:55Z</updated>

    <summary>The Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) Working Group has published a Working Draft of CSS Overflow Module Level 3. This module contains the features of CSS relating to new mechanisms of overflow handling in visual media (e.g., screen or paper). In...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Home Page Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/Style/CSS/members">Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) Working Group</a> has published a Working Draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-css-overflow-3-20130418/">CSS Overflow Module Level 3</a>. This module contains the features of CSS relating to new mechanisms of overflow handling in visual media (e.g., screen or paper). In interactive media, it describes features that allow the overflow from a fixed size container to be handled by pagination (displaying one page at a time). It also describes features, applying to all visual media, that allow the contents of an element to be spread across multiple fragments, allowing the contents to flow across multiple regions or to have different styles for different fragments. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/Style/">Style Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>W3C Invites Implementations of Efficient XML Interchange (EXI) Profile</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9791" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9791</id>

    <published>2013-04-16T17:56:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T17:56:10Z</updated>

    <summary>The Efficient XML Interchange Working Group invites implementation of the Candidate Recommendation of Efficient XML Interchange (EXI) Profile. This document describes a profile of the EXI 1.0 specification for devices with limited memory capacities. Learn more about the Extensible Markup...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Home Page Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="XML Core Technologies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/XML/EXI/">Efficient XML Interchange Working Group</a> invites implementation of the Candidate Recommendation of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/CR-exi-profile-20130416/">Efficient XML Interchange (EXI) Profile</a>. This document describes a profile of the EXI 1.0 specification for devices with limited memory capacities. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/XML/">Extensible Markup Language (XML) Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Call for Review: Emotion Markup Language (EmotionML) 1.0 Proposed Recommendation Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9790" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9790</id>

    <published>2013-04-16T17:50:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T17:50:58Z</updated>

    <summary>The W3C Multimodal Working Group has published a Proposed Recommendation of Emotion Markup Language (EmotionML) 1.0. As the web is becoming ubiquitous, interactive, and multimodal, technology needs to deal increasingly with human factors, including emotions. The specification of Emotion Markup...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Home Page Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Devices" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Services" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2002/mmi/">W3C Multimodal Working Group</a> has published a Proposed Recommendation of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/PR-emotionml-20130416/">Emotion Markup Language (EmotionML) 1.0</a>. As the web is becoming ubiquitous, interactive, and multimodal, technology needs to deal increasingly with human factors, including emotions. The specification of Emotion Markup Language 1.0 aims to strike a balance between practical applicability and scientific well-foundedness. The language is conceived as a "plug-in" language suitable for use in three different areas: (1) manual annotation of data; (2) automatic recognition of emotion-related states from user behavior; and (3) generation of emotion-related system behavior. Comments are welcome through 14 May. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2002/mmi/Activity.html">Multimodal Interaction Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>XML Signature and XML Encryption are W3C Recommendations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9789" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9789</id>

    <published>2013-04-16T17:22:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T17:22:00Z</updated>

    <summary>The XML Security Working Group has published three W3C Recommendations today: XML Signature Syntax and Processing Version 1.1. This document specifies XML digital signature processing rules and syntax. XML Signatures provide integrity, message authentication, and/or signer authentication services for data...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Home Page Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Top Story" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="XML Core Technologies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/xmlsec/">XML Security Working Group</a> has published three W3C Recommendations today:</p>
<ul class="show_items"><li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/REC-xmldsig-core1-20130411/">XML Signature Syntax and Processing Version 1.1</a>. This document specifies XML digital signature processing rules and syntax. XML Signatures provide integrity, message authentication, and/or signer authentication services for data of any type, whether located within the XML that includes the signature or elsewhere.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/REC-xmlenc-core1-20130411/">XML Encryption Syntax and Processing Version 1.1</a>. This document specifies a process for encrypting data and representing the result in XML. The data may be in a variety of formats, including octet streams and other unstructured data, or structured data formats such as XML documents, an XML element, or XML element content. The result of encrypting data is an XML Encryption element that contains or references the cipher data.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/REC-xmldsig-properties-20130411/">XML Signature Properties</a>. This document outlines the syntax, processing rules and an associated namespace for properties to be used in XML Signatures. These can be composed with any version of XML Signature using the XML SignatureProperties element. These properties are intended to meet code signing requirements.</li></ul>
<p>The group also published thirteen <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/tr-groups-all#tr_XML_Security_Working_Group">Working Group Notes</a> today. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/Security/">Security Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Media Source Extensions Draft Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9788" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9788</id>

    <published>2013-04-16T17:07:56Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T17:07:56Z</updated>

    <summary>The HTML Working Group has published a Working Draft of Media Source Extensions. This specification extends HTMLMediaElement to allow JavaScript to generate media streams for playback. Allowing JavaScript to generate streams facilitates a variety of use cases like adaptive streaming...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Home Page Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/html/wg/">HTML Working Group</a> has published a Working Draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-media-source-20130415/">Media Source Extensions</a>. This specification extends HTMLMediaElement to allow JavaScript to generate media streams for playback. Allowing JavaScript to generate streams facilitates a variety of use cases like adaptive streaming and time shifting live streams. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/MarkUp/Activity">HTML Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Last Call: API for Media Resources 1.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9786" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9786</id>

    <published>2013-04-11T14:09:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T14:09:39Z</updated>

    <summary>The Media Annotations Working Group has published a 3rd Last Call Working Draft of API for Media Resources 1.0. This specification defines an API to access metadata information related to media resources on the Web. The overall purpose is to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Devices" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Services" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/WebVideo/Annotations/">Media Annotations Working Group</a> has published a 3rd Last Call Working Draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-mediaont-api-1.0-20130411/">API for Media Resources 1.0</a>. This specification defines an API to access metadata information related to media resources on the Web. The overall purpose is to provide developers with a convenient access to metadata information stored in different metadata formats. The API provides means to access the set of metadata properties defined in the Ontology for Media Resources 1.0 specification. These properties are used as a pivot vocabulary in this API. The core of this specification is the definition of API interfaces for retrieving metadata information in synchronous and asynchronous. It also defines interfaces for structured return types along with the specification of the behavior of an API implementation. Comments are welcome through 03 June. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/WebVideo/">Video in the Web Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Last Call: JSON-LD 1.0, JSON-LD 1.0 Processing Algorithms and API</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9785" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9785</id>

    <published>2013-04-11T13:56:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T13:56:38Z</updated>

    <summary>The RDF Working Group and the JSON-LD Community Group have published two Last Call Working Drafts today: JSON-LD 1.0. JSON-LD harmonizes the representation of Linked Data in JSON by describing a common JSON representation format for expressing directed graphs; mixing...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Semantic Web" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2011/rdf-wg/wiki/Main_Page">RDF Working
Group</a> and the <a href="http://json-ld.org/">JSON-LD Community Group</a> have published two Last Call Working Drafts today:</p>
<ul class="show_items">
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-json-ld-20130411/">JSON-LD 1.0</a>.  JSON-LD harmonizes the representation of Linked Data in JSON by describing a common JSON representation format for expressing directed graphs; mixing both Linked Data and non-Linked Data in a single document. The syntax is designed to not disturb already deployed systems running on JSON, but provide a smooth upgrade path from JSON to JSON-LD. It is primarily intended to be a way to use Linked Data in Web-based programming environments, to build interoperable Linked Data Web services, and to store Linked Data in JSON-based storage engines. JSON-LD is capable of serializing any RDF graph or dataset and most, but not all, JSON-LD documents can be directly transformed to RDF.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-json-ld-api-20130411/">JSON-LD
1.0: Algorithms and API</a>. The JSON-LD 1.0 Algorithms and API specification describes useful Algorithms for working with JSON-LD data. It also specifies an Application Programming Interface that can be used to transform JSON-LD documents in order to make them easier to work with in programming environments like JavaScript, Python, and Ruby.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is a Last Call publication for both specifications. All substantive technical work on the specification is complete. Feedback on both specifications is encouraged and should be sent to <a href="mailto:public-rdf-comments@w3.org">public-rdf-comments@w3.org</a>. The Last Call period will end in 4 weeks, on May 10th 2013</p>
<p>Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2001/sw/">Semantic Web Activity</a> and <a href="http://www.w3.org/community/">W3C Community Groups</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Internationalization Tag Set (ITS) Version 2.0 Draft Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9784" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9784</id>

    <published>2013-04-11T13:51:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T13:51:16Z</updated>

    <summary>The MultilingualWeb-LT Working Group has published an updated working draft of Internationalization Tag Set (ITS) Version 2.0. The Internationalization Tag Set (ITS) 2.0 enhances the foundation to integrate automated processing of human language into core Web technologies. ITS 2.0 provides...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Services" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/International/multilingualweb/lt/">MultilingualWeb-LT Working Group</a> has published an updated working draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-its20-20130411/">Internationalization Tag Set (ITS) Version 2.0</a>. The Internationalization Tag Set (ITS) 2.0 enhances the foundation to integrate automated processing of human language into core Web technologies. ITS 2.0 provides metadata to foster the adoption of the multilingual Web. The draft reflects <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-its20-20130411/#changelog-since-20121023">changes</a> since the <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2012/WD-its20-20121206/">last call publication 6 December 2012</a> and asks for feedback on the <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-its20-20130411/#unresolved-issues">remaining 
open issues</a>. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/International/">Internationalization Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Clipboard API and events Draft Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9783" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9783</id>

    <published>2013-04-11T13:48:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-11T13:48:44Z</updated>

    <summary>The Web Applications Working Group has published a Working Draft of Clipboard API and events. This document describes APIs for clipboard operations such as copy, cut and paste in web applications. Learn more about the Rich Web Client Activity....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/webapps/">Web Applications Working Group</a> has published a Working Draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-clipboard-apis-20130411/">Clipboard API and events</a>. This document describes APIs for clipboard operations such as copy, cut and paste in web applications. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2006/rwc/">Rich Web Client Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Call for Review: Web Storage Proposed Recommendation Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9781" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9781</id>

    <published>2013-04-09T14:34:03Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T14:34:03Z</updated>

    <summary>The Web Applications Working Group has published a Proposed Recommendation of Web Storage. This specification defines an API for persistent data storage of key-value pair data in Web clients. Comments are welcome through 07 May. Learn more about the Rich...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/webapps/">Web Applications Working Group</a> has published a Proposed Recommendation of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/PR-webstorage-20130409/">Web Storage</a>. This specification defines an API for persistent data storage of key-value pair data in Web clients. Comments are welcome through 07 May. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2006/rwc/">Rich Web Client Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Working Drafts of RDF 1.1 Semantics and TriG, N-Triples and N-Quads published as Notes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9780" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9780</id>

    <published>2013-04-09T14:20:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T14:20:55Z</updated>

    <summary>The RDF Working Group has published two Working Drafts today: RDF 1.1 Semantics. This document describes a precise semantics for the Resource Description Framework 1.1 and RDF Schema. It defines a number of distinct entailment regimes and corresponding systems of...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Semantic Web" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2011/rdf-wg/">RDF Working Group</a> has published two Working Drafts today:</p>
<ul class="show_items">
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-rdf11-mt-20130409/">RDF 1.1 Semantics</a>. This document describes a precise semantics for the Resource Description Framework 1.1 and RDF Schema. It defines a number of distinct entailment regimes and corresponding systems of inference rules. It is part of a suite of documents which comprise the full specification of RDF 1.1.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-trig-20130409/">TriG</a>. This document defines a textual syntax for RDF called TriG that allows an RDF dataset to be completely written in a compact and natural text form, with abbreviations for common usage patterns and datatypes. TriG is an extension of the Turtle format.</li></ul>
<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2011/rdf-wg/">RDF Working Group</a> also published two Group Notes today:</p>
<ul class="show_items">
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/NOTE-n-triples-20130409/">N-Triples</a>. N-Triples is a line-based, plain text format for encoding an RDF graph.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/NOTE-n-quads-20130409/">N-Quads</a>. N-Quads is a line-based, plain text format for encoding an RDF dataset.</li></ul>
<p>Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2001/sw/">Semantic Web Activity</a>.</p>
]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) 2 Draft Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9779" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9779</id>

    <published>2013-04-09T14:17:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T14:17:45Z</updated>

    <summary>The SVG Working Group has published a Working Draft of Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) 2. This specification defines the features and syntax for Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) Version 2, a language for describing two-dimensional vector and mixed vector/raster graphics. Although...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/Graphics/SVG/WG/">SVG Working Group</a> has published a Working Draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-SVG2-20130409/">Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) 2</a>. This specification defines the features and syntax for Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) Version 2, a language for describing two-dimensional vector and mixed vector/raster graphics. Although an XML serialization is given, processing is defined in terms of a DOM. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/Graphics/">Graphics Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Two upcoming W3C Workshops on Digital Publishing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9778" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9778</id>

    <published>2013-04-09T07:53:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T07:53:12Z</updated>

    <summary><![CDATA[W3C announced today two closely related workshops, part of the W3C headlights 2013 exercise on Digital Publishing: eBooks &amp; i18n: Richer Internationalization for eBooks on 4 June 2013 in Tokyo, Japan. This workshop will investigate international functionality that needs to...]]></summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Browsers and Authoring Tools" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Devices" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Services" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>W3C announced today two closely related workshops, part of the W3C headlights 2013 exercise on Digital Publishing:</p>
<ul class="show_items">
<li><a href="https://www.w3.org/2013/06/ebooks/">eBooks &amp; i18n: Richer Internationalization for eBooks</a> on 4 June 2013 in Tokyo, Japan. This workshop will investigate international functionality that needs to be added to the Open Web Platform; the goal is to make the various eBook reading platforms suitable for electronic books that use the printing and typesetting traditions of different cultures. If you are interested in participating, please submit a position paper by 30 April 2013.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/2012/12/global-publisher/">Publishing and the Open Web Platform</a> on 16-17 September 2013 in Paris, France. This workshop will look at the "back-end" processing to make the Open Web Platform suitable for commercial publishing, especially in print, all the way from authoring through to delivering the printed product and beyond. If you are interested in participating, please submit a position paper by 1 July 2013.</li>
</ul>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Input Method Editor API Draft Published</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.w3.org/News/2013.html#entry-9776" />
    <id>tag:www.w3.org,2013://4.9776</id>

    <published>2013-04-04T15:30:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-04T15:30:23Z</updated>

    <summary>The Web Applications Working Group has published a Working Draft of Input Method Editor API. This specification defines an “IME API” that provides Web applications with scripted access to an IME (input-method editor) associated with a hosting user agent. This...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>W3C Staff</name>
    </author>
    
        <category term="Publication" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web Design and Applications" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Web of Devices" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.w3.org/">
        
        <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.w3.org/2008/webapps/">Web Applications Working Group</a> has published a Working Draft of <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2013/WD-ime-api-20130404/">Input Method Editor API</a>. This specification defines an “IME API” that provides Web applications with scripted access to an IME (input-method editor) associated with a hosting user agent. This IME API includes: an InputMethodContext interface, which provides methods to retrieve detailed data from an in-progress IME composition, a Composition dictionary, which represents read-only attributes about the current composition, such as the actual text and its style. This API is designed to be used in conjunction with DOM events. Learn more about the <a href="http://www.w3.org/2006/rwc/">Rich Web Client Activity</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

</feed>
