<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Australian Climate Madness</title>
	<atom:link href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com</link>
	<description>Just don&#039;t tell me the debate is over...</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 22:38:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='australianclimatemadness.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://1.gravatar.com/blavatar/34b87e5392f32a54d30037d614455599?s=96&#038;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs2.wp.com%2Fi%2Fbuttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Australian Climate Madness</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/osd.xml" title="Australian Climate Madness" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://australianclimatemadness.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Summer not so angry after all</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/summer-not-so-angry-after-all/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/summer-not-so-angry-after-all/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 09:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murry Salby]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The emotive language and graphics of the Climate Commission are there to scare the population into thinking the worst. It&#8217;s pure alarmism. As mentioned in the last post, the Climate Commission, Flannery, Steffen and the rest will all be gone... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/summer-not-so-angry-after-all/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13351&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13352" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/angry_summer_not.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13352" alt="Who can spot the angry summer?" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/angry_summer_not.jpg?w=300&#038;h=168" width="300" height="168" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Who can spot the angry summer?</p></div>
<p>The emotive language and graphics of the <a href="http://climatecommission.gov.au/" target="_blank">Climate Commission</a> are there to scare the population into thinking the worst. It&#8217;s pure alarmism.</p>
<p>As mentioned in the last post, the Climate Commission, Flannery, Steffen and the rest will all be gone by the end of the year &#8211; good riddance.</p>
<p>Murry Salby, professor of climate at Macquarie University, dismantles their latest explosion of hysteria:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>CLAIMS from the latest report by the Climate Commission, titled The Angry Summer, have been widely circulated through international media. On the basis of a few sporadic episodes, which in any other era would have been regarded as marginal weather (infrequent but perennial), the Climate Commission has proclaimed that such events are now the norm &#8211; the signature of climate change come home to roost.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>This report is but the latest in a series of dire proclamations from this panel. It just happens to buttress the government&#8217;s controversial carbon tax, a maladroit policy that will be pivotal in the forthcoming federal election.</em></strong></p>
<p><em>The commission&#8217;s position, as proclaimed by its chief commissioner, is that &#8220;the baseline has shifted&#8221; like &#8220;an athlete (who) takes steroids&#8221;. &#8220;The same thing is happening to our climate system . . . We&#8217;re getting fewer cold days and cold events and many more record hot events&#8221; (The New York Times, March 4).</em></p>
<p><strong><em>The evocative nature of these claims is matched only by the imagination behind them. On a continental scale (the scale relevant to climate), Australian temperature this summer was unremarkable &#8211; it was within the range of previous variability.</em></strong></p>
<p><em>The Climate Commission was enshrined as an &#8220;independent panel of experts&#8221;.<strong> It was installed and paid for by the government.</strong> The panel is comprised of biologists and ecologists, a materials engineer and members of the business community. <strong>It has no demonstrated expertise in the physics or chemistry of climate, or even in meteorology, the scientific underpinnings of its conclusions.</strong></em></p>
<p>…</p>
<p><em>Figure 1 displays the record of Australia mean temperature during January (blue) in its anomalous value (the departure from the long-term average January temperature). Last January was warmer than recent Januaries, but hardly unprecedented. It lies about a standard deviation above the average January temperature. And even during the relatively short satellite era, two Januaries were warmer. Superimposed is anomalous summertime temperature (red). It is even less remarkable. Near the three-decade average, it is no more significant than in preceding years. Neither record evidences a sustained shift in the continental baseline.</em></p>
<p><em>Figure 2 displays the record of anomalous temperature for all months. It places the summer of 2012-13 into perspective. Anomalous temperature (red solid circles) lies well within the envelope of other warm anomalies during the preceding three decades. Cold anomalies are just as numerous. If anything, they are even stronger.</em></p>
<p><em>For many on Australia&#8217;s eastern seaboard, this summer was not anomalously hot but, rather, anomalously cool and wet. This is confirmed by the temperature record at Sydney. The central station reported only two marginal days. And during the entire summer maximum temperature reached 32C on only three days.</em></p>
<p><em>In the light of the satellite record, as well as the absence of any systematic change in global temperature for almost two decades, the proclaimed interpretation of this summer should be recognised for what it is: a simplistic explanation of a complex physical system. </em>(<a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/opinion/last-summer-was-not-actually-angrier-than-other-summers/story-e6frgd0x-1226611988057" target="_blank">source</a>)</p></blockquote>
<p>No-one&#8217;s listening any more chaps.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13351&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/summer-not-so-angry-after-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/angry_summer_not.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Who can spot the angry summer?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flannery, your days are numbered</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/flannery-your-days-are-numbered/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/flannery-your-days-are-numbered/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 22:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate Commission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Flannery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Steffen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ah, the sweet satisfaction of seeing that government propaganda mouthpiece the Climate Commission shut down, and all its staff sent packing into the night. Tim Flannery will, with luck, disappear and never be heard of again, except in reference to... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/flannery-your-days-are-numbered/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13347&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13348" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/climate_commission.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13348" alt="The Climate Commission, 15 September 2013" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/climate_commission.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Climate Commission, 15 September 2013</p></div>
<p>Ah, the sweet satisfaction of seeing that government propaganda mouthpiece the Climate Commission shut down, and all its staff sent packing into the night.</p>
<p>Tim Flannery will, with luck, disappear and never be heard of again, except in reference to his laughably hopeless &#8220;predictions&#8221;. Will Steffen can go back to being an obscure academic, and we won&#8217;t have to suffer his endless alarmism on an almost daily basis.</p>
<p>And most importantly, the taxpayer will breathe a sigh of relief.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s hoping:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>A COALITION government would <strong>dismantle the climate change bureaucracy and put commissioners including Tim Flannery out of a job,</strong> Tony Abbott predicted yesterday as a report painted a gloomy picture of the future.</em></p>
<p><em>The Opposition Leader, who vows to remove the carbon tax if elected in September, said <strong>there would be no further need for the bureaucracy that supports it.</strong></em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;<strong>When the carbon tax goes all of those bureaucracies will go and I think you&#8217;ll find that particular position you&#8217;re referring to will go with them</strong>,&#8221; Mr Abbott said.</em></p>
<p><em>Mr Abbott will consider dumping the Howard government&#8217;s renewable energy target, which he says is &#8220;significantly increasing the cost of power&#8221;. [yes, finally - Ed]</em></p>
<p><em>Speaking to Sky News last night, he equivocated on his previous support for the scheme, which aims to ensure 20 per cent of electricity comes from renewable sources by 2020. <strong>&#8220;There is going to be a serious review of this, should there be a change of government,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We&#8217;ll wait for the review before deciding what we do, but I take your point that renewable energy is increasing the price of power.&#8221;</strong></em></p>
<p><em>The report, The Critical Decade: Extreme Weather, suggests worsening weather exacerbated by global warming is inevitable in coming decades, even if action is taken immediately to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</em></p>
<p><em>Report lead author, climate commissioner Will Steffen, and Climate Change Minister Greg Combet warned against complacency. &#8220;<strong>The action we take now in terms of getting emissions down . . . will have a big effect on what these extreme events will look like in the future,&#8221;</strong> Professor Steffen said in Sydney. (<a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/climate/climate-chiefs-face-abbott-axe/story-e6frg6xf-1226612076744" target="_blank">source</a>)</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Yes, that&#8217;s right Will, Australia&#8217;s 20% reduction of our 1.5% of global emissions (total, at absolute most, 0.3%) will really have a &#8220;big effect&#8221;&#8230; case closed.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13347&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/04/04/flannery-your-days-are-numbered/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/climate_commission.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Climate Commission, 15 September 2013</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twenty year hiatus in warming</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/30/13339/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/30/13339/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 02:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pause in warming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Throw another heretic on the fire. Graham Lloyd explores the view, becoming more accepted by the day, that global warming has slowed or plateaued over the past 15 or so years. It follows on from the Economist article which has caused quite... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/30/13339/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13339&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3152" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/burning_heretics1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3152 " alt="Burn the heretics" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/burning_heretics1.jpg?w=200&#038;h=222" width="200" height="222" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Burn the heretics</p></div>
<p>Throw another heretic on the fire. Graham Lloyd explores the view, becoming more accepted by the day, that global warming has slowed or plateaued over the past 15 or so years.</p>
<p>It follows on from the <em>Economist </em>article which has caused quite a stir (see ACM <a title="Apocalypse delayed?" href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/28/the-economist-apocalypse-delayed/">here</a>). Cue headbangers whining that even considering hypotheses that contradict the incessant alarmism of the AGW religion is part of a &#8216;war on science&#8217;, or some other such BS.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>DEBATE about the reality of a two-decade pause in global warming and what it means has made its way from the sceptical fringe to the mainstream.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>In a lengthy article this week, The Economist magazine said if climate scientists were credit-rating agencies, then climate sensitivity &#8211; the way climate reacts to changes in carbon-dioxide levels &#8211; would be on negative watch but not yet downgraded.</em> <em>Another paper published by leading climate scientist James Hansen, the head of NASA&#8217;s Goddard Institute for S</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>pace Studies, says the lower than expected temperature rise between 2000 and the present could be explained by increased emissions from burning coal.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>For Hansen the pause is a fact, but it&#8217;s good news that probably won&#8217;t last.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>International Panel on Climate Change chairman Rajendra Pachauri recently told The Weekend Australian the hiatus would have to last 30 to 40 years &#8220;at least&#8221; to break the long-term warming trend.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>But the fact that global surface temperatures have not followed the expected global warming pattern is now widely accepted.</em> <em>Research by Ed Hawkins of University of Reading shows surface temperatures since 2005 are already at the low end of the range projections derived from 20 climate models and if they remain flat, they will fall outside the models&#8217; range within a few years.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;The global temperature standstill shows that climate models are diverging from observations,&#8221; says David Whitehouse of the Global Warming Policy Foundation.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;If we have not passed it already, we are on the threshold of global observations becoming incompatible with the consensus theory of climate change,&#8221; he says.</em> <em>Whitehouse argues that whatever has happened to make temperatures remain constant requires an explanation because the pause in temperature rise has occurred despite a sharp increase in global carbon emissions.</em></p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p><em>The Economist says the world has added roughly 100 billion tonnes of carbon to the atmosphere between 2000 and 2010, about one-quarter of all the carbon dioxide put there by humans since 1750. This mismatch between rising greenhouse gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now, The Economist article says.</em></p></blockquote>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13339&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/30/13339/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2010/02/burning_heretics1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Burn the heretics</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lew &amp; Cook: economical with the truth</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/29/lew-cook-economical-with-the-truth/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/29/lew-cook-economical-with-the-truth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 23:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Cook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewandowsky]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A retarded amoeba with a half-a-dozen neurons for a brain could see that the Lew &#38; Cook conspiracy papers are a transparent attack on heretics of their AGW religion, and that they give junk science a bad name. As a... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/29/lew-cook-economical-with-the-truth/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13332&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13333" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/climate_clowns.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13333" alt="Climate clowns." src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/climate_clowns.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" width="300" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Lew &amp; Cook: climate clowns.</p></div>
<p>A retarded amoeba with a half-a-dozen neurons for a brain could see that the <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/tag/lewandowsky/" target="_blank">Lew &amp; Cook conspiracy papers</a> are a transparent attack on heretics of their AGW religion, and that they give junk science a bad name.</p>
<p>As a result of information obtained from FOI requests that ACM put in last year, Steve McIntyre posts a <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2013/03/28/lewandowsky-doubles-down/" target="_blank">withering attack</a> on their integrity:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Last fall, Geoff Chambers and Barry Woods established beyond a shadow of a doubt that no blog post linking to the Lewandowsky survey had ever been published at the Skeptical Science (SKS) blog. Chambers reasonably suggested at the time that the authors correct the claim in the article to reflect the lack of any link at the SKS blog. I reviewed the then available information on this incident in September 2012 <a href="http://climateaudit.org/2012/09/14/the-sks-link-to-the-lewandowsky-survey/">here</a>.</em></p>
<p><em>Since then, <strong>information obtained through FOI has shown that responses by both Lewandowsky and Cook to questions from Chambers and Woods were untrue.</strong> Actually, “untrue” does not really do justice to the measure of untruthfulness, as the FOI correspondence shows that the untruthful answers were given deliberately and intentionally. Chambers, in a post entitled <a href="http://geoffchambers.wordpress.com/2013/02/07/lewandowsky-the-liar/">Lewandowsky the Liar</a>, minced no words in <strong>calling Lewandowsky “a liar, a fool, a charlatan and a fraud.”</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Even though the untruthfulness of Lewandowsky and Cook’s stories had been clearly demonstrated by Geoff Chambers in a series of blog articles (e.g. <a href="http://geoffchambers.wordpress.com/2013/02/09/lews-lies-2-trick-or-tweet/">here</a>), in the published version of the Hoax paper, instead of correcting prior untrue claims about SKS, <strong>Lewandowsky doubled down, repeating and substantially amplifying the untrue claim.</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;m getting a little weary of giving this pair of clowns any more air time, but McIntyre&#8217;s (and others&#8217;) work exposing them is worth repeating.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13332&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/29/lew-cook-economical-with-the-truth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/climate_clowns.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Climate clowns.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apocalypse delayed?</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/28/the-economist-apocalypse-delayed/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/28/the-economist-apocalypse-delayed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 20:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate sensitivity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13323</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Economist tackles the issue to which many are intentionally blind, including the usual headbangers, our own Climate Commission, the IPCC and the majority of Western governments, namely, why have global temperatures levelled off despite ever increasing CO2 in the atmosphere?... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/28/the-economist-apocalypse-delayed/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13323&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13324" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/economist_sensitivity.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13324 " alt="© The Economist" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/economist_sensitivity.jpg?w=300&#038;h=182" width="300" height="182" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Times are changing&#8230;</p></div>
<p><em>The Economist</em> tackles the issue to which many are intentionally blind, including the usual headbangers, our own Climate Commission, the IPCC and the majority of Western governments, namely, why have global temperatures levelled off despite ever increasing CO2 in the atmosphere?</p>
<p>In an <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/leaders/21574490-climate-change-may-be-happening-more-slowly-scientists-thought-world-still-needs" target="_blank">editorial</a>, it writes:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>IT MAY come as a surprise to a walrus wondering where all the Arctic’s summer sea ice has gone. It could be news to a Staten Islander still coming to terms with what he lost to Hurricane Sandy. But some scientists are arguing that man-made climate change is not quite so bad a threat as it appeared to be a few years ago. They point to various reasons for thinking that the planet’s “climate sensitivity”—the amount of warming that can be expected for a doubling in the carbon-dioxide level—may not be as high as was previously thought. The most obvious reason is that, despite a marked warming over the course of the 20th century, temperatures have not really risen over the past ten years.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>And it dares to question the drive for alternative energy without regard to consequences:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Bad climate policies, such as backing renewable energy with no thought for the cost, or insisting on biofuels despite the damage they do, are bad whatever the climate’s sensitivity to greenhouse gases.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>In an accompanying <a href="http://www.economist.com/news/science-and-technology/21574461-climate-may-be-heating-up-less-response-greenhouse-gas-emissions" target="_blank">article</a> it deals with the science in some detail:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>OVER the past 15 years air temperatures at the Earth’s surface have been flat while greenhouse-gas emissions have continued to soar. The world added roughly 100 billion tonnes of carbon to the atmosphere between 2000 and 2010. That is about a quarter of all the CO₂ put there by humanity since 1750. And yet, as James Hansen, the head of NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies, observes, “the five-year mean global temperature has been flat for a decade.”</em></p>
<p><em>Temperatures fluctuate over short periods, but this lack of new warming is a surprise. Ed Hawkins, of the University of Reading, in Britain, points out that surface temperatures since 2005 are already at the low end of the range of projections derived from 20 climate models (see chart 1). If they remain flat, they will fall outside the models’ range within a few years.</em></p>
<p><em>The mismatch between rising greenhouse-gas emissions and not-rising temperatures is among the biggest puzzles in climate science just now. It does not mean global warming is a delusion. Flat though they are, temperatures in the first decade of the 21st century remain almost 1°C above their level in the first decade of the 20th. But the puzzle does need explaining.</em></p>
<p><em>The mismatch might mean that—for some unexplained reason—there has been a temporary lag between more carbon dioxide and higher temperatures in 2000-10. Or it might be that the 1990s, when temperatures were rising fast, was the anomalous period. Or, as an increasing body of research is suggesting, it may be that the climate is responding to higher concentrations of carbon dioxide in ways that had not been properly understood before. This possibility, if true, could have profound significance both for climate science and for environmental and social policy.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>It is a very encouraging sign that finally some in the mainstream media are beginning to acknowledge the divergence between models and observations, and are starting to ask questions. I encourage you to read it all.</p>
<p>(And wait for the inevitable headbanger backlash at <em>Un-Skeptical Pseudo-Science</em>, amongst other places, where they are always desperate to defend their religion at any cost. <span style="color:#0000ff;"><em><strong>UPDATE: </strong>As predicted, <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/news.php?n=1942" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">here</span></a> it is.</em></span>)</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13323&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/28/the-economist-apocalypse-delayed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/economist_sensitivity.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">© The Economist</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazing slow motion video</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/27/amazing-slow-motion-video/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/27/amazing-slow-motion-video/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General Science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And some science as well! Something a little different today &#8211; an exploration of Prince Rupert&#8217;s Drop &#8211; formed when molten glass is dropped into cold water. This video uses ultra-high-speed cameras to investigate these strange objects. Amazing! Enjoy.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13316&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13319" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 190px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/prince_rupert.png"><img class=" wp-image-13319 " alt="100,000 fps!" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/prince_rupert.png?w=180&#038;h=109" width="180" height="109" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">100,000 fps!</p></div>
<p>And some science as well! Something a little different today &#8211; an exploration of Prince Rupert&#8217;s Drop &#8211; formed when molten glass is dropped into cold water. This video uses ultra-high-speed cameras to investigate these strange objects. Amazing! Enjoy.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='385' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/xe-f4gokRBs?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13316&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/27/amazing-slow-motion-video/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/prince_rupert.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">100,000 fps!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gillard, Labor, CO2 tax: all likely gone in six months</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/gillard-labor-co2-tax-all-likely-gone-in-six-months/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/gillard-labor-co2-tax-all-likely-gone-in-six-months/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 01:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aussie Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julia Gillard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Labor &#8216;government&#8217; of Julia Gillard (in quotes because it isn&#8217;t really a government any more, it&#8217;s just a rabble) is in terminal decline after last week&#8217;s chaotic leadership non-contest. Newspoll puts Labor at 42% and the Coalition on 58%... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/gillard-labor-co2-tax-all-likely-gone-in-six-months/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13309&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13314" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cabinet_20131.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13314" alt="Why are you all smiling, you bunch of utter incompetents? You should be hanging your heads in abject shame." src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cabinet_20131.jpg?w=300&#038;h=181" width="300" height="181" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Why are you all smiling, you bunch of utter incompetents? You should be hanging your heads in abject shame.</p></div>
<p>The Labor &#8216;government&#8217; of Julia Gillard (in quotes because it isn&#8217;t really a government any more, it&#8217;s just a rabble) is in terminal decline after last week&#8217;s <a title="Another farcical day in the Gillard government…" href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/21/another-farcical-day-in-the-gillard-government/" target="_blank">chaotic leadership non-contest</a>. Newspoll puts Labor at 42% and the Coalition on 58% in the two party preferred, meaning Labor would be annihilated.</p>
<p>Half of her most experienced ministers have either resigned or been sacked, leaving the PM scraping the bottom of the cockatoo cage to fill the Cabinet. Craig Emerson [shudder] has been appointed minister for just about everything, including the kitchen sink, and the other spaces have been filled by political nobodies.</p>
<p>So one thing we can be sure of is that the &#8216;government&#8217; of this country will be even worse than it was before (if that is physically possible).</p>
<p><em>The Australian</em> <a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/labor-staring-at-landslide-defeat-newspoll/story-fn59niix-1226605883209" target="_blank">reports</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>JULIA Gillard&#8217;s personal standing has crashed to a 19-month low and Tony Abbott is clearly back in front as the nation&#8217;s preferred prime minister after Labor&#8217;s &#8220;appalling&#8221; two weeks of political and policy failure.</em></p>
<p><em>Labor&#8217;s primary vote has slumped five points to a disastrous 30 per cent after a fortnight ending with an aborted leadership spill and mass cabinet resignations, with one in two voters now siding with the Coalition.</em></p>
<p><em>The collapse in the Labor vote has completely wiped out the party&#8217;s recovery in the second half of last year, which was built on the back of the carbon tax compensation, and has entrenched the prospect of a landslide vote against the ALP in the election scheduled for September 14. After taking into account preference flows, federal Labor&#8217;s support is eight percentage points below its level at the 2010 election, at 42 per cent &#8211; a swing that if replicated in September would remove about 30 Labor MPs and could even put Kevin Rudd&#8217;s Queensland seat of Griffith at risk.</em></p>
<p><em>The Prime Minister said yesterday she was appalled at Labor&#8217;s &#8220;self-indulgence&#8221; during last week&#8217;s leadership bid, which was brought on after the party&#8217;s proposed media laws collapsed. She declared she wanted to show &#8220;self-belief&#8221; and that Labor&#8217;s &#8220;eyes&#8221; would be on the &#8220;Australian people&#8221;. But the latest Newspoll survey, taken exclusively for The Australian on the weekend, shows voter satisfaction with Ms Gillard down six percentage points to 26 per cent in the past two weeks.</em></p>
<p><em>Dissatisfaction with the Prime Minister rose eight points to 65 per cent, her worst personal ratings since September 2011 when she hit a record low satisfaction level of 23 per cent. There is now more than twice the number of voters dissatisfied with the way Ms Gillard is doing her job as Prime Minister than satisfied after a steady 12-point fall in satisfaction since January and a sharper rise of 16 points in dissatisfaction during the same period.</em></p>
<p><em>On the question of who would make the better prime minister, Ms Gillard&#8217;s support dropped seven percentage points to 35 per cent, its lowest since October 2011, while Mr Abbott&#8217;s support jumped five points to 43 per cent, his highest since September 2011.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Which means, of course, that when the election comes, the disastrous policies of this bunch of losers can be reversed and Australia may, MAY I add, be able to climb out of this enormous hole it&#8217;s in.</p>
<p>And we will almost certainly wave goodbye to the mining tax and the carbon tax. All we need is for the independents to do what they should have done months ago and put this government down.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13309&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/gillard-labor-co2-tax-all-likely-gone-in-six-months/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cabinet_20131.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Why are you all smiling, you bunch of utter incompetents? You should be hanging your heads in abject shame.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK: Chief Scientist exits in a blaze of hysteria</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/uk-chief-scientist-exits-in-a-blaze-of-hysteria/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/uk-chief-scientist-exits-in-a-blaze-of-hysteria/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 20:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ian Chubb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13302</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sir John Beddington is the outgoing Chief Scientific Adviser to the UK government, and, like our own Sir Ian Chubb, appears to take leave of his senses when it comes to climate. In a final whirlwind of alarmism, Beddington exits... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/uk-chief-scientist-exits-in-a-blaze-of-hysteria/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13302&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13303" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beddington.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13303" alt="Head scratch moment?" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beddington.jpg?w=300&#038;h=180" width="300" height="180" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Head scratch moment?</p></div>
<p>Sir John Beddington is the outgoing Chief Scientific Adviser to the UK government, and, like our own Sir Ian Chubb, appears to take leave of his senses when it comes to climate.</p>
<p>In a final whirlwind of alarmism, Beddington exits stage left, hopefully never to be seen or heard of again. As the <em>Telegraph</em> breathlessly <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/earth/environment/9951872/World-faces-decades-of-climate-chaos-outgoing-chief-scientific-adviser-warns.html" target="_blank">reports</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>The world faces decades of turbulent weather even if it takes drastic action to tackle climate change, the Government&#8217;s chief scientific adviser said today in a final stark warning as he prepares to step down.</em></p>
<p><em>Professor Sir John Beddington said that time lags in the climate system meant that accumulations of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere now will determine the weather we experience for the next 25 years.</em></p>
<p><em>Climate change is already manifesting itself in huge variations in the weather, clearly illustrated by the way Britain experienced both drought and extreme rainfall last year, he said.</em></p>
<p><em>The scientist said that the international community’s failure to agree binding targets for cutting carbon emissions meant problems were being stored up for the future.</em></p>
<p><em>“They may reach agreement, and they may start to reduce greenhouse gases in the next five years, or it may be a little longer,” he told BBC Radio 4’s Today programme.</em></p>
<p><em>“But they are still climbing, and when that increase is reversed, we will be left with the weather and the climate for the next 25 years from whenever that happens.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>What&#8217;s missing from this picture? Any acknowledgement that there has been a pause in warming which was not expected or predicted by the climate models, despite the <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/new-research-confirms-global-warming-has-accelerated.html" target="_blank">headbangers</a> claiming that warming is accelerating.*</p>
<p>Sir Ian Chubb falls into the same trap as Beddington &#8211; toeing a politically-correct line rather than responding to the evidence in an impartial, free-thinking manner.</p>
<p>More reaction here:</p>
<ul>
<li>Delingpole: <em><strong><a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/jamesdelingpole/100208918/global-warming-if-only-wed-listened-to-the-experts-eh/" target="_blank">Global warming: if only we&#8217;d listened to the experts, eh?</a></strong></em></li>
<li>Bishop Hill: <em><strong><a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/25/sjbs-last-hurrah.html" target="_blank">SJB&#8217;s last hurrah</a></strong></em></li>
<li>The Bishop again: <em><strong><a href="http://www.bishop-hill.net/blog/2013/3/19/avoid-like-the-plague.html" target="_blank">Avoid like the plague</a></strong></em></li>
</ul>
<p><em>*They do this by suddenly ignoring global temperatures and, like street magicians, using diversionary techniques to shift focus on to something else</em></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13302&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/26/uk-chief-scientist-exits-in-a-blaze-of-hysteria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beddington.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Head scratch moment?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Live blogroll returns… (kind of)</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/live-blogroll-returns-kind-of/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/live-blogroll-returns-kind-of/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 09:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog notes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13298</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have restored 90% of the functionality of the Live Blog Roll by adding RSS feeds for a dozen or so of the most popular blogs the sidebar on the right. If you hover over the post title, you will... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/live-blogroll-returns-kind-of/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13298&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13299" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/blog_roll.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13299" alt="Blog Roll Returns!" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/blog_roll.jpg?w=300&#038;h=182" width="300" height="182" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Blog Roll Returns!</p></div>
<p>I have restored 90% of the functionality of the Live Blog Roll by adding RSS feeds for a dozen or so of the most popular blogs the sidebar on the right. If you hover over the post title, you will get the first few lines of the post. They are in no particular order, apart from the granddaddy of them all, WUWT, being at the top. Unfortunately they won&#8217;t be sorted by recency of post as they were on the old blog, but I hope it&#8217;s better than nothing.</p>
<p>If anyone can suggest a better option using the WordPress.com platform, please let me know!</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13298&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/live-blogroll-returns-kind-of/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/blog_roll.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Blog Roll Returns!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bloggies: ACM wins best Australian &amp; New Zealand Blog!</title>
		<link>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/bloggies-acm-wins-best-australian-new-zealand-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/bloggies-acm-wins-best-australian-new-zealand-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 01:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Simon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog notes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://australianclimatemadness.com/?p=13279</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[UPDATE: Watts Up wins best Sci/Tech and Weblog of the Year, Small Dead Animals wins best Canadian Blog, and James Delingpole wins Best Political Blog. Also, Michael Smith won Best-Kept Secret Blog for Michael Smith News. Congratulations all! Commiserations to Jo Nova in Sci/Tech, but with Watts Up... <a href="http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/bloggies-acm-wins-best-australian-new-zealand-blog/" class="read-more">Read More &#8250;</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13279&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13290" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bloggies_2013.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-13290" alt="bloggies_2013" src="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bloggies_2013.png?w=300&#038;h=150" width="300" height="150" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">ACM &#8211; Best Aussie or NZ Blog!</p></div>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><em><strong>UPDATE: </strong><a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff0000;">Watts Up</span></a> wins best Sci/Tech and Weblog of the Year, <a href="http://smalldeadanimals.com" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff0000;">Small Dead Animals</span></a> wins best Canadian Blog, and <a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/author/jamesdelingpole/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff0000;">James Delingpole</span></a> wins Best Political Blog. <span style="color:#3366ff;">Also, Michael Smith won Best-Kept Secret Blog for <a href="http://michaelsmithnews.com" target="_blank">Michael Smith News</a></span>. Congratulations all! Commiserations to <a href="http://joannenova.com.au" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff0000;">Jo Nova</span></a> in Sci/Tech, but with Watts Up out of the picture having now won it three times, maybe next year!</em></span></p>
<p>Thank you to my many supporters who voted for ACM in the Bloggies. Having been runner up to Jo Nova last year, her elevation to the Best Science Blog category saw me in with a chance.</p>
<p>It is funny to watch the climate alarmists squirm as sceptical blogs take out many categories. Why don&#8217;t they just mobilise their supporters to vote for them, rather than complaining about how the competition is run? Or flouncing off&#8230;</p>
<p>Anyway, thanks again!</p>
<p>Simon, ACM</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=australianclimatemadness.com&#038;blog=48265344&#038;post=13279&#038;subd=australianclimatemadness&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://australianclimatemadness.com/2013/03/25/bloggies-acm-wins-best-australian-new-zealand-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5e6674f279bb367dca6fedfc85a442d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">auscm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://australianclimatemadness.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bloggies_2013.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bloggies_2013</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
