<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
	<atom:link href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Film Blogging Gone Gonzo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 21:10:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="The Movie Review Warehouse" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Barry Lyndon (1975)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/17/barry-lyndon-1975/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/17/barry-lyndon-1975/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 21:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1975]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Though I&#8217;ve mostly been impressed by Stanley Kubrick&#8217;s films, Barry Lyndon was one of his many acclaimed films that I had a great hesitation in watching. At over three hours long and seeming like one of those stuffy costume dramas, it had a great potential to be unbearable. While it was certainly unbearable, it also [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5202&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Though I&#8217;ve mostly been impressed by Stanley Kubrick&#8217;s films, Barry Lyndon was one of his many acclaimed films that I had a great hesitation in watching. At over three hours long and seeming like one of those stuffy costume dramas, it had a great potential to be unbearable. While it was certainly unbearable, it also proved a bit much.</p>
<p>The first thing that stands out is that Barry Lyndon is hardly a drama at all, rather playing much more as satire of the Victorian era aristocratic dignity. Underneath the powdered and made up exteriors, these were a bunch of petty individuals. Barry himself (Ryan O&#8217;Neal) is not wholly different from a character like Frank Abagnale of Catch Me If You Can; he&#8217;s a character that finds a way to slip into each subsequent setting creatively, if not always perfectly. It is this ability that gives the film license to take on an epic scope, spanning the character&#8217;s life and his travels across the countries of Europe.</p>
<p>While many of these satirical points is well taken, and the broad rise and fall story is interesting in establishing a certain karmic narrative about how a con always fails in the end, the film is ultimately too big for its own good. The story feels tortured at over three hours. While I&#8217;m sure this pacing can be considered part of the genre satire in itself, that doesn&#8217;t improve it any as a cinematic experience.</p>
<p>The film is a visual feat of locations and costumes, as a technical experience it is poorly served by poor acting on the whole. Having Ryan O&#8217;Neal at the heart is problem enough (see Tough Guys Don&#8217;t Dance) and it seems everyone else is cast around him to not make his lack of quality stand out too much. Without performances to engage, it is ultimately a pretty lukewarm experience.</p>
<p>2.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5202&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/17/barry-lyndon-1975/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Woman (1988)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/16/another-woman-1988/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/16/another-woman-1988/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 12:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1988]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Woody Allen is very much a director with auteurist characteristics, focusing so often on artsy sophisticates at the upper margins of urban life and generally the lack of consistent or genuine happiness found in their lives and relationships. Yet, I often find him at his best the further he ventures from this pattern. Another Woman, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5182&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Woody Allen is very much a director with auteurist characteristics, focusing so often on artsy sophisticates at the upper margins of urban life and generally the lack of consistent or genuine happiness found in their lives and relationships. Yet, I often find him at his best the further he ventures from this pattern.</p>
<p>Another Woman, unfortunately, falls right in the not all that enthusiastic comfort zone for Allen with Marion (Gena Rowlands) spending a very internal 80 minutes replaying and reinterpreting her life and finding it wanting. While the poster for the film suggests Bergman (and there are many connections on that front), in watching I got a sense of Dickens, as certain scenes almost had the dreamy effect of ghosts of relationships past, present and future. I wish it played out as interestingly as it sounds but at the end of the day it was not affecting or enlightening, just another Allen-esque story.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5182/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5182&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/16/another-woman-1988/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Undefeated (2011)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/15/undefeated-2011/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/15/undefeated-2011/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 17:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At first glance, the title Undefeated makes this documentary about a football team seem a bit anticlimactic, I mean, the title feels like a spoiler. Well, once the team loses the very first game of the season, the viewer has to reevaluate why the title is what it is. Focused on an inner-city Memphis high [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5199&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At first glance, the title Undefeated makes this documentary about a football team seem a bit anticlimactic, I mean, the title feels like a spoiler. Well, once the team loses the very first game of the season, the viewer has to reevaluate why the title is what it is. Focused on an inner-city Memphis high school team, this is a team that is known more for its lack of success, facing the constant struggles typical of these communities with broken and poor households, drug use/violence and generally low expectations. In this case a defeat isn&#8217;t a loss but whether these kids bounce back; one is only defeated if they stay down.</p>
<p>This does have the perhaps unfortunate link to The Blind Side, risking valorizing white head coach Bill Courtney as a savior of this group of black students rather than giving them credit for achieving ultimately. There&#8217;s even the story of one particularly talented player being partially taken in by a wealthy white family in order to enable his continued success. Having won an Oscar, like The Blind Side, it seems Academy voters are rather partial to this type of story however.</p>
<p>Though following the coach, the story is really about three students in particular, O.C., the most talented player but struggling with academics, Chavis whose temper issues have the risk of putting him at odds with both coach and the law, and Money, who faces his own challenge in football and in life. Early on, when the film is setting up the problems, it can often be hard to sympathize. As terrible as the backgrounds for many of these kids are, it is hard to have patience when they respond with irrational and clearly self-destructive behaviors. These are the things that makes someone want to spout a mantra of personal responsibility. However, this annoyance gives way as the film&#8217;s redemptive message starts to come through.</p>
<p>The film could probably be tightened up and it does a fairly poor job of depicting the games themselves. It really isn&#8217;t up to the top standards of artistry when it comes to documentaries which makes its win a bit more unexpected, but it is ultimately a solid story worth telling, perhaps more so than many of the selections made for ESPN&#8217;s 30 For 30 series.</p>
<p>3.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5199/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5199/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5199&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/15/undefeated-2011/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Shots Pt. 2</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/quick-shots-pt-2/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/quick-shots-pt-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1999]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2009]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[J]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5197</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The lack of writing inspiration continues apace. Julien Donkey-Boy (1999) Spring Breakers may be my favorite film of this young year but Harmony Korine continues to be more miss than hit. In this case, it is the first of the Dogme films that I haven&#8217;t liked. Unlike some others who have tackled the Dogme restrictions, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5197&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The lack of writing inspiration continues apace.</p>
<p><strong>Julien Donkey-Boy (1999)</strong></p>
<p>Spring Breakers may be my favorite film of this young year but Harmony Korine continues to be more miss than hit. In this case, it is the first of the Dogme films that I haven&#8217;t liked. Unlike some others who have tackled the Dogme restrictions, it isn&#8217;t very noticeable for Korine whose aesthetic tends toward the rough anyway (Spring Breakers notably excluded). Ultimately, this feels stylistically self-involved, offering no real narrative to provide a context for this strange individual played by Ewan Bremner.</p>
<p>1/5</p>
<p><strong>Ink (2009)</strong></p>
<p>This rewatch felt overdue and gave me the opportunity to share the magnificent fantasy world created here on a shoestring budget with another. Well entrenched in my top-100 for both its charming qualities and my own personal history with the film, having attended its first public screening, I&#8217;m always happy to get the word out on this.</p>
<p>5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5197/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5197/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5197&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/quick-shots-pt-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Shots</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/quick-shots/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/quick-shots/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 12:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1927]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1952]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Q]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5195</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Admittedly this blog has been a bit more spotty with posts this year than last year, and that was mostly planned, as it risked taking over my life to an unhealthy degree, but checking in and noting that I&#8217;ve got a half week gap, one might think I&#8217;ve been too busy to watch movies. In [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5195&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Admittedly this blog has been a bit more spotty with posts this year than last year, and that was mostly planned, as it risked taking over my life to an unhealthy degree, but checking in and noting that I&#8217;ve got a half week gap, one might think I&#8217;ve been too busy to watch movies. In this case, I&#8217;ve watched a few films in the past few days but been lacking the creative juices to write about them, so as an alternative, here is a quick recap of some of those films.</p>
<p><strong>The Quiet Man (1952)</strong><br />
Started but did not finish this non-Western from Johns Ford and Wayne. Wayne plays an Irish-born American, Sean, back to reestablish his family home. He&#8217;s a huge creeper with regards to the redheaded Mary Kate (Maureen O&#8217;Hara), apparently an old maid in this film&#8217;s telling. Somehow this leads to romance and there is petty conflicts between Sean and Mary Kate&#8217;s brother and a lot of valorization of stupid masculinity. I got frustrated and gave up.</p>
<p><strong>The Day I Saw Your Heart (2011)</strong><br />
This would be an entry for my mostly abandoned Film Movement marathon and goes to show that quirk doesn&#8217;t really work in a foreign language either. The general dramatic prompt, about a father set to be a father once again at old age and how that affects his now adult daughters to whom he wasn&#8217;t a very supportive father, is a solid one. However, that father character is so bizarre as to just be annoying. The rampant waste of medical resources involved in the film was a bit distracting as well.</p>
<p><strong>Seventh Heaven (1927)</strong><br />
After a disappointing finish to the otherwise decent Lucky Star, I must have used up all my Borzage energy as this one was mostly a pain from the start, with the sewer worker with social climbing aspirations (literally about climbing the ladder up to the street to clean them). My own biases I admit but having a melodrama that is in part about the atheist finding redemption through faith is a way to alienate me. Religious salvation stories are better when what they are being saved from isn&#8217;t rationality. The romance here reflects a bit poorly on the girl too. After this I had no energy left to view the shorter Borzage film included on the flip side of the DVD.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5195/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5195/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5195&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/quick-shots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lion In Winter (1968)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/09/the-lion-in-winter-1968/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/09/the-lion-in-winter-1968/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1968]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Among the moderately cultured, a category I&#8217;d include myself in when it comes to literature, Shakespeare stands virtually alone in the ranks of playwrights. While things may be called Shakespearean and there are adaptions and influences aplenty, there aren&#8217;t so many works that have come since that so comfortably have the quality to stand among [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5193&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Among the moderately cultured, a category I&#8217;d include myself in when it comes to literature, Shakespeare stands virtually alone in the ranks of playwrights. While things may be called Shakespearean and there are adaptions and influences aplenty, there aren&#8217;t so many works that have come since that so comfortably have the quality to stand among Shakespeare&#8217;s works as equals. The Lion In Winter, a play adapted to screen, is one such work and does through with a recipe very familiar to Shakespeare, drawing on historical figures for fictional drama and doing so with a lot of punchy dialogue.</p>
<p>This is the story of a holiday gathering of King Henry II (Peter O&#8217;Toole), his estranged (and imprisoned) Queen Eleanor (Katharine Hepburn) and their three surviving sons Richard (Anthony Hopkins), Geoffrey (John Castle) and John (Nigel Terry) as well as the subordinate French King Philip II (Timothy Dalton). In the grandest terms, this is a drama about the game of thrones, as O&#8217;Toole tries to sort out who to pass his title to and the others all jockey for position. However, Eleanor perhaps best captures it in the line, &#8220;Well, what family doesn&#8217;t have its ups and downs.&#8221; Suddenly this royal epic feels almost common, like a bad holiday dinner with in-laws (or so the popular joke goes, my relatives are awesome).</p>
<p>As a production, the film generally wears its theatrical nature on its sleeve, it is no technical wonder of cinema, and the acting occasionally feels too stagey but with this cast it really has a guarantee of quality. Hepburn made a career out of sharp witted women and Eleanor may be her best, every bit the schemer that Henry is. Their relationship is by far the most fascinating part of the film as it is a film that begins with that relationship already well broken but never fails to convince us why they were together initially. Even as, or even because they lash out at each other, you can see their love of having this even match. It may not be healthy exactly, and we also know why they can&#8217;t stay together, but there is a definite spark (and in a much more engaging way than paired misery in something like Who&#8217;s Afraid of Virginia Wolfe?).</p>
<p>Aside from this, the film&#8217;s main thematic thrust involves the nature of parental relationship. With the first born son, Henry, dead, Richard would seem the natural choice and does probably seem the most Kingly, but he seems saddled by being too close with Eleanor. John, the youngest and Henry&#8217;s favorite, is petulant and spoiled. Geoffrey is somewhat humorously sensitive of the fact he is never even considered, easily sold as we know Richard and John so well from the stories of Robin Hood and the Crusades but know nothing of Geoffrey. Still, I&#8217;m not sure how much the drama actually matters, it is easy to arrive at the end of the 135 minutes thinking it is pretty much where it begins but it is the getting there that counts and the compelling characters and sharp dialogue really does make this a special experience.</p>
<p>4.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5193/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5193/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5193&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/09/the-lion-in-winter-1968/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lucky Star (1929)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/08/lucky-star-1929/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/08/lucky-star-1929/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1929]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5191</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am not sure Frank Borzage understands leg injuries, but we&#8217;ll get to that later. Mary (Janet Gaynor) is a young farm girl who briefly meets Tim (Charles Farrell) and Wrenn (Guinn Williams) before they head off to war. Already their characters are established with Tim being upstanding and Wrenn being rather less pleasant. Thus [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5191&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am not sure Frank Borzage understands leg injuries, but we&#8217;ll get to that later. Mary (Janet Gaynor) is a young farm girl who briefly meets Tim (Charles Farrell) and Wrenn (Guinn Williams) before they head off to war. Already their characters are established with Tim being upstanding and Wrenn being rather less pleasant. Thus it is no big surprise when, during the war, one of Wrenn&#8217;s selfish decisions is directly tied to Tim suffering an injury seemingly leaving him paralyzed from the waist down.</p>
<p>After the war, Mary and Tim strike up a friendship, though there are clear hints of deeper feelings. There&#8217;s the curiosity by which Tim, seeing that Mary is filthy but finding out that Mary is 18 rather than a child (and Gaynor convincingly looks like she could be a teen), realizes he cannot bathe her, because there is nothing improper about bathing a teenage girl, apparently. And while I&#8217;ve not tended to be accused of moving too fast in romance, this one feels glacial and drags down the middle of the film, sweet as their courtship is.</p>
<p>Things get sped back up when, at a dance, Wren takes an interest in Mary. We can see that he&#8217;s no good but Mary&#8217;s mother fails to see past a respectable surface and approves of Wrenn, especially compared to the &#8220;cripple,&#8221; Tim. Seemingly set up for an ideal &#8220;don&#8217;t judge a book by its cover&#8221; ending, Borzage completely undercuts the message, and human physiology, by having love cure Tim. We get our happy ending but the film loses its bite. Ignoring for a second that Wrenn, whose face is criminally under punched in the film, seems intent only on deflowering Mary, yet seems set to marry her (which would be problematic for a different reason), this ending is the kind of sap that gives melodrama a bad name. Some moments of visual craft, especially the nighttime scene in France that effectively conveys war in the simplest and smallest-scale of ways, aside, the film is always a bit too gentle seeming, but the way the ending sells out the strongest moral point takes out even that simple quality.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5191/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5191/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5191&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/08/lucky-star-1929/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Firefly (2002-03) and Serenity (2005)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/07/firefly-2002-03-and-serenity-2005/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/07/firefly-2002-03-and-serenity-2005/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 14:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sci-Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2005]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2002]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While there are plenty of films based on TV shows, the Star Trek and Mission Impossible series perhaps foremost, the vast majority of these adaptations are notably removed from the television show. In the case of Serenity, adapted from the short-lived and prematurely cancelled sci-fi series Firefly, from Joss Weadon, the film operates much less [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5189&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While there are plenty of films based on TV shows, the Star Trek and Mission Impossible series perhaps foremost, the vast majority of these adaptations are notably removed from the television show. In the case of Serenity, adapted from the short-lived and prematurely cancelled sci-fi series Firefly, from Joss Weadon, the film operates much less as a stand-alone adaptation and more as closure.</p>
<p>It is easy to get high and mighty about the need for films to stand on their own, at least across media (I think it is foolish to expect sequels to stand on their own). One shouldn&#8217;t have to read a book to enjoy a film based on that book and one probably shouldn&#8217;t have to watch a TV show to enjoy a film based on that show. And watching Serenity without having seen Firefly originally, I didn&#8217;t like it much, probably because it in too many ways doesn&#8217;t stand on its own, losing so many key subtleties to the relationships between the characters and their motivations.</p>
<p>Having recently gone through the fourteen episodes of Firefly and now reapproaching Serenity, I can only evaluate it having that background. Now I can readily forgive (while noting) that it fails to spend the time to establish things and actually was occasionally annoyed in the moments where it felt like it was abandoning the series and either forgetting or deviating the growth the characters experienced there, such as having to revisit the crew&#8217;s doubts about whether River (Summer Glau) is worth the trouble. This was something I thought the series had finally put to rest in its strong finale but alas, it isn&#8217;t until fairly late in the film here that we get back to that point.</p>
<p>While most of the characters here take pretty minimal roles, relying on the traits they built over the show&#8217;s run, the film does address two of the areas I thought the show did not do enough to develop, the political context of the Alliance against the Independents, a driving force for Captain Mal (Nathan Fillion), and the elusive River. I can&#8217;t talk much about the political angle because it unfolds into the second half of the film, but it does finally provide a stronger joint cause between Mal and River&#8217;s stories.</p>
<p>I appreciate that we get more time with River here as she often felt neglected by the show. Giving us more insight into her backstory and her abilities opens her character up a lot more. On the other hand, this version of her doesn&#8217;t quite have that odd girlish, slightly autistic nature that can work so well in the show. Instead, both she and the film as a whole takes on a bizarrely sophisticated sense of combat. Leaving behind the wild west, suddenly both River and Mal have previously unseen martial arts talents, in the latter case, needed to match up against the new villain, The Operative (Chiwetel Ejiofor). The fact that Mal was actually somewhat mediocre in combat, at least compared with Zoe and Jayne, and that the whole operation was rather ragtag, was the appeal of the show and it does feel odd losing that. And while I believe River&#8217;s amazing mental gifts, her physical talents do stretch things a bit much.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, Serenity is slightly flawed but would still probably hold up as the best episode of the series, a fitting conclusion. It may not mesh tonally with the show&#8217;s character driven lightness, being far more serious and plot-driven, but it just doesn&#8217;t really work on its own. Still, the show is short enough and enjoyable enough that it would be silly to deny yourself the full experience.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5189/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5189/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5189&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/07/firefly-2002-03-and-serenity-2005/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Wicker Man (1973)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/06/the-wicker-man-1973/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/06/the-wicker-man-1973/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 13:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1973]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[W]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From Hot Fuzz to Kill List, The Wicker Man has left a wide trail of influence, though none as present for me as a joke in the show Coupling, referring to a nude scene early in the film. The dance that Britt Ekland (playing Willow) does in her room at the inn is talked about [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5184&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From Hot Fuzz to Kill List, The Wicker Man has left a wide trail of influence, though none as present for me as a joke in the show Coupling, referring to a nude scene early in the film. The dance that Britt Ekland (playing Willow) does in her room at the inn is talked about as being formative in the erotic imaginations of the male characters when they were youths. In a film about an eerie pagan community, her sexual dance is an effective siren song, reaching to the outsider, Sergent Howie (Edward Woodward) and the viewer alike. We might not believe in their ascientific beliefs, but we can believe in the strange power she seems to hold over us. In this way, aside from being damn sexy, it is one of the most contextually satisfying nude scenes.</p>
<p>As a horror film, The Wicker Man is less about scares and more about being unsettling and the community is strange enough, well served by the slightly dreamy pacing and editing, to sell it. This serves as an interesting setting for an argument about religion. There is a certain appeal to the naturalism of the paganism, lacking the unnatural pieties of Howie&#8217;s Christianity, yet there is an obvious illogic to this version of paganism as well. It is perhaps a fault that the film falls too much into pagan stereotype in practice and not just in perception. Still, the ending has a nice twist to put the two beliefs in contrast. In all, while it may not offer the pure entertainment value of Hot Fuzz&#8217;s interpretation, and in spite of its rough production value it deserves every bit of its legacy.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5184/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5184/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5184&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/06/the-wicker-man-1973/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Croods (2013)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/the-croods-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/the-croods-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5187</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Crood is a very apt name for the family at the center the new prehistoric animated film from Dreamworks. As the trailers certainly indicated, crude is an apt description of the sense of humor on display (not so much dirty as physical, there&#8217;s a lot of pain gags). Crude is also a reasonable depiction of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5187&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crood is a very apt name for the family at the center the new prehistoric animated film from Dreamworks. As the trailers certainly indicated, crude is an apt description of the sense of humor on display (not so much dirty as physical, there&#8217;s a lot of pain gags). Crude is also a reasonable depiction of the worldview of Grug (Nicolas Cage). We can&#8217;t fault his lack of understanding of the world and subsequent fear of it, he is a caveman after all, but his view of gender is oddly anachronistic, strongly patriarchal in a way that would come millennia later, though has started to seem caveman-like in modern times.</p>
<p>The Croods holds the best of its potential in this particular angle as Grug&#8217;s patriarchy is displayed generally in his construction of self-worth in his ability to protect his family, but specifically in his antagonism when his daughter, Eep (Emma Stone), meets a boy, Guy (Ryan Reynolds), who threatens to supplant him as the male figure in her life and also embarrasses him in the process by being more modern in the process. This isn&#8217;t far off the shotgun on the porch, just with more shoving people in logs. Unfortunately, this conflict, of Grug (and thus patriarchy) feeling no longer relevant could be pretty touching except it makes you have to sympathize with both a patriarch and Nicholas Cage, I&#8217;m not sure which is harder. This won&#8217;t go down as one of the finer moments of voice acting.</p>
<p>Crude is a descriptor for other, more unfortunate, aspects of the film as well. For example, the film&#8217;s sense of biology and physics (and I&#8217;ll go out on a limb and say geology) is pretty incoherent, seeing as this is broadly meant to be Earth circa the splitting of the supercontinent (which apparently happened in about a week). Lest I come off as taking an animated film too seriously (too late?), the problem as I see it is that the introduction of the film is meant to establish how precarious the livelihood for this family is, yet the first main scene, watching the family hunt, reveals them to basically be superpowered individuals largely impervious from harm. This may reassure the youngsters that the world is charmingly free of consequences so they needn&#8217;t worry but it assures me that I don&#8217;t have to care.</p>
<p>Another crude element, and it is rather a trend for Dreamworks, is the animation of the characters. I get that the uncanny valley is a problem in animation and there is a risk of making things worse by making the human characters more life-like, but when you place these erratically shaped characters in an environment that is often breathtaking in its beauty and realism, it creates a distracting contrast. Dreamworks really needs to pick a style and adhere the entire film to it.</p>
<p>Ultimately, for crude elements both good and bad, The Croods just feels a bit run of the mill. After being pleasantly surprised by Rise of the Guardians, The Croods never gets far enough beyond the general noise and action to engage. I mean, it&#8217;s a film in theory about moving beyond unenlightened patriarchy and it features a girl going crazy over a new pair of shoes; it doesn&#8217;t quite know what it wants to be.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5187/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5187&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/the-croods-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
