<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
	<atom:link href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Film Blogging Gone Gonzo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 07:29:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="The Movie Review Warehouse" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Shots Pt. 2</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/quick-shots-pt-2/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/quick-shots-pt-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 17:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1999]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2009]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[J]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5197</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The lack of writing inspiration continues apace. Julien Donkey-Boy (1999) Spring Breakers may be my favorite film of this young year but Harmony Korine continues to be more miss than hit. In this case, it is the first of the Dogme films that I haven&#8217;t liked. Unlike some others who have tackled the Dogme restrictions, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5197&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The lack of writing inspiration continues apace.</p>
<p><strong>Julien Donkey-Boy (1999)</strong></p>
<p>Spring Breakers may be my favorite film of this young year but Harmony Korine continues to be more miss than hit. In this case, it is the first of the Dogme films that I haven&#8217;t liked. Unlike some others who have tackled the Dogme restrictions, it isn&#8217;t very noticeable for Korine whose aesthetic tends toward the rough anyway (Spring Breakers notably excluded). Ultimately, this feels stylistically self-involved, offering no real narrative to provide a context for this strange individual played by Ewan Bremner.</p>
<p>1/5</p>
<p><strong>Ink (2009)</strong></p>
<p>This rewatch felt overdue and gave me the opportunity to share the magnificent fantasy world created here on a shoestring budget with another. Well entrenched in my top-100 for both its charming qualities and my own personal history with the film, having attended its first public screening, I&#8217;m always happy to get the word out on this.</p>
<p>5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5197/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5197/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5197&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/14/quick-shots-pt-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Shots</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/quick-shots/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/quick-shots/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 12:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1927]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1952]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Q]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5195</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Admittedly this blog has been a bit more spotty with posts this year than last year, and that was mostly planned, as it risked taking over my life to an unhealthy degree, but checking in and noting that I&#8217;ve got a half week gap, one might think I&#8217;ve been too busy to watch movies. In [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5195&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Admittedly this blog has been a bit more spotty with posts this year than last year, and that was mostly planned, as it risked taking over my life to an unhealthy degree, but checking in and noting that I&#8217;ve got a half week gap, one might think I&#8217;ve been too busy to watch movies. In this case, I&#8217;ve watched a few films in the past few days but been lacking the creative juices to write about them, so as an alternative, here is a quick recap of some of those films.</p>
<p><strong>The Quiet Man (1952)</strong><br />
Started but did not finish this non-Western from Johns Ford and Wayne. Wayne plays an Irish-born American, Sean, back to reestablish his family home. He&#8217;s a huge creeper with regards to the redheaded Mary Kate (Maureen O&#8217;Hara), apparently an old maid in this film&#8217;s telling. Somehow this leads to romance and there is petty conflicts between Sean and Mary Kate&#8217;s brother and a lot of valorization of stupid masculinity. I got frustrated and gave up.</p>
<p><strong>The Day I Saw Your Heart (2011)</strong><br />
This would be an entry for my mostly abandoned Film Movement marathon and goes to show that quirk doesn&#8217;t really work in a foreign language either. The general dramatic prompt, about a father set to be a father once again at old age and how that affects his now adult daughters to whom he wasn&#8217;t a very supportive father, is a solid one. However, that father character is so bizarre as to just be annoying. The rampant waste of medical resources involved in the film was a bit distracting as well.</p>
<p><strong>Seventh Heaven (1927)</strong><br />
After a disappointing finish to the otherwise decent Lucky Star, I must have used up all my Borzage energy as this one was mostly a pain from the start, with the sewer worker with social climbing aspirations (literally about climbing the ladder up to the street to clean them). My own biases I admit but having a melodrama that is in part about the atheist finding redemption through faith is a way to alienate me. Religious salvation stories are better when what they are being saved from isn&#8217;t rationality. The romance here reflects a bit poorly on the girl too. After this I had no energy left to view the shorter Borzage film included on the flip side of the DVD.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5195/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5195/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5195&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/13/quick-shots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lion In Winter (1968)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/09/the-lion-in-winter-1968/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/09/the-lion-in-winter-1968/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 01:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1968]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Among the moderately cultured, a category I&#8217;d include myself in when it comes to literature, Shakespeare stands virtually alone in the ranks of playwrights. While things may be called Shakespearean and there are adaptions and influences aplenty, there aren&#8217;t so many works that have come since that so comfortably have the quality to stand among [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5193&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Among the moderately cultured, a category I&#8217;d include myself in when it comes to literature, Shakespeare stands virtually alone in the ranks of playwrights. While things may be called Shakespearean and there are adaptions and influences aplenty, there aren&#8217;t so many works that have come since that so comfortably have the quality to stand among Shakespeare&#8217;s works as equals. The Lion In Winter, a play adapted to screen, is one such work and does through with a recipe very familiar to Shakespeare, drawing on historical figures for fictional drama and doing so with a lot of punchy dialogue.</p>
<p>This is the story of a holiday gathering of King Henry II (Peter O&#8217;Toole), his estranged (and imprisoned) Queen Eleanor (Katharine Hepburn) and their three surviving sons Richard (Anthony Hopkins), Geoffrey (John Castle) and John (Nigel Terry) as well as the subordinate French King Philip II (Timothy Dalton). In the grandest terms, this is a drama about the game of thrones, as O&#8217;Toole tries to sort out who to pass his title to and the others all jockey for position. However, Eleanor perhaps best captures it in the line, &#8220;Well, what family doesn&#8217;t have its ups and downs.&#8221; Suddenly this royal epic feels almost common, like a bad holiday dinner with in-laws (or so the popular joke goes, my relatives are awesome).</p>
<p>As a production, the film generally wears its theatrical nature on its sleeve, it is no technical wonder of cinema, and the acting occasionally feels too stagey but with this cast it really has a guarantee of quality. Hepburn made a career out of sharp witted women and Eleanor may be her best, every bit the schemer that Henry is. Their relationship is by far the most fascinating part of the film as it is a film that begins with that relationship already well broken but never fails to convince us why they were together initially. Even as, or even because they lash out at each other, you can see their love of having this even match. It may not be healthy exactly, and we also know why they can&#8217;t stay together, but there is a definite spark (and in a much more engaging way than paired misery in something like Who&#8217;s Afraid of Virginia Wolfe?).</p>
<p>Aside from this, the film&#8217;s main thematic thrust involves the nature of parental relationship. With the first born son, Henry, dead, Richard would seem the natural choice and does probably seem the most Kingly, but he seems saddled by being too close with Eleanor. John, the youngest and Henry&#8217;s favorite, is petulant and spoiled. Geoffrey is somewhat humorously sensitive of the fact he is never even considered, easily sold as we know Richard and John so well from the stories of Robin Hood and the Crusades but know nothing of Geoffrey. Still, I&#8217;m not sure how much the drama actually matters, it is easy to arrive at the end of the 135 minutes thinking it is pretty much where it begins but it is the getting there that counts and the compelling characters and sharp dialogue really does make this a special experience.</p>
<p>4.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5193/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5193/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5193&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/09/the-lion-in-winter-1968/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lucky Star (1929)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/08/lucky-star-1929/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/08/lucky-star-1929/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 13:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1929]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5191</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am not sure Frank Borzage understands leg injuries, but we&#8217;ll get to that later. Mary (Janet Gaynor) is a young farm girl who briefly meets Tim (Charles Farrell) and Wrenn (Guinn Williams) before they head off to war. Already their characters are established with Tim being upstanding and Wrenn being rather less pleasant. Thus [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5191&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am not sure Frank Borzage understands leg injuries, but we&#8217;ll get to that later. Mary (Janet Gaynor) is a young farm girl who briefly meets Tim (Charles Farrell) and Wrenn (Guinn Williams) before they head off to war. Already their characters are established with Tim being upstanding and Wrenn being rather less pleasant. Thus it is no big surprise when, during the war, one of Wrenn&#8217;s selfish decisions is directly tied to Tim suffering an injury seemingly leaving him paralyzed from the waist down.</p>
<p>After the war, Mary and Tim strike up a friendship, though there are clear hints of deeper feelings. There&#8217;s the curiosity by which Tim, seeing that Mary is filthy but finding out that Mary is 18 rather than a child (and Gaynor convincingly looks like she could be a teen), realizes he cannot bathe her, because there is nothing improper about bathing a teenage girl, apparently. And while I&#8217;ve not tended to be accused of moving too fast in romance, this one feels glacial and drags down the middle of the film, sweet as their courtship is.</p>
<p>Things get sped back up when, at a dance, Wren takes an interest in Mary. We can see that he&#8217;s no good but Mary&#8217;s mother fails to see past a respectable surface and approves of Wrenn, especially compared to the &#8220;cripple,&#8221; Tim. Seemingly set up for an ideal &#8220;don&#8217;t judge a book by its cover&#8221; ending, Borzage completely undercuts the message, and human physiology, by having love cure Tim. We get our happy ending but the film loses its bite. Ignoring for a second that Wrenn, whose face is criminally under punched in the film, seems intent only on deflowering Mary, yet seems set to marry her (which would be problematic for a different reason), this ending is the kind of sap that gives melodrama a bad name. Some moments of visual craft, especially the nighttime scene in France that effectively conveys war in the simplest and smallest-scale of ways, aside, the film is always a bit too gentle seeming, but the way the ending sells out the strongest moral point takes out even that simple quality.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5191/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5191/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5191&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/08/lucky-star-1929/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Firefly (2002-03) and Serenity (2005)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/07/firefly-2002-03-and-serenity-2005/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/07/firefly-2002-03-and-serenity-2005/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 14:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2002]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2005]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[F]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sci-Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While there are plenty of films based on TV shows, the Star Trek and Mission Impossible series perhaps foremost, the vast majority of these adaptations are notably removed from the television show. In the case of Serenity, adapted from the short-lived and prematurely cancelled sci-fi series Firefly, from Joss Weadon, the film operates much less [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5189&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While there are plenty of films based on TV shows, the Star Trek and Mission Impossible series perhaps foremost, the vast majority of these adaptations are notably removed from the television show. In the case of Serenity, adapted from the short-lived and prematurely cancelled sci-fi series Firefly, from Joss Weadon, the film operates much less as a stand-alone adaptation and more as closure.</p>
<p>It is easy to get high and mighty about the need for films to stand on their own, at least across media (I think it is foolish to expect sequels to stand on their own). One shouldn&#8217;t have to read a book to enjoy a film based on that book and one probably shouldn&#8217;t have to watch a TV show to enjoy a film based on that show. And watching Serenity without having seen Firefly originally, I didn&#8217;t like it much, probably because it in too many ways doesn&#8217;t stand on its own, losing so many key subtleties to the relationships between the characters and their motivations.</p>
<p>Having recently gone through the fourteen episodes of Firefly and now reapproaching Serenity, I can only evaluate it having that background. Now I can readily forgive (while noting) that it fails to spend the time to establish things and actually was occasionally annoyed in the moments where it felt like it was abandoning the series and either forgetting or deviating the growth the characters experienced there, such as having to revisit the crew&#8217;s doubts about whether River (Summer Glau) is worth the trouble. This was something I thought the series had finally put to rest in its strong finale but alas, it isn&#8217;t until fairly late in the film here that we get back to that point.</p>
<p>While most of the characters here take pretty minimal roles, relying on the traits they built over the show&#8217;s run, the film does address two of the areas I thought the show did not do enough to develop, the political context of the Alliance against the Independents, a driving force for Captain Mal (Nathan Fillion), and the elusive River. I can&#8217;t talk much about the political angle because it unfolds into the second half of the film, but it does finally provide a stronger joint cause between Mal and River&#8217;s stories.</p>
<p>I appreciate that we get more time with River here as she often felt neglected by the show. Giving us more insight into her backstory and her abilities opens her character up a lot more. On the other hand, this version of her doesn&#8217;t quite have that odd girlish, slightly autistic nature that can work so well in the show. Instead, both she and the film as a whole takes on a bizarrely sophisticated sense of combat. Leaving behind the wild west, suddenly both River and Mal have previously unseen martial arts talents, in the latter case, needed to match up against the new villain, The Operative (Chiwetel Ejiofor). The fact that Mal was actually somewhat mediocre in combat, at least compared with Zoe and Jayne, and that the whole operation was rather ragtag, was the appeal of the show and it does feel odd losing that. And while I believe River&#8217;s amazing mental gifts, her physical talents do stretch things a bit much.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, Serenity is slightly flawed but would still probably hold up as the best episode of the series, a fitting conclusion. It may not mesh tonally with the show&#8217;s character driven lightness, being far more serious and plot-driven, but it just doesn&#8217;t really work on its own. Still, the show is short enough and enjoyable enough that it would be silly to deny yourself the full experience.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5189/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5189/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5189&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/07/firefly-2002-03-and-serenity-2005/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Wicker Man (1973)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/06/the-wicker-man-1973/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/06/the-wicker-man-1973/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 13:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1973]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[W]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From Hot Fuzz to Kill List, The Wicker Man has left a wide trail of influence, though none as present for me as a joke in the show Coupling, referring to a nude scene early in the film. The dance that Britt Ekland (playing Willow) does in her room at the inn is talked about [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5184&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From Hot Fuzz to Kill List, The Wicker Man has left a wide trail of influence, though none as present for me as a joke in the show Coupling, referring to a nude scene early in the film. The dance that Britt Ekland (playing Willow) does in her room at the inn is talked about as being formative in the erotic imaginations of the male characters when they were youths. In a film about an eerie pagan community, her sexual dance is an effective siren song, reaching to the outsider, Sergent Howie (Edward Woodward) and the viewer alike. We might not believe in their ascientific beliefs, but we can believe in the strange power she seems to hold over us. In this way, aside from being damn sexy, it is one of the most contextually satisfying nude scenes.</p>
<p>As a horror film, The Wicker Man is less about scares and more about being unsettling and the community is strange enough, well served by the slightly dreamy pacing and editing, to sell it. This serves as an interesting setting for an argument about religion. There is a certain appeal to the naturalism of the paganism, lacking the unnatural pieties of Howie&#8217;s Christianity, yet there is an obvious illogic to this version of paganism as well. It is perhaps a fault that the film falls too much into pagan stereotype in practice and not just in perception. Still, the ending has a nice twist to put the two beliefs in contrast. In all, while it may not offer the pure entertainment value of Hot Fuzz&#8217;s interpretation, and in spite of its rough production value it deserves every bit of its legacy.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5184/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5184/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5184&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/06/the-wicker-man-1973/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Croods (2013)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/the-croods-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/the-croods-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 13:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5187</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Crood is a very apt name for the family at the center the new prehistoric animated film from Dreamworks. As the trailers certainly indicated, crude is an apt description of the sense of humor on display (not so much dirty as physical, there&#8217;s a lot of pain gags). Crude is also a reasonable depiction of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5187&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crood is a very apt name for the family at the center the new prehistoric animated film from Dreamworks. As the trailers certainly indicated, crude is an apt description of the sense of humor on display (not so much dirty as physical, there&#8217;s a lot of pain gags). Crude is also a reasonable depiction of the worldview of Grug (Nicolas Cage). We can&#8217;t fault his lack of understanding of the world and subsequent fear of it, he is a caveman after all, but his view of gender is oddly anachronistic, strongly patriarchal in a way that would come millennia later, though has started to seem caveman-like in modern times.</p>
<p>The Croods holds the best of its potential in this particular angle as Grug&#8217;s patriarchy is displayed generally in his construction of self-worth in his ability to protect his family, but specifically in his antagonism when his daughter, Eep (Emma Stone), meets a boy, Guy (Ryan Reynolds), who threatens to supplant him as the male figure in her life and also embarrasses him in the process by being more modern in the process. This isn&#8217;t far off the shotgun on the porch, just with more shoving people in logs. Unfortunately, this conflict, of Grug (and thus patriarchy) feeling no longer relevant could be pretty touching except it makes you have to sympathize with both a patriarch and Nicholas Cage, I&#8217;m not sure which is harder. This won&#8217;t go down as one of the finer moments of voice acting.</p>
<p>Crude is a descriptor for other, more unfortunate, aspects of the film as well. For example, the film&#8217;s sense of biology and physics (and I&#8217;ll go out on a limb and say geology) is pretty incoherent, seeing as this is broadly meant to be Earth circa the splitting of the supercontinent (which apparently happened in about a week). Lest I come off as taking an animated film too seriously (too late?), the problem as I see it is that the introduction of the film is meant to establish how precarious the livelihood for this family is, yet the first main scene, watching the family hunt, reveals them to basically be superpowered individuals largely impervious from harm. This may reassure the youngsters that the world is charmingly free of consequences so they needn&#8217;t worry but it assures me that I don&#8217;t have to care.</p>
<p>Another crude element, and it is rather a trend for Dreamworks, is the animation of the characters. I get that the uncanny valley is a problem in animation and there is a risk of making things worse by making the human characters more life-like, but when you place these erratically shaped characters in an environment that is often breathtaking in its beauty and realism, it creates a distracting contrast. Dreamworks really needs to pick a style and adhere the entire film to it.</p>
<p>Ultimately, for crude elements both good and bad, The Croods just feels a bit run of the mill. After being pleasantly surprised by Rise of the Guardians, The Croods never gets far enough beyond the general noise and action to engage. I mean, it&#8217;s a film in theory about moving beyond unenlightened patriarchy and it features a girl going crazy over a new pair of shoes; it doesn&#8217;t quite know what it wants to be.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5187/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5187&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/the-croods-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>She Monkeys (2011)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/she-monkeys-2011/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/she-monkeys-2011/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 13:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5180</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hearing a plot description that involves the words Swedish, teen and gymnasts, this sounded like a film that couldn&#8217;t fail. Clearly nothing is sacred as this work of first time director Lisa Aschan just seems rather aimless. Though I&#8217;m generally unable to evaluate acting quality in a foreign language, I will defer to my Swedish [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5180&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hearing a plot description that involves the words Swedish, teen and gymnasts, this sounded like a film that couldn&#8217;t fail. Clearly nothing is sacred as this work of first time director Lisa Aschan just seems rather aimless. Though I&#8217;m generally unable to evaluate acting quality in a foreign language, I will defer to my Swedish source, Jessica at <a href="http://thevelvetcafe.wordpress.com/category/she-monkeys/" />The Velvet Cafe<a>, in trusting that what is offered here is not all that special. Even if the delivery is beyond me, it is easy to tell that this is a film, whether from the acting or the directing, goes for a very emotionless approach to its story, which in my case left me largely apathetic. The lead, Emma, and her friend and/or teammate Cassandra share a somewhat undefined relationship that is at times friendly, at times sexually charged and at times downright hostile. Still, you don&#8217;t get anywhere close to their feelings so it all seems inexplicable, somehow teaching us nothing of their nature.</p>
<p>By far the more interesting character in the film is Emma&#8217;s younger sister. Early on, we see her at a swim class where one instructor insists that she must wear a top to her bathing suit to which her mom (?) tries to de-shame the situation. Still, in the reaction to this moment and her actions at other points, we see that this girl, very young though she is, is going through a tricky place with her identity as a female and eventual adult. Though handled better than the main plot, even this seems a bit icier than it needs to be. Everything is just treated more preciously than it merits. This may benefit the visual look of the film but the story is what ultimately</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5180/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5180/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5180&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/04/she-monkeys-2011/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Letter to Three Wives (1949)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/a-letter-to-three-wives-1949/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/a-letter-to-three-wives-1949/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1949]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While some worry about the risk, in modern times, of teens being told to grow up too fast, at least sexually, watching A Letter to Three Wives, I couldn&#8217;t help but think the adult women of the post-war era seemed slightly infantalized. After all, the film seems so much like a period version of Gossip [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5178&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While some worry about the risk, in modern times, of teens being told to grow up too fast, at least sexually, watching A Letter to Three Wives, I couldn&#8217;t help but think the adult women of the post-war era seemed slightly infantalized. After all, the film seems so much like a period version of Gossip Girl, complete with faceless narrator and a certain social scandal as the narrator, Addie Ross, informs three women that she is running away with one of their husbands. With drama that contrived, the film&#8217;s story is sure to take a back seat to its more fundamental qualities.</p>
<p>The wives, Debby (Jeanne Crain), Rita (Ann Sothern) and Lora Mae (Linda Darnell) each has reason to fear it is their husband who has gone as all three men seem to idolize Addie as the perfect woman (all the better she isn&#8217;t shown as who could live up to that billing) and each is self-conscious in their relationships, as evidenced by the three flashbacks that make up the bulk of the film.</p>
<p>Placing the story of Debby and Brad Bishop at the front is an unfortunate choice as it is the weakest tale and almost loses it at the start. He&#8217;s a son of wealth and she&#8217;s a farm girl who met in the Navy, but now in his setting, she feels out of place. This insecurity is understandable enough, especially as Addie is constantly referred to as the one everyone figured Brad would wind up with, but Crain&#8217;s acting is so heavy-handed it fails to deliver on the potential.</p>
<p>Things take a step up with Rita and George Phipps (Kirk Douglas). Their relationship feels a bit more grounded, though we see a tension in that she aspires to advancing in material class while he, as a teacher, pursues intellectual sophistication. Her work in radio, perfectly translatable to the television of today, risks being too pedestrian for George, and Addie happens to be sophisticated herself. Douglas is in fine form here in a lighter role than I&#8217;d seen from him.</p>
<p>The final story of Lora Mae and Porter Hollingsway (Paul Douglas) is more forcefully about class. This takes us clear back to the onset of their romance where we find her as a lower class employee in one of his stores. Being closer to the street, Lora Mae is a much craftier than the other women and this allows Darnell to really shine as she responds to what could easily be a problematic/coercive situation and plays it to her advantage. Unfortunately, the class chasm between them is a continuing source of weakness for the relationship.</p>
<p>Even if the story is inane, there are a few bits of insight into relationships and class here to make it hold on. With strong performances from Douglas and Darnell, as well as good comedic relief from Sadie (Thelma Ritter) as Rita&#8217;s maid and Lora Mae&#8217;s family friend, it ultimately recovers from a slow start to be a surprisingly entertaining venture.</p>
<p>3.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5178/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5178&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/a-letter-to-three-wives-1949/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smashed (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/smashed-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/smashed-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 13:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5164</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It takes a village to raise an alcoholic. Admittedly a true alcohol dependence is a physical addiction, often hereditary, that can exist beyond a social context, but much of the excessive and destructive drinking and other drug use that gets tucked under a term like alcoholism has a social origin. Living in one of the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5164&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5172" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smashed.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smashed.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="Amused and horrified, an expression to match a film." width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-5172" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Amused and horrified, an expression to match a film.</p></div>It takes a village to raise an alcoholic. Admittedly a true alcohol dependence is a physical addiction, often hereditary, that can exist beyond a social context, but much of the excessive and destructive drinking and other drug use that gets tucked under a term like alcoholism has a social origin. Living in one of the heaviest drinking states in America, where excessive drinking is one of the few activities presented to singles, I could certainly relate to the struggle facing Kate (Mary Elizabeth Winstead) in Smashed. One doesn&#8217;t like to choose between a social life and responsibility.</p>
<p>It is pretty easy to imagine a couple college students, light on responsibilities, meeting over a mutual appreciation for the party lifestyle. So Kate and Charlie (Aaron Paul) establish a relationship based on abuse with a group of friends and list of activities that all tend to involve drinking, but what happens when they move into the adult world that demands a bit more from them? Kate hits a clear decision point one morning when she, a first grade teacher, vomits in class and feels guilted into claiming she is pregnant. What follows is an interesting portrait of the challenges of recreating one&#8217;s life as a sober adult and also the closeted nature of these struggles. It is easy and even reasonable to look at Kate at the start and conclude that she clearly can&#8217;t be trusted to care for a class of young students but it is harder to navigate her needs to get on the right track.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve seen plenty of gritty films about addictions of various sorts that are agonizing journeys with a scared sober kind of approach. Watching Requiem For A Dream or Trainspotting isn&#8217;t likely to make someone want to start using drugs. Smashed takes a softer, more comedic touch while still being dramatic. There are unpleasant outcomes but there&#8217;s a softer edge to these harder moments and this makes for an appreciated change. Rather than engage in a hyperbole of life or death stakes, this is more about subtler questions of happiness and who one actually wants to be in life. Given this, certain comedic moments that go a bit too broad or dramatic moments that go too big do feel a bit out of place but generally it does get this tone right on the back of a strong lead performance from Winstead.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5164/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5164/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5164&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/30/smashed-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smashed.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Amused and horrified, an expression to match a film.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
