<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
	<atom:link href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Film Blogging Gone Gonzo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:12:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="The Movie Review Warehouse" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Rise of the Guardians (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/rise-of-the-guardians-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/rise-of-the-guardians-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 11:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5168</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Trailers are an odd thing. Their purpose is intended to sell people on watching a movie yet more often than not, for me, they provide reasons to stay away, typically emphasizing the most bland and &#8220;broadly appealing&#8221; elements of a film, not the things that make it special. Rise of the Guardians is definitely an [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5168&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riseofguardians.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riseofguardians.jpg?w=630" alt="RiseofGuardians"   class="alignright size-full wp-image-5170" /></a>Trailers are an odd thing. Their purpose is intended to sell people on watching a movie yet more often than not, for me, they provide reasons to stay away, typically emphasizing the most bland and &#8220;broadly appealing&#8221; elements of a film, not the things that make it special. Rise of the Guardians is definitely an example of a film being undersold in advertisement as the focus on the Santa and Easter Bunny characters, each with silly accent and cheesy jokes (and character animation that leaves something to be desired) that made it seem too typical of the Dreamworks animated films that have remained well back of the Pixar/Ghibli/Disney standard.</p>
<p>Watching the whole film is rather another experience. The character design remains a major weak point for the film but the rest of the animation is stunning with a combination of fairly realistic looking settings slamming into a great sense of the fantastic. Getting past the somewhat unfortunate voice work from Alec Baldwin as Santa, there is a gentle heart to the story and a fun interplay between the other guardians that include the Easter Bunny, Tooth Fairy, Sandman and, in response to a new threat posed by the Boogeyman, the newest guardian, Jack Frost.</p>
<p>Each character faces their own identity crisis that leads them to be a bit competitive as they strive to maintain the belief of children. While on the surface level this is the belief in the actual guardian, it is really what each represents about childhood that is put in question. In this way, the Boogeyman&#8217;s nightmares represent an end of innocence, but not in the healthy process of aging but in an abrupt and disturbing way. The film allows us to spend time in each guardian&#8217;s world, appreciating the distinct look of each and how it fits into their aspect. We also feel for Jack Frost&#8217;s sense of inadequacy next to these heavy hitters of holiday mythology as he tries to discover what he has to offer (besides annoying people with freezing temperatures into April, you listening to me Frosty?).</p>
<p>What also helps Guardians stand out from the typical is the effectiveness of the Boogeyman as a villain, in part due to the voice work of Jude Law. With echoes of Wreck-It-Ralph, this is a bad guy humanized. Unlike the Disney film, he remains the clear villain of the picture but his weakness is not so different as that of the guardians, he just wants to be relevant. When your effect on people is to give them nightmares it is hard not to be a villain, though perhaps the film does miss a beat by not noting the appeal of a good scare, whether it is childish ghost stories or adult horror films. In an otherwise very enjoyable film, this inability to take the final step is what keeps it from transcendence on the level of the best animated films. Still, after watching the trailer, I wasn&#8217;t expecting to talk about barely missed transcendence so that is a clear victory.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5168/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5168/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5168&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/rise-of-the-guardians-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/riseofguardians.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">RiseofGuardians</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sound on Sight: The Idealistic Theology of Victor Hugo</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/sound-on-sight-the-idealistic-theology-of-victor-hugo/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/sound-on-sight-the-idealistic-theology-of-victor-hugo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 11:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Essays]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5166</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In considering my two Blu-ray purchases of last week, I penned an article looking at Les Miserables and The Hunchback of Notre Dame over at Sound on Sight. Enjoy.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5166&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In considering my two Blu-ray purchases of last week, I penned an article looking at Les Miserables and The Hunchback of Notre Dame over at <a href="http://www.soundonsight.org/les-miserables-and-the-hunchback-of-notre-dame/">Sound on Sight</a>. Enjoy.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5166/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5166/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5166&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/sound-on-sight-the-idealistic-theology-of-victor-hugo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hud (1963)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/hud-1963/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/hud-1963/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1963]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5162</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Apparently I didn&#8217;t learn the lesson I was supposed to by watching Hud. In reading a few things after finishing the film, it seems the message I am supposed to take home is that Hud is a bad man who ultimately drives people away. Hud certainly isn&#8217;t a good man but I give a lot [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5162&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apparently I didn&#8217;t learn the lesson I was supposed to by watching Hud. In reading a few things after finishing the film, it seems the message I am supposed to take home is that Hud is a bad man who ultimately drives people away. Hud certainly isn&#8217;t a good man but I give a lot of credit to Paul Newman for making the character seem like a complicated individual with easily acknowledge flaws but perhaps values that go unappreciated by those around him.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.soundonsight.org/introverted-perspectives-the-quiet-passive-observer/" />Sound on Sight</a> recently had an article about the practice of having a quieter character in the lead to observe the action around from a more grounded place and Hud is actually placed more firmly in the viewpoint of Hud&#8217;s nephew, Lonnie. An only child who has lost his parents, Lon is seeking both father figure and older brother in Hud but is caught between seeing the appeal in Hud&#8217;s freer lifestyle and the stern responsibility of his grandfather, Homer.</p>
<p>While Hud&#8217;s drinking and womanizing gets him into a certain amount of trouble, Homer&#8217;s principled naivety also puts the family at risk. If the film has a flaw, it is in being too decisive in passing verdict in this tug-of-war. Even though Newman&#8217;s performance sets the stage for a slightly more nuanced battle, the character is ultimately constrained. This holds it a step short of greatness for me. Bonus points for Newman making a salad dressing joke though.</p>
<p>3.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5162/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5162/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5162&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/hud-1963/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Gatekeepers (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/the-gatekeepers-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/the-gatekeepers-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 17:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Documentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[G]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5159</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Israel-Palestine conflict is a tragic example of path dependence. Whether or not the formation of the modern country of Israel in 1948 itself was an action that could have resolved itself toward peace in time, as one prescient quote discussed in The Gatekeepers, a new Oscar-nominated documentary about the conflict, describes, the occupation of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5159&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5160" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gatekeepers.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gatekeepers.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" alt="Six heads, talking." width="300" height="199" class="size-medium wp-image-5160" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Six heads, talking.</p></div>The Israel-Palestine conflict is a tragic example of path dependence. Whether or not the formation of the modern country of Israel in 1948 itself was an action that could have resolved itself toward peace in time, as one prescient quote discussed in The Gatekeepers, a new Oscar-nominated documentary about the conflict, describes, the occupation of the Gaza Strip and West Bank following the Six Day War may have been a predictably bad decision. Unfortunately, what might have more easily been not done in 1967 is much more problematic to undo in 2013. Interviewing six heads of the secretive Shin Bet (seemingly the MI5 to Mossad&#8217;s MI6, focusing on domestic security concerns), the documentary looks for some insight into what has been learned from the actions of the past few decades.</p>
<p>As a documentary it is a curiously mixed bag. While mostly it is pretty conventional talking heads stuff with occasional archival footage, there are occasions when it throws in sort of video game-style animated reenactments. This almost seems needlessly elaborate as it doesn&#8217;t really provide much beyond a stylistic calling card (especially as it fades to photograph, tying the reenactment back into reality). More problematic is that the film seems overly concerned with replaying the history of Shin Bet&#8217;s actions. I certainly am no expert on these stories but nor does a fairly detailed knowledge of these events really pay off in understanding of the nature of the conflict beyond what I would have grasped already.</p>
<p>Where the film would seem to hold the most promise and interest is in how this history shapes the future. What does the experience of these six men teach them about where to go from here. On this the film is frustratingly brief. Maybe this is because even given their experiences, they too are at a loss at what to do. They seem to acknowledge that an aggressive response is doomed to fail but perhaps the Israeli right of settlers and the very religious will continue to team with the Palestinian militants to deter any hope of peace. After all, as is made clear in the film, it takes a whole nation to keep the peace and only one person to break it. Maybe it is asking too much of a documentary to solve a conflict of this level but it feels a bit unfulfilling for it to offer so little hope.</p>
<p>2.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5159/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5159/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5159&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/the-gatekeepers-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gatekeepers.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Six heads, talking.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>La Haine (1995)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/la-haine-1995/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/la-haine-1995/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 17:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1995]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5156</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Having The Crimson Rivers as my introduction to director Mathieu Kassovitz may have been a bit misleading. A juicy genre film, working the talents of Jean Reno and Vincent Cassel toward a satisfyingly gothic crime procedural, is worlds away from the serious cinema of La Haine and its look at the unrest among young economic [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5156&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having The Crimson Rivers as my introduction to director Mathieu Kassovitz may have been a bit misleading. A juicy genre film, working the talents of Jean Reno and Vincent Cassel toward a satisfyingly gothic crime procedural, is worlds away from the serious cinema of La Haine and its look at the unrest among young economic and ethnic minorities in France.</p>
<p>Vinz (Cassel), Hubert and Said are three young guys who are in that gap after leaving school (not necessarily through graduation) but not yet having found employment. The film doesn&#8217;t provide an immediate context on the employment situation but often times situations where we would be inclined to condemn those we see as lazy and milking the system simply have no ready opportunities for success. It would seem this is true of the time of the film, much as it is a reasonable description of life for those in their 20s, especially without much education, in present day America.</p>
<p>I feel like I harp on about unlikable protagonists too much but as much as one wants to sympathize with the situation of these kids but they sure don&#8217;t make it easy. While not lacking some legitimate grievances in terms of police aggression or discrimination, they seem needlessly provocative. When they are being idle and having little moments happen around them, the film holds together, but in those moments where things get macho, it becomes a bit obnoxious for me the way that machismo often does.</p>
<p>If the laziness of the plotting and reliance on machismo inhibits the film, the humor that is allowed to exist between friends at other times works with the strong black and white visual style to make the film more engaging than it maybe deserves to be, though still less than it should be.</p>
<p>2.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5156/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5156/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5156&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/la-haine-1995/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Breakers (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/spring-breakers-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/spring-breakers-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 14:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5153</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For a film that opens with a high-energy glimpse of spring break beaches that could be pulled from a Girls Gone Wild video, the interesting thing about Spring Breakers is that a much more voyeuristic scene happens not too much later as a group of four college friends, Faith (Selena Gomez), Candy (Vanessa Hudgens), Brit [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5153&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5154" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbreakers.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbreakers.jpg?w=630" alt="All rise!"   class="size-full wp-image-5154" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">All rise!</p></div>For a film that opens with a high-energy glimpse of spring break beaches that could be pulled from a Girls Gone Wild video, the interesting thing about Spring Breakers is that a much more voyeuristic scene happens not too much later as a group of four college friends, Faith (Selena Gomez), Candy (Vanessa Hudgens), Brit (Ashley Benson) and Cotty (Rachel Korine) just hang out in a casual way in their dorm as presumably girls of that age will do when boys aren&#8217;t around. It is not the slumber party of male fantasy but a normal hang-out still seen through a male gaze. In a film full of nudity and exploitation, having this scene seem the greatest violation of privacy is pretty powerful, after all, once the girls head off for spring break in Florida, it all seems so much less private and much more performative. In the age of social media, such debauchery becomes public and the only thing kept in reserve is wholesomeness.</p>
<p>With Disney alums in the cast, Spring Breakers is sure to be a film to shock the senses of many theatregoers, but even having seen Korine films before, it is hard not to be a bit overwhelmed by the energy of the first act of the film. It is the exhilaration of youth with that hedonistic sense of invincibility. But like youth or like the drugged high, this energy can&#8217;t last. It would be easy to punish the film for dragging into the second act if it didn&#8217;t make so much thematic sense. This section is the hangover of the first as the ache builds up inside, convincing you that you both want to never experience that again or else need it to return to that right away.</p>
<p>The choice one makes in response to this feeling is a critical one as we see in the film that those who refuse to get older and leave behind this hedonism become increasingly trapped by it, none more so than Alien (James Franco), a white rapper/gangster who takes the girls in. Though not out of place with the aggressive tone of the film, Franco does seem the film&#8217;s biggest weak point as his character is just too much of a type and doesn&#8217;t really exude a charm or appeal that would believably draw the girls in like he does.</p>
<p>Spring Breakers is ultimately a film that makes you ask questions of yourself. While I never got involved in &#8220;spring break&#8221; style craziness, as I recently crossed the threshold into my 30s I&#8217;ve been forced to think a bit about my own short-cuts to sensations of happiness and consider what can provide less illusory contentment. I&#8217;m still not sure what that answer is so for now I think I&#8217;ll hydrate and take an aspirin, may I never feel like this again</p>
<p>4.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5153/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5153/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5153&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/spring-breakers-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbreakers.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">All rise!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hunchback of Notre Dame II (2002)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame-ii-2002/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame-ii-2002/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2002]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5149</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whether born of a purist or nostalgic outrage, the parade of direct to video sequels to Disney&#8217;s biggest animated films can&#8217;t avoid feeling a bit shameful. Yet, the two Aladdin sequels, Return of Jafar and Aladdin and the King of Thieves were both remarkably solid animated films. Well, it turns out that having One Thousand [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5149&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5151" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hunchbackii.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hunchbackii.jpg?w=300&#038;h=206" alt="A saturday cartoon outing." width="300" height="206" class="size-medium wp-image-5151" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A saturday cartoon outing.</p></div>Whether born of a purist or nostalgic outrage, the parade of direct to video sequels to Disney&#8217;s biggest animated films can&#8217;t avoid feeling a bit shameful. Yet, the two Aladdin sequels, Return of Jafar and Aladdin and the King of Thieves were both remarkably solid animated films. Well, it turns out that having One Thousand and One Arabian nights gives you better source material to adapt because lacking Victor Hugo coming back from the grave to extend his original story, the writers involved with making a sequel to Hunchback of Notre Dame didn&#8217;t have any bright new ideas.</p>
<p>One of the powerful aspects for me in watching Hunchback (still my favorite Disney film) is that it doesn&#8217;t end with the cliche of the main character getting the girl. It tips its hand toward realism, acknowledging that Quasimodo simply wasn&#8217;t going to get Esmerelda, no matter his heroism, that the handsome co-hero was going to be the one to appeal to her. But for the sequel, the entire film&#8217;s story is pretty much based on a &#8220;this time it&#8217;ll happen&#8221; logic as Quasimodo meets Madellaine (Jennifer Love Hewitt), a woman in town with a traveling carnival headed by the obviously evil Sarousch (Michael McKean).</p>
<p>There is a vague promise in the comparison between Madellaine&#8217;s plight here and Quasi&#8217;s in the first film. Much like he feels a sense of duty to Frollo in the belief he saved his life, Madellaine feels in the debt to Sarousch and strains against this sense of obligation when seeing his immorality. Similarly, as Quasi struggled against the imposed isolation of his gnarled body, Madellaine feels diminished in her gendered role of just looking pretty for the magic show, wishing to be a tightrope walker instead. All of this seems really interesting but is only marginally delved into, with the bulk of the hour runtime spent on petty romance.</p>
<p>The film is a definite budget affair in terms of the animation, an obvious step back from the original. However, it does return basically the entire vocal cast of the original which is an impressive enough feat. Still, lacking a compelling story and no really memorable songs, it just feels a hollow echo that makes it fitting as basically a special feature attached to the new Blu-ray version of the main feature.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5149/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5149/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5149&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame-ii-2002/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hunchbackii.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A saturday cartoon outing.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Young Girls of Rochefort (1967)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/the-young-girls-of-rochefort-1967/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/the-young-girls-of-rochefort-1967/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1967]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Y]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5147</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If there is a more inane story to ever be stretched past two hours than The Young Girls of Rochefort, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve seen it. As film efficiency goes, this was a bad start as it is at least ten minutes before there&#8217;s any meaningful dialogue/lyrics, being content as it is with frivolous dancing [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5147&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If there is a more inane story to ever be stretched past two hours than The Young Girls of Rochefort, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve seen it. As film efficiency goes, this was a bad start as it is at least ten minutes before there&#8217;s any meaningful dialogue/lyrics, being content as it is with frivolous dancing with little context, something that would end up taking up closer to a half hour of the runtime when all is said and done.</p>
<p>Upon introducing us to the characters, from the twins Delphine and Solange (Catherine Deneuve and Francoise Dorleac) to the carnival guys Etienne and Bill down to the American Andy Miller (Gene Kelly), it hardly gets more contextualized as the film is so taken with its fluffy song and dance that no character operates beyond a very superficial level of motivation and emotion. People want love and the twins in particular want to get out of the small town and do big things. These are well worn themes but usually they are at least developed in a way that seems personalized. The problem here is that the film puts so little effort into having a story and brings in too many characters to make any of them matter.</p>
<p>It might compensate for this to some degree if the songs and dance were absolutely sparkling, but even there it seems lackluster. Admittedly, foreign language musicals are a rather steep hurdle. I liked Resnais&#8217; Not On The Lips but otherwise I&#8217;d be hard pressed to think of a musical I&#8217;ve fully appreciated in a foreign language. Not only is it a challenge to keep up on subtitles during the songs, it just makes it harder for the song to be catchy through translation (and notably Not On The Lips succeeded on story, not music). Demy&#8217;s own Umbrellas of Cherbourg provided much more story and style to survive this handicap. Rochefort just doesn&#8217;t offer anything to get off the mark.</p>
<p>1/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5147/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5147/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5147&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/the-young-girls-of-rochefort-1967/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rust and Bone (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/rust-and-bone-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/rust-and-bone-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 17:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In film circles it is popular to talk about auteur directors, whose stylistic or thematic fingerprints are left on all of their projects. In Rust and Bone, I see less of my previous experience with director Jacques Audiard, A Prophet, and more of my previous experience with actor Matthias Schoenaerts, Bullhead. We talk about range [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5143&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5145" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rustandbone.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rustandbone.jpg?w=630" alt="For when it is not shark week."   class="size-full wp-image-5145" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">For when it is not shark week.</p></div>In film circles it is popular to talk about auteur directors, whose stylistic or thematic fingerprints are left on all of their projects. In Rust and Bone, I see less of my previous experience with director Jacques Audiard, A Prophet, and more of my previous experience with actor Matthias Schoenaerts, Bullhead. We talk about range when it comes to actors but sometimes there is something in an actor that makes it much more productive to explore different angles of similar characters. With Alain, as with his character in Bullhead, Schoenaerts brooding physical form lends itself to a consideration of masculinity.</p>
<p>Stuck on the margins of society with a young son, Alain seems completely unsuited to being a parent. After all, his sources of income; as a bouncer, as an underground kickboxer and helping to install illicit surveillance for employers to monitor employees, are both marginal and tend to keep him away at various hours. They do fit his masculinity, as does his casual flings. Still, we get a bit more of a look into his persona when he meets Stephanie (Marion Cotillard) while working as a bouncer.</p>
<p>I believe it is no spoiler to say that Stephanie, an orca trainer at a Sea World like park, suffers an accident that renders her handicapped. In dealing with this change to her life, Alain&#8217;s masculinity actually proves ideal in a number of ways, bringing them closer, yet the final act is one revealing the limits of this singular approach.</p>
<p>While this is largely Alain&#8217;s story, it does paint a beneficial portrait of disability through Stephanie and their relationship is a rich one. One complaint about the film is that it does not involve her enough. Instead, it has a web of sideplots including that of Alain&#8217;s sister and the whole issue of unions that comes up with his work installing surveillance that doesn&#8217;t lead anywhere interesting enough to justify the distraction. It has plenty of interest but just isn&#8217;t tight enough to operate at a top level.</p>
<p>3.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5143/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5143&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/rust-and-bone-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rustandbone.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For when it is not shark week.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Man (1964)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-best-man-1964/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-best-man-1964/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 09:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1964]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some films just seem newer than they are because their grasp of their own era seems too spot on to have been captured without the benefit of hindsight. While the importance of the civil rights issue as a divisive issue within the Democratic Party would be obvious by 1964 (and the subsequent action on the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5140&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5141" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the_best_man.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the_best_man.jpg?w=300&#038;h=198" alt="Not The Best Man" width="300" height="198" class="size-medium wp-image-5141" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not The Best Man</p></div>Some films just seem newer than they are because their grasp of their own era seems too spot on to have been captured without the benefit of hindsight. While the importance of the civil rights issue as a divisive issue within the Democratic Party would be obvious by 1964 (and the subsequent action on the issue the most important of the subsequent 50 years for its political reverberations), there are other aspects about politics that would have seemed less obvious. If the 1960 Presidential Debate firmly placed image front and center in Presidential politics, personality and personal matters have only become more important in subsequent years.</p>
<p>William Russell (Henry Fonda) is the front-runner for the Democratic nomination and is the kind of person many of us claim we want, smart and hoping to remain above the dirty fray of politics. Things are complicated when his top rival, Joe Cantwell (Cliff Robertson) uncovers Russell&#8217;s past bout with mental illness. This is one of those particularly prescient aspects as there is no way Gore Vidal, on whose play the film is based, would know that in eight short years a history of mental illness would actually take a Vice Presidential candidate out of the race.</p>
<p>One place where the film feels of its era, and is well served for it, is being set amid the height of the Cold War with Cantwell&#8217;s McCarthyesque commie-hunting acting as a major indicator of his lack of character. The Cold War operated under a relative peace under the theory of mutually assured destruction. For these political candidates, the fact that everyone has a skeleton in their closet that could prove a political weakness would seem to indicate that a similar policy would be appropriate. While a natural peace or positive campaign would be ideal, perhaps it wouldn&#8217;t be so bad if it were the result of this mutual threat.</p>
<p>The tension as always, is will the instinct of self-preservation win out or will the darker call of vengeance overcome it. While less cinematic and less salacious than the recent House of Cards series, ultimately, The Best Man shares the appeal of enjoying the dark arts that we imagine lie beneath our political system. If the state of the media in the country proves anything, it is that, while we may talk up noble values, we can&#8217;t help but chase the drama.</p>
<p>Recent times are certainly not rid of the threat of political death based on personal issues, but it does seem to have grown less toxic. After the past few presidents, clearly former drug use has gone off the table and even infidelity has lost some of its bite. Though these things are generally overrated, one of the defining hits of the past election was Romney&#8217;s comment on the 47%, something that speaks directly toward important matters of policy and not as much about personal character. Perhaps The Best Man is more a story of the past than it seems, but it is one that remains thoroughly enjoyable.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5140/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5140/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5140&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-best-man-1964/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the_best_man.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Not The Best Man</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
