<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
	<atom:link href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Film Blogging Gone Gonzo</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 14:20:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>The Movie Review Warehouse</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="The Movie Review Warehouse" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Breakers (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/spring-breakers-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/spring-breakers-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 14:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5153</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For a film that opens with a high-energy glimpse of spring break beaches that could be pulled from a Girls Gone Wild video, the interesting thing about Spring Breakers is that a much more voyeuristic scene happens not too much later as a group of four college friends, Faith (Selena Gomez), Candy (Vanessa Hudgens), Brit [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5153&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5154" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbreakers.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbreakers.jpg?w=630" alt="All rise!"   class="size-full wp-image-5154" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">All rise!</p></div>For a film that opens with a high-energy glimpse of spring break beaches that could be pulled from a Girls Gone Wild video, the interesting thing about Spring Breakers is that a much more voyeuristic scene happens not too much later as a group of four college friends, Faith (Selena Gomez), Candy (Vanessa Hudgens), Brit (Ashley Benson) and Cotty (Rachel Korine) just hang out in a casual way in their dorm as presumably girls of that age will do when boys aren&#8217;t around. It is not the slumber party of male fantasy but a normal hang-out still seen through a male gaze. In a film full of nudity and exploitation, having this scene seem the greatest violation of privacy is pretty powerful, after all, once the girls head off for spring break in Florida, it all seems so much less private and much more performative. In the age of social media, such debauchery becomes public and the only thing kept in reserve is wholesomeness.</p>
<p>With Disney alums in the cast, Spring Breakers is sure to be a film to shock the senses of many theatregoers, but even having seen Korine films before, it is hard not to be a bit overwhelmed by the energy of the first act of the film. It is the exhilaration of youth with that hedonistic sense of invincibility. But like youth or like the drugged high, this energy can&#8217;t last. It would be easy to punish the film for dragging into the second act if it didn&#8217;t make so much thematic sense. This section is the hangover of the first as the ache builds up inside, convincing you that you both want to never experience that again or else need it to return to that right away.</p>
<p>The choice one makes in response to this feeling is a critical one as we see in the film that those who refuse to get older and leave behind this hedonism become increasingly trapped by it, none more so than Alien (James Franco), a white rapper/gangster who takes the girls in. Though not out of place with the aggressive tone of the film, Franco does seem the film&#8217;s biggest weak point as his character is just too much of a type and doesn&#8217;t really exude a charm or appeal that would believably draw the girls in like he does.</p>
<p>Spring Breakers is ultimately a film that makes you ask questions of yourself. While I never got involved in &#8220;spring break&#8221; style craziness, as I recently crossed the threshold into my 30s I&#8217;ve been forced to think a bit about my own short-cuts to sensations of happiness and consider what can provide less illusory contentment. I&#8217;m still not sure what that answer is so for now I think I&#8217;ll hydrate and take an aspirin, may I never feel like this again</p>
<p>4.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5153/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5153/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5153&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/spring-breakers-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbreakers.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">All rise!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hunchback of Notre Dame II (2002)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame-ii-2002/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame-ii-2002/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 20:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2002]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[H]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5149</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whether born of a purist or nostalgic outrage, the parade of direct to video sequels to Disney&#8217;s biggest animated films can&#8217;t avoid feeling a bit shameful. Yet, the two Aladdin sequels, Return of Jafar and Aladdin and the King of Thieves were both remarkably solid animated films. Well, it turns out that having One Thousand [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5149&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5151" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hunchbackii.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hunchbackii.jpg?w=300&#038;h=206" alt="A saturday cartoon outing." width="300" height="206" class="size-medium wp-image-5151" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A saturday cartoon outing.</p></div>Whether born of a purist or nostalgic outrage, the parade of direct to video sequels to Disney&#8217;s biggest animated films can&#8217;t avoid feeling a bit shameful. Yet, the two Aladdin sequels, Return of Jafar and Aladdin and the King of Thieves were both remarkably solid animated films. Well, it turns out that having One Thousand and One Arabian nights gives you better source material to adapt because lacking Victor Hugo coming back from the grave to extend his original story, the writers involved with making a sequel to Hunchback of Notre Dame didn&#8217;t have any bright new ideas.</p>
<p>One of the powerful aspects for me in watching Hunchback (still my favorite Disney film) is that it doesn&#8217;t end with the cliche of the main character getting the girl. It tips its hand toward realism, acknowledging that Quasimodo simply wasn&#8217;t going to get Esmerelda, no matter his heroism, that the handsome co-hero was going to be the one to appeal to her. But for the sequel, the entire film&#8217;s story is pretty much based on a &#8220;this time it&#8217;ll happen&#8221; logic as Quasimodo meets Madellaine (Jennifer Love Hewitt), a woman in town with a traveling carnival headed by the obviously evil Sarousch (Michael McKean).</p>
<p>There is a vague promise in the comparison between Madellaine&#8217;s plight here and Quasi&#8217;s in the first film. Much like he feels a sense of duty to Frollo in the belief he saved his life, Madellaine feels in the debt to Sarousch and strains against this sense of obligation when seeing his immorality. Similarly, as Quasi struggled against the imposed isolation of his gnarled body, Madellaine feels diminished in her gendered role of just looking pretty for the magic show, wishing to be a tightrope walker instead. All of this seems really interesting but is only marginally delved into, with the bulk of the hour runtime spent on petty romance.</p>
<p>The film is a definite budget affair in terms of the animation, an obvious step back from the original. However, it does return basically the entire vocal cast of the original which is an impressive enough feat. Still, lacking a compelling story and no really memorable songs, it just feels a hollow echo that makes it fitting as basically a special feature attached to the new Blu-ray version of the main feature.</p>
<p>2/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5149/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5149/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5149&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/the-hunchback-of-notre-dame-ii-2002/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hunchbackii.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A saturday cartoon outing.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Young Girls of Rochefort (1967)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/the-young-girls-of-rochefort-1967/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/the-young-girls-of-rochefort-1967/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 20:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Y]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1967]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musical]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5147</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If there is a more inane story to ever be stretched past two hours than The Young Girls of Rochefort, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve seen it. As film efficiency goes, this was a bad start as it is at least ten minutes before there&#8217;s any meaningful dialogue/lyrics, being content as it is with frivolous dancing [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5147&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If there is a more inane story to ever be stretched past two hours than The Young Girls of Rochefort, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve seen it. As film efficiency goes, this was a bad start as it is at least ten minutes before there&#8217;s any meaningful dialogue/lyrics, being content as it is with frivolous dancing with little context, something that would end up taking up closer to a half hour of the runtime when all is said and done.</p>
<p>Upon introducing us to the characters, from the twins Delphine and Solange (Catherine Deneuve and Francoise Dorleac) to the carnival guys Etienne and Bill down to the American Andy Miller (Gene Kelly), it hardly gets more contextualized as the film is so taken with its fluffy song and dance that no character operates beyond a very superficial level of motivation and emotion. People want love and the twins in particular want to get out of the small town and do big things. These are well worn themes but usually they are at least developed in a way that seems personalized. The problem here is that the film puts so little effort into having a story and brings in too many characters to make any of them matter.</p>
<p>It might compensate for this to some degree if the songs and dance were absolutely sparkling, but even there it seems lackluster. Admittedly, foreign language musicals are a rather steep hurdle. I liked Resnais&#8217; Not On The Lips but otherwise I&#8217;d be hard pressed to think of a musical I&#8217;ve fully appreciated in a foreign language. Not only is it a challenge to keep up on subtitles during the songs, it just makes it harder for the song to be catchy through translation (and notably Not On The Lips succeeded on story, not music). Demy&#8217;s own Umbrellas of Cherbourg provided much more story and style to survive this handicap. Rochefort just doesn&#8217;t offer anything to get off the mark.</p>
<p>1/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5147/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5147/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5147&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/the-young-girls-of-rochefort-1967/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rust and Bone (2012)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/rust-and-bone-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/rust-and-bone-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 17:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In film circles it is popular to talk about auteur directors, whose stylistic or thematic fingerprints are left on all of their projects. In Rust and Bone, I see less of my previous experience with director Jacques Audiard, A Prophet, and more of my previous experience with actor Matthias Schoenaerts, Bullhead. We talk about range [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5143&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5145" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rustandbone.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rustandbone.jpg?w=630" alt="For when it is not shark week."   class="size-full wp-image-5145" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">For when it is not shark week.</p></div>In film circles it is popular to talk about auteur directors, whose stylistic or thematic fingerprints are left on all of their projects. In Rust and Bone, I see less of my previous experience with director Jacques Audiard, A Prophet, and more of my previous experience with actor Matthias Schoenaerts, Bullhead. We talk about range when it comes to actors but sometimes there is something in an actor that makes it much more productive to explore different angles of similar characters. With Alain, as with his character in Bullhead, Schoenaerts brooding physical form lends itself to a consideration of masculinity.</p>
<p>Stuck on the margins of society with a young son, Alain seems completely unsuited to being a parent. After all, his sources of income; as a bouncer, as an underground kickboxer and helping to install illicit surveillance for employers to monitor employees, are both marginal and tend to keep him away at various hours. They do fit his masculinity, as does his casual flings. Still, we get a bit more of a look into his persona when he meets Stephanie (Marion Cotillard) while working as a bouncer.</p>
<p>I believe it is no spoiler to say that Stephanie, an orca trainer at a Sea World like park, suffers an accident that renders her handicapped. In dealing with this change to her life, Alain&#8217;s masculinity actually proves ideal in a number of ways, bringing them closer, yet the final act is one revealing the limits of this singular approach.</p>
<p>While this is largely Alain&#8217;s story, it does paint a beneficial portrait of disability through Stephanie and their relationship is a rich one. One complaint about the film is that it does not involve her enough. Instead, it has a web of sideplots including that of Alain&#8217;s sister and the whole issue of unions that comes up with his work installing surveillance that doesn&#8217;t lead anywhere interesting enough to justify the distraction. It has plenty of interest but just isn&#8217;t tight enough to operate at a top level.</p>
<p>3.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5143/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5143&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/rust-and-bone-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rustandbone.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For when it is not shark week.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Man (1964)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-best-man-1964/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-best-man-1964/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 09:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1964]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[4/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drama]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some films just seem newer than they are because their grasp of their own era seems too spot on to have been captured without the benefit of hindsight. While the importance of the civil rights issue as a divisive issue within the Democratic Party would be obvious by 1964 (and the subsequent action on the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5140&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5141" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the_best_man.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the_best_man.jpg?w=300&#038;h=198" alt="Not The Best Man" width="300" height="198" class="size-medium wp-image-5141" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not The Best Man</p></div>Some films just seem newer than they are because their grasp of their own era seems too spot on to have been captured without the benefit of hindsight. While the importance of the civil rights issue as a divisive issue within the Democratic Party would be obvious by 1964 (and the subsequent action on the issue the most important of the subsequent 50 years for its political reverberations), there are other aspects about politics that would have seemed less obvious. If the 1960 Presidential Debate firmly placed image front and center in Presidential politics, personality and personal matters have only become more important in subsequent years.</p>
<p>William Russell (Henry Fonda) is the front-runner for the Democratic nomination and is the kind of person many of us claim we want, smart and hoping to remain above the dirty fray of politics. Things are complicated when his top rival, Joe Cantwell (Cliff Robertson) uncovers Russell&#8217;s past bout with mental illness. This is one of those particularly prescient aspects as there is no way Gore Vidal, on whose play the film is based, would know that in eight short years a history of mental illness would actually take a Vice Presidential candidate out of the race.</p>
<p>One place where the film feels of its era, and is well served for it, is being set amid the height of the Cold War with Cantwell&#8217;s McCarthyesque commie-hunting acting as a major indicator of his lack of character. The Cold War operated under a relative peace under the theory of mutually assured destruction. For these political candidates, the fact that everyone has a skeleton in their closet that could prove a political weakness would seem to indicate that a similar policy would be appropriate. While a natural peace or positive campaign would be ideal, perhaps it wouldn&#8217;t be so bad if it were the result of this mutual threat.</p>
<p>The tension as always, is will the instinct of self-preservation win out or will the darker call of vengeance overcome it. While less cinematic and less salacious than the recent House of Cards series, ultimately, The Best Man shares the appeal of enjoying the dark arts that we imagine lie beneath our political system. If the state of the media in the country proves anything, it is that, while we may talk up noble values, we can&#8217;t help but chase the drama.</p>
<p>Recent times are certainly not rid of the threat of political death based on personal issues, but it does seem to have grown less toxic. After the past few presidents, clearly former drug use has gone off the table and even infidelity has lost some of its bite. Though these things are generally overrated, one of the defining hits of the past election was Romney&#8217;s comment on the 47%, something that speaks directly toward important matters of policy and not as much about personal character. Perhaps The Best Man is more a story of the past than it seems, but it is one that remains thoroughly enjoyable.</p>
<p>4/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5140/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5140/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5140&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-best-man-1964/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the_best_man.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Not The Best Man</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lovers on the Bridge (1991)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/the-lovers-on-the-bridge-1991/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/the-lovers-on-the-bridge-1991/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1991]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5138</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This film is a nasty piece of work. It is one of those things where the ending, in the context of the actions taken by characters in the film, is vile in its happiness. Alex (Denis Lavant) is a homeless addict and street performer with seemingly no aim until Michele (Juliette Binoche) shows up on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5138&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This film is a nasty piece of work. It is one of those things where the ending, in the context of the actions taken by characters in the film, is vile in its happiness. Alex (Denis Lavant) is a homeless addict and street performer with seemingly no aim until Michele (Juliette Binoche) shows up on his bridge. It&#8217;s not entirely clear what has brought her so low though her pressing concern is an eye disease threatening to make her go blind. Because he&#8217;s our lead and she&#8217;s the only woman around, naturally there is a romance…only Alex is legit crazy and worried she&#8217;ll move on.</p>
<p>This does seem of a kind with Holy Motors, Carax&#8217;s recent film. This may have a slightly more traditional story, but it is still told in a fairly chaotic way, patching together bizarre scenes that defy belief in many cases. I have to say that watching this I suddenly felt a greater respect for Holy Motors because for all its problems, it had style and ambition that this sorely lacks. Instead, it seems to try to get by on simply being shocking and gritty.</p>
<p>1/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5138/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5138/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5138&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/the-lovers-on-the-bridge-1991/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kill List (2011)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/16/kill-list-2011/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/16/kill-list-2011/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 17:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[K]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5135</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While predictability is, rightly or wrongly, almost always claim as a negative thing, surprise is a more mercurial characteristic. A good surprise can give a jolt to keep you in a film or to consider it long after it ends but a bad surprise can derail a film&#8217;s energy. Kill List is a film with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5135&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5136" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kill-list.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kill-list.jpg?w=300&#038;h=134" alt="Tunnels are inherently scary." width="300" height="134" class="size-medium wp-image-5136" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tunnels are inherently scary.</p></div>While predictability is, rightly or wrongly, almost always claim as a negative thing, surprise is a more mercurial characteristic. A good surprise can give a jolt to keep you in a film or to consider it long after it ends but a bad surprise can derail a film&#8217;s energy. Kill List is a film with more than a few surprises up its sleeves but increasingly they don&#8217;t pan out.</p>
<p>The film opens looking like one of those awkward relationship dramas where you just want the couple to break up so you don&#8217;t have to simmer in its failure, though as details emerge about Jay (Neil Maskell) and Shel (MyAnna Buring), the source of the tension gains depth; maybe this is about the economy or, upon learning Jay had served in Iraq, maybe this is some sort of PTSD thing. Throw in Jay&#8217;s friend Gal (Michael Smiley) with a mysterious job offer and Gal&#8217;s curious girlfriend and there are a lot of pieces suddenly in play. From there the film takes at least two more major turns, mixing up both genre and one&#8217;s understanding of the characters and for most of this time it is really engaging. There&#8217;s enough mystery to be on the edge of your seat and the friendship of Jay and Gal is strong enough to be enjoyable to watch when nothing more intense is happening.</p>
<p>The final main turn though seems a step too far. If I hadn&#8217;t known going into this that it was classified as a horror film, I would have been completely taken out. Even then, it stands at such a stark contrast that it almost renders what had seemed a somewhat serious drama completely absurd. Still, as annoying as the TI West ending was, at least the majority of the film leading up to it was a good watch, unlike a TI West film. This Ben Wheatley kid might just have some potential.</p>
<p>3/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5135/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5135&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/16/kill-list-2011/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kill-list.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tunnels are inherently scary.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oz: The Great and Powerful (2013)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/oz-the-great-and-powerful-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/oz-the-great-and-powerful-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 17:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[O]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5132</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fake it &#8217;til you make it. For Oscar, he can&#8217;t help that he doesn&#8217;t have magical powers, but how he answers the call of Oz is up to him. Does he let his nature define him or does he do what he can to be what is expected of him. Oz starts strong with Oscar [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5132&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5133" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oz.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oz.jpg?w=630" alt="Goodness is all blondes and rainbows."   class="size-full wp-image-5133" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Goodness is all blondes and rainbows.</p></div>Fake it &#8217;til you make it. For Oscar, he can&#8217;t help that he doesn&#8217;t have magical powers, but how he answers the call of Oz is up to him. Does he let his nature define him or does he do what he can to be what is expected of him.</p>
<p>Oz starts strong with Oscar (James Franco) existing as a simple trickster (though aren&#8217;t al magicians, we have no right to feel conned) but aches for something more. Given this, his struggles to accept the role bestowed upon him in Oz grows a bit tired in an overlong film. Still, there are a few elegant moments of &#8220;magic,&#8221; where the proof is the result, not the means. The dual role for Joey King represents this best. Theodora (Mila Kunis) holds potential for an interesting critique of women in fairy tales but instead ends up just being a woman in a fairy tale. It is the lost opportunities of greatness that sting here.</p>
<p>The film is at its best when exploring this question of what magic is and at its worst when indulging the broader moments involving wicked witches being really wicked and Zach Braff being Braffian (and I say this as a huge fan of both Garden State and Scrubs). At one moment, there&#8217;s this marvelous world of wonder, the next an overly frantic camera move or cut makes you feel like merely an observer. These are the moments that take me out of the magic and make me remember the mechanics behind the camera. I have no right to feel conned by this, but I so wanted to believe.</p>
<p>3/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5132/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5132/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5132&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/oz-the-great-and-powerful-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/oz.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Goodness is all blondes and rainbows.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diary of a Lost Girl (1929)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/diary-of-a-lost-girl-1929/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/diary-of-a-lost-girl-1929/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 14:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1929]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5130</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There have been plenty of tales of fallen women in cinema where, out of some unfortunate twist that has left a woman in dire straights, she falls to the place of the outcast, survival overriding social norms. With Diary of a Lost Girl, G.W. Pabst follows in the footsteps of the work of Lois Weber [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5130&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There have been plenty of tales of fallen women in cinema where, out of some unfortunate twist that has left a woman in dire straights, she falls to the place of the outcast, survival overriding social norms. With Diary of a Lost Girl, G.W. Pabst follows in the footsteps of the work of Lois Weber in pairing what would become a fairly typical story with hard hitting social commentary, showing some capacity for shocking the social norms in the process.</p>
<p>Amidst witnessing a tragedy involving their housekeeper, a victim of patriarchy in her own right, Thymian (Louise Brooks) is faced by the harsh hand of a society that treats women with little respect. Old though the film may be, these issues are no artifact of a bygone era as the rape at the start holds echoes of Steubenville and the pressure to marry the father of the subsequent child is still active in many Islamic countries. A victim already, by not playing along she is further victimized and sent down a path to ruin.</p>
<p>Now, one thing that could be offered as a complaint and contrasts with a lot of these tales is that this film is not excessively gloomy, for all its tragedy. There are moments of happiness that are allowed through, including a friendship with another &#8220;lost girl.&#8221; Maybe these moments unrealistically soften the blow but they don&#8217;t soften the social message and I&#8217;m nothing if not a sucker for a well made message film.</p>
<p>5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5130/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5130&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/diary-of-a-lost-girl-1929/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rosetta (1999)</title>
		<link>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/rosetta-1999/</link>
		<comments>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/rosetta-1999/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 21:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bondo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1999]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3/5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/?p=5126</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For those directors that I just haven&#8217;t found a way to connect with, even though they have received much acclaim elsewhere, there is one final test I attempt before deciding they just aren&#8217;t my thing. If their filmography allows it, I search for a female coming-of-age tale. I figure if their work cannot succeed in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5126&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_5128" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rosetta.jpg"><img src="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rosetta.jpg?w=300&#038;h=169" alt="Respect and fear a girl who chugs." width="300" height="169" class="size-medium wp-image-5128" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Respect and fear a girl who chugs.</p></div>For those directors that I just haven&#8217;t found a way to connect with, even though they have received much acclaim elsewhere, there is one final test I attempt before deciding they just aren&#8217;t my thing. If their filmography allows it, I search for a female coming-of-age tale. I figure if their work cannot succeed in this genre, one that I generally respond favorably to, there really isn&#8217;t much hope. After three experiences with the Dardennes, ranging from tepid to strong dislike, it was time to call the question and watch Rosetta, the story of an 18 year old dealing with trying circumstances.</p>
<p>Admittedly, there isn&#8217;t that much separating Rosetta from the other three films, each of which had as one of the primary characters a teen or young adult, living in economic distress, making often poor or unsympathetic decisions. Early on, Rosetta (Emilie Dequenne) works hard to lose our support, responding to losing her job with not just sadness or even anger but aggression. Her plight may not be fair, but her response is clearly self-sabotage.</p>
<p>One thing that works better here to ground our understanding of Rosetta&#8217;s decisions is we are shown her home conditions, an alcoholic mother that too often plays the dependent child to Rosetta&#8217;s relative level of responsibility. The other films tended to leave these aspects much more offscreen to their detriment. Watching her interaction with her mother and the toll that takes does more to explain Rosetta&#8217;s tiredness and lack of patience to the outside world. Also explaining the tiredness may be how much Rosetta runs around in this film. I got a bit tired just watching as she darted from place to place, crossing roads, cutting through forests, with a shaky cam following her, often at close range.</p>
<p>While much of Rosetta did work better than the films I&#8217;d seen previously from the Dardennes, it is held back from real success by another trademark aspect, lack of real resolution. The film shows a slice of a life but ultimately is quite ambiguous and denies you a sense of true development. I want these experiences to mean something to Rosetta but it isn&#8217;t entirely clear that a sequel would involve a changed character.</p>
<p>3.5/5</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5126/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/5126/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com&#038;blog=28829988&#038;post=5126&#038;subd=moviereviewwarehouse&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviereviewwarehouse.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/rosetta-1999/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68653a214870a39ca10cfb2a6be807c7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bondo112</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviereviewwarehouse.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rosetta.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Respect and fear a girl who chugs.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
