<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Gathering In Light | Re-Interpretating Quaker Faith in Today's World</title>
	
	<link>http://gatheringinlight.com</link>
	<description>Re-Interpretating Quaker Faith in Today's World</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:41:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/GatheringInLight" /><feedburner:info uri="gatheringinlight" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><geo:lat>34.114558</geo:lat><geo:long>-118.192333</geo:long><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/</creativeCommons:license><image><link>http://gatheringinlight.com</link><url>http://www.feedburner.com/fb/images/pub/fb_pwrd.gif</url><title>Gathering in Light</title></image><feedburner:emailServiceId>GatheringInLight</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Revelation 1: From Bafflement to Wonder</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/vKC_Pbg6Chs/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/04/14/revelation-1-from-bafflement-to-wonder/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 22:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4565</guid>
		<description>Bafflement During the retreat I was on last weekend with other young leaders led by Parker Palmer and Marcy Jackson, Parker mentioned that he never writes books about things he knows, he only writes on things that baffle him. You know the difference? You never google the stuff you are sure of, it&amp;#8217;s only the [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Screen-Shot-2013-04-14-at-9.40.09-AM.png"><img src="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Screen-Shot-2013-04-14-at-9.40.09-AM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2013-04-14 at 9.40.09 AM" width="575" height="616" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4567" /></a></p>
<h1>Bafflement</h1>
<p>During the retreat I was on last weekend with other young leaders led by Parker Palmer and Marcy Jackson, Parker mentioned that he never writes books about things he knows, he only writes on things that <strong>baffle</strong> him.</p>
<p>You know the difference?</p>
<p>You never google the stuff you are sure of, it&#8217;s only the stuff where there is a little bit of a question or uncertainty that prompts you to look something up. But it&#8217;s more than that too: I think he means that those things that come easy for you. The things that you could do in your sleep. Aren&#8217;t they often the things that have little life in them? The easy stuff doesn&#8217;t really energize us.</p>
<p><strong>It&#8217;s the challenging stuff</strong> that wakes you up and leaves us laying in bed all night mulling them over. Those things that baffle you, that confuse you, that you can&#8217;t quite get a grip on, there&#8217;s life in that. It might sometimes feel <strong>stressful</strong>, it might not always be clear the <strong>solution</strong>, but I have found at least for myself that it is usually in this bafflement that I come alive.</p>
<p><span id="more-4565"></span></p>
<p>Here are some other words for baffle: puzzle, bewilder, mystify, bemuse, confuse, confound, disconcert; informal flummox, faze, stump, make someone scratch their head, be all Greek to, floor, discombobulate.</p>
<p>We need things that baffle us and in our spiritual lives especially. This is why the focus of the messages over the next two months is going to be <strong>The book of Revelation.</strong></p>
<p>In fact many of the words for baffle above are the same words we might use for Revelation.</p>
<p>Friedrich <strong>Nietzsche</strong> considered Revelation to be &#8220;the most rabid outburst of vindictiveness in all recorded history.&#8221;</p>
<p>And another person has called it a &#8220;script for a horror movie.&#8221;</p>
<p>There is no other book of the Bible that baffles me more than Revelation. Even thought I have been studying the bible academically and as a minister since 1997, a lot of this baffles me still and yet this is part of what I love so much about it.</p>
<p>And so of course, after hearing Parker Palmer talk about the importance of bafflement I knew right away that this was the direction we were supposed to take.</p>
<p>I am convinced &#8211; and I hope to convince you &#8211; that the Bible is not a book to use or to extrapolate information out of but <strong>rather a book that is meant to help us listen to God</strong>.</p>
<p>Revelation is of course a perfect test case for bafflement &#8211; what if instead of avoiding what challenges us we met the challenge with imagination and curiosity? I think that by reflecting and listening to these texts over the next few weeks we will be helped in our listening to God and in our own relationship to scripture.</p>
<h1>We were not the intended audience of Revelation</h1>
<p>So the first observation I want to make about the book of revelation is very simple: it wasn&#8217;t written first and foremost for you and me. It&#8217;s not our book. It&#8217;s not meant to predict the future. It doesn&#8217;t represent our world. At least not at first. And we have a lot of work to do if we are to get to the bottom of what is going on in this book.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Read 1:3-8: “Blessed is the one who reads aloud the words of the prophecy, and blessed are those who hear and who keep what is written in it; for the time is near. John to the seven churches that are in Asia…”
</p></blockquote>
<p>&#8220;We were not the intended audience of Revelation&#8221; as Eric Barreto, a NT professor, puts it.</p>
<p>This is to say that when John was imprisoned on the island of Patmos and had this divinely inspired day dream, what he wrote down was first and foremost for the churches he was a pastor of in Asia Minor.</p>
<p>The biblical text is always first and foremost a localized, historical work. The bible teaches us that God always speaks directly to the people where they are at, what they are facing, their fears and their celebrations.</p>
<p><a href="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/7397929352_9a556dd03b_o.jpg"><img src="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/7397929352_9a556dd03b_o.jpg" alt="7397929352_9a556dd03b_o" width="612" height="612" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4569" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p>
  Where you live, where you pray is essential to who God is and reveals himself to be (E. Peterson).
</p></blockquote>
<p>We have often treated the <strong>Revelation as a code</strong> that is to be broken as though it were a math formula to solve our problems. This matches this, that matches that and whallah <strong>Jimmy Carter</strong> is the Anti-Christ.</p>
<p>We should not be tricked into this way of reading any of the bible &#8211; as though it holds a secret or that it is detached from the people who it was written for (Luke 12:2). As much as I love math &#8211; Faith is not a math formula. <strong>As we read through these passages let me encourage you to avoid the revelation as code approach.</strong></p>
<p>And yet we have to recognize that when we read it not only are we are not the intended audience for this book but that its meanings are not easy to get at.</p>
<p>One of my professors in seminary liked to talk about Revelation as a kind of <strong>political cartoon</strong>. Until we are well-acquainted with the people and the times it was written to the joke will be lost on us (Reading Facebook in 2000 years).</p>
<p>Of central importance is knowing that John wrote a letter from prison to a <strong>several tiny, powerless communities</strong>, that were minorities in their culture and were being harassed and even killed by the powers of empire. Much to the contrary of what we have often been taught, Revelation&#8217;s sympathies lie with the marginalized and the persecuted within the dominant Roman empire (181). The original hearers of the Revelation were not unlike the Hebrew people in Exodus, or early Anabaptists in Germany, or Early Quakers in England, or African-Americans prior to emancipation and civil rights, and we could go on…</p>
<p>John&#8217;s letter is similar to <strong>Martin Luther King&#8217;s Letter from Birmingham prison</strong>, smuggled out on napkins, aimed to encourage a minority people to not give up hope in the struggle for peace through nonviolence. In fact, that is the basic overall message of Revelation.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t give up, do not fight back, follow the way of the slaughtered lamb.</p>
<p>For (NT Scholar) <strong>Elizabeth Schussler Fiorenza</strong> says:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Something very strange happens when happens when this text is appropriated by readers in a comfortable, powerful, majority community: it becomes a gold mine for paranoid fantasies and for those who want to preach revenge and destruction.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Feeling adequately baffled yet?</p>
<p>One lesson I am able to take away from this</p>
<blockquote><p>
  We have to be careful that we don&#8217;t confuse reading the bible with understanding the bible. We have to be careful how we interpret what these words say and who we think they apply to. We have to be <strong>extra cautious</strong> about assuming that what we read on face-value has direct correlations to society today.</p>
<p>  So the question for us is what did the original hearers hear and how does this work in the community of believers of which we are a part?
</p></blockquote>
<h1>Imagination</h1>
<p>In fact, Revelation, if we allow it, can sharpen and enliven our imaginations.</p>
<p>John begins by saying &#8220;I was in the Spirit on the Lord&#8217;s day,&#8221; which to me sounds a lot like when we talk about being fully yielded to God&#8217;s spirit, fully aligned within our inner and outer selves so that we are able to listen and hear God&#8217;s word to us?</p>
<p>Revelation revels God&#8217;s concern for his people who are crushed and marginalized by those in power. It shows who God sides with.</p>
<p>It is a letter of hope and courage to a people whose way of life and understanding of God was the cause of cruelty, imprisonment, and hatred.</p>
<p>It is a letter meant to spark the imagination of nonviolent resistance. The central image that forms the Christian imagination is the &#8220;Lamb that was slain,&#8221; the lamb who did not fight back, who was slain, and who God honored as the innocent victim. This is a total reversal from humanity&#8217;s constant effort to project on and blame the scapegoat.</p>
<p>These are the words being smuggled on napkins to small bands of Christians taking on a force more powerful and terrifying than anything they could imagine.</p>
<p>They call its readers to be in solidarity with one another no matter how distressing the situation becomes. And to know that the time of Jesus present with us is at hand.</p>
<p>Eugene Peterson says this:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  I do not read the Revelation to get additional information about the life of faith in Christ. I have read it all before in the law and prophet, in gospel and epistle. Everything in the Revelation can be found in the previous sixty-five books of the Bible. The Revelation adds nothing of substance to what we already know. The truth of the gospel is already complete, revealed in Christ. There is nothing new to say on the subject. But there is a new way to say it. I read the Revelation not to get more information but to revive my imagination (xii-xii). It is not a question of what does this mean, but rather how does this work in our community of believers? It is not a code to be broken but a book meant to evoke our wonder (xiii).
</p></blockquote>
<p>Revelation teaches us that the remedy for Bafflement is wonder. I hope that you will allow this time of reflecting on Revelation to evoke wonder in you and to help shape your imagination for the ways in which God can move and change us.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vKC_Pbg6Chs:3OZ-cVrCzPA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vKC_Pbg6Chs:3OZ-cVrCzPA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vKC_Pbg6Chs:3OZ-cVrCzPA:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=vKC_Pbg6Chs:3OZ-cVrCzPA:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vKC_Pbg6Chs:3OZ-cVrCzPA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/vKC_Pbg6Chs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/04/14/revelation-1-from-bafflement-to-wonder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/04/14/revelation-1-from-bafflement-to-wonder/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Into the Tomb Luke (23:50-24:12)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/FurCxcDh-rw/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/04/01/into-the-tomb-luke-2350-2412/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 16:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sermons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4560</guid>
		<description>Unless we are dead we are on a journey. Our journeys might be more inward focused at the moment, they might be more about outward changes, but either way life is filled with journeys. But the best kind of journeys are the ones that cost us something: where risk is involved, where we are stretched [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/USA_LA.png"><img src="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/USA_LA.png" alt="From Ohio to LA" width="1024" height="642" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4562" /></a></p>
<p>Unless we are dead we are on a journey. Our journeys might be more inward focused at the moment, they might be more about outward changes, but either way life is filled with journeys.</p>
<p>But the best kind of journeys are the ones that cost us something: where risk is involved, where we are stretched to or beyond our capacity, where we are made alive in the the process of change.</p>
<p>In August 2003 Emily and I packed had one of these life-changing journeys when we moved from Ohio to someplace called Pasadena where there is a little old lady who owns a new shiny red Super Stock Dodge.</p>
<p><span id="more-4560"></span></p>
<p>See we got married in Ohio in 2001 and by 2003 we were ready for change. Emily had finished a degree in middle-childhood education &#8211; she was drawn to teach english to poor kids in public school. I was youth pastoring at a Friends church and began feeling the itch to get my masters degree.</p>
<p>We labored with this decision for at least a year. We prayed. <strong>We talked to every sage we knew</strong>. We even made honorary sages just so we had more people to talk to about it. We argued. We cried. To be honest, we were afraid. <strong>The thought of such a huge risk with so few resources and no friends or connections on the other side of the country was both exhilarating and terrifying</strong>.</p>
<p>What would it be like to move across the country from the <strong>only home I&#8217;d ever known</strong>? (I had up until that point always lived within a 25 mile radius of where I was born in Canton Ohio.) <strong>Would we fail?</strong> Would we make friends? What would living in So.Cal be like? <strong>Could Emily find a job?</strong> Looking out across the map of the United States we were filled with equal amounts of hope and fear of the unknown.</p>
<p>Should we take the safe route or take the leap into the unknown?</p>
<p>There were good reasons to stay and good reasons to go, there were challenges with both. But I have to say that part of our decision what that when I thought about staying <strong>I felt like something in me would die if we did that</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>So that August we threw</strong> the dice and took a gamble, packed up the U-haul and hoped that it would meet us where we were headed to. Emily and I set out on a 5-day across the US in our little Mitsubishi Sedan.</p>
<p>Driving across <strong>Kansas</strong> I wasn&#8217;t sure we&#8217;d make the trip. When we got to the <strong>Rockies</strong> I felt we&#8217;d finally seen where God resides. And driving through <strong>Arizona</strong> and Nevada we literally jammed cardboard in the windows to block the August Sun.</p>
<p>I remember when the 210 freeway &#8211; the main highway through Pasadena &#8211; opened up into a 6 lane highway (on each side). We had arrived, but where on earth had we come to? What had we done?</p>
<p>That summer we both experienced &#8220;<strong>little deaths</strong>&#8221; and in the following 6 years of our life together in So. Cal. we experienced an aliveness and new birth we&#8217;d never felt. But it started with a leap into the darkness, a huge risk, and the willingness to cross a threshold that had terrified both of us.</p>
<p>It reminds me of what Howard Thurman says:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  “Don’t ask yourself what the world needs, ask yourself what makes you come alive, and then go do it. Because what the world needs is people who have come alive.” –Howard Thurman
</p></blockquote>
<p>By staking out into the unknown, <strong>passing through what felt like a kind of death not only drew us closer to one another, it drew us closer to Jesus</strong>. As we crossed over a threshold of death to our old lives I am helped in understand the meaning of the cross and the empty tomb on Easter morning.</p>
<h1>Passing through the Cross</h1>
<p>Jesus&#8217; death on the cross has held different meanings for Christians throughout history. Sometimes we stress the outward meaning &#8212; the liberation from oppressive structures, the defeating of death, the victory of nonviolence. Sometime we emphasize the inward &#8212; the freedom from sin and brokenness, the call to discipleship, forgiveness and reconciliation with God and one another.</p>
<p>If I were to ask all of you &#8220;what is the meaning of the cross?&#8221; I know given our diverse make-up and experiences that we would have many varied and rich ideas about it.</p>
<p>The beauty of the Cross is that our questions and yearnings are met with the vastness and mercy of God&#8217;s love wherever we are at.</p>
<p>In a similar way to our road-trip across the country offered both hope and mystery, the cross holds the tension of both hope and mystery, of both reality and new possibility.</p>
<p>*We can face any journey, no matter how challenging and scary it might be if we accept the cross as a paradigm for our inner and outer lives.</p>
<p><strong>Jesus showed that despite our fears and anxieties related to death, to pass through the experience of the cross is something that we must each do.</strong></p>
<p>Jim Miller put it this way:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  We tend to keep the cross over there at a safe distance, but we need to be put on the cross.
</p></blockquote>
<p>*The truth of the cross is that there is life on the other side of the journey, even when death and change are a part it and that is where God wants to take us.</p>
<p>Christ&#8217;s experience of the cross is not meant to be &#8220;for us&#8221; <strong>passively</strong> &#8211; like &#8220;thanks chief for taking one for the team&#8221; or &#8220;better him than me.&#8221;</p>
<p>I believe that it is a revealing of the movement towards fullness in God. That we must be put on the cross, everything: our fears, our ego, our broken families, our back stories, our beliefs about religion, our complicity in the systems of the world, our addictions, our self-loathing, all of the things that we cling-to as the old world slips away.</p>
<p>The cross stands for a stripping away of all mediators, all obstacles, everything that stands between you and your neighbor, and you and your savior.</p>
<p><strong>Now we don&#8217;t have to get up on the cross</strong>. If the old world has worked for you, then you may find no need for Jesus to create a new world of possibility.</p>
<p><strong>We don&#8217;t have to get up on the cross</strong> &#8211; the fear it evokes, the facing of our own death of self, and death to what is comfortable, norma, predictable is justifiable.</p>
<p>But if the old world has not worked for you &#8211; then it is time to be put on the cross.</p>
<p>If keeping things the say within your inner and outer self feels like a kind of death and you long for new life &#8211; then it is time to get up on the cross.</p>
<p>If liberation is what you seek then follow Jesus and he will liberate you, but not first without you have to surrender your very life.</p>
<p>Only then can we be broken open into a the hope of resurrection.</p>
<h1>Resurrection Doubt</h1>
<p>[Ill. One part of the story I left out was that I wanted to go to school because I had given up on ministry. I decided to go a different path. But it was while in seminary that Jesus broke me open again and renewed my call to ministry. A result I was not expecting.]</p>
<p>Because Jesus rose from the dead, because he &#8220;came back&#8221; Easter is not about escaping this world and going somewhere else &#8211; it is about constantly called back to the divine present.</p>
<p>Easter is not about avoiding the difficulty and conflict of living life. It is about learning how to die and live anew within this reality. It is about witnessing where God is already at work within the world &#8211; in the places we expect God and and in the places were we may have been running from God.</p>
<p>This is why <strong>the accent mark for the Quaker church is not on the cross, it is on the empty tomb.</strong></p>
<p>The reason we continue to remember Easter is because we can &#8220;cross over&#8221; into a new life of freedom, love and celebration in this life.</p>
<p><strong>But let&#8217;s face it no one expects resurrection! We never do!</strong></p>
<p>If you&#8217;ll notice the first people to witness the resurrection &#8211; in every Gospel story &#8211; suffers from what we might call resurrection doubt. They did not believe their own eyes.</p>
<p>And this is because Resurrection is unbelievable. Or as David Lose puts it,</p>
<blockquote><p>
  &#8220;If It&#8217;s Not Hard to Believe, You&#8217;re Probably Not Paying Attention!&#8221;
</p></blockquote>
<p>And that seems about right.</p>
<p>Even the fact that Jesus told his followers this would happen, they still were confused and thought it was an <strong>&#8220;idle tale.</strong>&#8221;</p>
<p>No one slaps their knee and says &#8220;I knew it! Good one, Jesus.&#8221;</p>
<p>Why is it that we tend to expect the worst, we anticipate the far more pain and the gloomiest endings, when we are told in plain Scripture:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  &#8220;Why do you look for the living among the dead?&#8221;
</p></blockquote>
<p>In other words &#8211; why do you look for the dead ends, when you could be looking for all the ways in which God can transform you through these moments and difficult times?</p>
<p>Even though we know that we can pass through these challenging situations, conflict, and fear &#8211; we too suffer from resurrection doubt.</p>
<p>But if we are to get to the part where we are, as Thurman said, &#8220;people who have come alive,&#8221; we must first be carried into the tomb.</p>
<p>Whether the tomb stands for a move to a wholly new place and experience as it did for Emily and I, or the tomb is a letting go of control, or the tomb is a turning with a new sense of surrender to Jesus, we must, like Jesus, be carried into the tomb.</p>
<p>If we allow ourselves to pass through the cross and enter the tomb with Jesus we too will find ourselves on the other side of hope and freedom. We will find that in Christ all things are possible.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t imagine what our life would be like had we not set out on the journey 10 years ago. I know we would be vastly different people. I know I would not know any of you and that my life would not be as alive as it is now. I know that through it all Christ has walked with us.</p>
<p>This Easter &#8211; Let resurrection break in on you in a new way.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FurCxcDh-rw:C1CyWehcwWY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FurCxcDh-rw:C1CyWehcwWY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FurCxcDh-rw:C1CyWehcwWY:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=FurCxcDh-rw:C1CyWehcwWY:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FurCxcDh-rw:C1CyWehcwWY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/FurCxcDh-rw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/04/01/into-the-tomb-luke-2350-2412/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/04/01/into-the-tomb-luke-2350-2412/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Bread and the last(ing) Supper (Luke 22)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/7hGIpZX1PmU/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/28/bread-and-the-lasting-supper-luke-22/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sermons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4551</guid>
		<description>This is the message I gave on Palm Sunday this year at Camas Friends. A dinner party When I look at this text I see a very unusual and meaningful dinner party. It is nothing like a dinner party at the White House, or what we might find on Downton Abbey &amp;#8211; the mixed company [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the message I gave on Palm Sunday this year at Camas Friends.</p>
<p><img src="http://downtonabbeycooks.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/downstairstreats3e3.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<h1>A dinner party</h1>
<p>When I look at this text I see a very <strong>unusual and meaningful dinner party</strong>. It is nothing like a dinner party at the White House, or what we might find on <strong>Downton Abbey</strong> &#8211; the mixed company of this group wouldn&#8217;t allow for it.</p>
<p>It is far more like the dinners that happen in the servants quarters downstairs.</p>
<p>This is because Jesus&#8217; disciples were a very interesting and strange lot to have over for dinner. Many of whom were not people who would ever be &#8220;invited upstairs&#8221; to have dinner with the Lord of the manor. They were all a part of the poor working class of their day. Others were hungry to follow him but lacked the theological understanding or appropriate degrees. There were at least a couple of whom said they were his friends to his face but loyalty to them was rather fair-weather and flimsy.  Some came from riddled pasts, broken and suffering from what others had done to them or choices they made along the way.</p>
<p><span id="more-4551"></span></p>
<p>In a way it was a lot like Mad Hatter&#8217;s tea party in Alice in Wonderland.</p>
<p>And today we don&#8217;t have to look very far to see people who could make up our own rather mishmashed dinner group.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t have to look very far to find people who aren&#8217;t normally invited over to other people&#8217;s homes for dinner.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t have to look too far to find brokenness and suffering in the world or to find people who have been mistreated, unloved and rejected by others.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t have to look too far to find people in this church and in our community who are poor and only one pay check or two away from being without a home or food to eat.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t have to look too far to find those who hunger and thirst for connection and understanding but who lack the community or confidence to learn.</p>
<p>On the other hand, we do have to look pretty hard to find where such a mix of people are all invited to eat together and be together in the same place today.</p>
<h1>Jesus&#8217; Table Fellowship</h1>
<p>Luke&#8217;s Gospel written was written to <strong>an economically diverse group of people</strong>. Matthew and Mark&#8217;s Gospel are poor people writing for poor people. Luke&#8217;s Gospel is one that is written for a community that had both rich and poor located within it (via Aaron Scott).</p>
<p>This is important to note because, for those of you who know your bible well, know that Bread &#8211; and more generally food &#8211; features significantly in Luke&#8217;s Gospel. In fact, if I was forced to sum up Luke&#8217;s Gospel I might say the word &#8220;<strong>Eat</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p>I had a <strong>professor</strong> in Seminary who said that Jesus&#8217; table fellowship is so essential to the overall theology of Luke that he had always been tempting to write a book called &#8220;Eating your way through the Gospel of Luke.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8216;Who ate with who&#8217; was highly symbolic as it can be still today.  Think of all the hub-bub in the news when the President invites someone to the White House for dinner. Or think of the stress involved in knowing who to invite over for thanksgiving dinner, &#8220;do we invite cousin-so-and-so over, you know they all talk about X during dinner.&#8221;</p>
<p>For religious leaders of Jesus&#8217; time &#8220;table fellowship rules&#8221; were something you took very seriously. It was not only a matter of being potentially ritually unclean, but it was a statement about your social class, and who were <strong>your</strong> people/disciples.</p>
<p>In other words, if you&#8217;re a <strong>popular high school student</strong>, you would never be caught sitting at a table filled with the JR High nerd herd. That would wreck you street-cred instantly.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s about more than just credibility too. In the first century &#8211; if you are a religious leader who eats with <strong>you is counted as an equal</strong>,  or at least someone who is acceptable in your eyes and in the eyes of God.</p>
<p>So when Jesus ate with women, fishermen, prostitutes, tax collectors, soldiers, zealots, people with disabilities, drunkards, pharisees, he broke all kinds of rules.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve watched any <strong>British TV</strong> at all you know that the <strong>chauffeur</strong> is not supposed to sit down and eat with the <strong>Lord</strong> of the manor!</p>
<p>So the problem with Jesus isn&#8217;t that he ate with people, it&#8217;s who he ate with. Jesus invited all the &#8220;wrong&#8221; people to be his dinner guests.</p>
<p>This is because he wanted to redefine who was to be welcomed in the kingdom of God, who was to be cared for, and who would become the central leaders and participants of his growing movement.</p>
<h1>Inward/Outward</h1>
<p>Besides this blending and transgressing of social boundaries that happens when Jesus sits down to eat with &#8211; here are a two others things I think are important to take away from Jesus&#8217; last meal with his disciples that can help frame our own inward/outward journey as a church.</p>
<ol>
<li>Suffering servant: The entire meal is couched both within the context of passover as well as the looming threat of his own arrest and death. Jesus takes on the posture of a suffering servant &#8211; the one who is prepared to die at the hands of the Roman Empire rather than fight his way free, doing so in service to his own people and on their behalf. </li>
</ol>
<blockquote><p>
  “He said to them, “I have eagerly desired to eat this Passover with you before I suffer…” (Luke 22:15)
</p></blockquote>
<p>Passover is a powerful time in Israel&#8217;s history. It was a reminder of God&#8217;s faithfulness in time of deep suffering and darkness. The passover was the promise of liberation and rescue out of the oppressive Egyptian empire. Both liberation and rescue are really good biblical words for &#8220;salvation.&#8221; In Exodus we read how YHWH rescued the Hebrew people by liberating them out of Egypt.</p>
<p>Jesus is saying that this posture of servanthood is essential to the shape of how his disciples are to be towards one another and the world. Our eating and fellowshipping together should reflect these values.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  We are not happy because we are unforgiving, and we are unforgiving because we feel superior to others. Mercy is the fruit of the highest degree of love, because love creates equals, and a greater love makes us inferior. -Carlo Carretto
</p></blockquote>
<p>Jesus&#8217; suffering servanthood was not meant to help us avoid ours or others suffering, or make us superior to others &#8211; instead &#8211; it is an invitation into both suffering and being servants in the world.</p>
<ol>
<li>Shared Distribution &#8211; In Jesus last supper Luke goes to great lengths to stress the everyday material elements present. There is a the loaf of bread and a cup of wine. Jesus follows the standard ritual any Jew would follow and gave thanks for what the had. And then he passes the food around to his disciples.</li>
</ol>
<p>He says:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  “<strong>Take this and divide it among yourselves</strong>…Then he took a loaf of bread, and when he had given thanks, he <strong>broke it and gave it</strong> to them, saying, “This is my body, which is given for you. <strong>Do this in remembrance of me</strong>.&#8221; (Luke 22:17–19)
</p></blockquote>
<p>What I think Jesus is doing here is connecting the everyday act of eating together and saying that this kind of sharing should be &#8220;broken open&#8221; and poured out for the world. The word <strong>divide</strong> literally means &#8220;distribute.&#8221; And there is a similar feel with breaking and giving.</p>
<p>At the heart of the church should be this act of generous distribution and sharing what we have with one another. Often we feel like we cannot give or share or extend ourselves until we have more than enough, until we are finally in control of our lives, etc. But Jesus&#8217; example here is to take the everyday simple things and share them. The act of sharing is the breaking and giving that Jesus tells us to do here.</p>
<p>Another part of this is that by attaching everyday things that all people do &#8211; like eating a common meal together &#8211; to himself &#8220;this is my body, this is my blood&#8221; I believe that he was suggesting that there is a priority of the of knowing and serving God together in community.</p>
<p>Jesus’ bread and wine is meant to bind our spirituality not only to him, but to one another. It means that God will always be found within the body of Christ and that very real and tangible should be met by that same body of people. These are some of the ways that the inward and outward needs we have are to be met.</p>
<h1>The lasting Supper (Remembering…)</h1>
<p>Finally, Jesus says <strong>Do this in remembrance of me</strong>. In other words, make this way of eating together, make this servanthood, make this generous sharing with others, the thing you remember to do as you gather in my name. Do it in my honor.</p>
<p>This was not meant to be a &#8220;last supper,&#8221; but instead a &#8220;lasting supper&#8221; where all people are welcome and real needs are met continually. This is not something that happened once, or that some churches may do during Sunday morning worship, but rather an entire way of life.</p>
<p>Both the inward and the outward are to be cared for by each of us, directed at one another and the world.</p>
<p>We show our faithfulness and our commitment to Jesus by how we remember this.</p>
<p>And this lasting supper gives us a picture of what a real Jesus-inspired dinner party can look like.</p>
<p>The lasting supper is one in which people are invited to share meals together and those invited are not always the usual suspects but those who are unsuspecting and uninvited.</p>
<p>The lasting supper is a supper where we are the servants of others, where we assume a posture of humility, and where we are willing to not only help, but forgive, and show mercy to anyone.</p>
<p>The lasting supper breaks down barriers that keep people away from the &#8220;table of the Lord.&#8221; AS the church we can create opportunities where real needs are actually met and real boundaries are actually broken.</p>
<p>The lasting supper reminds us that God is found within the everyday acts of sharing and in the gathered community. We need to find more and better opportunities for this to happen and organize our lives in such a way that these things take precedence in our lives.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  If we were invited to a dinner party of this nature would we be willing to go? And are we willing to live into and let the lasting supper shape the way we live our lives?
</p></blockquote><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=7hGIpZX1PmU:VJr00oRFVj0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=7hGIpZX1PmU:VJr00oRFVj0:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=7hGIpZX1PmU:VJr00oRFVj0:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=7hGIpZX1PmU:VJr00oRFVj0:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=7hGIpZX1PmU:VJr00oRFVj0:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/7hGIpZX1PmU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/28/bread-and-the-lasting-supper-luke-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/28/bread-and-the-lasting-supper-luke-22/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Holding the Tension, Umwelt and Hearts Broken Open</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/uVcXm97o208/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/19/holding-the-tension-umwelt-and-hearts-broken-open/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sermons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4543</guid>
		<description>This is the message I gave Sunday March 17, 2013 at Camas Friends Church and is drawn from Isaiah 43: 16-21. Holding the Tension This past weekend I had the chance to go to Philadelphia to participate in a consultation with a Quaker foundation. Not only did I learn a lot by participating in the [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the message I gave Sunday March 17, 2013 at Camas Friends Church and is drawn from <a href="http://bible.oremus.org/?ql=230375319">Isaiah 43: 16-21</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8381/8544194566_c36094ab95_b.jpg" width="1024" height="680" class="aligncenter" /></p>
<h2>Holding the Tension</h2>
<p>This past weekend I had the chance to go to Philadelphia to participate in a consultation with a Quaker foundation. Not only did I learn a lot by participating in the foundation but I got to see a little of downtown Philly and enjoy the sites. I got to see Friend <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8540092413/in/photostream/">Mary Dyer</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8541201684/in/photostream/">William Penn</a>, some <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8541201794/in/photostream/">old</a> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8540091095/in/photostream/">Friends</a>, see a <a href="http://greenstreetfriendsmeeting.org/about.php">couple</a> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8540091891/in/photostream/">meetinghouses</a> and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8560833306/in/photostream/">make some new friends too</a>.</p>
<p>Our Saturday meeting was great. There were 15 young friends invited and the goal was to draw on the excitement and creativity of these Friends to help the Shoemaker Foundation in their discernment about where to invest their money for the future.</p>
<p>One of the things that stood out to me about our time together was the <strong>many tensions</strong> that have to be held when a group of Quakers get together.  <span id="more-4543"></span></p>
<p>When you get that many Quakers together you are going to have <strong>different views</strong> of God expressed, different religious experiences and often very different language about how to talk about those things, and yet from the moment I arrived I had this very distinct sense of being in a safe space and welcomed by community. I remember feeling instantly connected to these Friends, many of whom I hadn’t met before. I had this sense that <strong>“these are my people.”</strong> I love that feeling.</p>
<p><strong>Another tension</strong> is related to some of the responses we came up with to the various queries. One that really stuck with me was in response to #question 2 above:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  &#8220;Quakerism is open to all people, but it isn&#8217;t whatever you want it to be.&#8221;
</p></blockquote>
<p>How do we hold these differences together?</p>
<p>It means that while we are open to all no one individual has the power to decided or control the direction of the group. It takes a process of listening and coming to clearness before God before we move on anything. We believe that only Jesus, who is living and present, gets to be our teacher, final word, and guiding light.</p>
<p>As we all well know, the difficult part is to actually live this tension out in our meetings. And not only is it true that our faith communities are filled with tensions, but so <strong>is the rest of life</strong>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some of the tensions we find are in our relationships, Jobs, kids, aging and health and injustices within society. </li>
</ul>
<p>All of these tensions we are faced with are the gap between reality and new possibility.</p>
<p>So I like the statement: &#8220;Quakerism is open to all people, but it isn&#8217;t whatever you want it to be.&#8221; Because it reminds us that it is human and a deeply spiritual practice to actually be able to hold things in tension.</p>
<p>Of course this is no easy task and the reality is often far different from this. It is much easier to withdrawal and avoid these tension, refraining from saying what you feel led to say or feeling like any discussion on a difficult matter is simply a waste of time are common feelings. But they won&#8217;t help us grow or change.</p>
<h1>Umwelt</h1>
<ul>
<li>[In her book E. O'Connor writes about] The biologist Esther Harding argues that all of nature even humans have a very limited awareness of the inward and outward world. In her study of nature she has found that every creature, both great and small, only sees and hears what concerns itself &#8211; every thing else it ignores (12-13).</li>
</ul>
<p>Harding suggests that each animal lives in a world of its own or an Umwelt. <strong>Umwelt basically means environment or surrounding. It can be translated “self-centered world.”</strong> Every creature has its own Umwelt that it responds to while ignoring everything else.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.thegreatmorel.com/images/woodtick.jpg" width="564" height="486" class="aligncenter" /></p>
<p>Harding gives the example of the wood tick which needs blood from a warm-blooded animal in order to reproduce. When the wood tick is ready to reproduce it attaches itself to a tree and waits for a deer or some other warm-blooded animal to walk by with its thumb out hoping for a little carpool. Because there are so many wood ticks in the forest and not enough warm-blooded animals to go around &#8211; Harding says that some wood ticks have stood around waiting for a ride for as long as <strong>17 years</strong>! They apparently had a pretty open calendar. It is so fixed on its own situation that it will not change trees, move around, or find an alternative. It is an animal unable to hold the tension between reality and possibility.</p>
<p>This kind of stubborn limitedness works for us as well. Many times we find ourselves in need of making adjustments, changing our expectations, learning how to do something new, or interact with new people and yet we will just hang on that same darn tree for 17 years refusing to budge. It is easy to be like the wood tick and only focus on what concerns us, to live in a self-centered world, while being blind to others’ realities.</p>
<p>[Slide] > The life task of each person is to enlarge his [or her] own narrow umwelt, or to grow in awareness &#8211; &#8220;Awake, O sleeper, and Christ will give you light.&#8221; E. O&#8217;Connor (13).</p>
<h1>Hearts Break Open</h1>
<p>The broader our Umwelts, the easier it is for us to be able to hold the tensions of reality and possibility, the more capable we will be of growing and moving past those stuck places in our spiritual and emotional places of life, the more readily we will be able to accept the differences of those around us and the new possibilities that break upon us by God&#8217;s good grace.</p>
<p>We might define grace as God’s help expanding each of our Umwelts. I believe that this is the kind of work that Jesus was constantly engaged in as was Paul and the prophets in the OT.</p>
<p>In <strong>Isaiah 43</strong> the people are invited to have their umwelts broken open so that they can be ready for the new thing that God is about to do. This was written most likely in the late sixth century when the Hebrew people were exiled in Babylon. There was a lot of suffering in this time, the people felt the weight of oppression from their Babylonian captors.</p>
<p>The first part of the passage is to remind the people of their foundational narrative of the Exodus and the power of God who has worked to save them who &#8220;makes a way in the sea, a path in the mighty waters.&#8221; The author drums up their collective memory and reminds the people that God is capable of delivering them and that Babylon is no match for YHWH. No matter how difficult their situation is, how much of an impasse they believe they are in, or how afraid they are &#8211; this is the God who &#8220;brings out chariot and horse, army and warrior, and extinguishes them&#8221; just as happened at the Reed Sea with Moses and Pharaoh&#8217;s army.</p>
<p>When times are difficult we are to draw on our collective memory of the many ways in which God has helped us, redeemed us and walked us through the valley of death in the past.</p>
<p>But then something even more interesting happens. Isaiah says:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Do not remember the former things, or consider the things of old. I am about to do a new thing: now it springs forth, do you not perceive it?
</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>What the author is saying is not to forget your tradition and your history, but instead not to be limited by it. Don&#8217;t let it become the binding umwelt</strong>. Instead, be ready for it to be expanded. Even if you are the wood tick and every time up until now hanging out on this old tree really worked for you, maybe there&#8217;s a new way to do it. Maybe there is a new thing that is arising, a new possibility and if you&#8217;re stuck with the same-old tree you&#8217;re going to miss it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Do not Remember…&#8221; is the prophet&#8217;s way of saying don’t get stuck waxing nostalgic about the “good old days.” Callie Plunket-Brewton says:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  The prophet aims <strong>to create an imaginative space</strong> in the minds of the people so that their conception of the past can transform their understanding of the present and, thus, the future: “I am about to do a new thing; now it springs forth, do you not perceive it?” In a seemingly hopeless situation, the prophet calls on the people not to lose heart but to look with anticipation for the signs of God’s approaching redemption, for the “new thing” that is coming.
</p></blockquote>
<p>In what ways does our own grappling the &#8220;good ol&#8217; days&#8221; and a limited umwelt play out in our own spiritual lives? Is there a new thing God is working among us now?</p>
<p>I love that Isa 43 names the tensions between reality and the possibility of something new that God is about to do with his people. <strong>It is meant to be a surprise,</strong> a kind of shattering of what we expect so that the hearers might have a new capacity to hear something new.</p>
<p>Broken Hearts &#8211; [ILL - Slide] &#8220;There is an old Hasidic tale that tells us how such things happen. The pupil comes to the rebbe and asks, &#8220;Why does the Torah tell us to &#8216;place these words upon your hears?&#8217; Why does it not tell us to place these holy words in our hearts?&#8217; The rebbe answers, &#8216;It is because as we are, our hearts are closed, and we cannot place the holy words in our hearts. So we place them on top of our hearts. And there they stay until, one day, the heart breaks, and the words call in.&#8221; (Parker Palmer &#8211; A Hidden Wholeness, 181)</p>
<p>We are often afraid to enter into the difficult space of holding tensions and allowing our imaginations to be opened up for fear that our hearts will be broken. It is very possible that we will discover we have been wrong about something. We may find that others have legitimate and deeply held beliefs and experiences that are different from our own. We may hear stories that are too painful to bear, or find ourselves powerless in the face of tragedy we have no power over.  It is always possible that entering a difficult space and in seeking to hold tensions that we may experience a loss, but if it is grounded by God’s grace then that brokenness can bring us into a new capacity to love, listen and care for one another.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Prayer: Break open my heart, guide my thoughts, help me to hold the tensions around me. And those places I dare go, provide a path for me to enter in.
</p></blockquote>
<p>It is not only possible but desirable to be broken into a new capacity. Just as the Hebrew people would come to desire that new thing God would do in their midst &#8211; even if it meant leaning into the difficult and scary unknowns of the wilderness they would do it.</p>
<p>It is not only possible but desirable to hold the tensions of life. Jesus’ ministry was filled with tensions, with people who knew they wanted to follow him, but didn’t always understand or do what he taught. The point was never to rid the church of tension, but to create a community that could hold those tensions while being rooted and centered in Jesus.</p>
<p>I believe that it is possible to live with a greater capacity for acceptance and love, but it will not be easy and our hearts may be broken in the process. We can only pray they are not shattered but broken open into a new capacity.</p>
<p>We can actually honor our collective memory and our past experiences while at the same time accepting the new thing that God is doing in our midst. Sitting with our worshipping community and working through our differences is one of the most powerful ways to do this.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  As we grow in depth of relationship with those whose values and experiences are different from ours, the horizons of our little worlds are pushed back &#8211; our Umwelts are enlarged. Life comes to have a variety and a richness that was not there before. (E. O&#8217;Connor 25)
</p></blockquote><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=uVcXm97o208:YL4XnYZ8I3M:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=uVcXm97o208:YL4XnYZ8I3M:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=uVcXm97o208:YL4XnYZ8I3M:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=uVcXm97o208:YL4XnYZ8I3M:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=uVcXm97o208:YL4XnYZ8I3M:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/uVcXm97o208" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/19/holding-the-tension-umwelt-and-hearts-broken-open/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/19/holding-the-tension-umwelt-and-hearts-broken-open/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Emperor, Little Deaths and the Fig Tree (Lk 13:6-9)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/5VUORfSLLT8/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/05/the-emperor-little-deaths-and-the-fig-tree-lk-136-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sermons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4535</guid>
		<description>On Sunday we did a reader&amp;#8217;s theater of the Hans Christen Andersen&amp;#8217;s fable &amp;#8220;The Emperor&amp;#8217;s New Suit.&amp;#8221; That helped set the stage for the rest of the discussion that followed. Idols Create a false sense of self During Lent, Michaela Bruzzese, says that &amp;#8220;we are offered a unique opportunity to discard [our] false idols.&amp;#8221; Idols [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4536" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/ens.png"><img src="http://gatheringinlight.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/ens-1024x837.png" alt="Illustration by Joel Stewart" width="1024" height="837" class="size-large wp-image-4536" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Illustration by Joel Stewart</p></div>
<p>On Sunday we did a reader&#8217;s theater of the Hans Christen Andersen&#8217;s fable &#8220;<a href="https://dl.dropbox.com/u/24261/emperorsnewsuite.pdf">The Emperor&#8217;s New Suit</a>.&#8221; That helped set the stage for the rest of the discussion that followed.</p>
<p><span id="more-4535"></span></p>
<h2>Idols Create a false sense of self</h2>
<p>During Lent, Michaela Bruzzese, says that &#8220;we are offered a unique opportunity to discard [our] false idols.&#8221;</p>
<p>Idols in our time can be anything that creates a false-self,  layers us behind walls of protection, keeps us holding onto something so strong that inner change is unable to occur, or is an investment into &#8220;goods&#8221; that distract us from deeper and more meaningful ways of living in the world.</p>
<p>For the emperor his false idols were his ego and his vanity. For you and I it may be something different. We are all aware of those parts of our lives that can operate in the capacity of idols, none of us are beyond the reach of the Emperor&#8217;s story &#8211; even if that story is an extreme.</p>
<h1>You are dust</h1>
<p>What we do share, I believe, is a need to pass through the experience of what we might call &#8220;little deaths&#8221; from time to time, just as the emperor experienced a little death at the hand of some swindlers and a child.</p>
<p>This is not the &#8220;great death&#8221; that we all have no choice over.</p>
<p>Parker Palmer says that Little deaths are those experiences that &#8220;deepen our appreciation for life&#8221; and have the capacity to help move us towards a more undivided life.</p>
<p>A number of years ago when Emily and I were still attending Pasadena Mennonite Church we decided to attend an Ash Wednesday service. Mennonites tend to be more liturgical than Quakers and so we went as a good learning experience. It was much more than that for me. When the time came to spread the ashes on the forehead Jennifer, our pastor, called everyone to line up. And then one by one she spread a little ash on my forehead and said <strong>“Wess, Remember that you are Dust!”</strong></p>
<p>Now I didn&#8217;t take this as a self-deprecatory statement. It didn&#8217;t encourage me into self-loathing, nor did it induce a feeling of guilt.</p>
<p>This little statement &#8220;Remember you are dust&#8221; is a description. It names reality.</p>
<p>I am made of earth and to earth I shall return.</p>
<p>I took this as an invitation to enter into a &#8220;little death&#8221; before I arrive at the great big one. It was an invitation to allow Christ to work in me a new kind of beauty and wholeness that will constantly evade me if I try to live as though I were a man  made of steel, ageless, tireless; a machine without limits.</p>
<p>When death comes will I have produced with my life the kind of fruit I hope to leave behind?</p>
<h2>Mary Oliver : When death comes</h2>
<p>When death comes<br />
like the hungry bear in autumn<br />
when death comes and takes all the bright coins from his purse<br />
to buy me, and snaps his purse shut;<br />
when death comes like the measle-pox;<br />
when death comes like an iceberg between the shoulder blades,<br />
I want to step through the door full of curiosity, wondering;<br />
what is it going to be like, that cottage of darkness?</p>
<p>[And therefore I look upon everything<br />
as a brotherhood and a sisterhood,<br />
and I look upon time as no more than an idea,<br />
and I consider eternity as another possibility,<br />
and I think of each life as a flower, as common<br />
as a field daisy, and as singular,<br />
and each name a comfortable music in the mouth<br />
tending as all music does, toward silence,<br />
and each body a lion of courage, and something<br />
precious to the earth.]</p>
<p>When it’s over, I want to say: all my life<br />
I was a bride married to amazement.<br />
I was a bridegroom, taking the world into my arms.</p>
<p>When it’s over, I don’t want to wonder<br />
if I have made of my life something particular, and real.<br />
I don’t want to find myself sighing and frightened<br />
or full of argument.<br />
I don’t want to end up simply having visited this world.</p>
<hr />
<p>I love that she says &#8220;when death comes like an iceberg between the shoulder blades, I want to step through the door full of curiosity, wondering; what is it going to be like, that cottage of darkness?&#8221;</p>
<p>And &#8211;</p>
<p>&#8220;When it’s over, I want to say: all my life. I was a bride married to amazement. I was a bridegroom, taking the world into my arms.&#8221;</p>
<p>Little deaths can help to facilitate this kind of deep awareness and appreciation for life. They can, if we allow them, move us deeper into an undivided life.</p>
<h2>Luke 13</h2>
<p>In Luke 13 Jesus tells a parable about a fig tree that sheds light on both the Emperor&#8217;s New Suite and this movement of passing through &#8220;little deaths&#8221; to bearing new fruit in life.</p>
<p>Questions: What do you hear in this parable that resonates? What is the little death here?</p>
<p>This parable focuses on the sterility of the tree. The owner has had a enough. After three years of walking out to his vineyard in hopes of finding some tasty figs to put on his morning cereal he finds nothing at all!</p>
<p>This is a fig tree that makes no figs! What good is that? He says it&#8217;s worthless and should be cut down.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the interesting part.</p>
<p><strong>The gardener disagrees with the owner</strong>. He says, &#8220;leave it alone. Give it another shot. I think you are wrong about this tree. If it gets a little more tending, if it drinks the right water, and eats the right food, it will begin to produce fruit.&#8221;</p>
<p>The gardener see that something is beautiful about the tree, something is still possible. That it can become a fruit-bearing tree despite its sterile past. But it needs some time, some effort and some care. It needs to confront its own &#8220;little death.&#8221;</p>
<p>Isn&#8217;t this true for us? We can find ourselves in a place where we feel we need a second lease on life. A <strong>second chance</strong> before God. This parable is about God being a God of second chances and Jesus as the gardener who sees the beauty of a tree that appears to be all but dead.</p>
<p>It is about the tree embracing a little death and I&#8217;d like to think that it goes on to produce fruit of its own in the coming years.</p>
<p>Like all of us it needs a little pruning, tending and the rich conditions, good food that produces an authentic and undivided life.</p>
<p>I think this telling of the parable is meant to open us up and make us reflect &#8211; do we choose life or death? Will we allow ourselves to be pruned, or will our destructive coarse lead only to further heartache and a divided life? Jesus invites his hearers to enter into a vulnerability.</p>
<p>Barbara Brown Taylor says about this text:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  “It is not a bad thing for them to feel the full fragility of their lives. It is not a bad thing for them to count their breaths in the dark &#8212; not if it makes them turn toward the light.</p>
<p>  “It is that turning he wants for them, which is why he tweaks their fear,&#8221; she writes. &#8221; . . . That torn place your fear has opened up inside of you is a holy place. Look around while you are there. Pay attention to what you feel. It may hurt you to stay there and it may hurt you to see, but it is not the kind of hurt that leads to death. It is the kind that leads to life.
</p></blockquote>
<h2>A New Story</h2>
<p>I&#8217;d like to close with a re-writing of the Emperor&#8217;s story.</p>
<p>What if we were to re-write the story about the emperor and instead of the tailors being criminals they were Quakers who wanted to help strip the king of his falsehoods and help him facilitate an honest look at his life and what he was investing himself in?</p>
<p>What if in the story nakedness is a good thing, it represents a kind of integrity, transparency, a wholeness that we long for?</p>
<p>Our Quaker tailors were working to invite the King into a kind of &#8220;little death&#8221; to which he might move from sterility to fecundity.</p>
<p>The Child was the first to help him see it for himself because children are often able to see the inner beauty of others. They are able to see beyond the veil of lies, falsehoods and the &#8220;wisdom of the crowds.&#8221;</p>
<p>And instead of the king running off as soon as he found himself naked &#8212; as I would have done &#8212; he continues to march on in his birthday suite.</p>
<p>But in our story he doesn&#8217;t keep walking in order to keep up appearances, instead he walks because in that moment he had in fact entered fully into his own nakedness.</p>
<p>He accepted the little death, or George Fox&#8217;s once said, he passed through the flaming sword and into the paradise of God.</p>
<p>He was able to parade around in a new kind of naked beauty of the wholeness. He was able to enter that holy and torn place:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Look around while you are there. Pay attention to what you feel. It may hurt you to stay there and it may hurt you to see, but it is not the kind of hurt that leads to death. It is the kind that leads to life.
</p></blockquote>
<h2>Open Worship</h2><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5VUORfSLLT8:JOGkToQRSiY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5VUORfSLLT8:JOGkToQRSiY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5VUORfSLLT8:JOGkToQRSiY:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=5VUORfSLLT8:JOGkToQRSiY:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5VUORfSLLT8:JOGkToQRSiY:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/5VUORfSLLT8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/05/the-emperor-little-deaths-and-the-fig-tree-lk-136-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/03/05/the-emperor-little-deaths-and-the-fig-tree-lk-136-9/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Bullies Called Him Pork Chop</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/vBQQbIhuuPI/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/4532/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 23:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bullies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4532</guid>
		<description></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ltun92DfnPY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vBQQbIhuuPI:A7xbzW0ONUA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vBQQbIhuuPI:A7xbzW0ONUA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vBQQbIhuuPI:A7xbzW0ONUA:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=vBQQbIhuuPI:A7xbzW0ONUA:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=vBQQbIhuuPI:A7xbzW0ONUA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/vBQQbIhuuPI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/4532/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/4532/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>When it’s over, I want to say: all my life I was a bride married to amazement.</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/FfYnBHs2xvo/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/when-its-over-i-want-to-say-all-my-life-i-was-a-bride-married-to-amazement/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 22:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4531</guid>
		<description>When death comes by Mary Oliver When death comes like the hungry bear in autumn when death comes and takes all the bright coins from his purse to buy me, and snaps his purse shut; when death comes like the measle-pox; when death comes like an iceberg between the shoulder blades, I want to step [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When death comes by Mary Oliver</p>
<p>When death comes<br />
like the hungry bear in autumn<br />
when death comes and takes all the bright coins from his purse</p>
<p>to buy me, and snaps his purse shut;<br />
when death comes<br />
like the measle-pox;</p>
<p>when death comes<br />
like an iceberg between the shoulder blades,</p>
<p>I want to step through the door full of curiosity, wondering;<br />
what is it going to be like, that cottage of darkness?</p>
<p>And therefore I look upon everything<br />
as a brotherhood and a sisterhood,<br />
and I look upon time as no more than an idea,<br />
and I consider eternity as another possibility,</p>
<p>and I think of each life as a flower, as common<br />
as a field daisy, and as singular,</p>
<p>and each name a comfortable music in the mouth<br />
tending as all music does, toward silence,</p>
<p>and each body a lion of courage, and something<br />
precious to the earth.</p>
<p>When it&#8217;s over, I want to say: all my life<br />
I was a bride married to amazement.<br />
I was a bridegroom, taking the world into my arms.</p>
<p>When it&#8217;s over, I don&#8217;t want to wonder<br />
if I have made of my life something particular, and real.<br />
I don&#8217;t want to find myself sighing and frightened<br />
or full of argument.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to end up simply having visited this world.</p>
<p><a href='http://www.panhala.net/archive/when_death_comes.html'>When Death Comes &#8212; Mary Oliver</a>.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FfYnBHs2xvo:Basx7sfFeiI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FfYnBHs2xvo:Basx7sfFeiI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FfYnBHs2xvo:Basx7sfFeiI:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=FfYnBHs2xvo:Basx7sfFeiI:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=FfYnBHs2xvo:Basx7sfFeiI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/FfYnBHs2xvo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/when-its-over-i-want-to-say-all-my-life-i-was-a-bride-married-to-amazement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/when-its-over-i-want-to-say-all-my-life-i-was-a-bride-married-to-amazement/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Signposts, Abraham and the Unknown (Genesis 15)</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/3z2DglPKuSk/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/signposts-abraham-and-the-unknown-genesis-15/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sermons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4523</guid>
		<description>In her book Journey Inward, Journey Outward, Elizabeth O&amp;#8217;Connor says of the importance of self-reflection: &amp;#8220;We must be engaged with ourselves, if we are going to find out where are, and where it is we want to go.&amp;#8221; One of the ways that we know where we are, and where we are going is by [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.ella-foundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/You-Are-Here-v21.jpg" width="306" height="468" class="alignleft" /> In her book Journey Inward, Journey Outward, Elizabeth O&#8217;Connor says of the importance of self-reflection: &#8220;We must be engaged with ourselves, if we are going to find out where are, and where it is we want to go.&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the ways that we know where we are, and where we are going is by landmarks and signposts. This is true in the natural world as much as it is in the spiritual one.</p>
<p>Spiritual signposts are often favorite stories we tell about your our life, pivotal moments where we have encountered God. Like a regular signpost or landmark, these spiritual counterparts are meant to mark our directions and remind us of where God is leading us. They help us in our journey towards wholeness.<span id="more-4523"></span></p>
<p>The story I shared a couple weeks ago about going down into the basement of an old meetinghouse and finding studs and the supportive structure of that building as having names on it was a kind of spiritual signpost for me. That image came to me during open worship and has stuck with me as describing and reminding me what my work is to be about. And the idea of a church community made up of the names who helped build it is itself an image of signposts.</p>
<p>These aren&#8217;t just really important stories that I tell. These are moments in my life when I was given direction, reminded of direction, or reminded of God&#8217;s love for me. Signposts are often things we can go back to again and again and draw new insight out of them.</p>
<ul>
<li>Share: What about for you? What are your spiritual signposts? Are you willing to share one with us?</li>
</ul>
<h1>The Unknown</h1>
<p>And the reason why remembering our signposts is so important is that all of life is embraced by a certain level of uncertainty, of the unknown.</p>
<p>The fact that we start out in families we did not choose, countries we did not choose, with bodies, and abilities we did not choose is the first great uncertainty we all face.</p>
<p>ILL. The first time my family learned I had severe allergy-induced asthma was when I was four-years old and had been playing in a pile of fallen leaves. My mom found me outside a light shade of blue from asphyxiation and rushed me to the ER. The fact that my body had this special feature to it was unknown and a quite a surprise.</p>
<p>As <strong>young children</strong> we learn that life is uncertain in so many ways and coming to grips with this can be very unsettling. One question we face as parents: How do we teach our children about the uncertainties of the world without making them afraid?</p>
<p>But our acquaintance with the unknown doesn&#8217;t change when we get old, in fact it can often greatly increase.</p>
<p>As <strong>our bodies begin to age</strong> and change we wonder how much longer we will be able to work, take care of ourselves, our homes, our loved ones. We wonder what we should do with the rest of our lives and want to know how to continue to make meaning while in the middle of rapid change.</p>
<p>If signposts are God&#8217;s way of showing us where we have been and remind us where we are going, it is because the landscape of life is marked by the constant unknown.</p>
<p>There is a tension between these signposts and the unknown.</p>
<h1>Abraham</h1>
<p>Father Abraham, as our daughters &#8211; L. and M. like to call him because as L. told me the other day, we are all his children &#8211; knows this tension between signposts and the unknown.</p>
<p>Abraham is well past retirement age by our standards when God calls him on a mission to &#8220;get up and go&#8221; settle in a new land:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  &#8220;Now the Lord said to Abram, &#8216;Go from your country and your kindred and your father&#8217;s house to the land that I will show you. I will make you a great nation, and I will bless you, and make your name great, so that you will be a blessing.&#8217;&#8221; (Gen. 12:1-2).
</p></blockquote>
<p>Abraham at the age of 75 is called into a new uncertainty. He and Sarah are called to get up and go and leave everything behind them. I like how Karen Armstrong puts it.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  &#8220;Abraham had to leave the consolations of familiarity and tradition far behind. He had to jettison his family, his homeland, and the old ways of worship. The destination was vague. Abraham was simply to journey to &#8216;the land that I will show you,&#8217; with no guarantees&#8221; (56).
</p></blockquote>
<p>Reading this I am confronted with the question, how would do I do when God asks me to walk into the unknown with no guarantees?</p>
<p>Not only are Abraham and Sarah in the dark about where God was taking them, but God tells them they&#8217;re going to have a son. Hearing that at their age would have been quite a shock to anyone.</p>
<p>Much of Abraham and Sarah&#8217;s journey is a journey of wandering from place to place, sometimes hearing God and responding well, sometimes not so well:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  “Then Abraham fell on his face and laughed, and said to himself, “Can a child be born to a man who is a hundred years old? Can Sarah, who is ninety years old, bear a child?” And Abraham said to God, “O that Ishmael might live in your sight!” (Genesis 17:16–18 NRSV)
</p></blockquote>
<p>Abraham&#8217;s story, like ours, emphasizes the unknown, the struggles of getting it right, and that faith is about accepting a world of uncertainty. There are no guarantees in Abraham&#8217;s story and there is no way for him to bring about the things God has said to him. He has to wait and journey faithfully.</p>
<p>This should come as quite a stark contrast to our world that wants to guarantee safety and protection. A society based on technological advance, and the &#8220;guarantees&#8221; of economic analysis, scientific discovery, and whatever the latest &#8220;experts.&#8221; In our society mystery is denigrated while we become obsessed with &#8220;guarantees.&#8221;</p>
<p>But all these, and many others, fly in the of Father Abraham&#8217;s wisdom.</p>
<p>A story that emphasizes a faith where there are no guarantees is also the story of Jesus who called each of his disciples saying &#8220;follow me.&#8221; Their step was a step out into the unknown. They would find signposts along the way to help them, but they had to accept the uncertainty that comes with being a person of faith as the first step.</p>
<p>Again Karen Armstrong writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Religious people often speak of &#8220;faith&#8221; as though it were a matter of conserving the old and the traditional; they claim that it gives them absolute certainty and is not compatible with doubt. Genesis shows that in fact faith began by demanding a radical break with the past and facing the terrors and enigmas of the unknown (56).
</p></blockquote>
<p>Abraham gets up and goes. And along the way he builds altars to God to remind him of where he has been and where God has met him (Cf. Gen. 12). Abraham had signposts. He was not abandoned or left out to dry. God does indeed guide him on his way. But I think Abraham &#8211; like any of us &#8211; was still freaked out by the unknown. This is why tries to do things his way, this is why he lies to the pharaoh of Egypt and says that his wife is his sister. This is why he marries a second woman, Hagar &#8212; his wife&#8217;s maidservant, so that she maybe she would give birth to the promised baby. Abraham is a lot like us, when faced with the unknown we respond in ways that are not always faithful to the signposts we&#8217;ve been given in the past.</p>
<p>And this is why in Genesis 15 &#8211; and many other places in Abraham&#8217;s story &#8211; God gives Abraham a signpost.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  “Do not be afraid, Abram, I am your shield; your reward shall be very great.” (Genesis 15:1)
</p></blockquote>
<p>Here God reminds Abraham that he is with him, even in the unknown and that the promise that God has made to him will be kept.</p>
<h1>Closing</h1>
<p>My <a href="robinmsf.blogspot.com/2013/02/conflicting-concerns.html">friend Robin Mohr wrote recently on her blog</a> about the kind of experience I am talking about &#8211; she writes that every once in awhile a concern arises in your heart so much that it causes everything to be re-prioritized in light of that concern.</p>
<p>Here was her experience:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  …An insight&#8230;came to me in worship this morning. A 100 year old Friend spoke about how grateful she is that 90 years ago, a Sunday school teacher made her memorize certain passages from the Bible. She still remembers the Beatitudes, for example. She was recently reminded of these because a couple of months ago she was temporarily blind after a surgery but she still had these verses, and some poetry she also memorized over the years. She is so grateful now even though at the time she wondered what good it would do.
</p></blockquote>
<p>She says that this was a signpost for her.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  I want to…&#8221;consider what I’m going to care about 90 years from now. Ok, maybe 50 years is all the horizon I need to worry about. In any case, I need to ask not just what has the most heat and Light in it right now, but what will I care about later? What will I regret? What will my grandchildren care about? What does God care about? What will I be held accountable for in the long run?&#8221;
</p></blockquote>
<p>What are the signposts, the &#8220;special moments&#8221; in your life when God has met you and spoke to you as he did Abraham? Return to them and draw on them in your time of need. These signposts can lead us into the unknown and help us know which direction to head.</p>
<p>Those moments, like Robin expresses here where we are invited to re-prioritize our our lives, take stock of the direction we are on and respond accordingly?</p>
<p>It may require that we take a step out into the unknown, but we know that this is the movement of faith, and we hear God whisper to us: &#8220;Do no be afraid, I am your shield…&#8221;</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=3z2DglPKuSk:9QHt8dGG4Mw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=3z2DglPKuSk:9QHt8dGG4Mw:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=3z2DglPKuSk:9QHt8dGG4Mw:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=3z2DglPKuSk:9QHt8dGG4Mw:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=3z2DglPKuSk:9QHt8dGG4Mw:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/3z2DglPKuSk" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/signposts-abraham-and-the-unknown-genesis-15/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/28/signposts-abraham-and-the-unknown-genesis-15/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bible is the People’s Book</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/jkKa1c0XuhM/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/25/the-bible-is-the-peoples-book/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 23:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Biblical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4518</guid>
		<description>This is a message I gave a couple years ago and coming across it today I feel it&amp;#8217;s worth sharing again. We in the church have a paradoxical relationship with the bible. Many inside and outside the church have misgivings about certain texts or whole swaths of texts, while other texts serve as basic idioms [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a message I gave a couple years ago and coming across it today I feel it&#8217;s worth sharing again. We in the church have a paradoxical relationship with the bible. Many inside and outside the church have misgivings about certain texts or whole swaths of texts, while other texts serve as basic idioms and metaphors in our culture so much so that we don&#8217;t even notice it anymore. Is the Bible still a relevant book for us? I contend yes, but not in the ways we&#8217;ve often been taught. I argue that there is a Quaker way of reading the bible that bypasses at least some of our modern hang-ups, and I suggest that the Bible really is the people&#8217;s book. It is a collection of stories that give witness to God&#8217;s liberating work throughout human history. Seen in this light, we can find ways to enter into the story as our own and become participants in God&#8217;s transformation of ourselves and the world.</p>
<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="http://w.soundcloud.com/player?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F20876581"></iframe><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=jkKa1c0XuhM:NDwWdM4-Xxg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=jkKa1c0XuhM:NDwWdM4-Xxg:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=jkKa1c0XuhM:NDwWdM4-Xxg:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=jkKa1c0XuhM:NDwWdM4-Xxg:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=jkKa1c0XuhM:NDwWdM4-Xxg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/jkKa1c0XuhM" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/25/the-bible-is-the-peoples-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/25/the-bible-is-the-peoples-book/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Cutting the Pentagon’s Budget @fcnl</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~3/5j8dHDBOkDA/</link>
		<comments>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/21/cutting-the-pentagons-budget-fcnl/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 21:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gatheringinlight.com/?p=4509</guid>
		<description>Friends Committee on National Legislation started a campaign to cut the pentagon&amp;#8217;s budget &amp;#8211; in 2011 it was a staggering $664.84 billion, which is 60% of the overall federal budget &amp;#8211; so that we do not have to make drastic cuts on important services like education, healthcare, nutrition assistance and housing that keep our communities [...]</description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/prh/8495966744/" title="Untitled by C. Wess Daniels, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8236/8495966744_3e0e14c53e_o.jpg" width="480" height="640" alt="Untitled"></a></p>
<p>Friends Committee on National Legislation started <a href="http://fcnl.org/events/week_of_action/cut_the_pentagon_not_our_communities/">a campaign to cut the pentagon&#8217;s budget</a> &#8211; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Military_budget_of_the_United_States">in 2011 it was a staggering $664.84 billion</a>, which is 60% of the overall federal budget &#8211; so that we do not have to make drastic cuts on important services like education, healthcare, nutrition assistance and housing that keep our communities thriving. Since 2011 the price-tag for defense has sky-rocketed from 287 billion to where we are today, no wonder our country is broke (<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/01/07/everything-chuck-hagel-needs-to-know-about-the-defense-budget-in-charts/">Link</a>). As a Christian and Quaker preacher, I want to see us invest in eliminating poverty in our country.</p>
<p>FCNL has asked individuals to post their image with their name and an area that they feel our government could do better at putting our money into rather than in Defense. This is mine.</p>
<p>My friends <a href="http://questforadequacy.blogspot.com/2013/02/a-sign.html">Ashley Wilcox</a> and <a href="http://www.jonwatts.com/2013/we-must-cut-our-military-budget/">Jon Watts</a> were the ones who tipped me off to this.</p>
<p>Make <a href="http://fcnl.org/events/week_of_action/cut_the_pentagon_not_our_communities/">yours here</a>.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5j8dHDBOkDA:yQZNJ1ZbZiQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5j8dHDBOkDA:yQZNJ1ZbZiQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5j8dHDBOkDA:yQZNJ1ZbZiQ:glZ967esw7I"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?i=5j8dHDBOkDA:yQZNJ1ZbZiQ:glZ967esw7I" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?a=5j8dHDBOkDA:yQZNJ1ZbZiQ:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GatheringInLight?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GatheringInLight/~4/5j8dHDBOkDA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/21/cutting-the-pentagons-budget-fcnl/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://gatheringinlight.com/2013/02/21/cutting-the-pentagons-budget-fcnl/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
