<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mommy Wants Vodka</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com</link>
	<description>I Suck At Life So You Don&#039;t Have To</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 14:00:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>

   <image>
    <title>Mommy Wants Vodka</title>
    <url>http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f7b8bb1a85fb36e40784ee59700c8e16.png?s=48</url>
    <link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com</link>
   </image><!-- Gravatar Favicon by Patrick http://patrick.bloggles.info/ -->
		<item>
		<title>Music Is My Nature</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/music-is-my-nature/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/music-is-my-nature/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daddy's Little Girl Loves Disco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=14011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today, Pranksters, I share not my story, but the story my son, Ben, tells. To give you some background as to why this story matters, I suggest reading this and this first. And now, Pranksters, I give you my firstborn son, Ben. Music has always been important to me.  Somehow, I never got the chance [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommys-little-boy-loves-disco/"     class="crp_title">Mommy&#8217;s Little Boy Loves Disco</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/nashtucky-rca-studio-b-tour/"     class="crp_title">NashTucky: The Midnight Special</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/when-amelia-yells-eye-of-the-tiger-you-know-its-a-party/"     class="crp_title">When Amelia Yells, &#8220;Eye of the Tiger,&#8221; You Know&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/iphone-possessed/"     class="crp_title">Possession Is Nine Tenths Of The Law?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wild-world-things-to-do-while-divorcing/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s A Crazy, Mixed-Up, Beautiful Wild World</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/music-is-my-nature/">Music Is My Nature</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: right;"><em>Today, Pranksters, I share not my story, but the story my son, Ben, tells. To give you some background as to why this story matters, I suggest reading <a title="music is my nature" href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/music-hath-soothed-the-savage-child/" target="_blank">this</a> and <a title="music is my nature" href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommys-little-boy-loves-disco/" target="_blank">this</a> first.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>And now, Pranksters, I give you my firstborn son, Ben.</em></p>
<p>Music has always been important to me.  Somehow, I never got the chance to really shine with my violin, until 5th grade.</p>
<p>The day before the concert, I was practicing and giving my mom, dad, and brother a concert. During my last song, I finally did the last bit of the song right. I played it right, it sounded right and it felt right.</p>
<p>After I played the last note right, my mom, dad, and brother clapped loud &#8211; my dad even whistled with his fingers.</p>
<p>“Great Job! Ben!” My Mom exclaimed.</p>
<p>“Yah! Ben! Amazing Job!” My Brother agreed.</p>
<p>Then my Mom said something I will never forget. “Ben… you have amazing talent, I will say! But… it’s up to you what you do with it!”</p>
<p>I will never forget those words.</p>
<p>I finished my practice and went up to dinner, wondering what those words meant.</p>
<p>The next night was my big concert. I was getting ready &#8211; I put on my pale-yellow dress shirt, my pants, my socks and shoes. &#8220;I&#8217;m busy as a bee,&#8221; I thought to myself. I grabbed my violin and went downstairs.</p>
<p>“Break a leg!” my Mom said encouragingly.</p>
<p>“Good Luck!” my Brother exclaimed.</p>
<p>“I’ll do my best” I promised, then grinned. We went out to the car and I got in. I was <em>really</em> nervous. Nervous as a Scardy Cat. My hands were shaking. The whole way to the auditorium, I thought about what my Mom had said. When we got to the building, my mom and dad whispered, “Good luck!&#8221;</p>
<p>I whispered back “Thanks!”</p>
<p>They went and sat down in their seats as I went to warm up with my group. My Orchestra Teacher gave us a pep talk before wishing us good luck. We got on stage and I craned my neck to look for my parents. As usual, I don’t see them beyond the stage lights. Our music teacher talks for a bit; her last words were “These guys have worked really hard. I hope you enjoy their music and thank you for coming out here tonight. Ladies and Gentlemen the 5th grade Orchestra!” she exclaimed.</p>
<p>We started to play. I played better than ever; I played perfectly for the first song. The second song, I&#8217;d played better than the first. During the last song, I remembered my mom’s words “It’s up to you what you do with your talent, Ben.”</p>
<p>So I tried to show of my talent to the world. When I was done playing, I felt like a new person. I knew music was my real talent. The audience went wild, so wild you couldn’t even talk without somebody yelling “What?”</p>
<p>We bowed and I think I even saw my dad wink at me. If, of course, that <em>was</em> my dad.</p>
<p>We came back after the applauding, screaming and going wild. My family congratulated me. I knew my mom knew that I knew that music was my talent. We celebrated over McDonald&#8217;s that night.</p>
<p>The Ben that walked into the auditorium was different than the Ben that walked out. I had accomplished something I thought I couldn’t do. I thought so many doubtful things. I was so nervous that my hands shook. But now? Now I know that…</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Music is me. Music is in my blood. Music is my nature.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>And THIS is why we&#8217;re taking a trip to NashVegas this summer, just the two of us. It&#8217;s time to teach my son the history of music.</em></p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=14011" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommys-little-boy-loves-disco/"     class="crp_title">Mommy&#8217;s Little Boy Loves Disco</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/nashtucky-rca-studio-b-tour/"     class="crp_title">NashTucky: The Midnight Special</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/when-amelia-yells-eye-of-the-tiger-you-know-its-a-party/"     class="crp_title">When Amelia Yells, &#8220;Eye of the Tiger,&#8221; You Know&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/iphone-possessed/"     class="crp_title">Possession Is Nine Tenths Of The Law?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wild-world-things-to-do-while-divorcing/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s A Crazy, Mixed-Up, Beautiful Wild World</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/music-is-my-nature/">Music Is My Nature</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/music-is-my-nature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Like A David Lynch Movie</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-a-david-lynch-movie/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-a-david-lynch-movie/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daddy's Little Girl Loves Disco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13998</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I live in an area affectionately known as the &#8220;tri-cities,&#8221; for reasons that should be obvious: we are three cities. Okay, the name is a misnomer because, quite frankly, we&#8217;re more like a cluster of seventy-niner cities, which means you can&#8217;t spit without hitting one city or another. Therefore, we&#8217;ve accepted the more appropriate moniker [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/im-slug-a-licious/"     class="crp_title">I&#8217;m Slug-a-Licious.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/love-chicago-style/"     class="crp_title">Love. Chicago Style.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/it-is-always-better-to-stare-stupidly-at-a-problem-than-actually-fix-it/"     class="crp_title">It Is Always Better To Stare Stupidly At A Problem Than&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/lollapaloozadog-days-are-not-over/"     class="crp_title">Lollapalloza: Dog Days Are NOT Over</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/munger-road/"     class="crp_title">Munger Road</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-a-david-lynch-movie/">Like A David Lynch Movie</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I live in an area affectionately known as the &#8220;tri-cities,&#8221; for reasons that should be obvious: we are three cities. Okay, the name is a misnomer because, quite frankly, we&#8217;re more like a cluster of seventy-niner cities, which means you can&#8217;t spit without hitting one city or another. Therefore, we&#8217;ve accepted the more appropriate moniker of &#8220;Chicago,&#8221; which runs about forty miles out from the city and abruptly stops.</p>
<p>That dividing line is called &#8220;Not Chicago.&#8221;</p>
<p>Everything that happens outside of Chicago is, effectively, &#8220;Not Chicago.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;ve lived here in Saint Charles for as long as my three remaining firing synapses allow, which means that I&#8217;m accustomed to suburbia. I&#8217;m not exactly a city girl gone country, because, to be honest, Chicago is the most wonderful city on earth, but I like my wide lawns and mornings without seeing seven or eight people peeing on things.</p>
<p>*<em>shrugs</em>*</p>
<p>Considering the size of Chicago, it&#8217;s probably (like most things that make sense to the rest of the world) just me.</p>
<p>(pointless and non-pithy aside: did you know that &#8220;East Chicago&#8221; is actually in Indiana? That, my dear Pranksters, is a hot pile of bullshit).</p>
<p>After spending my formative years creating a massive carbon footprint, tooling around in my wee del Sol, playing Summer Car,* smoking cigarettes, and getting lost on the long winding roads, driving just to see where we&#8217;d end up, I assumed that when I got the job in a town so small I can&#8217;t even tell you the name because you&#8217;ll be all, &#8220;whaaa-<em>huh</em>?&#8221; in the same way most people assume I&#8217;m from St. Charles, Missouri, which I assure you I am not, that I&#8217;d be well-suited to both the locale and the commute.</p>
<p>(holy run-on sentence, Batman)</p>
<p>The commute, well, there&#8217;s no better form of therapy than a fresh cup of coffee, a full tank of gas, and miles of open road. I use the time to compose hilarious tweets I never end up sending because I&#8217;m fucking driving. This whole &#8220;texting and driving&#8221; bullshit confuses me. I may be able to make a sandwich, chug a coke, and paint my nails while driving a stick, but texting (or Tweeting) while driving? It both baffles and annoys me.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the <em>locale</em> of the hospital I can&#8217;t quite understand.</p>
<p>I walked into my office on my first day and noted that the mysterious filing cabinets had disappeared while a desk had appeared in its place. Win! There was no computer on the desk. Not Win!</p>
<p>The very next thing I attempted to do baffled me further. I grabbed my i(can&#8217;t)Phone and went to tweet something about a time-warp and/or my lack of computer making me feel as though half my body had mysteriously disappeared, when I noted something I didn&#8217;t even know existed.</p>
<p>Roaming.</p>
<p>My fucking i(can&#8217;t)Phone was <strong>roaming</strong>.</p>
<p>Pranksters, I didn&#8217;t even know phones DID that anymore. I&#8217;d honestly thought that roaming charges went the way of Friendster. When I mentioned this to my boss, she said, &#8220;Oh yeah, I have to stand in the middle of the road to send a text.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m almost entirely certain that I amassed a large collection of flies as my mouth hung dumbly open.</p>
<p>&#8220;No&#8230;cell phone coverage?&#8221;</p>
<p>She just laughed. I shuddered.</p>
<p>Later that afternoon, as I was leaving, I realized the old tank was on empty so I pulled off to a tiny gas station chain that I&#8217;ve only ever seen in the deep south. The wind howling outrageously around me (no buildings around = wind blows sharply from the plains), I tried to grab out my debit card to pay at the pump because, well, duh. You have to do that shit here.</p>
<p>It was then that I noted that for the first time in probably 7 years, I had the option to pump my gas BEFORE paying for it. Underneath that shocking revelation, a sign said neatly, &#8220;Only In-State Checks Allowed.&#8221; As in, <strong>you could pay for your gas via check.</strong></p>
<p>And here I was thinking I was the last person on earth to both take baths (which is neither here nor there) and write checks. I&#8217;d always thought it was nearing time for my <em>Murder She Wrote</em> marathons, tripping young people with my cane, and chugging a mysterious substance called &#8220;Geritol.&#8221;</p>
<p>Apparently not.</p>
<p>Apparently, Pranksters, there exists a world OUTSIDE of Chicago that allows for personal checks while banning cell phones.</p>
<p>I also learned that I could buy a shed the approximate size and shape of the FBI Surveillance Van with a free metal roof, which just plain old seems like a bad idea. I mean, metal attracts lightening and shit. Or at least, it does in Chicago. Not Chicago, though, maybe that&#8217;s how they cook the wild boars the mens hunt all day long.</p>
<p>All I need is a midget dressed as a hot dog and a diner with a creepy waitress to make this a full-on David Lynch movie.</p>
<p>And the oddest part? I enjoy it.</p>
<p>What.</p>
<p>The.</p>
<p>Fuck.</p>
<p>Happened.</p>
<p>To.</p>
<p>Me?</p>
<p>*A game in which you remove most of your clothes, crank the heat, and attempt to confuse other drivers, who are, no doubt, bundled and shivering from the cold January winter.</p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13998" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/im-slug-a-licious/"     class="crp_title">I&#8217;m Slug-a-Licious.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/love-chicago-style/"     class="crp_title">Love. Chicago Style.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/it-is-always-better-to-stare-stupidly-at-a-problem-than-actually-fix-it/"     class="crp_title">It Is Always Better To Stare Stupidly At A Problem Than&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/lollapaloozadog-days-are-not-over/"     class="crp_title">Lollapalloza: Dog Days Are NOT Over</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/munger-road/"     class="crp_title">Munger Road</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-a-david-lynch-movie/">Like A David Lynch Movie</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-a-david-lynch-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;d Rather Chug Gasoline</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/id-rather-chug-gasoline/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/id-rather-chug-gasoline/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 14:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daddy's Little Girl Loves Disco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13984</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>To call my father &#8220;fastidious&#8221; would be akin to saying that &#8220;diet Coke tastes okay.&#8221; Sure, they&#8217;re both true statements, but they don&#8217;t quite delve into the true essence of the statement. I&#8217;d say he probably has some degree of obsessive-compulsive disorder, but I&#8217;d imagine it&#8217;s more the &#8220;compulsive&#8221; rather than obsessive part of the [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/iron-man/"     class="crp_title">Iron Man</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/it-is-always-better-to-stare-stupidly-at-a-problem-than-actually-fix-it/"     class="crp_title">It Is Always Better To Stare Stupidly At A Problem Than&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/where-the-sidewalk-ends/"     class="crp_title">Where The Sidewalk Ends.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/well-ive-only-kinda-ruined-summer/"     class="crp_title">Well, I&#8217;ve Only KINDA Ruined Summer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/three-dumbasses-drive-out-of-the-ghetto/"     class="crp_title">Three Dumbasses Drive OUT Of The Ghetto</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/id-rather-chug-gasoline/">I&#8217;d Rather Chug Gasoline</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To call my father &#8220;fastidious&#8221; would be akin to saying that &#8220;diet Coke tastes okay.&#8221; Sure, they&#8217;re both true statements, but they don&#8217;t <em>quite</em> delve into the true essence of the statement. I&#8217;d say he probably has some degree of obsessive-compulsive disorder, but I&#8217;d imagine it&#8217;s more the &#8220;compulsive&#8221; rather than obsessive part of the diagnosis.</p>
<p>(he reminds me too much of my daughter and her <a title="I'd rather chug gasoline" href="http://www.argos.co.uk/static/Browse/ID72/33014678/c_1/1%7Ccategory_root%7CToys%7C33006252/c_2/2%7C33006252%7CDolls+and+playsets%7C33008723/c_3/3%7Ccat_33008723%7CDolls%7C33014678/r_001/9%7CBrands%7CBarbie%7C1.htm" target="_blank">great range of Barbie dolls</a>, which she obsessively fusses over)</p>
<p>When I was a wee Aunt Becky, rather than swatting me or yelling, he&#8217;d sit calmly in his chair, insist that I take a seat on the couch and begin to <del>drone on</del> lecture me:</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;Well you know, Rebecca, that I like my hairbrush to be on this specific shelf.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: &#8220;Yes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;And this morning, when I went to brush my remaining three hairs, it wasn&#8217;t on my shelf.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: &#8220;Yes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;This is a problem.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: &#8220;Yes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;I need my things to be where they are put.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: &#8220;Yes.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>(three hours later)</em></p>
<p><em>(by this time, I&#8217;ve already rearranged the features on his face to make him look like a Picasso and begun a letter to my Congressman about unfair lecturing by an adult to a minor</em>)</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;So, when I went to the bathroom this morning to find my hairbrush it wasn&#8217;t there.&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: *stares at wall*</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;REBECCA ELIZABETH, ARE YOU EVEN LISTENING?&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: *<em>nods</em>*</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;What did I say?&#8221;</p>
<p>Wee AB: *<em>drones back</em>* &#8220;I should always put your hairbrush away.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;<strong>Right</strong>. Now, where was I?&#8221;</p>
<p>This tactic worked well on my brother, who&#8217;d have been wracked with guilt and pleading for forgiveness by this point, but I&#8217;m more of a quick, &#8220;hey put my crap back,&#8221; or &#8220;smack me across the face,&#8221; kinda girl. Always have been. My father has never understood that about me, so for years, I&#8217;d get The Lectures. It became a running joke once he realized that I wasn&#8217;t listening to him or feeling in the slightest bit guilty for committing such a heinous and unspeakable crime.</p>
<p>When it comes to his compulsiveness, though, nothing matches the way he feels about his car. Now most of you Pranksters know that I&#8217;m a bit of a car nut myself, but I&#8217;ve never had the opportunity to select a car for myself, so I don&#8217;t show the proper amount of respect for a car the way my father does. Someday I will and when I do, I am positive I&#8217;ll similarly warp my children.</p>
<p>Thursday evening, I&#8217;d left Not Chicago on time and had managed to wrangle my children into my CR-V without too much mayhem, which I considered a bonus. They were even wearing pants!</p>
<p>Sitting in the turn lane, waiting to make a left through &#8220;rush hour traffic,&#8221; I finally saw my opportunity and I took it. We sped off toward home for a nice night of lounging against the machine. Except&#8230; there was this rattling noise coming from the bottom of the car. Not the Oh CRAPBALLS You Blew A Tire noise, it was more You Ran Over A Branch, Moron,&#8221; so I wasn&#8217;t particularly concerned. I figured I&#8217;d lose the branch on the drive back to the FBI Surveillance Van or extract it when we arrived.</p>
<p>Alex sprang out of the car to examine it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Uh, Mom?&#8221; He said unhappily. &#8220;There&#8217;s something broken under there.&#8221;</p>
<p>I groaned. I&#8217;d just gone through the most ridiculously dramatic blown tire event of my life and now this? Really? I bent down to examine it. What appeared to be half a gigantic metal pill was, in fact, actually hanging off the bottom of my truck. Which meant absolutely nothing to me, which is I why I snapped a picture and sent it to <a title="I'd rather chug gasoline" href="http://twitter.com/mommywantsvodka" target="_blank">The Twitter. </a>Really, it&#8217;s the best course of action. The Twitter is ALL knowing.</p>
<p>Always a Daddy&#8217;s Girl, even after suffering the lectures about my improper placement of personal items, I called my father, who then stopped by on his way to visit my mother in the hospital, and explained the problem as I understand it to be. I sighed a little bit, cursed the CR-V and went about my night.</p>
<p>Until it dawned on me: I shouldn&#8217;t be driving the thing until that was fixed, and there was no way in balls I&#8217;d manage to get to the dealership for a couple of days.</p>
<p>Once again, I called my father, which I consider repayment for hours lost to lectures and asked him the most dreaded of all questions: &#8220;Can I borrow your car?&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, my father loves his car more than he loves his children, of this I am quite certain. Hours upon hours he spends babying the thing, carefully detailing it on his days off, making sure it&#8217;s beyond pristine. He&#8217;s so fastidious about his car that I normally refuse to ride in it for fear of somehow breaking it and being subjected to yet another lecture. I mean, I don&#8217;t breathe near the thing &#8211; my breath might contain something that could potentially damage it&#8217;s impeccable paint job. I don&#8217;t even look at the thing when I&#8217;m at my parents house, just in case my eyes somehow refract sunbeams onto the wrong spot and cause a dent.</p>
<p>So for me to ask to borrow it took a few Klonapin and a whole lot of &#8220;calm the balls down.&#8221; Honestly, I&#8217;d rather chug gasoline than ask him for this favor. He responded in a way most unlike him:</p>
<p>Not-So-Wee-AB: (deep breath) &#8220;Dad, can I borrow your car to get to work tomorrow in Not Chicago?&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;Yes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Not-So-Wee-AB: &#8220;Are you feeling okay?&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;I&#8217;m fine. Hey, you do know how to drive stick, right?&#8221;</p>
<p>Not-So-Wee-AB: &#8220;Yes, Dad, you taught me.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;And you were terrible.&#8221;</p>
<p>Not-So-Wee-AB: &#8220;No, I drove home in a winter storm. I&#8217;m excellent at working a manual &#8211; I miss the crapballs outta it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Dad: &#8220;Oh, that&#8217;s right. It&#8217;s the BIKE you had issues with. You were 11 before you could properly pedal.&#8221;</p>
<p>Not-So-Wee-AB: &#8220;Thanks for the reminder, Dad.&#8221;</p>
<p>Friday morning, bright and blurry, I drove my father&#8217;s car for the first time since he&#8217;d bought it, back when I was pregnant with Ben. And with the exception of the sixth gear, which I wasn&#8217;t accustomed to using, it was a blast.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s going to have a <em>heck</em> of a time dragging those keys out of my hands.</p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13984" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/iron-man/"     class="crp_title">Iron Man</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/it-is-always-better-to-stare-stupidly-at-a-problem-than-actually-fix-it/"     class="crp_title">It Is Always Better To Stare Stupidly At A Problem Than&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/where-the-sidewalk-ends/"     class="crp_title">Where The Sidewalk Ends.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/well-ive-only-kinda-ruined-summer/"     class="crp_title">Well, I&#8217;ve Only KINDA Ruined Summer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/three-dumbasses-drive-out-of-the-ghetto/"     class="crp_title">Three Dumbasses Drive OUT Of The Ghetto</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/id-rather-chug-gasoline/">I&#8217;d Rather Chug Gasoline</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/id-rather-chug-gasoline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Providence, Part Deux*</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence-part-deux/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence-part-deux/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[As Navel Grazing As I Wanna Be.]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13956</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t get the impression, Pranksters, that a lot of us hold much stock in the idea of Providence (always with a capitol &#8220;P&#8221;) because, well, we&#8217;re a little bit jaded. It&#8217;s hard to see a world in which so many bad things happen to good people and say &#8220;everything happens for a reason.&#8221; I [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence/"     class="crp_title">The Nervous Breakdown Chronicles: Providence</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/the-nervous-breakdown-chronicles-the-calm-before-the-shitstorm/"     class="crp_title">The Nervous Breakdown Chronicles: Sometimes, I Wonder What&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/aunt-becky-job-search/"     class="crp_title">Things I&#8217;ve Learned While Searching For Jobs</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/go-ask-aunt-becky-et-al/"     class="crp_title">Go Ask Aunt Becky Et Al</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/"     class="crp_title">Tears Dry On Their Own</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence-part-deux/">Providence, Part Deux*</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t get the impression, Pranksters, that a lot of us hold much stock in the idea of Providence (always with a capitol &#8220;P&#8221;) because, well, we&#8217;re a little bit jaded. It&#8217;s hard to see a world in which so many bad things happen to good people and say &#8220;everything happens for a reason.&#8221;</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t buy that statement.</p>
<p>What I do believe, as cynical as I can be, is that sometimes, <em>sometimes</em>, we&#8217;re given a nudge from the very most <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence/" target="_blank">unexpected of places</a>.</p>
<p>Providence, I suppose.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, I&#8217;d been chatting with <a title="Providence, Part Deux" href="http://ewokmama.com/" target="_blank">Crys</a>, who is not only my pseudo-shrink (read: I don&#8217;t pay her to listen to my babbling), but my friend, about jobs.</p>
<p>Crys: &#8220;I need to call this lady back about an interview.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;Oh yeah? What for? Toxic waste handling?&#8221;</p>
<p>Crys: &#8220;Hahahaha. No.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;What about being Billy Mays replacement? Or being the MOVIE PHONE guy?&#8221;</p>
<p>Crys: &#8220;Hahahaha. No.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;Okay, well, I&#8217;m out of ideas then.&#8221;</p>
<p>Crys: &#8220;I don&#8217;t even have the energy to call them back. I mean, I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m up to interviewing right now.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;*<em>nods</em>* Yeah, I get that. I&#8217;m burnt out on applying for jobs. I can&#8217;t even fathom trying to interview somewhere without shitting myself.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;Which I do every single time I get a text message. I also drop a remote, which is neither here nor there.&#8221;</p>
<p>Crys: &#8220;You&#8217;re so weird.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;I&#8217;ll take <strong>that</strong> as a compliment!&#8221;</p>
<p>After several hours of watching dancing cactus videos, my cell rang. A number I didn&#8217;t recognize, which is generally code for someone looking for my &#8220;expert&#8221; opinion on salt or attempting to guilt me into donating to the &#8220;People Affected By Sarah McLaughlin ASPCA Commercial,&#8221; so I tend not to answer.</p>
<p>For some reason, unbeknownst to me, I answered.</p>
<p>It was a friend of mine &#8211; we&#8217;d worked together as servers when Ben was a baby, sneaking off and chugging beers in the coolers during our breaks, causing mischief and mayhem wherever we went. Ah, the days of wine and roses.</p>
<p><em>*looks mistily off into the distance*</em></p>
<p>ANYWAY.</p>
<p>Her: &#8220;Hey, you still looking for work? The (insert rural hospital here) is hiring.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;Yes.&#8221;</p>
<p>Her: &#8220;Okay, here&#8217;s my boss.&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;?&#8230;?&#8221;</p>
<p><em>*cue annoying hold music*</em></p>
<p>Boss: &#8220;When can you come in to interview?&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;I can make time any day that works for you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Boss: &#8220;Tomorrow, 10AM, okay?&#8221;</p>
<p>Me: *<em>does happy dance</em>*</p>
<p>See, Pranksters, I&#8217;ve been working on finding gainful employment since July, when The &#8220;D&#8221; Word was made official. I&#8217;ve written resumes, studied how best to create one. I&#8217;ve had friends read them and editors examine them. I&#8217;ve applied to places until my fingers were cut to the bone. And? Nothing. Nada. Zilch.</p>
<p><em>Zippity-motherfucking-doo-dah.</em></p>
<p>Now, don&#8217;t get me wrong, Pranksters &#8211; I love blogging like I love diet Coke, but I want to be able to come here, stare at a blank WordPress box and fill it with words. With stories. With tales <em>this</em> side of normal.</p>
<p>What I don&#8217;t (and have never) wanted to have to do was to resort to blogging as a means to pay the bills. While I&#8217;m entirely aware that <a title="Providence, Part Deux" href="http://dooce.com" target="_blank">Dooce</a> can and does, we <em>all</em> know I&#8217;m no Dooce.</p>
<p>When I&#8217;m staring at a blank WordPress box, trying to come up with an extraordinarily dull tale in order to &#8220;put something; anything up here,&#8221; a fat wad of <strong>nothing</strong> fills my brain. When I tell that motherfucking organ to get all creative, it tells me to shut the fuck up. Trying to force creativity is akin to putting flippers on a monkey &#8211; it <em>can</em> be done, but why should it?</p>
<p>So that call? That, right there, was Providence. With a Capitol P.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been blogging, you see Pranksters, since Jesus rode me to class on his handlebars and gave me noogies on the playground behind the slides, and I&#8217;ve watched the evolution of blogging as a way to tell our tales into a way to &#8220;get famous&#8221; and &#8220;make monies,&#8221; by allowing advertisers to pay us pennies to promote their product.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s not a damn thing wrong with that, I should add, it&#8217;s just not why <em>I</em> started to write.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also not why I continue to write. My space is my own and I want it to remain that way &#8211; I don&#8217;t want to be a corporate shill for a shitty product and I don&#8217;t want to be a &#8220;brand.&#8221; I&#8217;m me. I&#8217;m really Aunt (Motherfucking) Becky, and I&#8217;m really real. End of fucking story.</p>
<p>By taking a job at a hospital in the real world, where people are judged by their merit, not by number of &#8220;fans&#8221; or &#8220;comments,&#8221; I&#8217;ve inadvertently liberated myself from the business end of blogging. An unexpected side effect, I suppose.</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t be happier to be back.</p>
<p>And without you, Pranksters, I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;d be standing today. I hope you know just how much you mean to me. You&#8217;re my family and without you, I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;d have survived the Dark Time.</p>
<p>Now if you&#8217;ll excuse me, I have something in my eye.</p>
<p>Damn allergies.</p>
<address style="text-align: right;">*two</address>
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<address>What&#8217;s been going on since I&#8217;ve been away, Pranksters? How are you?</address>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13956" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence/"     class="crp_title">The Nervous Breakdown Chronicles: Providence</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/the-nervous-breakdown-chronicles-the-calm-before-the-shitstorm/"     class="crp_title">The Nervous Breakdown Chronicles: Sometimes, I Wonder What&hellip;</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/aunt-becky-job-search/"     class="crp_title">Things I&#8217;ve Learned While Searching For Jobs</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/go-ask-aunt-becky-et-al/"     class="crp_title">Go Ask Aunt Becky Et Al</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/"     class="crp_title">Tears Dry On Their Own</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence-part-deux/">Providence, Part Deux*</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/providence-part-deux/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Somehow, I Don&#8217;t Think This Is What My Mother Meant</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/somehow-i-dont-think-this-is-what-my-mother-meant/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/somehow-i-dont-think-this-is-what-my-mother-meant/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 00:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daddy's Little Girl Loves Disco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13948</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>First things first, Pranksters &#8211; allow me to answer the two most burningest questions on your mind: Yes, I did get a job, but I have yet to find myself craving Mr. Rogers sweaters or penny loafers, nor have I decided that a &#8220;five year plan&#8221; is worth my brain power, so it&#8217;s safe to [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/"     class="crp_title">Tears Dry On Their Own</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/when-refrigerators-attack/"     class="crp_title">When Refrigerators Attack</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/my-mother-the-drug-dealer/"     class="crp_title">My Mother, The Drug Dealer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/pranksters-id-like-you-to-meet-my-new-boyfriend/"     class="crp_title">Pranksters, I&#8217;d Like You To Meet My New Boyfriend</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommy-drinks-because-you-lie/"     class="crp_title">Mommy Drinks Because You Lie</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/somehow-i-dont-think-this-is-what-my-mother-meant/">Somehow, I Don&#8217;t Think This Is What My Mother Meant</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First things first, Pranksters &#8211; allow me to answer the two most burningest questions on your mind:</p>
<p><em>Yes</em>, I <em>did</em> get a job, but I have yet to find myself craving Mr. Rogers sweaters or penny loafers, nor have I decided that a &#8220;five year plan&#8221; is worth my brain power, so it&#8217;s safe to say that I still haven&#8217;t grown up. More on that another time when I have more than two misfiring synapses to work with.</p>
<p>No, I have not gotten less annoying. Sorry. Thems be the breaks, I guess.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I was probably five or six the first time my mother threatened me: &#8220;Rebecca,&#8221; she said sternly after I&#8217;d chosen to repaint her dull white walls with some beautiful markers and my most prized stickers. I&#8217;d thought that a picture of my unicorn, Mr. Snuffles was a fabulous addition to our dining room, but she, apparently felt otherwise, because she finished the lecture by throwing up her hands and yelling, exasperated, &#8220;someday, you&#8217;re going to grow up and have a child just like you.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">She said it ominously enough that I paid attention until I realized what she was saying.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;No,&#8221; I replied, all big eyes and curly hair. &#8220;I&#8217;m going to have a robot. I don&#8217;t like babies.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">She just stared at me, until she huffed off to her room to center herself by playing some depressing music. Turns out? She was right.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This weekend, I spent a good deal of my time doing the second, and most important part of any move.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">(I know, I know, I&#8217;ve lived here since October, but trust me when I say that when it comes to funk, I am a junkie. Also: horrifyingly depressed)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I began to unpack the items I&#8217;d stowed in cupboards and closets when I was in the frantic, &#8220;OMG UNPACK, UNPACK! THE SPANISH ARE COMING!&#8221; stage of the move. Once everything was assembled and the resident OCD apartment owner a couple of buildings over had suitably drilled the whole, &#8220;do not recycle big boxes&#8221; thing into my head, I sat down. I didn&#8217;t really get up again for four months.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">For those four months, I was The Ghost of Apartment 6B, shutting my blinds, and staring off into space. I&#8217;d shuffle to the computer to occasionally peck out a post and apply for some jobs when I wasn&#8217;t feeling suicidal, then shuffle back to the couch and pretend this was all a bad dream.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">It, as I don&#8217;t have to point out to you, Pranksters, wasn&#8217;t.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">So this weekend, I got off my ass and got to work whipping my house into the approximate shape of a home, which meant that I spent a great deal of time wondering why on earth I&#8217;d packed this or that, puzzling over the reasons the cupboards could possibly be sticky, and trying to turn my life into, well, a life worth living. I&#8217;m not stupid enough to say &#8220;the dark days are over,&#8221; quite yet, but I know I&#8217;ve turned some sort of corner, and for that, I&#8217;m grateful.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">My daughter wandered into the Batcave while I was organizing some of my jewelry. It was time to go through a massive purge, and I&#8217;d figured that there was no time like the present to do so.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Oooooooh!&#8221; she squealed loudly as she saw all the &#8220;pretties&#8221; I&#8217;d pulled out of one of my jewelry boxes. &#8220;That&#8217;s so BEAUTIFUL, Mama!&#8221; Her rapture was unlike anything I&#8217;d seen, unless I&#8217;d been looking in the mirror after a particularly wonderful sale.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I took a break from untangling a knot that was probably tied by a roving gang of sailors while I was sleeping and sat back and watched my daughter marvel at the pretties with me. Her unbridled joy made my heart grow about twenty sizes.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Mimi,&#8221; I said. &#8220;Would you like your own jewelry box to put your jewelry in?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Oh MAMA,&#8221; she breathed in deeply. &#8220;That would be beautiful. How about I take this one?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I laughed &#8211; that one was my favorite too.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;How about we find you your own jewelry box? You can store your pretties in here until I find you one, okay?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">She grinned, ear to ear, and then wrapped me in her spindly arms.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Oh, MAMA,&#8221; she said. &#8220;THANK YOU!&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I beamed into her hair, feeling, for the first time in a long time, that same unbridled sense of joy that was oozing from her pores. This was <strong>truly</strong> one of the happiest moments of my life.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Do you like the pretty picture of kittens I drew on your wall?&#8221; she asked daintily. &#8220;I used PINK! My favorite color! And Hello Kitty stickers!&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">&#8220;Let&#8217;s take a look at it, Mimi!&#8221; I suggested, my legs creaking and groaning as I got up off the floor, still smiling.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">A child after my own likeness, indeed.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/Amelia-party-dress.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-11030" alt="Amelia party dress" src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/Amelia-party-dress.jpg" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Now, if you&#8217;ll excuse me, Pranksters, I&#8217;m off to find some costume jewelry to fill up my daughter&#8217;s new jewelry box.</p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13948" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/"     class="crp_title">Tears Dry On Their Own</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/when-refrigerators-attack/"     class="crp_title">When Refrigerators Attack</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/my-mother-the-drug-dealer/"     class="crp_title">My Mother, The Drug Dealer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/pranksters-id-like-you-to-meet-my-new-boyfriend/"     class="crp_title">Pranksters, I&#8217;d Like You To Meet My New Boyfriend</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommy-drinks-because-you-lie/"     class="crp_title">Mommy Drinks Because You Lie</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/somehow-i-dont-think-this-is-what-my-mother-meant/">Somehow, I Don&#8217;t Think This Is What My Mother Meant</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/somehow-i-dont-think-this-is-what-my-mother-meant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tears Dry On Their Own</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 17:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging About Blogging Makes Me a Douche]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13940</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you&#8217;re a blogger, most conversations with people outside of the computer go something like this: Them: &#8220;So now that I&#8217;ve finished telling you about the luxury yacht I just bought with the interest from my accounts, what is it that you do again? Me: &#8220;I&#8217;m a writer.&#8221; Them: &#8220;Oh? That&#8217;s positively charming. Where do [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/when-refrigerators-attack/"     class="crp_title">When Refrigerators Attack</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/my-mother-the-drug-dealer/"     class="crp_title">My Mother, The Drug Dealer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/pranksters-id-like-you-to-meet-my-new-boyfriend/"     class="crp_title">Pranksters, I&#8217;d Like You To Meet My New Boyfriend</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/go-ask-aunt-becky-89/"     class="crp_title">Go Ask Aunt Becky</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommy-drinks-because-you-lie/"     class="crp_title">Mommy Drinks Because You Lie</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/">Tears Dry On Their Own</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you&#8217;re a blogger, most conversations with people outside of the computer go something like this:</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;So now that I&#8217;ve finished telling you about the luxury yacht I just bought with the interest from my accounts, what is it that you do again?</p>
<p>Me: &#8220;I&#8217;m a writer.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Oh? That&#8217;s positively <em>charming</em>. Where do you write?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;Erms. It&#8217;s a blog.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Pardon me?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;I write on the Internet.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Are you like those dreadful people of Walmart?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;Heh-Heh. No. I write for a site of my own.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;I&#8217;m not certain I understand.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;It&#8217;s called Mommy Wants Vodka. I write drivel and dreck about my life.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Oh, so (<em>whispers</em>) you have a drinking problem?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;Ha. No. It&#8217;s sarcastic. <em>Mommy Wants Vodka: because Mommy Wants Vicodin Sounded Too Suburban.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: (blank stare) &#8220;I&#8217;m not certain I follow. How can writing a diary online be a &#8216;job?&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;Well, it&#8217;s not. I also freelance for The Stir and Nickelodean. One time I got fifty likes from The Facebook!&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: (blank stare): &#8220;So you sit around all day writing?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;On a good day, yeah. See lookit! I even have business cards. Do you want one?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Oh, no dear. I wouldn&#8217;t put you out like that.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;It&#8217;s truly no trouble.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;I was being polite &#8211; what<em>ever</em> would I do with your card?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;It makes a good coaster, I guess.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them (<em>titters</em>): &#8220;Oh you&#8217;ve always been SO FUNNY.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: (<em>quizzically</em>): &#8220;Um. Thanks?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;I&#8217;m afraid I still don&#8217;t understand what it is, exactly, that you do.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;Well, once I got named one of the top ten controversial bloggers by Babble.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;You&#8217;re not particularly controversial.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;I know. I should have more opinions about things.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them (<em>twitters a bit</em>): &#8220;So when are you going to grow up?&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;I&#8217;m 32. I have three kids.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;No, I mean, you can&#8217;t simply write about your life forever. You&#8217;ll need a real job &#8211; with benefits!&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: *shrugs* &#8220;I like what I do.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;No, it&#8217;s really true &#8211; you need to grow up. That way we can go do pretentious things together.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me (<em>sarcastically</em>): &#8220;Wow. That sounds <strong>fun</strong>.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Oh, it is, darling. It <em>is</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;It&#8217;s been *uh* swell seeing you.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Them: &#8220;Do call me when you grow up, darling.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Me: &#8220;But.. I <em>am</em> a grown-up&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And then you walk away feeling like total garbage because YOU HAVE BUSINESS CARDS, DAMMIT, and sometimes people leave you comments and you have FRIENDS! All over the world! How cool is that?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">(answer: pretty fucking rad)</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">But then one day, you wake up, look around at your apartment, which you&#8217;ve carefully decorated, and realize, &#8220;shit, they were right &#8211; I DO need to grow up.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I start Monday.</p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13940" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/when-refrigerators-attack/"     class="crp_title">When Refrigerators Attack</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/my-mother-the-drug-dealer/"     class="crp_title">My Mother, The Drug Dealer</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/pranksters-id-like-you-to-meet-my-new-boyfriend/"     class="crp_title">Pranksters, I&#8217;d Like You To Meet My New Boyfriend</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/go-ask-aunt-becky-89/"     class="crp_title">Go Ask Aunt Becky</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mommy-drinks-because-you-lie/"     class="crp_title">Mommy Drinks Because You Lie</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/">Tears Dry On Their Own</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/us-and-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/four/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/four/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 17:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Proof That Aunt Becky Has Feelings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>My Girl, Today at 4:3&#8230;uh, erms, *mumbles incoherently* you will be four years old. The squishy maternal part of me wants to throw you back into a onesie and one of those wee diapers that nearly engulfs your tiny bum and turn back the clock four years to the time when my youngest baby was [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/robin-waits-on-the-sidewalk/"     class="crp_title">Robin Waits On The Sidewalk</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/life-unexpected/"     class="crp_title">Life, Unexpected</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/on-behalf-of-my-daughter-amelia/"     class="crp_title">On Behalf Of My Daughter, Amelia</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/maternity/"     class="crp_title">Maternity</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mockingbird/"     class="crp_title">Mockingbird</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/four/">Four</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My Girl,</p>
<p>Today at 4:3&#8230;uh, erms, *<em>mumbles incoherently</em>* you will be four years old.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Robin-Waits-In-The-Car-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13573" alt="robin waits on the sidewalk" src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Robin-Waits-In-The-Car-2.jpg" width="338" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>The squishy maternal part of me wants to throw you back into a onesie and one of those wee diapers that nearly engulfs your tiny bum and turn back the clock four years to the time when my youngest baby was <em>actually</em> a baby. The other part of me wonders how it&#8217;s only been four years since you rocketed into this chaotic world.</p>
<p>I still have to pinch myself to make sure that I&#8217;m not dreaming &#8211; I have a daughter. Me! A daughter! I&#8217;d always expected my household to be full of boys, stinky socks, and fart jokes (I&#8217;d also planned to name house plants after my television husbands, which, frankly, is neither here nor there). I never expected to be <strong>lucky</strong> enough to become the mother of a daughter.</p>
<p>But here we are, four years into it, and I can&#8217;t imagine my life without you by my side.</p>
<p>I wanted to start this letter to you, my Sweet Girl, by telling you how sorry I am. I wish that things between your Dad and I had managed to work themselves out. I know it&#8217;s confusing right now and I know it well, but I have to believe that this is what&#8217;s best for everyone. My hope is that you&#8217;ll learn from this experience that you should never settle for anything less than what you deserve out of life, out of a partner, and that you won&#8217;t be afraid to say &#8220;no, this isn&#8217;t working,&#8221; and change your life.</p>
<p>Because you, me, everyone &#8211; we <em>all</em> deserve the very best. That&#8217;s why you&#8217;ve got to take life by the balls, make it your bitch and never let anything get in your way. Ever.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re more like me than simply the way we look. We both share the opinion that glitter is mandatory for something to be truly beautiful, you happily wear a pair of ridiculously adorable and incredibly uncomfortable shoes just because they&#8217;re pretty, and you don&#8217;t sway your opinion, once your mind has been made up. You&#8217;re a spitfire of a person, and you&#8217;re going to be one hell of a lady. Surviving the insurmountable odds that you did, well, I can&#8217;t help but wonder what you&#8217;ve been put on this planet to do.</p>
<p>I can hardly wait to find out.</p>
<p>My Girl, I hope that you learn to stand tall and stand proud, knowing that what you do is <em>exactly</em> what you&#8217;re supposed to be doing. Don&#8217;t let anyone else tell you different. Take criticism as a sign to do more, be better, and show people what you&#8217;re made of. Don&#8217;t stoop to spreading rumors, calling names, or lying to make a point  &#8211; it&#8217;s unbecoming and it&#8217;s tacky. Knowing that you&#8217;re in the right, well, that is enough.</p>
<p>Never let anyone tell you how you&#8217;re &#8220;supposed&#8221; to look or feel &#8211; your feelings are your own, looks change, and if someone thinks that you&#8217;re &#8220;supposed&#8221; to be doing something different, well, it&#8217;s clear that they don&#8217;t know you. Truly their loss.</p>
<p>Loves in your life may come and go, sort of like busboys filling your water in a crowded restaurant, but the greatest love, and the one person you matter to most, well, she&#8217;s not going anywhere. That would be <em>you</em>, Lovie. You don&#8217;t need the love of anyone but yourself to make it through the day, and if someone makes you feel otherwise, he or she isn&#8217;t worth your time or energy.</p>
<p>Accept that your journey may never be easy, and if it&#8217;s not, don&#8217;t fight it. This is your life, your story, and you can be the victim or you can be the hero &#8211; your call. Use your experiences to help others; to be better, rather than wallowing in your story. Grieve your losses, nurse your wounds, and come back to the world better and stronger than ever.</p>
<p>Be kind to those you meet, even if they are unkind to you. You never will know how that spot of kindness will affect those around you. No act of kindness is too small.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t take people at who they say they are; their actions will speak volumes while their words are just those: words. Accept one unalienable truth: most people <em>are</em> good, and no matter how angry you are at them, know that they were simply doing the best they could. Same as anyone else.</p>
<p>Speaking of choices, don&#8217;t put too much stock in the wrong ones you make. Mistakes are your way of learning what works and what does not, and what you learn from the wrong choices you make is often volumes larger than you do from the right ones.</p>
<p>Never be too proud to apologize when you&#8217;ve hurt someone. You don&#8217;t need to crawl to the Alter of Your Wrongness, but you should always own up to what you&#8217;ve done and how you&#8217;ve hurt someone. They can choose to accept your apology or ignore it, but either way, you&#8217;ve done your best to make things right.</p>
<p>And when you&#8217;re done, my sweet thing, changing the world, don&#8217;t forget to call your Mom. She loves you so.</p>
<p>Love always,</p>
<p>Mama</p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13912" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/robin-waits-on-the-sidewalk/"     class="crp_title">Robin Waits On The Sidewalk</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/life-unexpected/"     class="crp_title">Life, Unexpected</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/on-behalf-of-my-daughter-amelia/"     class="crp_title">On Behalf Of My Daughter, Amelia</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/maternity/"     class="crp_title">Maternity</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/mockingbird/"     class="crp_title">Mockingbird</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/four/">Four</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/four/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solving for Zero</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/crossed-wires/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/crossed-wires/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Cat Lady]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13898</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Sorting through my stuff after I&#8217;d moved into the FBI Surveillance Van, I came across a picture taken many years ago. One of my Pranksters had suggested that I find a truly happy picture of myself and put it somewhere important to remind myself that there is happiness to be had again, so I slapped [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/toddler-sings-britney-spears-criminal/"     class="crp_title">Who&#8217;s In Love With A Criminal?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wayback-machine/"     class="crp_title">Wayback Machine</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/ill-have-to-say-i-love-you-in-a-blog/"     class="crp_title">I&#8217;ll Have To Say I Love You In A Blog</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/its-never-ever-safe-to-sleep/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s Never, EVER Safe To Sleep.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/dating-sucks-but-so-does-becoming-the-crazy-hot-dog-lady/"     class="crp_title">Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Hot Dog Lady</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/crossed-wires/">Solving for Zero</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorting through my stuff after I&#8217;d moved into the FBI Surveillance Van, I came across a picture taken many years ago. One of my Pranksters had suggested that I find a truly happy picture of myself and put it somewhere important to remind myself that there is happiness to be had again, so I slapped it onto my fridge. That way, when I go for my diet Coke, I&#8217;m stuck looking at a happier version of me.</p>
<p>The picture had been taken years ago, during a party at my parents house.</p>
<p>Being a server meant that, because everyone else on the planet was snuggled up in their wee beds, we were like an insta-party &#8211; just add booze. Every night, we&#8217;d go out to clubs, bars, or (rarely) party at someone&#8217;s house.</p>
<p>That night, my parents were out of town, which meant it was party at Becky&#8217;s. We managed to invite everyone &#8211; bar patrons, serving staff, friends of friends, restaurant managers, you name it, we were there. The picture from that night had been taken by one of those old disposable cameras, and clearly shows me with my arms around a dude, smiling brightly into the camera, his arms still in the air, caught before he&#8217;d had a chance to put them around me.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a fitting picture, I think, for our relationship, which had begun years before.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d met Mikey at my first job: an upscale dining establishment that had been around since the beginning of time, where I, not yet 18, was a hostess. He, also not yet 18, was a busboy. We struck up a friendship of sorts, at least, the sort of friendship you have with someone you are also crushing on. And <em>boy</em>, was I crushing.</p>
<p>The guy had everything that made my young heart go pitter-patter in my chest: he was wryly funny, clever, could, upon occasion, be sweet, was kind, and showed me the little things in life.</p>
<p>Once, I remember, when we were both old enough to serve liquor, we spent the 4th of July working the outside part of the sprawling restaurant complex, serving beer in plastic cups and nachos with day-glow cheese so bright it nearly glowed in the dark. I&#8217;d just come out of the bathroom, where I&#8217;d been sneaking a smoke, when he grabbed my arm and led me across the pond, not speaking, refusing to answer my question, &#8220;Where the fuck are we going?&#8221;</p>
<p>Eventually, we stopped. He turned my shoulders so that I was facing North.</p>
<p>&#8220;Look,&#8221; he said. And I did.</p>
<p>From that vantage point, we could see the fireworks going off in three separate towns, peppering the sky with shimmery reds, whites, and blues. I breathed in, deeply, happily. It was <em>beautiful</em>.</p>
<p>Mikey was <em>always</em> doing shit like that. When I dyed my hair a terrible shade of red by accident, he insisted that I come over for an inspection right away. There, in the hot sunlight, he peered at my hair, studying it. &#8220;I like it,&#8221; he finally said. &#8220;It suits you.&#8221;</p>
<p>We stayed friends after my first son was born, he and I driving around late at night, the baby strapped in the backseat, soothed by the music I played and the gentle rocking of the car. We&#8217;d get out, now and again, to look at the stars, far away from the lights of the city, the silence filling the air deafening as the baby slumbered on.</p>
<p>I often pictured life together, he and I. Raising my son. Helping each other grow and learn. Relying on the other to remind us to do better; be better. I never spoke these words to him, of course, because, I suppose, I didn&#8217;t know if we <em>could</em> solve for zero. Knowing that some words, once spoken, can&#8217;t be unspoken.</p>
<p>With him, I was never sure where I stood. <em>Did he like me? Did he like me as a friend? Did he respect me? Did he love me</em>?</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t answer those questions. In small part, because I didn&#8217;t want to know the answer and in larger, more annoying part, because I don&#8217;t think he even knew the answer. Trying to decipher Mikey was like trying to solve for zero &#8211; <em>impossible</em> unless you know the other factors. And I never did.</p>
<p>Eventually, after seven years of friendship, it happened. One drunk night, we hooked up. It was nothing I&#8217;d dreamed of. No romance, no courtship, no flowers, no nothing. Wham, bam, thank you ma&#8217;am. Entirely unlike either of us.</p>
<p>After that night, nothing was the same. I wanted more. He did not. But, of course, these words remained unspoken, probably because we finally understood where the other was coming from.</p>
<p>Things finally came to a head seven years after I&#8217;d met him. I&#8217;d been invited to an unveiling of Sam Adams Light in the city and G Love, one of my favorite bands, was playing. Having some extra tickets, I, of course, invited Mikey. Ten of us crawled inside the limo that was already full of booze and we began the party before the party began. By the time we arrived at the club, we were all toast.</p>
<p>Mikey chose this opportunity to start hitting on my friend and coworker. I pretended not to see.</p>
<p>That is, until he began to tell me, in his drunken stupor how much he liked her, and began to grill me for her phone number. Disgusted, I took off and wobbled in my heels down to Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll McDonald&#8217;s to &#8220;catch some air&#8221; and &#8220;eat a cheeseburger.&#8221; When I returned, he was still all over my friend, who was trying her best to dissuade him.</p>
<p>I rolled my eyes.</p>
<p>In the limo going home, we were all silent. That is, except for Mikey, who was <em>still</em> drunkenly hitting on my friend.</p>
<p>The next time I saw Mikey, we&#8217;d gone out to the golf course where we&#8217;d once watched the sunset on the 9th hole, a couple of friends along for the ride. Once again, he asked after my friend, specifically for her phone number. I stared at him.</p>
<p>Seven years.</p>
<p>Seven fucking years.</p>
<p>For seven fucking years I&#8217;d held this guy in the highest regard, never solving for zero, never asking after the formula, always assuming that we were &#8220;meant to be&#8221; or some happy-crappy bullshit.</p>
<p>At that moment, I knew that it was over; I&#8217;d never solve for zero, not with him.</p>
<p>He continued to look at me as I stared, not quite understanding my behavior. Finally, I spoke, &#8220;Mikey, you&#8217;re either an idiot or an asshole. Either way, I don&#8217;t need you in my life.&#8221;</p>
<p>Flipping the bird in his general direction, I turned heel and walked off across the perfectly maintained lawn, chastising myself, knowing he&#8217;d never follow. It simply wasn&#8217;t who he was.</p>
<p>Slamming my foot on the clutch and starting the car, it dawned on me.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d <strong>finally</strong> solved for zero.</p>
<p><object width="450" height="338" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0">
<param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" />
<param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" />
<param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/epy384Gc9Ic?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0" />
<param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed width="450" height="338" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/epy384Gc9Ic?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0" allowFullScreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /></object></p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13898" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/toddler-sings-britney-spears-criminal/"     class="crp_title">Who&#8217;s In Love With A Criminal?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wayback-machine/"     class="crp_title">Wayback Machine</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/ill-have-to-say-i-love-you-in-a-blog/"     class="crp_title">I&#8217;ll Have To Say I Love You In A Blog</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/its-never-ever-safe-to-sleep/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s Never, EVER Safe To Sleep.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/dating-sucks-but-so-does-becoming-the-crazy-hot-dog-lady/"     class="crp_title">Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Hot Dog Lady</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/crossed-wires/">Solving for Zero</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/crossed-wires/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Like Chatroulette But With Less Wang</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 17:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beaver Talk With Aunt Becky]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13874</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Do you remember Chatroulette, Pranksters? I only came across it back when I was writing online sex shop reviews for Toy With Me and searching for an angle to cover. If you have NO idea what I&#8217;m talking about, lemmie give you the very briefest of rundowns to the very best of my dwindling brain [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/toddler-sings-britney-spears-criminal/"     class="crp_title">Who&#8217;s In Love With A Criminal?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wayback-machine/"     class="crp_title">Wayback Machine</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/dating-sucks-but-so-does-becoming-the-crazy-hot-dog-lady/"     class="crp_title">Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Hot Dog Lady</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/its-never-ever-safe-to-sleep/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s Never, EVER Safe To Sleep.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/while-i-was-not-dead-i-did-this/"     class="crp_title">While I Was Not Dead, I Did This</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/">Like Chatroulette But With Less Wang</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you remember Chatroulette, Pranksters?</p>
<p>I only came across it back when I was writing <a title="online sex shop" href="http://www.loverinthebox.com" target="_blank">online sex shop</a> reviews for Toy With Me and searching for an angle to cover. If you have NO idea what I&#8217;m talking about, lemmie give you the very briefest of rundowns to the very best of my dwindling brain capacity.</p>
<p>Chatroulette was created by some college kid in (I believe) Russia who had the grand idea to create a site in which you could talk to various people around the globe via webcam. Neat, right? But you <em>do</em> see problem inherent, don&#8217;t you, Pranksters? THIS IS THE INTERNET WE&#8217;RE TALKING ABOUT.</p>
<p>If you have no idea what I mean by that, well, let&#8217;s just say, Internet = Penis-Galore.</p>
<p>So you could pop on your webcam and, in theory, make friends across the globe, so that you and your new-found globular friends could join hands and sing &#8220;We Are The World&#8221; a-Capella. In <strong>theory</strong>. Like communism. In <strong>theory</strong>.</p>
<p>If you got bored with the person you were talking to, you could simply switch to someone else to chat with&#8230;. except it didn&#8217;t work out so well. Basically, a Chatroulette session showed many a teenage girl what, exactly, a creepers pervert and his trouser snake looked like. Over. And. Fucking. Over. Sometimes, the mystique was, you&#8217;d manage to meet a celeb. IN <strong>THEORY</strong>.</p>
<p>This probably explains Chatroulette better than I can (is safe for work. Probably):<br />
<object width="450" height="253" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0">
<param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" />
<param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" />
<param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/0bBkuFqKsd0?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" />
<param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed width="450" height="253" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/0bBkuFqKsd0?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" allowFullScreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /></object></p>
<p>What you just saw, Pranksters, is Chatroulette at it&#8217;s finest. Apparently, the site&#8217;s still around to disgust the masses (just like this <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="http://mommywantsvodka.com/" target="_blank">one</a>!)</p>
<p>(holy long-winded intro, Batman!)</p>
<p>When Google Plus came out, I was all, <em>why the balls am I getting invites to another social media network? Is this Google&#8217;s version of <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="http://facebook.com/mommywantsvodka" target="_blank">The Facebook</a>? Why does my cat wipe his ass on the carpet? What the fuck is a hobby?</em></p>
<p>(pointless and un-pithy aside: I&#8217;m a firm believer that one can be good at between one and three social media platforms, but no more).</p>
<p>Most people who signed up with Google Plus were all, &#8220;<em>daar, this isn&#8217;t Facebook</em>,&#8221; and rather than just go back to where they came from (read: The Facebook) to continue playing with their fake farms, they complained bitterly about how G+ wasn&#8217;t Facebook. All over G+. That&#8217;s a fuck-ton of energy wasted right there.</p>
<p>Initially, I gave G+ the good old &#8220;meh,&#8221; and went back to <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="http://twitter.com/mommywantsvodka" target="_blank">The Twitter </a>to spew my garbage in 140 characters or less. I had a couple G+ accounts because I have 76 email addresses for no good reason which meant that I inadvertently had 76 G+ accounts. But considering half of what I saw on there were those lame-ass picture quotes (like so):</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/chatroulette/" rel="attachment wp-att-13880"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13880" alt="chatroulette" src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Chatroulette.jpg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Okay, so <em>generally</em> the quotes are more like this:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/chatroulette-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-13881"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13881" alt="Chatroulette 2" src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Chatroulette-2.jpg" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Erms, sorta.</p>
<p>In my head it went something like this: &#8220;G+ is like Pinterest but with dudes.&#8221;</p>
<p>That was, of course, until the night of the Sandy Hook shooting. Since, as most of you are aware, I work for <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="http://www.bandbacktogether.com/all-posts/" target="_blank">The Band Back Together Project</a>, we decided that it would be a good night for us to do a G+ hangout to discuss our grief. That lasted 10 minutes before a bunch of people showed up and we got to know people, literally, around the world.</p>
<p>We&#8217;d been using G+ to conduct our board meetings for ages, but somehow, we&#8217;d never managed to connect that to the idea that there might be new and exciting people on Google Plus who did new and exciting things, like &#8220;NOT SHOW THE WORLD THEIR PEEN.&#8221; It was a fucking Internet Miracle.</p>
<p>If you have any doubts of it&#8217;s randomness, check out this video (skip to minute 1), taken by a friend of mine who&#8217;d been live-screening this G+ chat on YouTube (if you skip around, you can see how bizarre it is).</p>
<p><object width="450" height="253" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0">
<param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" />
<param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" />
<param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/1TEQTkyNMlY?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" />
<param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed width="450" height="253" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/1TEQTkyNMlY?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" allowFullScreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /></object></p>
<p>So if&#8217;n you&#8217;re ever on G+ and want to chat, here&#8217;s <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/b/102312735174095617096/102312735174095617096/posts" target="_blank">my page</a> and <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/104717128031475975329/posts" target="_blank">my profile</a>. I&#8217;ve made a couple of communities for us (one for <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/b/102312735174095617096/communities/103343219946885057207" target="_blank">mah blog</a> and one for<a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/b/102312735174095617096/communities/106979540267623889962" target="_blank"> Teh Band</a>) so we can hang out together and, quite frankly, I&#8217;d love to meet you, Pranksters. <a title="like chatroulette but with less wang" href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/b/102312735174095617096/communities/106979540267623889962" target="_blank">The Band community</a> is hosting a hangout tonight at 7CST and I&#8217;ll be there.</p>
<p>Gaps in geography means that it&#8217;s hard to really hang out, unless, of course, we do it online. And so, we make our way into the future. A future with less peen and more community.</p>
<p>I gotta say, it looks pretty bright from here.</p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13874" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/toddler-sings-britney-spears-criminal/"     class="crp_title">Who&#8217;s In Love With A Criminal?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wayback-machine/"     class="crp_title">Wayback Machine</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/dating-sucks-but-so-does-becoming-the-crazy-hot-dog-lady/"     class="crp_title">Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Hot Dog Lady</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/its-never-ever-safe-to-sleep/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s Never, EVER Safe To Sleep.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/while-i-was-not-dead-i-did-this/"     class="crp_title">While I Was Not Dead, I Did This</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/">Like Chatroulette But With Less Wang</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-chatroulette-but-with-less-wang/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Like Some Passing Afternoon</title>
		<link>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-some-passing-afternoon/</link>
		<comments>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-some-passing-afternoon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 16:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Aunt Becky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Free To Be You + Me]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?p=13859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>There are very few questions I detest more than &#8220;Are you okay?&#8221; (Runners up include: &#8220;Where are your pants?&#8221; &#8220;Why do you hate thousand island dressing?&#8221; and the statement, &#8220;I&#8217;m worried about you.&#8221;) I must&#8217;ve asked that question to thousands of people over the years, especially when I was serving. The standard greeting of a [...]<div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/toddler-sings-britney-spears-criminal/"     class="crp_title">Who&#8217;s In Love With A Criminal?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wayback-machine/"     class="crp_title">Wayback Machine</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/its-never-ever-safe-to-sleep/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s Never, EVER Safe To Sleep.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/ill-have-to-say-i-love-you-in-a-blog/"     class="crp_title">I&#8217;ll Have To Say I Love You In A Blog</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/dating-sucks-but-so-does-becoming-the-crazy-hot-dog-lady/"     class="crp_title">Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Hot Dog Lady</a></li></ul></div></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-some-passing-afternoon/">Like Some Passing Afternoon</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are very few questions I detest more than &#8220;<strong>Are you okay</strong>?&#8221;</p>
<p>(Runners up include: &#8220;Where are your pants?&#8221; &#8220;Why do you hate thousand island dressing?&#8221; and the statement, &#8220;I&#8217;m worried about you.&#8221;)</p>
<p>I must&#8217;ve asked that question to thousands of people over the years, especially when I was serving. The standard greeting of a new table was something like, &#8220;Hi, my name is Becky and I&#8217;ll be taking care of you tonight. How is everyone doing?&#8221; 999/1000 times people would reply with the standard, &#8220;We&#8217;re doing fine&#8221; or &#8220;What the fuck kinda name is &#8220;Becky?&#8221;"</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re in the weeds, slammed beyond control, have one eye on the three tables you haven&#8217;t yet greeted that are looking around for you, the bartender yelling at you across the restaurant that he&#8217;s somehow out of sour mix and you just heard your second set of dinners hit the line, you don&#8217;t really have the time for more detailed interaction with people.</p>
<p>That 0.001% of people, though, responded with something to the effect of, &#8220;I&#8217;m alive,&#8221; or &#8220;do you really want to know the answer to that?&#8221; When you&#8217;re juggling three sections and dealing with half a kitchen that&#8217;s doing the YMCA (<em>en espanol</em>)(which really makes you want to join them) instead of cooking your food and you can&#8217;t find spoons for the coffee you just brewed after dumping out the last of the coffee and cleaning the maker, and trying to figure out how, exactly someone drinks an amaretto stone sour without yacking, you don&#8217;t have the time for personals. Even if you wanted to.</p>
<p>Because you walked in that day wondering if you&#8217;d be making enough to cover formula, diapers and gas to get to school, you&#8217;re worried about your own problems: <em>does my son have autism? What am I supposed to do about the dude that&#8217;s stalking me? What do I do with the rest of my life?</em> You can&#8217;t <strong>really</strong> handle any problems besides what&#8217;s directly in front of you: get food, drinks, and merriment to your tables <strong>without</strong> having to sing Happy Birthday with the few cooks who don&#8217;t speak English and your manager who thinks singing to customers is dumb, but they asked so you gotta start begging the cooks and the busboy and the brand-new dishwasher to help you out here, <em>please</em>? And you look up from your soggy birthday cake and notice that the inept hostess is now triple-seating you at 10:30PM on a Thursday night.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s simply no time to be a counselor. Which is why I still hate the question.</p>
<p>&#8220;Are you okay?&#8221; most people want a reply that sounds positive, &#8220;why yes, I&#8217;m delightful, thank you for asking! Little Jimmy, the highest human pedigree of child, well, he&#8217;s just been enrolled in NASA&#8217;s young genius program, I&#8217;ve been promoted from CEO to heiress, and I just bought the most gorgeous 874,623,722 foot yacht &#8211; you should come over for a sail and I can regale you with perfect stories of my very perfect life.&#8221;</p>
<p>(okay, that just sounds like one of those Christmas card letters, but you know what I mean).</p>
<p>No one wants you to reply to &#8220;Are you okay?&#8221; with &#8220;No, not really.&#8221; Simply put, they don&#8217;t exactly <em>want</em> to know if you&#8217;re okay; it&#8217;s a formality, something that fills the space between &#8220;hello&#8221; and &#8220;goodbye.&#8221; I get it &#8211; I&#8217;ve been there and I understand that there&#8217;s not a lot of room for the truth.</p>
<p>Which is why I&#8217;m no longer able to really answer that simple question. The qualifiers, stories, the explanation is far longer than most people care to hear &#8211; especially when your primary response would be (if you actually said it), &#8220;No.&#8221;</p>
<p>Because while I&#8217;d love to come here and type you a wonderful story of how much better my life has gotten since July, it&#8217;d be a lie. Things are different, that&#8217;s for certain, and not always in the best of ways. I&#8217;m getting a crash-course on Living Alone 101, and it&#8217;s one motherfucker of a ride.</p>
<p>There are good moments and bad. Feeling liberated and feeling defeated. Darkness and light. Continue obnoxious comparisons <em>ad nauseum</em>.</p>
<p>But the truth of the matter is this: I&#8217;m <strong>not</strong> okay. I&#8217;ll <em>be</em> okay again, but I can&#8217;t tell you precisely when or how. Making the right decision doesn&#8217;t always mean that it&#8217;s the easy one.</p>
<p>And for now, for this very moment, and, I&#8217;m certain, many moments after this one, I&#8217;m not okay &#8211; I&#8217;m simply learning to be okay with not being okay.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the best I can do; it&#8217;s the best we <em>all</em> can do.</p>
<p>We grab a life raft where we can, hold onto the hope that this, too, will pass, and that someday, this will all be a time we can look back upon as The Time Things Weren&#8217;t Okay. We&#8217;ll wake up each day hoping to slay the dragons, hoping the darkness won&#8217;t win, and we fight to do better; to be better.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s growth to be had. There are changes to be made. And there are things to be done. Life will, once again, be good.</p>
<p>Some day, some passing afternoon, in the not-so-distant future, I know that I will be able to once again answer the question, &#8220;how are you doing?&#8221; without feeling as though I&#8217;m lying through my teeth when I say breezily, like our endless numbered days, &#8220;Oh, I&#8217;m fine.&#8221;</p>
<p>And mean it.</p>
<p><object width="450" height="338" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0">
<param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" />
<param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" />
<param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/xg_Xxcv5VLs?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0" />
<param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed width="450" height="338" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/xg_Xxcv5VLs?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0" allowFullScreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /></object></p>
 <img src="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/?feed-stats-post-id=13859" width="1" height="1" style="display: none;" /><div class="crp_related"><h3>Related Posts:</h3><ul><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/toddler-sings-britney-spears-criminal/"     class="crp_title">Who&#8217;s In Love With A Criminal?</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/wayback-machine/"     class="crp_title">Wayback Machine</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/its-never-ever-safe-to-sleep/"     class="crp_title">It&#8217;s Never, EVER Safe To Sleep.</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/ill-have-to-say-i-love-you-in-a-blog/"     class="crp_title">I&#8217;ll Have To Say I Love You In A Blog</a></li><li><a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/dating-sucks-but-so-does-becoming-the-crazy-hot-dog-lady/"     class="crp_title">Dating Sucks, But So Does Becoming The Crazy Hot Dog Lady</a></li></ul></div><p>The post <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-some-passing-afternoon/">Like Some Passing Afternoon</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.mommywantsvodka.com">Mommy Wants Vodka</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.mommywantsvodka.com/like-some-passing-afternoon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
