<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>5by5 Master Audio Feed</title>
    <link>http://5by5.tv/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>5by5 - All Audio Broadcasts</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:new-feed-url>http://feeds.5by5.tv/master</itunes:new-feed-url>
    <itunes:subtitle>5by5 - All Audio Broadcasts</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:author>5by5 and Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>5by5 is an internet broadcast studio making podcasts for people like you.</itunes:summary>
    <itunes:image href="http://5by5.tv/assets/5by5-itunes.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>5by5, 5x5, 5 by 5, five by five</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>5by5 Studios and Dan Benjamin</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>itunes@5by5.tv</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:category text="Technology">
      <itunes:category text="Tech News"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 117: It Itches When It Gets Rainy </title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/117</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/117</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie are joined by Myke Hurley to kick off their live video stream of The Frequency and chat about the tech and weird news of the day including: the Roku 3, the new Porche Hybrid, the cruise ship that just won't quit, 20 great covers from the US Space Program, and pecan pie is now the official state pie of Texas. Dan and Haddie also share their favorite super powers.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-117.mp3" length="37847068" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie are joined by Myke Hurley to kick off their live video stream of The Frequency and chat about the tech and weird news of the day including: the Roku 3, the new Porche Hybrid, the cruise ship that just won't quit, 20 great covers from the US Space Program, and pecan pie is now the official state pie of Texas. Dan and Haddie also share their favorite super powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13579_3-57577597-37/the-untold-story-behind-apples-%2413000-operating-system/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The untold story behind Apple&amp;#x27;s $13,000 operating system | Apple - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Apple II was introduced at the inaugural West Coast Computer Faire in April, 1977, it suffered from what, in retrospect, was a glaring shortcoming: It had no disk drive. Thanks to 35-year-old documents that have recently surfaced after three-plus decades in storage, we now know exactly how Apple navigated around that obstacle to create the company's first disk operating system. In more than a literal sense, it is also the untold story of how Apple booted up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.neowin.net/news/meet-gabriel-weinberg-the-man-taking-on-google-and-bing" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Meet Gabriel Weinberg, the man taking on Google and Bing - Neowin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;n 1998, two college friends decided to build a method of analysing every website on the Internet to find the most relevant information when a user put in a small amount of text. Their names were Sergey Brin and Larry Page, and they had just founded Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step forward Gabriel Weinberg. Back in 2006, Weinberg sold "The Names Database" to Classmates.com for around $10 million. At the time, Weinberg was in his 20s, married and had cash to spare and nothing to do with it, until he thought of DuckDuckGo. Some of you may not have heard of DuckDuckGo, as it operates quietly with very little advertisement. But DuckDuckGo is the most significant thing to happen to the search world since Page and Brin founded Google back in 1998.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/mobile/2013/04/03/flurry-android-and-ios-users-spend-32-of-their-app-time-playing-games-20-in-the-browser-18-in-facebook/?fromcat=facebook" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Flurry: Android and iOS users spend 32% of their app time playing games, 20% in the browser, 18% in Facebook - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android and iOS users in the US spend an average of 2 hours and 38 minutes every day using apps on smartphones and tablets. 20 percent of that time (or 31 minutes) is spent on the mobile Web using a browser, while 80 percent of that time (or 2 hours and 7 minutes) is spent inside other apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://laughingsquid.com/then-now-composites-of-famous-historical-photos-created-for-know-where-you-stand-history-channel-ad-campaign/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Then &amp;amp; Now Composites of Famous Historical Photos Created for ‘Know Where You Stand’ History Channel Ad Campaign&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photographer Seth Taras created then and now composites out of famous photos of momentous historical events for the 2004 “Know Where You Stand” ad campaign for the History Channel. The campaign was orchestrated by the Ground Zero ad agency and included four tv spots. Ground Zero has since merged with Wong, Doody, Crandall, Wiener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://laughingsquid.com/high-schooler-hallway-swims-between-lockers/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;High Schooler Hallway Swims Between Lockers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High school student Cole Pugsley flaunts his ‘hallway swimming‘ skills by lying down sideways on the floor and repeatedly pushing off with his feet back and forth between sets of lockers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://laughingsquid.com/farmstand-a-farmers-market-app-for-ios/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Farmstand, iOS App That Helps Find Information on Farmer’s Markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farmstand is an iOS app that allows users to find nearby farmer’s markets and search for market hours and directions. With the app, users can also share photos and updates of their experiences at the farmer’s market. The app is available now from the iTunes App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/03/panamera-s-e-hybrid/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Porsche Unveils Panamera S E-Hybrid, Its First Plug-In Hybrid [PICS]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plug-in hybrid trend must be getting serious when Porsche jumps into the ring. The German car manufacturer announced on Wednesday the Panamera S E-Hybrid, its first plug-in hybrid.True to the Porsche tradition, this four-door sedan is no slouch in the performance department, with its parallel hybrid gas/electric combo power plant creating a respectable 416 hp. The car gets 95 of those horses from its electric motor, and the other 320 hp from its all-new 3.0-Liter bi-turbo V6 gas engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/03/twitter-weather-channel/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter, Weather Channel Ink Deal to Create Custom Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the weather becomes a hot topic on Twitter, the Weather Channel will try to seize the moment with some custom content thanks to a new deal with Twitter.The agreement, which is similar to Twitter's deal last year with ESPN, will include video clips of local forecasts, user-generated content and coverage related to major weather events, according to AllThingsD. Because it employs Twitter's Cards technology, the content will stay within the Twitter stream rather than lead off-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/04/03/dnp-roku-3-review/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Roku 3 review: our favorite media streamer, and the simplest to use, too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the Roku 3 is still a simple $99 box that brings internet content including video, some simple apps and even games to your TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/U/US_DISABLED_CRUISE_SHIP?SITE=AP&amp;amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT&amp;amp;CTIME=2013-04-03-16-08-51" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;WORKER MISSING; CRUISE SHIP BREAKS FROM ALA. PORT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officials say a Carnival cruise ship that had been disabled for days in the Gulf of Mexico has broken away from its moorings in a Mobile, Ala. shipyard.The U.S. Coast Guard tweeted Wednesday afternoon that high winds are likely to blame for the Triumph becoming dislodged.Carnival spokesman Vance Gulliksen says the ship drifted and is resting against a cargo vessel. Gulliksen says tug boats and U.S. Coast Guard officials are on the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/03/happy-cheese-weasel-day-3/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Happy (Belated) Cheese Weasel Day! | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unknown to most, April 3rd is Cheese Weasel Day, the holiday where the Cheese Weasel brings dairy goodness to all the good boys and girls in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/04/03/ready-player-one-author-ernest.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ready Player One author Ernest Cline to host pilot of Geek Out TV show - Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geek Out will feature Cline and his co-host as they pay it forward by traveling the country and surprising obsessed fans. Whether it be the guy who turned his apartment into an exact replica of the Starship Enterprise, the comic book fan whose body is covered in X-Men tattoos, or the suburban mom whose entire house is overflowing with Twilight memorabilia, it explores why that person is a super-fan and offers the surprise of a lifetime when the fan is given an awesome, otherwise unattainable experience related to their obsession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://laughingsquid.com/if-game-of-thrones-characters-were-on-facebook/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;If Game of Thrones Characters Were on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Game of Thrones on Facebook” is a clever collection of custom Facebook updates created by Team Pwnicorn for Funny or Die that shows characters from Game of Thrones interacting with each other in an expected manner. You can view the whole collection at Funny or Die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://world.g-shock.com/us/en/ble/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;BLUETOOTH WATCH - G-SHOCK - CASIO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.distancetomars.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;How Far is it to Mars?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://space.kinja.com/twenty-awesome-covers-from-the-us-space-program-461436874" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twenty Awesome Covers From The US Space Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4182024/vietnam-opens-fire-breathing-dragon-bridge" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fire-breathing dragon bridge opens in Vietnam | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the 38th anniversary of the end of the Vietnam War, authorities in the port city of Da Nang have opened the world's largest dragon bridge. Featuring more than 2,500 energy-efficient Philips LED lights, the dragon is capable of releasing bursts of fire from its mouth and can spit water during the country's major festivals or at weekends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4181852/bill-gates-and-paul-allen-pose-for-microsoft-photo-reenactment" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Bill Gates and Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen recreate classic photo from 1981 | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many were surprised in 2011 when Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen slammed Bill Gates in the pages of his autobiography, Idea Man&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/HTNext/LifeAndUniverse/Russian-billionaire-plans-to-make-humans-immortal-by-2045/Article1-1036706.aspx" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Russian billionaire plans to make humans immortal by 2045 - Hindustan Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Russian billionaire has unveiled plans to make humans immortal by converting them into 'Terminator-style' cyborgs - a creature that's part human and part machine - within the next three decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.legis.state.tx.us/tlodocs/83R/billtext/pdf/HC00053I.pdf#navpanes=0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Pecan Pie is now the Official State Pie of Texas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chromium.org/blink" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Blink - The Chromium Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00003CXE4/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Me, Myself &amp;amp; Irene (Special Edition): Jim Carrey, Renée Zellweger, Anthony Anderson, Mongo Brownlee, Jerod Mixon, Chris Cooper, Michael Bowman, Richard Jenkins, Robert Forster, Mike Cerrone, Rob Moran, Daniel Greene, Bobby Farrelly, Peter Farr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000MNOXZI/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Me, Myself &amp;amp; Irene [Blu-ray]: Jim Carrey, Chris Cooper, Tony Cox, Daniel Greene, Jessica Harper, Richard Jenkins, Rob Moran, Shannon Whirry, Robert Forster, Renée Zellweger, Zen Gesner, Traylor Howard, Anthony Anderson, Mike Cerrone, Mongo Bro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/frequency"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY4 for 10% off) and &lt;a href="http://hobancards.com"&gt;Hoban Press&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY for free shipping).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:17:56</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie are joined by Myke Hurley to kick off their live video stream of The Frequency and chat about the tech and weird news of the day including: the Roku 3, the new Porche Hybrid, the cruise ship that just won't quit, 20 great covers from the US</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie are joined by Myke Hurley to kick off their live video stream of The Frequency and chat about the tech and weird news of the day including: the Roku 3, the new Porche Hybrid, the cruise ship that just won't quit, 20 great covers from the US Space Program, and pecan pie is now the official state pie of Texas. Dan and Haddie also share their favorite super powers.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F117&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 37: Thursday, April 4, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/37</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/37</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Myke Hurley</author>
      <description>
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-037.mp3" length="4500066" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2013/04/03/mozilla-and-samsung-collaborate-on-next-generation-web-browser-engine/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mozilla and Samsung Collaborate on Next Generation Web Browser Engine | The Mozilla Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla and Samsung Collaborate on Next Generation Web Browser Engine bringing both the Rust programming language and Servo, the experimental web browser engine, to Android and ARM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/3/4180260/google-forks-webkit-with-new-blink-rendering-engine-for-chrome" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google forks WebKit with new Blink rendering engine for Chrome and Opera | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big news for the web today: Google has announced that it's going to stop using WebKit as the rendering engine that's behind displaying web pages in Chrome. Instead, it's forking WebKit to create its own rendering engine, called "Blink." The move, Google says, is to speed up development on Chrome thanks to reducing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-10797_3-57577786-235/disney-shuttering-lucasarts-moving-to-licensed-games-model/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Disney shuttering LucasArts, moving to licensed games model | Tech Culture - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disney has shut down LucasArts, the video game arm of the Lucas entertainment empire, laying off its staff and ceasing its development of two forthcoming "Star Wars" games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2013/04/03/instagram-says-that-almost-half-of-its-over-100m-users-are-using-the-android-app/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Instagram says that almost half of its over 100M users are using the Android app - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram has shared that a year after it launched its most-sought after Android app, today, half of all of its Instagrammers use it to share photos with their friends and family. To put that into context, at the beginning of 2013, the company reported that it had 100 million active monthly users. By those numbers, some might take Instagram’s news today that there are 50 million Instagram users on Android.Just a few months (197 days to be exacty) after it launched on Android, Instagram said that the app had been downloaded 50 million times. Obviously we cannot expect everyone of those downloads to equate to an active user, so that number could come fairly close to that 50 million mark. If this number is to be believed, it would be an incredible rise for the app version that amassed one million users within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/twitter/2013/04/03/twitter-updates-android-app-bigtime-with-native-experience-app-cards-borderless-timeline-and-more/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter updates Android app bigtime with ‘native’ experience, app Cards, borderless timeline and more - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter has updated its Android app as well as its iOS app today, both of which now support its new app install cards. That’s only a portion of what the Android update brings, though, as it’s really a long overdue overhaul of the Twitter experience on Android.The Android app has lagged behind the iOS version in both looks and functionality for a while now, so it’s great to see it’s getting some love. One improvement is that there is no longer an artificial ‘margin’ or border along the edges of the timeline. Tweets now span edge to edge and the timeline is taller overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/03/twitter-weather-channel/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter, Weather Channel Ink Deal to Create Custom Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the weather becomes a hot topic on Twitter, the Weather Channel will try to seize the moment with some custom content thanks to a new deal with Twitter.The agreement, which is similar to Twitter's deal last year with ESPN, will include video clips of local forecasts, user-generated content and coverage related to major weather events, according to AllThingsD. Because it employs Twitter's Cards technology, the content will stay within the Twitter stream rather than lead off-site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/03/bitcoin-value-plunges/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Bitcoin Plunges By Nearly $30 As Largest Market Suffers Outage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of digital currency Bitcoin fell from above $145 to below $117 Wednesday as Mt. Gox, the largest market for trading the digital currency, suffered an outage for approximately an hour. At the time of writing mid-afternoon Wednesday, the value seems to have leveled out at about $125, a $20 drop for the day.
"Due to high volume trading at the moment, there is a lag in trading and order cancellation," reads a statement from Mt. Gox.
It's not believed that Mt. Gox was the victim of hackers, a scenario feared by some Bitcoin naysayers. More likely, it collapsed under the strain of heavy traffic sparked by a sudden spike in interest in Bitcoin. Mt. Gox's problems, in turn, may have caused Bitcoin's sudden drop in value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/03/vdio-opens-in-the-u-s-and-uk-with-no-subscription-model-rdio-unlimited-users-targeted-first/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Vdio Opens In The U.S. And UK With No Subscription Model For Movies And TV, Rdio Users Targeted First | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vdio, a video streaming service created to complement the Rdio music service, soft-launched Tuesday evening. The site — offering not all-you-can consume subscriptions but pay-per-view films and TV shows, with an emphasis on new releases — is opening for previews in the U.S. and UK, with $25/£20 gift certificates going out to people who are already subscribers to Rdio’s premium Unlimited tier, or who subscribe in the next 60 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/cycling/22023732" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;BBC Sport - Lance Armstrong set for competitive return as a swimmer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disgraced American cyclist Lance Armstrong is planning to return to competitive sport as a swimmer.Armstrong, 41, has entered the Masters South Central Zone Swimming Championships  in Texas this weekend.He is able to compete as US Masters Swimming events are not subject to USA or World Anti-Doping Agency codes.Armstrong was stripped of his seven Tour de France titles after deciding not to defend doping charges filed against him last August.Armstrong is scheduled to compete in freestyle races over 500 yards, 1,000 yards and 1,650 yards at the event held in his home city of Austin.The Texan will compete with swimmers his own age or older. His first race, the 1,650 yards freestyle, takes place on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4182174/apple-campus-2-spaceship-overbudget-rumor" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Campus 2 nearly $2bn over budget and a year behind schedule, says Bloomberg | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg Businessweek is reporting that the budget for Apple's new "spaceship" campus has risen from $3 billion to "nearly $5 billion." Citing five anonymous sources, the publication notes that the stretched budget would make Apple Campus 2 more expensive than the World Trade Center complex currently under construction. The project was originally scheduled for completion in 2015, but the move-in date has now been pushed back to 2016 as architects Foster   Partners search for a way to cut the current cost by a billion dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4182210/arrested-development-season-4-release-date-may-26" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;#x27;Arrested Development&amp;#x27; Season 4 will debut May 26th on Netflix | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After months of hype, Netflix has finally announced the release date for the new season of Arrested Development. In a post on Twitter, Netflix says the new season will debut on May 26th with 15 new episodes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4182256/anonymous-hack-Uriminzokkiri-north-korea-twitter-flickr-website" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;North Korea&amp;#x27;s Twitter and Flickr accounts hacked by Anonymous | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uriminzokkiri, the North Korean central news agency's website, has been hacked, along with with its Twitter and Flickr accounts. The hacktivist collective Anonymous has claimed responsibility for the hack. As of this morning, the site is offline, and its Twitter account has ceased posting the regular stream of patriotic photos and links, instead posting links to all of the sites that have been hacked. Its Flickr account, usually home to regular photographic updates on the North Korean administration, now contains a number of images that indicate it has almost certainly been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/4/4183172/facebook-home-android" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Home revamps any Android phone to make it about &amp;#x27;people, not apps&amp;#x27; | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook's throwing its hat in the Android ring in a big, big way. Today at an event at the company's campus in California, Mark Zuckerberg announced Facebook Home, a deep software integration with Android that puts Facebook services front and center. Home is a family of Facebook apps that overhauls your entire device, turning it into a Facebook phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Myke Hurley</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>8:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F37&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Beta 43: Automatically Generate Engaging Content</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/inbeta/43</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/inbeta/43</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Gina Trapani &amp; Kevin Purdy</author>
      <description>How does a Kickstarter project, an app, or a Google prototype headset manage expectations among early adopters? And what makes for good online behavior, versus the bad/wrong/abusive we can pretty easily spot?
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/inbeta/2013/inbeta-043.mp3" length="30003264" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;How does a Kickstarter project, an app, or a Google prototype headset manage expectations among early adopters? And what makes for &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; online behavior, versus the bad/wrong/abusive we can pretty easily spot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1pgI8K-gHv-TWO-BA8mUSTDt3rKRUDJS-td-ALJQgsqE/viewform" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;In Beta Sticker Request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/blog/kickstarter-is-not-a-store" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Kickstarter Is Not a Store » The Kickstarter Blog — Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3007275/innovation-agents/one-week-my-incredible-pebble-smartwatch-was-all-it-promised-be-and-then-i" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;For One Week, My Incredible Pebble Smartwatch Was All It Promised To Be--And Then It Stopped Working | Fast Company | Business + Innovation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6BTCoT8ajbI" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;How It Feels through Glass - Google Glass Official Promo 20/02/2013 - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.thinkup.com/post/46935797464/were-shooting-for-emotion-not-automation" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;ThinkUp - We&amp;#x27;re shooting for emotion, not automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mikeindustries.com/blog/archive/2011/07/mind-your-metweets" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mind Your MeTweets | Mike Industries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GameOfThrones/status/318426937691369473" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter / GameOfThrones: May your baby Khaleesi grow ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://perksapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Perks - Twitter on Autopilot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nbc30rock" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;30 Rock (nbc30rock) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://mailchimp.com/5by5"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/5by5"&gt;Smile&lt;/a&gt;. Bandwidth sponsored by &lt;a href="http://airlock.io"&gt;Airlock&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Gina Trapani &amp; Kevin Purdy</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:01:52</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>On managing expectations for products and apps, and on encouraging good social network behavior.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>How does a Kickstarter project, an app, or a Google prototype headset manage expectations among early adopters? And what makes for good online behavior, versus the bad/wrong/abusive we can pretty easily spot?
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>web, open source software, oss, tools, mobile, social</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/37/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Finbeta%2F43&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 116: The Android of Pixar</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/116</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/116</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in entertaining news including: giant spiders, how to scramble an egg without cracking the shell, Wes Anderson's new Prada ad, the new Pixar movie, and the cell phone's 40th birthday. Dan also quizzes Haddie on all those sounds at the beginning of movies that trick us into thinking that the movie is starting. But it's not.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-116.mp3" length="26151307" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in entertaining news including: giant spiders, how to scramble an egg without cracking the shell, Wes Anderson's new Prada ad, the new Pixar movie, and the cell phone's 40th birthday. Dan also quizzes Haddie on all those sounds at the beginning of movies that trick us into thinking that the movie is starting. But it's not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/28/wes-anderson-prada/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Watch Wes Anderson&amp;#x27;s 3-Part Ad for Prada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director Wes Anderson's next film, titled The Grand Budapest Hotel, won't be out until next year. In the meantime, fans can tide themselves over with this short film/advertisement for Prada Candy L'Eau perfume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/2/4175046/finding-dory-pixar-finding-nemo-movie-sequel-coming-november-2015" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Pixar sequel &amp;#x27;Finding Dory&amp;#x27; set to hit theaters November 2015 | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixar is diving into its back catalog of beloved characters for a new movie set to hit theaters November 25, 2015. Finding Dory, the sequel to 2003's Oscar-winning Finding Nemo, will center on the loquacious, memory-deficient Blue Tang fish supporting character voiced by Ellen DeGeneres. The story will focus on reuniting Dory, who was seen swimming alone in the original film, with her loved ones. DeGeneres will return as the voice of Dory and Andrew Stanton will resume directing duties. Albert Brooks was previously confirmed back onboard, too, reprising his role as the voice of Marlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/twitter/2013/04/02/twitter-gets-its-first-vine-related-copyright-complaint-from-princes-record-label/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sign o’ the Times: Twitter gets a Vine copyright complaint from Prince’s record label - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter has been served a DMCA copyright complaint for content that was published using the Vine video platform it acquired and launched earlier this year.Twitter openly shares how many DMCA takedown notices it gets from copyright holders concerned with content shared on Twitter (or in this case, one of its third-party products), and where the complaints are coming from, on a site called Chilling Effects.In this particular case, the takedown request came from NPG Records, the 20-year old record label owned by Prince. ‘NPG’ is short for New Power Generation, the name of the artist’s former backing band.A representative of NPG Records wrote to Twitter to say eight video clips hosted on Vine contained “unauthorized recordings” and “unauthorized synchronizations” and asked the company to remove them immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57577462-93/game-of-thrones-sets-piracy-record-report-says/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;#x27;Game of Thrones&amp;#x27; sets piracy record, report says | Internet &amp;amp; Media - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Game of Thrones," the wildly popular fantasy drama on HBO, has set an all-time record via BitTorrent, according to data collected by Torrent Freak.The site, which tracks the world of BitTorrent and piracy, was tracking uploads and downloads of the first episode of the latest season of "Game of Thrones." It found that just a few hours after the first torrent was shared on the site, 163,088 people were sharing just one torrent. The so-called "swarm" of people sharing the torrent outpaced the previous titleholder, "Heroes," which had 144,663 peers sharing one torrent. According to TorrentFreak, another 110,303 people were sharing a complete copy of the "Game of Thrones" episode, and 52,786 people were downloading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/2/4175384/game-of-thrones-season-4-confirmed-for-next-year" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;#x27;Game of Thrones&amp;#x27; Season 4 confirmed for next year | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of Thrones will be coming back for a fourth season, Entertainment Weekly confirms. HBO has renewed another 10 episodes to premiere in 2014 — given the series' success so far, that's completely unsurprising, though executive producer David Benioff did note last month that it hadn't been renewed at that point. No further details are forthcoming right now, but it's generally accepted that a fourth season will cover the second half of A Storm of Swords, the third book in George R.R. Martin's A Song of Ice and Fire series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-17938_105-57577562-1/watch-how-to-brush-your-teeth-in-space/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Watch: How to brush your teeth in space | Crave - CNET&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International Space Station Commander Chris Hadfield shows the world how astronaut's clean their chompers in orbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://laughingsquid.com/how-to-scramble-hard-boiled-eggs-inside-their-uncracked-shell/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;How to Scramble Hard Boiled Eggs Inside Their Uncracked Shell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NightHawkInLight demonstrates an amazing way to scramble hard-boiled eggs inside of their own uncracked shell. He was inspired by a recipe on the WonderHowTo site. So cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2417337,00.asp" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google Play Hit by One-Click Fraud Apps | News &amp;amp; Opinion | PCMag.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching for porn on your smartphone could lead to more than embarrassment. Symantec this week reported a surge in adult-oriented, "one-click" fraud apps in Google Play designed to scam users into signing up for pricey adult sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2013/04/new-giant-tarantula/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;New Giant Tarantula Discovered in Sri Lanka | Wired Science | Wired.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new type of tarantula about the size of your face has been found in northern Sri Lanka. Scientists found the spiders — with a leg span up to 8 inches across — living in trees and the old doctor’s quarters of a hospital in Mankulam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-21954779" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;BBC News - Hagfish slime: The clothing of the future?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists believe hagfish slime or similar proteins could be turned into tights or breathable athletic wear, or even bullet-proof vests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/02/yolo-suspension/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;YOLO Ruins Lives: Student Suspended Over Test Prank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today's life lesson: YOLO will seriously screw up your life.A Texas teenager learned that lesson recently when he was dealt a four-day suspension for scribbling the acronym on a state-required standardized test. Arlington High School junior Kyron Birdine snapped a photo of the cheeky essay answer and tweeted the image to the Texas Education Agency and the Arlington school district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/cheats/2013/04/02/ap-stylebook-drops-illegal-immigrant.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;AP Stylebook Drops ‘Illegal Immigrant’ - The Daily Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Associated Press Stylebook is getting a 21st-century makeover. The world’s largest news-gathering organization has decided to drop the label from its widely used guide. “The Stylebook no longer sanctions the term ‘illegal immigrant’ or the use of ‘illegal’ to describe a person. Instead, it tells users that ‘illegal’ should describe only an action, such as living in or immigrating to a country illegally,” Executive Editor Kathleen Carroll wrote in a blog post on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/02/sec-social-media-rules/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;SEC Says It&amp;#x27;s OK for Companies to Make Announcements via Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Security and Exchange Commission announced Tuesday that businesses can use social networks like Twitter and Facebook to reveal information company information to the public — as long as they give investors a heads up first.The new policy comes in response to a case involving Netflix CEO Reed Hastings, who used his personal Facebook page last July to announce that Netflix had exceeded one billion hours of streaming for the first time, causing the stock price to rise. In December, the SEC launched an investigation into whether Hastings and Netflix had violated fair disclosure rules because the news had not been disclosed to the public through more traditional channels like a press release or SEC filing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/2/4174650/yahoo-mail-now-supports-dropbox-attachments-web-client" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Yahoo Mail adds Dropbox attachment support, deepens cloud integration | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yahoo just announced a new partnership with Dropbox that lets you attach files stored with the popular cloud service to outbound emails. The company is touting the integration as yet another way it's making the email experience simpler for customers. "The way we see it, you should be able to go into your inbox, do what you need to do and move on with your day," writes David McDowell. Dropbox support brings some nice benefits to users of both services: since files are located in the cloud, Yahoo's traditional 25MB attachment limit no longer applies. Additionally, Dropbox users can choose to save email attachments directly to the cloud — no local storage necessary. Dropbox support is available now for the web version of Yahoo Mail in English, French, Spanish, German and Italian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/02/watch-the-daily-show-clip-that-sparked-twitter-ire-between-egypts-president-and-u-s-embassy/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Watch ‘The Daily Show’ Clip That Sparked Twitter Ire Between Egypt’s President And The U.S. Embassy | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter became the unexpected battleground for tensions between the United States and Egypt, after the American embassy tweeted an episode of The Daily Show, which tore into the oppressive tactics of President Mohammed Morsi. “@USEmbassyCairo @TheDailyShow @DrBassemYoussef It’s inappropriate for a diplomatic mission to engage in such negative political propaganda,” responded the official account of Egypt’s president.Egypt has taken a turn for the worse since the election of Morsi. Most recently, he arrested the host of a satirical news show, Bassem Youssef, after promising that no critic of the president would be harmed. No surprise, Daily Show host Jon Stewart went after Morsi is a (brilliant) 10 minute sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/3/4177844/the-cellphone-is-forty-years-old-today" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The cellphone is 40 years old today | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On April 3rd, 1973, Motorola engineer Marty Cooper placed the first public call from a cellphone. In midtown Manhattan, Cooper called Joel Engel — head of rival research department Bell Labs — saying "Joel, this is Marty. I'm calling you from a cell phone, a real handheld portable cell phone." The call was placed on a Motorola DynaTAC 8000x, which weighed 2.5 pounds, a far cry from today's 4-ounce handsets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://sleepyti.me/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;sleepyti.me bedtime calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/frequency"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY4 for 10% off) and &lt;a href="http://hobancards.com"&gt;Hoban Press&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY for free shipping).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>53:34</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in entertaining news including: giant spiders, how to scramble an egg without cracking the shell, Wes Anderson's new Prada ad, the new Pixar movie, and the cell phone's 40th birthday. Dan also quizzes Haddie on all those </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in entertaining news including: giant spiders, how to scramble an egg without cracking the shell, Wes Anderson's new Prada ad, the new Pixar movie, and the cell phone's 40th birthday. Dan also quizzes Haddie on all those sounds at the beginning of movies that trick us into thinking that the movie is starting. But it's not.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F116&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 36: Wednesday, April 3, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/36</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/36</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Myke Hurley</author>
      <description>
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-036.mp3" length="4884380" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/02/tesla-motors-partners-with-wells-fargo-and-us-bank-to-finance-model-s-electric-cars/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Tesla Motors Partners With Wells Fargo And US Bank To Finance Model S Electric Cars | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Elon Musk’s Tesla Motors has announced a new plan to allow consumers to finance its Model S Electric cars, thanks to a partnership with Wells Fargo and US Bank.The company says that this is a new kind of financing product that “combines the surety and comfort of ownership with all the advantages of a traditional lease.” So while this isn’t a straight-up lease, this is a hybrid that is as close to owning one of these cars as you’re going to get without paying cash for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/02/watch-the-daily-show-clip-that-sparked-twitter-ire-between-egypts-president-and-u-s-embassy/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Watch ‘The Daily Show’ Clip That Sparked Twitter Ire Between Egypt’s President And The U.S. Embassy | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter became the unexpected battleground for tensions between the United States and Egypt, after the American embassy tweeted an episode of The Daily Show, which tore into the oppressive tactics of President Mohammed Morsi. “@USEmbassyCairo @TheDailyShow @DrBassemYoussef It’s inappropriate for a diplomatic mission to engage in such negative political propaganda,” responded the official account of Egypt’s president.Egypt has taken a turn for the worse since the election of Morsi. Most recently, he arrested the host of a satirical news show, Bassem Youssef, after promising that no critic of the president would be harmed. No surprise, Daily Show host Jon Stewart went after Morsi is a (brilliant) 10 minute sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887323611604578398663619783622.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple to Begin iPhone Production This Quarter - WSJ.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple plans to begin production of a refreshed iPhone similar in size and shape to its current one in the second quarter of the year, according to people familiar with the device's production, teeing up a possible summer launch for the next version of its flagship device. BCG Financial senior financial analyst Colin Gillis discusses Apple's plans to start iPhone production this quarter, the sagging stock price, and Tim Cook's management style.At the same time, Apple continues to work with its manufacturing partners in Asia on a less expensive iPhone that could be launched as soon as the second half of this year, these people said. The four-inch device will likely use a different casing from the higher-end iPhone. Apple has been working on different color shells for the phone but its plans remain unclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://betabeat.com/2013/04/omgpop-founder-dan-porter-departs-zynga-will-be-replaced-by-vp-of-mobile-sean-kelly/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;OMGPOP CEO Dan Porter Departs Zynga; Will Be Replaced by VP of Mobile Sean Kelly | Betabeat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Porter, the former CEO of New York-based gaming company OMGPOP which was purchased by Zynga in March of last year, has left the company, according to a release obtained by Betabeat.Zynga confirmed to Betabeat that the decision was mutual and unrelated to the expiration of any “golden handcuff” clause in his contract keeping him at the company after the acquisition. Mr. Porter had been working on developing the sequel to Draw Something for the past year and felt it was in good enough shape to make the transition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://allthingsd.com/20130402/facebook-photo-phenom-instagram-gets-a-business-lead-to-scale-its-operations-and-presumably-revenues/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Photo Phenom Instagram Gets a Business Lead to Scale Its Ops - Kara Swisher - Mobile - AllThingsD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to sources, Facebook has moved well-regarded exec Emily White to a new job as director of business operations at its Instagram mobile photo-sharing unit.In this capacity, she will work with Instagram head and co-founder Kevin Systrom to scale nascent efforts to expand partnerships, improve user operations and, presumably, come up with ways to make some money. The fast-growing service, which the social networking site bought a year ago in a billion-dollar mega-deal, has been popular with consumers, but it has not focused as much on its business operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/02/itunes-urls-appear-to-be-losing-rank-in-google-search/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;iTunes URLs Appear To Be Losing Rank In Google Search | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google search is making it more difficult to surface iOS applications using typical user queries, like “Whatsapp iTunes,” “Whatsapp iPhone,”  or searches by app name, for example. In the past, this would return a page of search results where the iTunes URL would be ranked highly. Today, those links are further down in Google’s results pages.In Whatsapp’s case, the iTunes URL doesn’t even appear until close to the bottom of the second page of search results, when logged in while searching for “Whatsapp iTunes,” and it’s at the bottom of page 3 when logged out. It’s even more difficult to find it using “Whatsapp iPhone,” whether logged in or out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.technewsworld.com/story/Court-Rules-Broadcasters-Cant-Pull-the-Plug-on-Aereo-77682.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Court Rules Broadcasters Can&amp;#x27;t Pull the Plug on Aereo | Tech Law | TechNewsWorld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TV signals will keep streaming on PCs and mobile devices, and Aereo's tiny antennas will stay busy thanks to a court decision that denied an injunction by broadcasters looking to shut down the company. Representatives for ABC and other networks vow to see Aereo at a trial, where the case may come down to whether the company's antenna technology enables copyright violations of network programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.technewsworld.com/story/Russian-Clampdown-on-Web-Content-Raises-Red-Flags-77679.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Russian Clampdown on Web Content Raises Red Flags | Tech Law | TechNewsWorld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media giants Facebook, Twitter and YouTube have been caught up in a new Russian law designed to protect children from objectionable material. Critics say the law is too broad and can also be used to limit speech online. While online rights groups are keeping an eye on how the law is used, the social networks have removed content from their Russian versions. YouTube, however, is fighting back via lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/04/02/york-announces-pay-as-you-go-ev-charging-network/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;York announces pay-as-you-go EV charging network, beats London to the punch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city of York just announced a plan to install a network of pay-as-you-go charging stations for electric vehicles, the first such system to launch in the UK. York is already home to 12 free charging points, but these are located in lesser-known areas such as private parking lots. The new stations will be installed in public lots in the city center as well as near supermarkets and hotels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2013/04/new-giant-tarantula/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;New Giant Tarantula Discovered in Sri Lanka | Wired Science | Wired.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new type of tarantula about the size of your face has been found in northern Sri Lanka. Scientists found the spiders — with a leg span up to 8 inches across — living in trees and the old doctor’s quarters of a hospital in Mankulam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Covered in beautiful, ornate markings, the spiders belong to the genus Poecilotheria, known as “Pokies” for short. These are the tiger spiders, an arboreal group indigenous to India and Sri Lanka that are known for being colorful, fast, and venomous. As a group, the spiders are related to a class of South American tarantula that includes the Goliath bird-eater, the world’s largest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say again, these are as big as your face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/02/robocall-blocking-technology_n_2999297.html?utm_hp_ref=technology" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;FTC Seek Technology To Block Illegal Robocalls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Federal Trade Commission on Tuesday announced winners for its national contest to develop a blocking technology for illegal sales calls.The winners are Aaron Foss, a freelance software developer based in Long Island, N.Y., and Serdar Danis, a computer engineer who did not wish to disclose his hometown. Each winner will receive $25,000.The different technologies developed by Foss and Danis involve software that could analyze and filter calls to screen out those being placed from a computer or from someone who has been identified as an unwanted caller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/2/4174650/yahoo-mail-now-supports-dropbox-attachments-web-client" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Yahoo Mail adds Dropbox attachment support, deepens cloud integration | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yahoo just announced a new partnership with Dropbox that lets you attach files stored with the popular cloud service to outbound emails. The company is touting the integration as yet another way it's making the email experience simpler for customers. "The way we see it, you should be able to go into your inbox, do what you need to do and move on with your day," writes David McDowell. Dropbox support brings some nice benefits to users of both services: since files are located in the cloud, Yahoo's traditional 25MB attachment limit no longer applies. Additionally, Dropbox users can choose to save email attachments directly to the cloud — no local storage necessary. Dropbox support is available now for the web version of Yahoo Mail in English, French, Spanish, German and Italian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/3/4177844/the-cellphone-is-forty-years-old-today" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The cellphone is 40 years old today | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On April 3rd, 1973, Motorola engineer Marty Cooper placed the first public call from a cellphone. In midtown Manhattan, Cooper called Joel Engel — head of rival research department Bell Labs — saying "Joel, this is Marty. I'm calling you from a cell phone, a real handheld portable cell phone." The call was placed on a Motorola DynaTAC 8000x, which weighed 2.5 pounds, a far cry from today's 4-ounce handsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://mailchimp.com/5by5"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Myke Hurley</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>9:31</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F36&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Taking Pictures 49: Happiness is an Inside Job</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/otp/49</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/otp/49</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bill Wadman &amp; Jeffery Saddoris</author>
      <description>Things get a little heavy as Bill and Jeffery discuss the importance of dreams and what often keeps us from chasing them. Plus, standing up for the value of your work, just how limited are limited editions and pioneering female photographer Margaret Bourke-White as Photographer of the Week.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/otp/2013/otp-049.mp3" length="49321463" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Things get a little heavy as Bill and Jeffery discuss the importance of dreams and what often keeps us from chasing them. Plus, standing up for the value of your work, just how limited are limited editions and pioneering female photographer Margaret Bourke-White as Photographer of the Week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://asmp.org/free/guide-crcf" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Get ASMP Photographer&amp;#x27;s Guide to Copyright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://anandtech.com/show/6777/understanding-camera-optics-smartphone-camera-trends" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;AnandTech | Understanding Camera Optics &amp;amp; Smartphone Camera Trends, A Presentation by Brian Klug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thecandidframe.blogspot.com/2013/03/the-candid-frame-179-alison-turner.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Candid Frame #179 - Alison Turner | The Candid Frame: A Photography Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00AA277FY/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Bones Brigade: Tony Alva, Steve Caballero, Tony Hawk, Rodney Mullen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alisonturnerphoto.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Alison Turner Photography | Alison Turner Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lomography/the-lomography-smartphone-film-scanner" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Lomography Smartphone Film Scanner by Lomography — Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theartnewspaper.com/articles/Court+dismisses+lawsuit+over+Eggleston+reprints+/29285" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Court dismisses lawsuit over Eggleston reprints - The Art Newspaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.charlescramer.com/dyetransfer.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dye Transfer Printing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://richardkocihernandez.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Richard Koci Hernandez Multimedia Journalist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/112546386059769751629" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;On Taking Pictures - Google+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Bourke-White" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Margaret Bourke-White - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0810943816/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Margaret Bourke White: Susan Goldman Rubin: 9780810943810: Amazon.com: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1567922996/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Margaret Bourke-white: The Early Work, 1922-1930 (Pocket Paragon Series): Ronald E. Ostman, Harry Littell, Margaret Bourke-White: 9781567922998: Amazon.com: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1938922123/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Margaret Bourke-White: Moments in History (9781938922121): Sean Quimby, Oliva María Rubio, Margaret Bourke-White: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0839828586/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Portrait of Myself: Margaret Bourke-White, Jonathan Silverman: 9780839828587: Amazon.com: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="" target="_blank"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; Use code PICTURES3 for 30% off.&lt;br /&gt;and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/otp" target="_blank"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; Use the coupon code ‘FANCYOROLD’ at checkout to save 10% on your order and get a free domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Bill Wadman &amp; Jeffery Saddoris</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:42:24</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Things get a little heavy as Bill and Jeffery discuss the importance of dreams and what often keeps us from chasing them. </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Things get a little heavy as Bill and Jeffery discuss the importance of dreams and what often keeps us from chasing them. Plus, standing up for the value of your work, just how limited are limited editions and pioneering female photographer Margaret Bourke-White as Photographer of the Week.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>photography, camera, images, photos, pictures</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/48/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fotp%2F49&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplified 51: I Do This For A Living</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/amplified/51</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/amplified/51</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jim Dalrymple &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Jim discuss Apple and China, the Pebble Smartwatch, a fantastic 6-year-old drummer, and more.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/amplified/2013/amplified-051.mp3" length="37667145" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Jim discuss Apple and China, the Pebble Smartwatch, a fantastic 6-year-old drummer, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/2013/04/02/hot-for-teacher-performed-by-a-6-year-old-drummer/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;“Hot For Teacher” performed by a 6-year-old drummer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://512pixels.net/2013/03/pebble-review/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Pebble: Is the Time Right for a Smartwatch? — 512 Pixels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://9to5mac.com/2013/04/01/san-francisco-da-met-with-apples-government-liason-regarding-mobile-device-thefts-hints-next-two-iphones-developed-under-steve-jobs/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;San Francisco DA met with Apple over phone thefts, hints next two iPhones designed under Jobs | 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/04/02/us-apple-china-apology-idUSBRE93108320130402" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sorry Apple gets respect in China after tabloid trial | Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With its rare apology, Apple Inc went from pariah to praiseworthy in the eyes of China's state-controlled media, a lesson for other foreign firms not to underestimate the speed and power of the government press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://justinguitar.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Free guitar lessons : Complete Beginners Method and loads of Blues, Jazz and rock : Learn how to play Guitar free here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many hundreds of free guitar lessons here, most with video and audio, and as you can imagine it's taken quite a lot of work for me to put it together. It's important to me to help everyone that wants to learn to play the guitar, not just those with money to spend on tuition, so I run it on an "honour system"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://mailchimp.com/5by5"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/5by5"&gt;Smile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Jim Dalrymple &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:17:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Jim discuss Apple and China, the Pebble Smartwatch, a fantastic 6-year-old drummer, and more.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Jim discuss Apple and China, the Pebble Smartwatch, a fantastic 6-year-old drummer, and more.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>apple, mac, ipad, iphone, ios, guitars, music, recording</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/35/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Famplified%2F51&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant Size 19: Signed Peter Laird (Kevin Munroe)</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/giantsize/19</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/giantsize/19</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Moisés Chiullan</author>
      <description>The creator of comics Olympus Heights and El Zombo also directed 2007's TMNT, worked in the videogame industry, and is a huge comic geek himself. In this second part of a discussion that began in Screen Time 32, we find out what it means "to be a Reggie".
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/giantsize/2013/giantsize-019.mp3" length="19326826" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The creator of comics Olympus Heights and El Zombo also directed 2007's TMNT, worked in the videogame industry, and is a huge comic geek himself. In this second part of a discussion that began in Screen Time 32, we find out what it means "to be a Reggie".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.darkhorse.com/Comics/12-604/El-Zombo-1-of-3" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;El Zombo #1 (of 3) :: Profile :: Dark Horse Comics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.comicvine.com/el-zombo/4005-59614/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;El Zombo (Character)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.comicbookresources.com/?page=article&amp;amp;id=3432" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;IDW Publishing Rises To New Heights… &amp;quot;Olympus Heights&amp;quot; - Comic Book Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.comicvine.com/olympus-heights/4050-23650/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Olympus Heights (Volume)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archie_Comics" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Archie Comics - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reggie_Mantle" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Reggie Mantle - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0785108009/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Spider-Man Visionaries, Vol. 1: Todd McFarlane: David Michelinie, Todd McFarlane: 9780785108009: Amazon.com: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sgt._Rock" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sgt. Rock - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plastic_Man" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Plastic Man - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninja_turtles" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.comicvine.com/city-at-war/4045-56138/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;City At War (Story Arc)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://turtlepedia.wikia.com/wiki/City_at_War,_Part_1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;City at War, Part 1 - TMNTPedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newsarama.com/tv/report-bruce-timm-quits-warner-bros-animation.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Newsarama.com : Report: Bruce Timm Exits Warner Bros. Animation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Dini" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Paul Dini - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0227704/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Paul Dini - IMDb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Paul_Dini" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Paul_Dini (Paul_Dini) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jinglebelle.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;JingleBelle.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/screentime/32" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Screen Time #32: Science Ninja Team (Kevin Munroe part 1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://shopify.com/5by5"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://getharvest.com/5by5"&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; (use code 5BY5 for 50% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Moisés Chiullan</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>39:29</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>The creator of comics Olympus Heights and El Zombo also directed 2007's TMNT, worked in the videogame industry, and is a huge comic geek himself. In this second part of a discussion that began in Screen Time 32, we find out what it means "to be a Reggie".</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>The creator of comics Olympus Heights and El Zombo also directed 2007's TMNT, worked in the videogame industry, and is a huge comic geek himself. In this second part of a discussion that began in Screen Time 32, we find out what it means "to be a Reggie".
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>comics, art, geek, books</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/46/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fgiantsize%2F19&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screen Time 32: Science Ninja Team (Kevin Munroe)</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/screentime/32</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/screentime/32</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Moisés Chiullan</author>
      <description>Director, animator, and über-geek Kevin Munroe (TMNT, Wild 9, Olympus Heights) joins Moisés to talk about game design, animation, chasing the creative work you want to be doing, and working directly with George Lucas.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/screentime/2013/screentime-032.mp3" length="26406454" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Director, animator, and über-geek Kevin Munroe (TMNT, Wild 9, Olympus Heights) joins Moisés to talk about game design, animation, chasing the creative work you want to be doing, and working directly with George Lucas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://arthousecowboy.com/journal/2007/3/23/tmnt-interview.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Arthouse Cowboy - TMNT interview (2007)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wild_9" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Wild 9 - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ltmnDKuqom0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Wild 9 (PS1) Gameplay - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/3417/postmortem_shiny_entertainments_.php" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gamasutra - Features - Postmortem: Shiny Entertainment&amp;#x27;s Wild 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://animatedviews.com/2007/director-kevin-munroe-on-tmnt/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Director Kevin Munroe on TMNT • Animated Views&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Black_Cauldron_(film)" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Black Cauldron (film) - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imagi_Animation_Studios" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Imagi Animation Studios - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science_Ninja_Team_Gatchaman" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Science Ninja Team Gatchaman - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.firstshowing.net/2007/brief-gatchaman-update-from-tmnt-director-kevin-munroe/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Brief Gatchaman Update from TMNT Director Kevin Munroe | FirstShowing.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=DqxIS-oyXwQ" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;#x27;Gatchaman&amp;#x27; Teaser - ANIME EXPO &amp;#x27;09 (off-screen) - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dylan_Dog" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dylan Dog - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dylan_Dog:_Dead_of_Night" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dylan Dog: Dead of Night - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cCeLIa02iy0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dylan Dog : Dead of Night - Official Trailer [HD] - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://collider.com/kevin-munroe-interview-dylan-dog/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Munroe Exclusive Interview DYLAN DOG | Collider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://moviesblog.mtv.com/?p=28972" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;George Lucas Producing CG-Animated Musical About Fairies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vulture.com/2010/01/george_lucas_hard_at_work_on_c.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;George Lucas Hard at Work on CGI-Fairy Musical -- Vulture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/giantsize/19" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Giant Size #19: Signed Peter Laird (Kevin Munroe part 2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://shopify.com/5by5"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://getharvest.com/5by5"&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; (use code 5BY5 for 50% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Moisés Chiullan</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>53:59</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Director, animator, and über-geek Kevin Munroe (TMNT, Wild 9, Olympus Heights) joins Moisés to talk about game design, animation, chasing the creative work you want to be doing, and working directly with George Lucas.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Director, animator, and über-geek Kevin Munroe (TMNT, Wild 9, Olympus Heights) joins Moisés to talk about game design, animation, chasing the creative work you want to be doing, and working directly with George Lucas.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>movies, TV, media, games, HD, entertainment</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/40/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fscreentime%2F32&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic 38: Patrick Rhone on Challenges and Success</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/systematic/38</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/systematic/38</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Brett Terpstra</author>
      <description>Writer and Commentator Patrick Rhone joins Brett to talk about conquering physical and mental challenges, career decisions and "unconscious computing."
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/systematic/2013/systematic-038.mp3" length="35967242" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Writer and Commentator Patrick Rhone joins Brett to talk about conquering physical and mental challenges, career decisions and "unconscious computing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://patrickrhone.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;patrickrhone / journal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://minimalmac.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Minimal Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://patrickrhone.com/2013/03/29/you-cant/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;patrickrhone / journal » Blog Archive » You Can’t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.goruck.com/events" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;MAP | GORUCK | Built in the USA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://readandtrust.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Read &amp;amp; Trust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://qsapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Quicksilver — Mac OS X at your Fingertips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://lifehacker.com/5541901/liteswitch-x-makes-macs-application-switcher-far-more-useful" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;LiteSwitch X Makes Mac&amp;#x27;s Application Switcher Far More Useful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/quiet/id421759530" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mac App Store - Quiet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alfredworkflow.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Alfred 2 Workflow List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://abyssoft.com/software/teleport/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;abyssoft - teleport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/moves/id509204969?mt=8&amp;amp;partnerId=30&amp;amp;siteID=vRL5rYo4h5A" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Moves for iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.subtraction.com/2013/03/27/magic-and-mobile-apps" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Subtraction.com: Magic and Mobile Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=42&amp;amp;t=20396&amp;amp;start=0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Literature and Latte • Scapple Beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/glass/start/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google Glass - Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.colorschemer.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;ColorSchemer | Instant Color Schemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/patrickrhone" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;patrickrhone (patrickrhone) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://alpha.app.net/patrickrhone" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;patrickrhone on App.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code &lt;strong&gt;DANSENTME&lt;/strong&gt; for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://mailchimp.com/5by5"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/5by5"&gt;Smile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Brett Terpstra</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:14:14</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Writer and Commentator Patrick Rhone joins Brett to talk about conquering challenges and career decisions.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Writer and Commentator Patrick Rhone joins Brett to talk about conquering physical and mental challenges, career decisions and "unconscious computing."
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>productivity, work, creativity, mac, iOS</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/39/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fsystematic%2F38&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to Work 113: Entropy's Gonna Do Its Business</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/b2w/113</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/b2w/113</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Merlin Mann &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>TOPIC: Drafts for iOS, and Who You Want to Be

This week, Dan and Merlin cover two very different topics.

First, there's a detailed discussion of one of Merlin's favorite iOS apps, Drafts, including a deep dive on the app's extraordinary interactions with everything from Twitter to calendars to Dropbox.

Second, Dan and Merlin have an A-plus conversation on the hardest question you&amp;#8217;ll ask yourself this week: &amp;#8220;Is this who I want to be?&amp;#8221;

</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/b2w/2013/b2w-113.mp3" length="39437786" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOPIC&lt;/strong&gt;: Drafts for iOS, and Who You Want to Be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, Dan and Merlin cover two very different topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there's a detailed discussion of one of Merlin's favorite iOS apps, &lt;a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts" title="Drafts is a different kind of note taking app. In Drafts, text comes first – open the app and get a new, blank draft. Don’t get bogged down in a timeline to tweet or post to Facebook and App.net. Don’t tap through multiple screens to compose an email or SMS. Don’t navigate folders, create files and name them just to jot down a note or create a todo. Drafts is available for both iPhone and iPad."&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;, including a deep dive on the app's extraordinary interactions with everything from Twitter to calendars to Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Dan and Merlin have an A-plus conversation on the hardest question you&amp;#8217;ll ask yourself this week: &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Is &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; who I want to be?&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[SPONSOR] Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Royalty-Free Subscription Stock Photography &amp;amp; Vector Art - Search and select from millions of high resolution royalty free images, stock photos, vector art, and stock photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.scruffy.tv/scruffy/2013/3/26/fancy-monkeys.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fancy Monkeys - Scruffy Thinking - Scruffy.TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this special That Scruffy Post Show Kanen sits down with Stu Maschwitz and Merlin Mann on their second visit to the show! They discuss delegation, dealing with email and to do lists, assistants, and working hard to make being lazy possible. Does it get better than that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.indiewire.com/article/television/why-adventure-time-is-the-best-sci-fi-show-on-tv-right-now" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Why &amp;#x27;Adventure Time&amp;#x27; Is the Best Sci-Fi Show on TV Right Now | Filmmakers, Film Industry, Film Festivals, Awards &amp;amp; Movie Reviews | Indiewire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you love a show so much it can do weird things to your head. I've gone out on a limb with Cartoon Network's "Adventure Time" by deeming it a groundbreaking form of cartoon storytelling that fuses several eras of animation into a delightfully surreal and yet oddly familiar experience. I also wondered if the entire show was one big metaphor for sex. I stand by the former and wince a little when contemplating the latter as anything other than one more manifestation of the fun possibilities involved in reading into a show that has a deceptively simple surface and tangibly dark interiors. But after last night's wonderful flashback special episode, "Simon and Marcy," I'm convinced of one thing: "Adventure Time" is the best science fiction show on television right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://qsapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Quicksilver — Mac OS X at your Fingertips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quicksilver is a fast and free Mac OS X productivity application that gives you the power to control your Mac quickly and elegantly. Quicksilver learns your habits, making your everyday chores simple and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.qsapp.com/post/46268365849/quicksilver-comes-of-age" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Quicksilver — LoveQuicksilver Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After almost 10 years of testing, Quicksilver lays the beta tag to rest. (If the lack of an eszett brings a tear to your eye, you can always reminisce by hitting ?S on your keyboard). What does this release mean? It means more than just a change in the version numbering system - it signifies a maturity of Quicksilver and a sign of what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.qsapp.com/post/46268470658/quicksilver-an-interview-with-the-developers" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Quicksilver — LoveQuicksilver Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the release of Quicksilver v1.0, I sat with Quicksilver’s lead developers (at our respective far-flung computers) to gather their thoughts on this historic occasion, and to find out a bit more about Quicksilver behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Drafts - Agile Tortoise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drafts is a different kind of note taking app. In Drafts, text comes first – open the app and get a new, blank draft. Don’t get bogged down in a timeline to tweet or post to Facebook and App.net. Don’t tap through multiple screens to compose an email or SMS. Don’t navigate folders, create files and name them just to jot down a note or create a todo. Drafts is available for both iPhone and iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0307387895/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: &amp;quot;The Road&amp;quot; by Cormac McCarthy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/46786245163/i-steal-jewels" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gunter - The Adventure Time Wiki. Mathematical! | kung fu grippe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depeche_mode" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Depeche Mode - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depeche Mode (pron.: /d&amp;#x268;&amp;#x2C8;p&amp;#x25B;&amp;#x283;/) are an English electronic music band formed in 1980 in Basildon, Essex. The group&amp;#8217;s original line-up consisted of Dave Gahan (lead vocals, occasional songwriter since 2005), Martin Gore (keyboards, guitar, vocals, chief songwriter after 1981), Andy Fletcher (keyboards) and Vince Clarke (keyboards, chief songwriter 1980–81). Clarke left the band after the release of their 1981 debut album, Speak &amp;amp; Spell, and was replaced by Alan Wilder (keyboards, drums, occasional songwriter) with Gore taking over songwriting. Wilder left the band in 1995; Gahan, Gore, and Fletcher have since continued as a trio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://prolost.com/about/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Prolost - About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stu Maschwitz is a filmmaker, photographer, and writer, with a passion for kinetic storytelling. A graduate of CalArts, Maschwitz spent four years at Industrial Light&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stu_Maschwitz" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Stu Maschwitz - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stuart T. Maschwitz, commonly known as Stu Maschwitz, was the co-founder and chief technology officer of The Orphanage, a visual effects company that was based in California. He has worked as senior visual effects supervisor on several films. He previously worked at Industrial Light and Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/5tu" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Stu Maschwitz (5tu) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filmmaking nerd.Bay Area, CA &lt;br/&gt;
http://prolost.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0556179/?ref_=fn_al_nm_1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Stuart T. Maschwitz - IMDb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://adventuretime.wikia.com/wiki/I_Remember_You" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;I Remember You - The Adventure Time Wiki. Mathematical!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ice King visits Marceline to ask for help in creating a song to attract princesses, but Marceline struggles to deal emotionally with his presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://adventuretime.wikia.com/wiki/Simon_and_Marcy" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Simon and Marcy - The Adventure Time Wiki. Mathematical!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Synopsis: Ice King and Marceline 996 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://adventuretime.wikia.com/wiki/Simon_and_Marcy/Transcript" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Simon and Marcy/Transcript - The Adventure Time Wiki. Mathematical!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://adventuretime.wikia.com/wiki/Gunter" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gunter - The Adventure Time Wiki. Mathematical!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gunter is the name of the penguin that most commonly accompanies the Ice King, although in "Princess Monster Wife," it is shown that multiple penguins have subtle variants of that name but the Ice King pronounces the other penguins' names differently. The Ice King uses Gunter as his personal servant, whereas the other penguins working for the Ice King are more or less slaves. It is not completely clear whether Gunter is male or female.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120623/combined" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;A Bug&amp;#x27;s Life (1998)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0005581/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;David L. Lander - IMDb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar_number" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dunbar&amp;#x27;s number - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dunbar's number is a suggested cognitive limit to the number of people with whom one can maintain stable social relationships. These are relationships in which an individual knows who each person is, and how each person relates to every other person.[1] Proponents assert that numbers larger than this generally require more restrictive rules, laws, and enforced norms to maintain a stable, cohesive group. It has been proposed to lie between 100 and 230, with a commonly used value of 150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://audiob.us/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Audiobus: Live, app-to-app audio.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your audio apps together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/drafts-for-ipad/id542797283?mt=8&amp;amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Drafts for iPad for iPad on the iTunes App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drafts, where text starts on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tv.com/shows/sherlock/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sherlock - TV.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This three-part series retells the tale of England's most celebrated detective but in a modern-day setting, with Benedict Cumberbatch and Martin Freeman taking the leads as Sherlock Holmes and Dr John Watson respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oPORqvsWwFM" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Nuts (Pitiful Old Man) / Remember You - Marceline and The Ice King (aka Simon) - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is from the cartoon Adventure Time from episode 4x25 called 'I Remember You'. Olivia Olson played Marcy and The Ice King is played by Tom Kenny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/anna_debenham" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Anna Debenham (anna_debenham) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Front-end Astronaut&lt;br/&gt;
Brighton · http://www.maban.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NXF2kjSZjo" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Marceline &amp;amp; Simon - &amp;quot;Remember You&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This magic keeps me alive&lt;br/&gt;
But, it's making me crazy&lt;br/&gt;
And, I need to save you&lt;br/&gt;
But, who's going to save me?&lt;br/&gt;
Please forgive me for whatever I do&lt;br/&gt;
When I don't remember you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lyricsreg.com/lyrics/adventure+time/Remember+you+Marceline+and+the+Ice+King/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Remember you (Marceline &amp;amp; the Ice King) lyrics - ADVENTURE TIME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Marceline…I can feel myself slipping away"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://flexibits.com/fantastical" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Flexibits | Fantastical for Mac | Meet your Mac&amp;#x27;s new calendar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mac calendar you'll actually enjoy using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://appcubby.com/launch-center/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;App Cubby • Hand Crafted iPhone Apps - Launch Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch actions, not just apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like speed dial, but for more than just phone calls! Launch Center Pro creates lightning quick shortcuts to specific features buried deep within apps. Call a loved one, message a friend, launch Instagram’s camera to quickly snap a pic, tweet, or turn your iPhone into a flashlight. Launch Center Pro gets you to where you’re going faster than ever before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/hypercritical/15" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Hypercritical #15: The Bridges of Siracusa County&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w/13" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Back to Work #13: The Kid&amp;#x27;s Great&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan and Merlin talk about "Cranking" - Merlin's latest post at 43folders.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/mpu" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Mac Power Users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://huffduffer.com/merlinmann/106852" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fancy Monkeys - That Scruffy Post Show with guests Merlin Mann and Stu Maschwitz on Huffduffer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this special That Scruffy Post Show Kanen sits down with Stu Maschwitz and Merlin Mann on their second visit to the show! They discuss delegation, dealing with email and to do lists, assistants, and working hard to make being lazy possible. Does it get better than that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0432283/combined" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;IMDB: Fantastic Mr. Fox (2009)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_Mr_Fox" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fantastic Mr Fox - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantastic Mr Fox is a children's novel written by British author Roald Dahl. It was published in 1970 by George Allen &amp;amp; Unwin in the UK and Alfred A. Knopf in the U.S., with illustrations by Donald Chaffin. The first UK Puffin paperback edition, first issued in 1974, featured illustrations by Jill Bennett. Later editions have featured illustrations by Tony Ross (1988) and Quentin Blake (1996). The story is about Mr Fox and how he outwits his farmer neighbours to steal their food from right under their noses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.foxsearchlight.com/fantasticmrfox/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fantastic Mr. Fox | Fox Searchlight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this special That Scruffy Post Show Kanen sits down with Stu Maschwitz and Merlin Mann on their second visit to the show! They discuss delegation, dealing with email and to do lists, assistants, and working hard to make being lazy possible. Does it get better than that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6288.The_Road" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;quot;The Road&amp;quot; by Cormac McCarthy - Reviews, Discussion, Bookclubs, Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A searing, postapocalyptic novel destined to become Cormac McCarthy’s masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A father and his son walk alone through burned America. Nothing moves in the ravaged landscape save the ash on the wind. It is cold enough to crack stones, and when the snow falls it is gray. The sky is dark. Their destination is the coast, although they don’t know what, if anything, awaits them there. They have nothing; just a pistol to defend themselves against the lawless bands that stalk the road, the clothes they are wearing, a cart of scavenged food—and each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marceline_the_Vampire_Queen" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Marceline the Vampire Queen - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marceline the Vampire Queen is a main character in the American animated television series Adventure Time created by Pendleton Ward. She is voiced by Olivia Olson in most appearances, by Ava Acres as a child and by Cloris Leachman as an old woman. Marceline is a fun-loving 1,000-year-old trickster vampire queen. The name Marceline is based on the middle name of a childhood friend of Ward's, Marie. The artistic design for Marceline was created by Ward, with small changes and additions added by Phil Rynda, former lead character designer and prop designer for Adventure Time. Unlike a traditional vampire, Marceline does not need to drink blood to survive; rather, she eats the color red. Marceline is a musician who plays an electric bass that she made from her family's heirloom battle-axe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://handleopenurl.com/about-handleopenurl" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;About handleOpenURL: - handleOpenURL: Shared Interapp Communication on iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set up handleOpenURL.com because we were looking for a central place where we could find more info about the schemes other apps were using and where we could share the schemes we implemented in our apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching the Internet turned up information scattered all over the net. We thought it would be a nice thing to set up a place where this information is collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;handleOpenURL.com is open to developers to share their URL schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.akosma.com/IPhone_URL_Schemes" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;IPhone URL Schemes - akosma wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page centralizes code samples for URL schemes available in many iPhone applications, not only in Apple's but in many others. It also includes programming tips and references about implementing apps registering or consuming URL schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://getwritingkit.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Writing Kit 3.x · Unitasking at its finest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced Markdown Text Editor…Meets Awesome Researching Tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.retrologic.com/jargon/W/whacker.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;whacker - The Jargon File v4.4.7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person, similar to a hacker, who enjoys exploring the details of programmable systems and how to stretch their capabilities. Whereas a hacker tends to produce great hacks, a whacker only ends up whacking the system or program in question. Whackers are often quite egotistical and eager to claim wizard status, regardless of the views of their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antonio_Gramsci#Hegemony" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Antonio Gramsci (Hegemony) - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Gramsci, hegemonic dominance ultimately relied on a "consented" coercion, and in a "crisis of authority" the "masks of consent" slip away, revealing the fist of force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week's episode of &lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w" title="5by5 | Back to Work - 5by5 - Back to Work"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back to Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is kindly sponsored by: &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com/" title="Stock Photos | Shutterstock: Royalty-Free Subscription Stock Photography &amp;amp; Vector Art - Search and select from millions of high resolution royalty free images, stock photos, vector art, and stock photography."&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;BACKTOWORK4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" for 30% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Merlin Mann &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:21:22</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>TOPIC: Drafts for iOS, and Who You Want to Be</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>TOPIC: Drafts for iOS, and Who You Want to Be

This week, Dan and Merlin cover two very different topics.

First, there's a detailed discussion of one of Merlin's favorite iOS apps, Drafts, including a deep dive on the app's extraordinary interactions with everything from Twitter to calendars to Dropbox.

Second, Dan and Merlin have an A-plus conversation on the hardest question you&amp;#8217;ll ask yourself this week: &amp;#8220;Is this who I want to be?&amp;#8221;

</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>productivity, communication, work, barriers, constraints, tools</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/19/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fb2w%2F113&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 115: The Topo Chico Fiasco </title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/115</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/115</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 17:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie are joined by Ashley Baxter to discuss gaming, the Loch Ness Monster and photography. Plus Heidi Klum saves her kids, a video game meant to induce synesthesia is released, Austin is on Kim Jung Un's hit list, and meal worms burrow out of stomachs.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-115.mp3" length="32856210" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie are joined by Ashley Baxter to discuss gaming, the Loch Ness Monster and photography. Plus Heidi Klum saves her kids, a video game meant to induce synesthesia is released, Austin is on Kim Jung Un's hit list, and meal worms burrow out of stomachs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/01/white-house-kid-president/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Kid President Stars in White House April Fools Prank [VIDEO]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The White House has employed the motivational talents of Kid President for its April Fools Day prank.The official White House YouTube channel released a video Monday morning titled "A Special Message From the President," but instead of Barack Obama, viewers got a message from the charming suit-and-tie-sporting Internet celeb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2013/04/gentlemint_manteresting_tapiture_is_it_sexist_to_create_a_pinterest_for.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gentlemint, Manteresting, Tapiture: Is it sexist to create a Pinterest for dudes? - Slate Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not guys understood Pinterest’s appeal, they had no difficulty intuiting that pins could make them rich. (Investors recently pegged Pinterest’s value at $2.5 billion.) If Pinterest was disproportionately attracting women, thought clever entrepreneurs, why not zag and target an underserved market? The race was on to create a visual sharing site designed for men. Soon enough, an onslaught of “Pinterests for Dudes” hit the scene, starting with Gentlemint and Manteresting, followed not long after by Dudepins, PunchPin, and probably a whole slew of other clones that feature portmanteaus built from the word bro. Strongest out of the gate so far, in terms of traffic and funding, has been Tapiture, which received $825,000 in seed investments in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/02/jimmy-fallon-jay-leno-rumors/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Falllon and Leno Face &amp;#x27;Tonight Show&amp;#x27; Rumors in Duet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosts Jimmy Fallon and Jay Leno turned rumors about the future of NBC's Tonight Show into a hilarious self-mocking duet.Media has speculated that Fallon will take over in 2014 as host of The Tonight Show, which Leno has hosted for 21 seasons. Though neither side has officially confirmed the rumors, the hosts addressed them Monday night in between their two shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/26/beard-beer-rogue-ales-yeast-john-maier_n_1917119.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Beard Beer: Rogue Ales Creates Brew Out Of Yeast From Brewmaster John Maier&amp;#x27;s Facial Hair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rogue Ales, a brewery and pub based in Newport, Ore., is developing an ale made out of yeast harvested from the beard of award-winning brewmaster John "More Hops" Maier.The whole thing started as a joke. Brett Joyce, president of Rogue Ales, told KPTV on Sunday that the folks at Rogue Ales had been trying to harvest a new yeast strain from their hop yard for some time, but with little success.Then the thought occurred to Joyce, "Why not look for a different place that might have some magic yeast in it?"Brewery employees took nine follicles from Maier's beard, which Maier says has not been shaved since 1978.Miraculously, lab workers found a yeast that turned out to be perfect for fermenting beer, according to the brewery's blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/2/4173468/air-samoa-pricing-flights-according-to-passenger-weight" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Air Samoa starts charging passengers by body weight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samoa Air has scrapped its traditional pricing structure and switched to a pay-what-you-weigh system. Under the new rules, passengers are required to enter their weight along with the weight of their baggage when booking. The combined weight will then be used to calculate the fare, and the details will be verified again at the airport to stop people from lying to get a cheaper rate. The cost will vary significantly depending on the length of the flight, but passengers will pay roughly $50 - $200 per 100lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/cheats/2013/04/02/heidi-klum-saved-son-from-drowning.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Heidi Klum Saved Son From Drowning - The Daily Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This no April Fools’ Day prank. Heidi Klum and her bodyguard boyfriend, Martin Kirsten, saved her 7-year-old son, Henry, and two nannies from being pulled into a riptide while vacationing in Hawaii on Sunday. “Of course, as a mother, I was very scared for my child and everyone else in the water,” Klum told Us Weekly. “Henry is a strong swimmer and was able to swim back to land. We got everyone else out safely.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://torrentfreak.com/game-of-thrones-pirates-break-bittorrent-swarm-record-130401/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Game of Thrones Pirates Break BitTorrent Swarm Record | TorrentFreak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a million downloads on BitTorrent in less than a day, the season premiere of Game of Thrones is breaking records on multiple fronts. Never before has there been a torrent with so many people sharing a file at the same time, more than 160,000 simultaneous peers. Data gathered by TorrentFreak further shows that Australia has the highest piracy rate of the popular download destinations, while London tops the list of pirate cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://marketingland.com/twitter-relaunches-its-twitter-for-business-site-38331" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter Relaunches Its Twitter For Business Site With More Content, New Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter has relaunched its Twitter For Business website with a new look, plus additional content that Twitter hopes will help businesses learn how to build a successful presence there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wherehaveallthewildlingsgone.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Game of Thrones / by Nigel Evan Dennis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designer Nigel Evan Dennis has created Where have all the wildlings gone?, a stylized guide to the many Game of Thrones characters and their ever-changing allegiances, as well as a minimalist timeline of Westeros’ recorded history dating back about 13,000 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://unaustin.tumblr.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Why Kim Jong Un Hates Austin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why Kim Jong Un Hates Austin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/tsXkj3i.gif" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Louisville Team Reacts to Kevin Ware&amp;#x27;s Injury [SFW]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Ware's benched teammates react to his injury after he broke his leg in the first half of the NCAA Tournament game at Lucas Oil Stadium in Indianapolis on March 31, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/01/april-fools-day-origin/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Where Does April Fools&amp;#x27; Day Originate?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common theory about the earliest April Fools’ celebrations goes like this: In 1582, Pope Gregory XIII issued a papal bull decreeing a new standard calendar for Christian Europe that would take his name and centuries later become the standard internationally in the 21st century.Prior to the 15th century, Europe’s nations and city states operated using the Julian calendar. The Gregorian calendar moved the date of the new year from April 1 to January 1, among other changes. Catholic monarchies were naturally its earliest adopters, though Protestant nations later followed suit.Given the nature of the reform, both in terms of communicating such a fundamental change to a large population and dealing with critics of the new calendar, some Europeans continued to celebrate the new year between March 25 and April 1. April fools were those who still celebrated the holiday in the spring, and were the subject of pranks and ridicule by those who observed the new year months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.swiss-miss.com/2013/03/marina-abramovic-and-ulay.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;swissmiss | Marina Abramovic and Ulay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was moved to tears last night while watching this moment between the artist Marina Abramovic and her former love Ulay. Apparently they started an intense love story in the 70s and when they felt the relationship had run its course, they decided to walk the Great Wall of China, each from one end, meeting for one last big hug in the middle and never seeing each other again.During her 2010 MoMA retrospective Ulay arrived without her knowing and this is what happened. Really moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/02/new-york-times-prudential-ad/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;#x27;New York Times&amp;#x27; Ad Shows Paper on Day You Were Born&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add this to the list of clever display ads: Life insurance company Prudential is staging a front-page takeover of the NYTimes.com Tuesday. The takeover includes a large interactive unit above the fold that asks you to enter your birth date to see the front page of the Times on the day you were born.To execute the ad, the Times developed an API with an index of 139 years of front pages, from 1863 to 2002, a spokesperson said. That's more than 50,000 covers in total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/02/funny-or-die-steve-jobs-trailer/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Funny or Die&amp;#x27;s Steve Jobs Biopic Releases April 15 [VIDEO]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, Funny or Die announced that it would be making a film about the life of Steve Jobs called iSteve, poking fun at the number of biopics currently in the works.The first trailer released on Tuesday, advertising an April 15 release. The 60 to 75-minute online film features comedian Justin Long (known for the "Get a Mac" commercials) as the late Apple co-founder who died in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/synesthesia" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;syn·es·the·sia  [sin-uhs-thee-zhuh, -zhee-uh, -zee-uh]  Show IPA noun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a sensation produced in one modality when a stimulus is applied to another modality, as when the hearing of a certain sound induces the visualization of a certain color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcodesign.com/1672228/a-video-game-designed-to-induce-synesthesia#1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;1 | A Video Game Designed To Induce Synesthesia | Co.Design: business + innovation + design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound wasn’t the thing most of us focused on while playing childhood platform games. We waited on visual cues to know when to jump, or grab the feather, or dodge a flaming rock. Yet the audio soundtracks were actually hugely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/2/4173522/hyundai-e4u-personal-mobility-vehicle-tron-concept" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Hyundai dreams up egg-shaped E4U personal transporter | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking like a bumblebee-colored egg that fell into Tron's grid, the E4U moves by using a semisphere that constantly spins horizontally. The spinning semisphere is tilted to generate drive while two stabilizing wheels at the rear keep it moving straight. A fully-drivable E4U was recently demoed for the first time at the Seoul Motor Show. Hyundai's demo unit is limited to walking speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://iamashley.co.uk/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ashley Baxter | I am Ashley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iamashley" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ashley Baxter (iamashley) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://girlwithacamera.co.uk/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Girl With A Camera | Pictographs of Ashley Baxter&amp;#x27;s life.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/04/01/dinners-revenge-mealworms.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dinner’s Revenge: mealworms that survive in the stomach, then eat their way out of predators - Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/frequency"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY4 for 10% off) and &lt;a href="http://hobancards.com"&gt;Hoban Press&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY for free shipping).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:07:32</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie are joined by Ashley Baxter to discuss gaming, the Loch Ness Monster and photography. Plus Heidi Klum saves her kids, a video game meant to induce synesthesia is released, Austin is on Kim Jung Un's hit list, and meal worms burrow out of st</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie are joined by Ashley Baxter to discuss gaming, the Loch Ness Monster and photography. Plus Heidi Klum saves her kids, a video game meant to induce synesthesia is released, Austin is on Kim Jung Un's hit list, and meal worms burrow out of stomachs.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F115&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 35: Tuesday, April 2, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/35</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/35</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Myke Hurley</author>
      <description>
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-035.mp3" length="4286070" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/01/now-with-3-million-new-users-google-readers-heir-apparent-feedly-relaunches-on-ios-android-reveals-how-it-plans-to-make-money/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Now With 3 Million New Users, Google Reader’s Heir Apparent Feedly Relaunches On iOS &amp;amp; Android, Reveals How It Plans To Make Money | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedly, the RSS feed-reading client that is rapidly becoming the one to beat following the planned Google Reader shutdown, is today launching new versions of its Feedly Mobile client for iPhone, iPad, iPod touch, and Android phones and tablets. This update, built-in response to user feedback, is focused on improving search, productivity, discovery and sharing. But the feature, which is likely to appeal to ex-Google Reader users the most is the new “title only” mode, designed to make headline scanning more efficient.The startup says it has now seen 3 million new users sign up for its service in the wake of Google’s announcement that it’s shuttering Google Reader on July 1, 2013. Prior to this, Feedly had grown its own user base organically to 4 million users since its founding in 2008, to give you some perspective on how rapid this growth has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/01/500-startups-backed-food-delivery-startup-chewse-raises-1-million-from-chris-sacca-and-others/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;500 Startups-Backed Food Delivery Startup Chewse Raises $1 Million From Chris Sacca And Others | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chewse is the newest entrant into the food delivery game, as it seeks to provide office admins a new, easy way to get lunch catered. To do so, the company has raised $1 million in seed funding from a group of investors that include Chris Sacca and 500 Startups.Unlike Postmates’ Get It Now, Seamless, or GrubHub, Chewse is focused on getting offices of workers fed, and its target decision maker is the office manager tasked with making sure that all employees are happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/01/facebook-htc-homescreen/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Phone Leak Points To Budget HTC Device, Homescreen App For All Androids | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s new “Home” on Android will debut on a mediocre HTC handset codenamed “Myst” but will be available on standard Android phones, according to an autopsy of a leaked developer build of the Facebook “phone” scored by Android Police. This aligns with our scoop and predictions from last week about what Facebook will launch at its big press event on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/2032765/macworld-iworld-2014-rescheduled-for-march-27-through-march-29.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Macworld/iWorld 2014 rescheduled for March 27 through March 29 | Macworld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next year’s Macworld/iWorld expo will now take place March 27 through March 29, 2014. It had previously been scheduled for the first three days of February. The rescheduled event will move from Moscone West to Moscone North in San Francisco, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/02/technology/apples-chief-tim-cook-apologizes-to-china-over-warranty-policy.html?partner=rss&amp;amp;emc=rss&amp;amp;smid=tw-nytimes&amp;amp;_r=0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Tim Cook of Apple Apologizes to China Over Warranty Policy - NYTimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s chief executive, Tim Cook, took the unusual step Monday of apologizing to Chinese customers over the company’s warranty policy and said he would improve customer service in the country. More Tech CoverageNews from the technology industry, including start-ups, the Internet, enterprise and gadgets.On Twitter: @nytimesbits.Apple’s apology late Monday was the latest twist in a strange spectacle that has unfolded in recent weeks in China over Apple’s warranty policies here, underscoring the challenges the company is facing as the country becomes an important market for its products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/04/01/amazon-kindle-fire-hd-8-9-lte-hits-atandt-retail-on-april-5th/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Kindle Fire HD 8.9 LTE hits AT&amp;amp;T retail on April 5th with a $249 contract option&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T will now be selling the LTE version of Amazon's Kindle Fire HD 8.9 beginning April 5th. The carrier is also offering an alternative purchase model. The $399 contract-free purchase is still available for those who want their freedom, but the initial price can drop to $249 for anyone willing to sign a two-year contract for a data plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/04/02/rosetta-stone-buys-up-online-language-learning-community-livemocha-for-8-3m-in-cash/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Rosetta Stone Buys Up Online Language Learning Community Livemocha For $8.5M In Cash | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosetta Stone has just acquired Seattle-based online language-learning community Livemocha for $8.5 million in cash. Livemocha has one of the largest online language-learning communities in the world, boasting over 16 million members from over 195 different countries.Rosetta Stone will likely use Livemocha’s cloud platform to offer its language packages online — they were once only available via disc set, with a complimentary iPad app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13579_3-57577403-37/next-two-iphones-may-have-been-designed-under-steve-jobs/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Next two iPhones may have been designed under Steve Jobs | Apple - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Steve Jobs era may not quite be over at Apple.The late co-founder may have been involved in the development of the next two versions of iPhone, according to a report in the San Francisco Examiner. That information was supposedly imparted to San Francisco District Attorney George Gascón by Apple's government liaison, Michael Foulkes, during discussions with Apple regarding the growing problem of mobile phone theft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/4/1/4170788/mp3s-cant-be-resold-online-court-rules-capitol-redigi" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;MP3s can&amp;#x27;t be resold online, says district court | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reselling copies of MP3s you legally purchased violates copyright, according to a ruling made over the weekend by a New York district court judge. The ruling is a victory for Capitol Records, a subsidiary of Vivendi, and marks a devastating loss to ReDigi, a website that lets users resell copies of their legally purchased MP3s. The decision applies only to the New York jurisdiction for now, but could serve as a model for other states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2013/joke-amazon-hires-windows-phone-vet-charlie-kindel-something-secret/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;No joke: Amazon hires Windows Phone vet Charlie Kindel for &amp;#x27;something secret&amp;#x27; - GeekWire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlie Kindel, the Seattle tech veteran who left his job as a Microsoft Windows Phone general manager in 2011 to join the startup world, has now been hired by Amazon.com as the director of an undisclosed project inside the company.“I’m building a new team going after a totally new area for Amazon. I’m hiring cloud and mobile developers and testers, program managers, and product managers, he writes on his LinkedIn profile, which describes the position as director of “something secret.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2013/04/01/googles-privacy-director-is-stepping-down/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google&amp;#x27;s Privacy Director Is Stepping Down - Forbes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Alma Whitten was tapped to be Google‘s first director of privacy in 2010, CNet declared hers the “hardest job at Google.” A long time engineer at the company with expertise in computer security, she was put in charge of a program overseeing products in development at Google to try to prevent the release of those that got privacy wrong.Now she’s giving that job up. Whitten announced internally at Google that she is stepping down from her post with plans to retire. She’s remaining for a couple of months while the privacy team transitions to new leadership. Whitten, who has been overseeing privacy at Google from the company’s London office, will be replaced by Lawrence You, an engineer who has been with the company for eight years and is based in Mountain View, where much of the privacy-violating magic happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/04/02/twitter-for-business-relaunch/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter Relaunches Twitter For Business, Offers Companies Tips For Success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter relaunched Twitter for Business Monday, an online resource for businesses to learn the best practices in incorporating Twitter into their marketing efforts. Online lessons include everything from mastering the basics and building your community to how to use Twitter Ads self-service functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://torrentfreak.com/game-of-thrones-pirates-break-bittorrent-swarm-record-130401/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Game of Thrones Pirates Break BitTorrent Swarm Record | TorrentFreak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a million downloads on BitTorrent in less than a day, the season premiere of Game of Thrones is breaking records on multiple fronts. Never before has there been a torrent with so many people sharing a file at the same time, more than 160,000 simultaneous peers. Data gathered by TorrentFreak further shows that Australia has the highest piracy rate of the popular download destinations, while London tops the list of pirate cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/imyke" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Myke Hurley (imyke) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://mailchimp.com/5by5"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Myke Hurley</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>8:16</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F35&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Critical Path 78: Facebook Inside</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/criticalpath/78</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/criticalpath/78</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Horace Dediu &amp; Moisés Chiullan</author>
      <description>Youtubers, BlackBerries and what Facebook is planning with their "Home on Android". Horace and Moisés discuss how co-branding, strategy, and secret deals intertwine, with illustrations from Intel, Sony-Ericsson, and Acura
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/criticalpath/2013/criticalpath-078.mp3" length="34534555" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Youtubers, BlackBerries and what Facebook is planning with their "Home on Android". Horace and Moisés discuss how co-branding, strategy, and secret deals intertwine, with illustrations from Intel, Sony-Ericsson, and Acura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/criticalpath/77" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | The Critical Path #77: Making Sausages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://edwardspoonhands.com/post/46305605617/lessons-learned-from-youtubes-300m-hole" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Lessons Learned from YouTube&amp;#x27;s $300M Hole - Hank&amp;#x27;s Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/screentime/30" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Screen Time #30: TableTop Day (with Boyan Radakovich)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.asymco.com/2013/03/30/samsung-vs-google-an-interview-with-rafael-barbosa-barifouse-of-redacao-epoca/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Samsung vs. Google: an Interview with Rafael Barbosa Barifouse of Redacao Epoca | asymco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://shopify.com/5by5"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://getharvest.com/5by5"&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; (use code 5BY5 for 50% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Horace Dediu &amp; Moisés Chiullan</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:11:13</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Youtubers, BlackBerries and what Facebook is planning with their "Home on Android". Horace and Moisés discuss how co-branding, strategy, and secret deals intertwine, with illustrations from Intel, Sony-Ericsson, and Acura</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Youtubers, BlackBerries and what Facebook is planning with their "Home on Android". Horace and Moisés discuss how co-branding, strategy, and secret deals intertwine, with illustrations from Intel, Sony-Ericsson, and Acura
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>mobile, apple, iphone, ipad, ios, rim, blackberry, nokia, android, google</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/24/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fcriticalpath%2F78&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 114: Trapped In A Lion Cage</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/114</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/114</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 17:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie discuss the tech April Fools jokes from around the web including Google's Nose and the retirement of the Youtube site. Dan also tries to convince Haddie she needs an at home perm.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-114.mp3" length="35988605" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie discuss the tech April Fools jokes from around the web including Google's Nose and the retirement of the Youtube site. Dan also tries to convince Haddie she needs an at home perm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-31/michael-dell-said-to-consider-blackstone-lbo-with-ceo-guarantee.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Dell Said to Consider Blackstone LBO Only With CEO Guarantee - Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dell Inc. (DELL) founder Michael Dell will only consider backing a buyout by Blackstone Group LP (BX) if the private-equity firm guarantees he can remain as chief executive officer, according to a person familiar with the discussions.In several recent meetings in Austin, Texas, with Chinh Chu and David Johnson -- the Blackstone executives overseeing the firm’s bid -- Michael Dell said he would be more likely to support their proposal if he retained an influential role, a second person familiar with the talks said. Negotiations are ongoing and the two sides may not reach an understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/31/googles-doodle-features-american-labor-leader-cesar-chavez-on-easter-sunday-users-retaliate-on-twitter/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google’s Doodle Features American Labor Leader Cesar Chavez On Easter Sunday, Users Retaliate On Twitter | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s Doodles on the Google.com search page don’t frequently stir up too much controversy, but today many users are outraged by the search giant’s choice in featuring Cesar Chavez, an American farm worker, labor leader and civil rights activist. Of course, today is also Easter, which is one of the most observed and celebrated religious holidays for Christians around the world.Users have taken to Twitter, expressing anger over the fact that the Doodle features the labor leader instead of a drawing honoring the holiday (Google search engine rival Bing did feature Easter Eggs on its homepage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/31/raspberry-pi-model-a-arrives-in-us/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Lowest Cost Raspberry Pi Microcomputer Now On Sale In The U.S. — $25 Model A Suited For Battery/Solar Powered Projects | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi microcomputer prides itself on being affordable, with its tiny $35 price-tag for the original Model B Pi. But now its lowest cost board — the $25 Model A — has gone on sale in the U.S. The Raspberry Pi Foundation confirmed to TechCrunch that Model A can now be purchased in the U.S. via reseller Allied Electronics (which currently appears to have 70 units in stock).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/30/4164126/we-are-the-explorers-nasa-trailer-crowdfunding-goal-star-trek" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;NASA trailer reaches crowdfunding goal, will be shown before &amp;#x27;Star Trek: Into Darkness&amp;#x27; | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A clip created by the Aerospace Industries Association (AIA) of America, gives a brief overview of NASA's history and its latest developments in spacecraft technology, but federal law prohibits the agency from purchasing advertising time to air it. That will soon change, though, now that AIA — an aerospace trade group not affiliated with NASA — has reached its its crowdfunded goal of $33,000. The organization plans to convert a short NASA film into a 30-second trailer that will run in theaters across major US markets, beginning with the premiere of Star Trek: Into Darkness on May 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13579_3-57577169-37/apple-application-to-trademark-ipad-mini-denied/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple application to trademark iPad Mini denied | Apple - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Patent and Trademark Office has denied Apple's bid to trademark the term "iPad Mini," contending that "mini" is "merely descriptive" of goods or services sold in miniature form.In a letter sent to Apple in January but only recently published, the USPTO reviewer denied Apple's application because "the applied-for mark merely describes a feature or characteristic of applicant's goods." Apple can appeal the decision, but to win a reversal the company will need to address the office's reasons for denial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/30/4162862/list-of-googles-if-i-had-glass-winners-reveals-celebrities-and-high-follower-counts" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google&amp;#x27;s &amp;#x27;If I Had Glass&amp;#x27; winners list dominated by celebrities, popular Twitter accounts | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google's "If I Had Glass" competition has always been a public affair: applications were submitted using a hashtag on Twitter and Google , and winners offered the opportunity to be among the first to purchase Glass started receiving notifications in the form of public replies earlier this week. Stanford computer science Ph.D student Andrej Karpathy has accumulated data on winners who entered using Twitter from the publicly-available data, and it provides the opportunity for a bit of analysis into how winners were chosen. In the wake of the competition, it became apparent that not everyone who had been selected embodied the spirit of the competition, and Google has since announced that it will rescind some of its Google Glass offers after taking a closer look at the applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/03/27/175371800/solar-powered-plane-uses-its-lightness-to-fly-in-the-dark" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Solar-Powered Plane Uses Its Lightness To Fly In The Dark : All Tech Considered : NPR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next month, a very odd looking plane will take off from Moffett Field in Mountain View, Calif., and head east to New York. The Solar Impulse — the world's first solar-powered plane — is capable of flying nonstop all day and all night. Its creators plan to fly it across the U.S. this spring, and by 2015 they hope to fly a similar aircraft around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/31/da-vinci-invent-google-glass/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Did Da Vinci Invent Google Glass?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leonard Da Vinci, the 15th-century Renaissance man, is credited with envisioning or outright inventing hundreds of modern-day devices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/31/world-backup-day-2013/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s World Backup Day: no time like the present to protect the past&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of computer owners: those that backup their data, and those who will backup after they lose something irreplaceable. It's that last group for whom World Backup Day exists, and the special occasion has returned for a third year to make sure we all wind up in that first, very responsible camp. Thankfully, it's easier than ever to have at least some kind of safety net. Along with ridiculously high-capacity external hard drives, both Mac and Windows users have simple built-in software to make backup a set-it-and-forget-it affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/31/all-things-sxsw-reconsidered/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;All Things SXSW (Re)Considered | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Things SXSW (Re)Considered is an analytical look at the changes seen at SXSW over the last 20 years. From a music conference to a sea of start ups, free t-shirts and energy drinks SXSW just isn't quite the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slashgear.com/april-fools-2013-the-round-up-01275930/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;April Fools 2013: The Round-up - SlashGear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 1st is upon us, and that can only mean one thing: pranks, gags, and joke products of dubious comedic value, as the tech world tries to make you crack a smile. Whether you love it or loath it, April Fools is inescapable. But if you missed any of the tech jokes, Slash Gear has compiled a fantastic list of all the 2013 hoaxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/31/youtube-announces-that-it-has-been-an-8-year-contest-will-shut-down-on-april-1-to-determine-the-winner/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube Announces That It Has Been An 8-Year Contest, Will Shut Down On April 1 To Determine The Winner | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube is shutting down.The platform launched eight years ago, and some of us have gotten so distracted by YouTube videos that we’ve forgotten that the whole thing is actually a competition. Or, YouTube never actually mentioned that it is a competition. Either way, that competition, called YouTube, is coming to a close.To decide who has made the best YouTube video of all time, the company has put together an expert panel of judges, complete with film critics, prolific YouTube commenters, and YouTube celebrities including Charlie from “Charlie bit my Finger” and Antoine Dodson of “Antoine Dodson News Blooper (Original).” Or the website Tech Crunch.com played a terrible April Fools joke on its readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/landing/nose/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google Nose BETA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming to your senses: go beyond type, talk, and touch for a new notation of sensation.Your internet sommelier: expertly curated Knowledge Panels pair images, descriptions, and aromas.Take a whiff: the Google Aromabase - 15M  scentibytes.Don't ask, don't smell: For when you're wary of your query - SafeSearch included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.microsofttranslator.com/bv.aspx?from=&amp;amp;to=en&amp;amp;a=http%3A%2F%2Fraskalov-vit.livejournal.com%2F131308.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;raskalov-vit.livejournal.com/131308.html - Translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B006JH8T3S/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Logitech HD Pro Webcam C920, 1080p Widescreen Video Calling and Recording (960-000764): Computers &amp;amp; Accessories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.walgreens.com/store/c/ogilvie-home-perm-kit/ID=prod6055324-product#descriptionNamedTab" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ogilvie Home Perm Kit | Walgreens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/07/laura-linney-downton-abbey_n_2426321.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Why Does Laura Linney Introduce &amp;#x27;Downton Abbey&amp;#x27;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ct6Zj8Fyg2Y" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Masterpiece Classic Opening - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U3xnUdt5Zm0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Downton Abbey - Intro - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/frequency"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY4 for 10% off) and &lt;a href="http://hobancards.com"&gt;Hoban Press&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY for free shipping).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:14:04</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie discuss the tech April Fools jokes from around the web including Google's Nose and the retirement of the Youtube site. Dan also tries to convince Haddie she needs an at home perm. </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie discuss the tech April Fools jokes from around the web including Google's Nose and the retirement of the Youtube site. Dan also tries to convince Haddie she needs an at home perm.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F114&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 34: Monday, 1 April, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/34</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/34</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Myke Hurley</author>
      <description>The news for Monday, 1 April, 2013.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-034.mp3" length="3275652" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The news for Monday, 1 April, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Myke Hurley</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>6:10</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>The news for Monday, 1 April, 2013.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>The news for Monday, 1 April, 2013.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F34&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Incomparable 133: Incomparable Radio Theater of the Air</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/incomparable/133</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/incomparable/133</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jason Snell</author>
      <description>How much do we love old-time radio dramas and full-cast audioplays? This much.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/incomparable/2013/incomparable-133.mp3" length="23059009" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;How much do we love old-time radio dramas and full-cast audioplays? This much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.davidjloehr.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Our beloved author&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theincomparable.com/podcast/incomparable133.m4a" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Enhanced AAC podcast version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Jason Snell</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>47:13</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Old-time radio dramas and other audioplays.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>How much do we love old-time radio dramas and full-cast audioplays? This much.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>books, movies, tv, comics, sci-fi, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/30/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fincomparable%2F133&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac Power Users 131: Markdown Revisited</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/mpu/131</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/mpu/131</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>David Sparks &amp; Katie Floyd</author>
      <description>David and Katie are joined by Eddie Smith of Practically Efficient to discuss the new MacSparky Field Guide: Markdown co-authored by David and Eddie.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/mpu/2013/mpu-131.mp3" length="40554156" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;David and Katie are joined by Eddie Smith of Practically Efficient to discuss the new MacSparky Field Guide: Markdown co-authored by David and Eddie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.hover.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[Sponsor] Hover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://agilebits.com/store?d=MacPowerUsers" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[Sponsor] 1Password&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[Sponsor] The Omni Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.daisydiskapp.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[Sponsor] DaisyDisk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://macsparky.com/markdown" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Markdown Field Guide Landing Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=TQ5lwGfcQQI&amp;amp;offerid=146261&amp;amp;type=3&amp;amp;subid=0&amp;amp;tmpid=1826&amp;amp;RD_PARM1=https%253A%252F%252Fitunes.apple.com%252Fus%252Fbook%252Fmarkdown%252Fid622433972%253Fmt%253D11%2526uo%253D4%2526partnerId%253D30" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Markdown Field Guide in the iBookstore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://macsparky.fetchapp.com/sell/liexohbo" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Markdown Field Guide PDF Version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.practicallyefficient.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Practically Efficient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://bywordapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Byword&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;nvALT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://notesy-app.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Notesy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://nebulousapps.net/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Nebulous Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.iawriter.com/mac/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://writemonkey.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;WriteMonkey (for PC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please Support our Sponsors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1Password
&lt;a href="https://agilebits.com/store?d=MacPowerUsers"&gt;Have you ever forgotten a password? Now you don't have to worry about that anymore. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Omni Group
&lt;a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/powerusers"&gt;We're passionate about productivity for Mac, iPhone and iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DaisyDisk
&lt;a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/daisydisk/id411643860?mt=12"&gt; Manage your Mac’s drive with panache. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hover
&lt;a href="http://www.hover.com/macpowerusers"&gt;Domain name and email management made simple.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>David Sparks &amp; Katie Floyd</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:23:41</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>David and Katie are joined by Eddie Smith of Practically Efficient to discuss the new MacSparky Field Guide: Markdown co-authored by David and Eddie.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>David and Katie are joined by Eddie Smith of Practically Efficient to discuss the new MacSparky Field Guide: Markdown co-authored by David and Eddie.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>mac, apple, power user, productivity, workflows</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/25/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fmpu%2F131&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quit! 18: The Problem Is Always You</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/quit/18</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/quit/18</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan takes calls and responds to listener feedback. Topics include living in a basement, staying in school, quitting a good job you hate to mow lawns, what to do when your family moves and you want to finish school, getting pushed out of your own business and taking a corporate stooge job, quilting as a business, and more.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/quit/2013/quit-018.mp3" length="42564816" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan takes calls and responds to listener feedback. Topics include living in a basement, staying in school, quitting a good job you hate to mow lawns, what to do when your family moves and you want to finish school, getting pushed out of your own business and taking a corporate stooge job, quilting as a business, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/webahead/04" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | The Web Ahead #4: Pat Aufderheide on Fair Use &amp;amp; Copyright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair Use expert Pat Aufderheide joins Jen Simmons to explain when you can use other people's copyrighted material in your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://corporatestooge.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;QUIT! on 5by5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/quitshow" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;QUIT! (quitshow) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://corporatestooge.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The QUIT! Corporate Stooge Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://shopify.com/5by5"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://getharvest.com/5by5"&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; (use code 5BY5 for 50% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:28:07</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan takes calls and responds to listener feedback. Topics include living in a basement, staying in school, quitting a good job you hate to mow lawns, what to do when your family moves and you want to finish school, getting pushed out of your own business </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan takes calls and responds to listener feedback. Topics include living in a basement, staying in school, quitting a good job you hate to mow lawns, what to do when your family moves and you want to finish school, getting pushed out of your own business and taking a corporate stooge job, quilting as a business, and more.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>quit, work, job, awesome</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/44/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fquit%2F18&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geek Friday 67: I didn’t know there were boundaries</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/geekfriday/67</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/geekfriday/67</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Faith Korpi &amp; Jason Seifer</author>
      <description>In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith talks about fire trucks, Jason talks about craft beer, and they both come to a compromise on the helicopter/submarine debate.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/geekfriday/2013/geekfriday-067.mp3" length="39454462" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith talks about fire trucks, Jason talks about craft beer, and they both come to a compromise on the helicopter/submarine debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vanityfair.com/culture/my-phone/2013/03/dave-morin-path-facebook-apple" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Path’s Dave Morin on Circa, Mailbox, and the Secret App He Invented to Talk to His Assistant | Vanity Fair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://geckodesigns.kinja.com/so-i-bought-a-firetruck-252516685" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;So...I Bought A Firetruck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.smithsonianmag.com/ideas-innovations/Photos-The-U-S-Militarys-Prototype-for-a-Flying-Submarine-199180041.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Photos: The U.S. Military’s Prototype for a Flying Submarine | Ideas &amp;amp; Innovations | Smithsonian Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.smartbear.com/software-quality/bid/173560/What-Medieval-Castles-Can-Teach-You-About-Web-Security" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;What Medieval Castles Can Teach You About Web Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcodesign.com/1672194/a-stylish-table-made-from-legos-which-anyone-can-make#5" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5 | A Stylish Table Made From Legos, Which Anyone Can Make | Co.Design: business + innovation + design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3007498/most-innovative-companies-2013/spacex-successfully-touches-down-pacific-ocean" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;SpaceX Successfully Touches Down In The Pacific Ocean | Fast Company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://faitherina.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Trust Me, I&amp;#x27;m Faith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://schedulingapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Make Perfect Work Schedules - Scheduling Employee Scheduling Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://shopify.com/5by5"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://getharvest.com/5by5"&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; (use code 5BY5 for 50% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Faith Korpi &amp; Jason Seifer</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>54:16</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith talks about fire trucks, Jason talks about craft beer, and they both come to a compromise on the helicopter/submarine debate.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith talks about fire trucks, Jason talks about craft beer, and they both come to a compromise on the helicopter/submarine debate.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>technology, tech, geek, tv, movies, comics, music, gear</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/29/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fgeekfriday%2F67&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
