<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>5by5 Master Audio Feed</title>
    <link>http://5by5.tv/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>5by5 - All Audio Broadcasts</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:new-feed-url>http://feeds.5by5.tv/master</itunes:new-feed-url>
    <itunes:subtitle>5by5 - All Audio Broadcasts</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:author>5by5 and Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary>5by5 is an internet broadcast studio making podcasts for people like you.</itunes:summary>
    <itunes:image href="http://5by5.tv/assets/5by5-itunes.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>5by5, 5x5, 5 by 5, five by five</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>5by5 Studios and Dan Benjamin</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>itunes@5by5.tv</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:category text="Technology">
      <itunes:category text="Tech News"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic 37: Jonathan Snook on the open source career</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/systematic/37</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/systematic/37</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Brett Terpstra</author>
      <description>Jonathan Snook joins Brett to discuss open source web development, building careers in tech and the (mostly cheery) disposition of the web developer community.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/systematic/2013/systematic-037.mp3" length="22210116" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Snook joins Brett to discuss open source web development, building careers in tech and the (mostly cheery) disposition of the web developer community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://snook.ca/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Snook.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/snookca" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Snook (snookca) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://alpha.app.net/snookca" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;snookca on App.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mixture.io/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mixture - A rapid prototyping and static site generation tool for designers and developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://macsparky.com/markdown/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Markdown — MacSparky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/reeder/id439845554?mt=12&amp;amp;partnerId=30&amp;amp;siteID=vRL5rYo4h5A" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mac App Store - Reeder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/reeder/id325502379?mt=8&amp;amp;partnerId=30&amp;amp;siteID=vRL5rYo4h5A" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Reeder for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/reeder/id375661689?mt=8&amp;amp;partnerId=30&amp;amp;siteID=vRL5rYo4h5A" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Reeder for iPad for iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/a-second-spring-of-cleaning.html?source=email_rt_mc_body" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Official Blog: A second spring of cleaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.feedafever.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fever° Red hot. Well read.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://superherojs.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Superhero.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://responsive.victorcoulon.fr/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Responsive Design Bookmarklet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/aptus/id510487565?mt=12&amp;amp;partnerId=30&amp;amp;siteID=vRL5rYo4h5A" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mac App Store - Aptus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fxnetworks.com/archer" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Archer | Thursdays 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://shop.fxnetworks.com/archer-sterling-archer-mens-t-shirt/detail.php?p=294651&amp;amp;v=fx_shows_archer&amp;amp;pagemax=all" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Archer Sterling Archer Men&amp;#x27;s T-Shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week's episode of Systematic is brought to you by &lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/systematic"&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt; (use code &lt;strong&gt;SYSTEMATIC&lt;/strong&gt; for 20% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code &lt;strong&gt;DANSENTME3&lt;/strong&gt; for 30% off), &lt;a href="http://shopify.com/5by5"&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://getharvest.com/5by5"&gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; (use code &lt;strong&gt;5BY5&lt;/strong&gt; for 50% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Brett Terpstra</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>45:34</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Web developer Jonathan Snook guests to talk about building careers in tech.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Jonathan Snook joins Brett to discuss open source web development, building careers in tech and the (mostly cheery) disposition of the web developer community.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>productivity, work, creativity, mac, iOS</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/39/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fsystematic%2F37&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to Work 112: Touching Pizza and Robotron</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/b2w/112</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/b2w/112</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 22:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Merlin Mann &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>TOPIC: Choosing Your Forks.

This week, Dan and Merlin talk about some of the deeper and more slippery issues behind changes in our career and life.

In particular, how do we go from a vague tickle to that feeling of full-blown intolerability that can end up driving a change? Are we looking backward at what we should be doing as we slavishly catalog our many petty aggrievements? Or, do we take two giant steps back and apply a cooler eye to what we really want to do next?

Even before we find our forks in the road, how can we know a big decision might or should be coming our way? And, how do we stay current on that never-ending need to accept and plan for the changes we never could  have anticipated?

It's tough at 23, it's super-hard at 30, and, brother, is it ever murder at 50.

Sure, it's a little fruity, but, yeah: you need to write the story you really want to live. Rather than just cobbling together a flattering post-mortem on how you magically ended up where you are.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/b2w/2013/b2w-112.mp3" length="45842380" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOPIC&lt;/strong&gt;: Choosing Your Forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, Dan and Merlin talk about some of the deeper and more slippery issues behind changes in our career and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, how do we go from a vague tickle to that feeling of full-blown &lt;em&gt;intolerability&lt;/em&gt; that can end up driving a change? Are we looking backward at what we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be doing as we slavishly catalog our many petty aggrievements? Or, do we take two giant steps back and apply a cooler eye to what we really want to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before we find our forks in the road, how can we know a big decision might or should be coming our way? And, how do we stay current on that never-ending need to accept and plan for the changes we never could  have anticipated?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's tough at 23, it's super-hard at 30, and, brother, is it ever murder at 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it's a little fruity, but, yeah: you need to write the story you really want to live. Rather than just cobbling together a flattering post-mortem on how you magically ended up where you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://tonx.org/pushatonx" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[SPONSOR] We Source, Roast, and Ship Coffee. You Brew. | Tonx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You're about to join Merlin Mann on a coffee journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/PDFpen/index.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[SPONSOR] PDFpen: Mac PDF Editor - Edit, Sign, and Correct PDFs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The all-purpose Mac PDF editor! Add signatures, text, and images. Make changes and correct typos. OCR scanned docs. Fill out forms. New in version 6: Microsoft® Word export!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="www.squarespace.com/backtowork" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[SPONSOR] Build a Website - Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything You Need to Create an Exceptional Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;[SPONSOR] Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Royalty-Free Subscription Stock Photography &amp;amp; Vector Art - Search and select from millions of high resolution royalty free images, stock photos, vector art, and stock photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.squarespace.com/blog/gaining-momentum" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gaining Momentum — The Official Squarespace Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Momentum is a beautiful, flexible design built especially for photographers and designers who are ready to take their work front and center. With this template, you have the option of showcasing your portfolio with the cinematic full-bleed image display, or preserving the original resolution and visual integrity with the centered image display. You can add information for each image, video, or project to add context to your galleries. Momentum is also our first multi-index template, created for folks that have multiple projects or galleries that they’d like to share. The index view shows all of your galleries with aspect-correct thumbnails, so that visitors can scroll through your work on one page, without interruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/61987977" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;PDFpen for Mac Version 6 on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDFpen for the Mac version 6 has some great new features including a new user interface, conversion to Word, and auto form generation. This screencast shows off some of my favorite things about the new version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/articles/find-the-thing-youre-most-passionate-about-then-do,31742/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Find The Thing You&amp;#x27;re Most Passionate About, Then Do It On Nights And Weekends For The Rest Of Your Life | The Onion - America&amp;#x27;s Finest News Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t stress this enough: Do what you love…in between work commitments, and family commitments, and commitments that tend to pop up and take immediate precedence over doing the thing you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.merlinmann.com/roderick/ep-67-all-of-the-small-beer.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ep. 67: &amp;quot;All of the Small Beer&amp;quot; - Roderick on the Line - Merlin Mann&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Problem: Fixing the problem at the attitude level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.walgreens.com/store/c/pill-organization/ID=360531-tier2general" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Pill Organization | Walgreens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/ideas/articles/2011/07/17/a_whiff_of_history/?page=full" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;A whiff of history - The Boston Globe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But despite its primacy in our lives, our sense of smell is often overlooked when we record our history. We tend to connect with the past visually - we look at objects displayed in a museum, photographs in a documentary, the writing in a manuscript. Sometimes we might hear a vintage speech, or touch an ancient artifact and imagine what it was like to use it. But our knowledge of the past is almost completely deodorized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AdamSholds/status/316591826410811393"&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State-dependent_memory" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;State-dependent learning - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-dependent learning, or state-dependent memory, is the phenomenon in which the retrieval of a memory is most effective when an individual is in the same state of consciousness as it was when the memory was formed.[1] The term is typically used to describe states of consciousness induced by psychoactive drugs—most commonly, alcohol.[2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/djbender/status/316591443563134976"&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFBPQhB1GMQ" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;How to Memorize a Deck of Cards with Dominic O&amp;#x27;Brien - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great clip from a Dutch TV show, in which Dominic O'Brien shows you how to memorize a deck of cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[via Athelstane Aamodt]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transactive_memory" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Transactive memory - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transactive memory system is a mechanism through which groups collectively encode, store, and retrieve knowledge. Transactive memory was initially studied in couples and families where individuals had close relationships but was later extended to teams, larger groups, and organizations to explain how they develop a "group mind"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/emersunn/status/316593415489982465"&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1907486453/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;You Can Have an Amazing Memory: Learn Life-Changing Techniques and Tips from the Memory Maestro: Dominic O&amp;#x27;Brien: 9781907486456: Amazon.com: Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never forget a name or a number again! Dominic O'Brien is legendary for winning the World Memory Championship eight times and outwitting the casinos of Las Vegas to win a fortune at blackjack. Here, for the first time, he reveals his secrets for memory mastery. Follow his brain-boosting techniques and turn your mind into a super-powered computer that will recall PIN numbers with ease, remember directions, and help bring you success in business, leisure, and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.muleradio.net/newdisruptors/3/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Good from the First Drop - The New Disruptors - Mule Radio Syndicate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony Konecny, better known as Tonx, has been sourcing and roasting beans for a numbers of years, and recently founded Tonx Coffee, a subscription service that delivers whole beans from small batch roasting every two weeks. It’s not a bean of the month club. It’s a way to bypass the overchoice that one can face in specialty coffee shops, and get the assurance that the beans are fresh and good every time. In this episode, listen to Tonx and his ecommerce guru Nik Bauman talk about the joys of coffee and the joys of starting a business in which you can talk directly to your customers without anyone else getting in the way. There’s a brief interlude in which the host and a friend have a little Tonx tasting, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B007VL8Y2C/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Logitech Wireless Solar Keyboard K760 for Mac/iPad/iPhone (920-003884): Computers &amp;amp; Accessories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charges itself with lamplight or sunlight, indoors or outdoors; Fully charged, it works for at least three months-even in total darkness; Easy-switching Bluetooth connection enables switching from Mac to iPad or iPhone as simple and easy as pushing a button; Unique concave key design delivers fast, quiet typing, with more precision than your iPad or iPhone on-screen keyboard; From the PVC-free construction to the fully recyclable box, designed to reduce its environmental footprint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://macsparky.com/blog/2013/3/new-field-guide-markdown" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;New Field Guide: Markdown — MacSparky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown started as a clever way to write for the web but has become so much more. This book demystifies Markdown, making it easy for anybody to learn. This book includes 130 pages and 27 screencasts totaling more than one and a half hours of video. There is also an additional hour of audio interviews. This book will take you from zero knowledge of Markdown to being a Markdown pro and change the way you write for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.radiolab.org/2007/jun/07/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Memory and Forgetting - Radiolab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembering is an unstable and profoundly unreliable process--it’s easy come, easy go as we learn how true memories can be obliterated, and false ones added. And Oliver Sacks joins us to tell the story of an amnesiac whose love for his wife and music transcend his 7-second memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/montewv/status/316594588838162433"&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XS1SxufSPKU" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Crazy: The Best Pick Pocket Ever On The Today Show - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apollo Rollins is a mind-blowing pickpocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2013/01/07/130107fa_fact_green" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Green: The Spectacular Thefts of Apollo Robbins, Pickpocket : The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, at a Las Vegas convention for magicians, Penn Jillette, of the act Penn and Teller, was introduced to a soft-spoken young man named Apollo Robbins, who has a reputation as a pickpocket of almost supernatural ability. Jillette, who ranks pickpockets, he says, "a few notches below hypnotists on the show-biz totem pole," was holding court at a table of colleagues, and he asked Robbins for a demonstration, ready to be unimpressed. Robbins demurred, claiming that he felt uncomfortable working in front of other magicians. He pointed out that, since Jillette was wearing only shorts and a sports shirt, he wouldn?t have much to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Come on," Jillette said. "Steal something from me."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Rock-afire_Explosion" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Rock-afire Explosion - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rock-afire Explosion is an animatronic robot band that played in Showbiz Pizza Place from 1980 to 1990, and in various Showbiz Pizza locations between 1990-1992 as Showbiz rebranded and the band was steadily replaced by Chuck E. Cheese characters. The show was pioneering in many respects to other animatronics shows of the early 1980s, featuring life-sized characters capable of facial expression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_Seagal#Aikido" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Steven Seagal - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seagal moved to Japan in his late teens after he went to Japan with his father who was visiting for military purposes and met karate masters and decided to remain in Japan. He received his 1st dan degree (Shodan) under the direction of Koichi Tohei. He continued to train in aikido as a student of Seiseki Abe, Koichi Tohei (whose aikido organization, Ki Society, Seagal refused to join in favor of staying with the Aikikai), Kisaburo Osawa, Hiroshi Isoyama and the second doshu Kisshomaru Ueshiba. He attained a 7th dan degree and Shihan in aikido and became the first foreigner to operate an aikido dojo in Japan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/quit/4" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Quit! #4: The Answer Is &amp;quot;Do Both&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan talks with Phil Coffman, Shlok Vaidya, Producer Robin Welch, and callers about so-called "moderate success", passion, starting out, paying your dues, making changes, the myth of job security, and finding a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/quit/14" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Quit! #14: Don&amp;#x27;t Run A Sh*tty Company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan is joined by David Heinemeier Hansson, Shlok Vaidya, Producer Haddie Cooke to discuss telecommuting vs. being in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/quit/9" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Quit! #9: Four O&amp;#x27;Clock In the Morning Courage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Benjamin is joined by Joel Bush, Shlok Vaidya, Tina Nikolova and producer Haddie Cooke to discuss what it means to have "four o'clock in the morning courage".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aikido" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Aikido - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aikido is performed by blending with the motion of the attacker and redirecting the force of the attack rather than opposing it head-on. This requires very little physical strength, as the aikid?ka (aikido practitioner) "leads" the attacker's momentum using entering and turning movements. The techniques are completed with various throws or joint locks.[5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.comixology.com/Guardians-of-the-Galaxy-Vol-3-1/digital-comic/JAN130642" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 #1 - Comics by comiXology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a new rule in the galaxy: No one touches Earth! Join the brightest stars in the Marvel U: Star-Lord, Gamora, Drax, Rocket Raccoon, Groot and Iron Man, as they embark upon one of the most explosive and eye-opening chapters of Marvel NOW!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%C3%B8ren_Kierkegaard" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Søren Kierkegaard - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Søren Aabye Kierkegaard (/?s?r?n ?k??rk???rd/ or /?k??rk???r/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_of_faith" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Leap of faith - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leap of faith, in its most commonly used meaning, is the act of believing in or accepting something intangible or unprovable, or without empirical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisbachalo.net/profile.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Bachalo Illustration : Profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CHRIS BACHALO is internationally recognized as one of the most popular artists in the comic industry. His body of work covers a wide spectrum of genres ranging from the critically acclaimed “Sandman,” “Shade,” “Death, The High Cost of Living” and “Batman” series for DC to “Incredible Hulk,” “Uncanny X-Men,” “The Amazing Spider-man,” “Captain America” and the quirky pop favorite “Generation X,” which he co-created with Scott Lobdell for Marvel Comics. Generation X, became the first title from Marvel that was adapted into a live action film for Fox.The short story “The Wheel” written by Stardust and Beowulf writer Neil Gaimen and illustrated by Chris featured the Death character and was inducted into the library of Congress in 2003. It was created as part of a tribute to 911. His cover work for the title Hunter, The Age of Magic for DC was included as part of a New York gallery show for the Society of Illustrators. He is currently working on Marvels’ newest XMEN title, the critically acclaimed, Wolverine and the X-Men with Jason Aaron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://maban.co.uk/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Anna Debenham, freelance front-end developer based in Brighton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelance front end developer based in Brighton, UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/46263158122/the-doctor-is-in" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;“Hey, everybody! Look at me! I’m Dr. Octagon!” I... | kung fu grippe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, everybody! Look at me! I’m Dr. Octagon!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/systematic/35" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Systematic #35: Rob Corddry - Fiddling for Fun and Profit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob Corddry (Daily Show, Hot Tub Time Machine, Warm Bodies...) guests to talk about screenwriting, GTD, workflows and why we spend our free time fiddling with all of the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://fountain.io/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fountain | A markup language for screenwriting.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fountain is a simple markup syntax for writing, editing and sharing screenplays in plain, human-readable text. Fountain allows you to work on your screenplay anywhere, on any computer or tablet, using any software that edits text files.Taking its cues from John Gruber’s Markdown, Fountain files are eminently readable. When special syntax is required, it is straightforward and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/mpu" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Mac Power Users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn about getting the most from your Apple technology with focused topics and workflow guests. Creating Mac Power Users, one geek at a time since 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robotron:_2084" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Robotron: 2084 - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robotron: 2084 (also referred to as Robotron) is an arcade video game developed by Vid Kidz and released by Williams Electronics in 1982. It is a shooting game that features two-dimensional (2D) graphics. The game is set in the year 2084, in a fictional world where robots have turned against humans. The aim is to defeat endless waves of robots, rescue surviving humans, and earn as many points as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week's episode of &lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/b2w%20%22Back%20to%20Work%20on%205by5.tv"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back to Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is generously sponsored by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com/" title="Stock Photos | Shutterstock: Royalty-Free Subscription Stock Photography &amp;amp; Vector Art - Search and select from millions of high resolution royalty free images, stock photos, vector art, and stock photography."&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;BACKTOWORK3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" for 30% off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://smilesoftware.com/PDFpen/index.html" title="PDFpen: Mac PDF Editor - Edit, Sign, and Correct PDFs - PDFpen is a powerful Mac PDF editor: add text, images, and signatures to PDFs, make corrections on a PDF, fill out PDF forms, OCR scanned pages."&gt;Smile's PDF Pen Pro 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/backtowork" title="Build a Website - Squarespace - Squarespace is the easiest way for anyone to create an exceptional website. Pages, galleries, blogs, domains, hosting, analytics, 24/7 support - all included."&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use offer code "&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;CASH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;" for an additional 10% off).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tonx.org/pushatonx" title="We Source, Roast, and Ship Coffee. You Brew. | Tonx - Tonx finds awesome coffee from around the world, roasts it, and ships it to your doorstep every other week."&gt;Tonx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Merlin Mann &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:34:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>TOPIC: Choosing Your Forks.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>TOPIC: Choosing Your Forks.

This week, Dan and Merlin talk about some of the deeper and more slippery issues behind changes in our career and life.

In particular, how do we go from a vague tickle to that feeling of full-blown intolerability that can end up driving a change? Are we looking backward at what we should be doing as we slavishly catalog our many petty aggrievements? Or, do we take two giant steps back and apply a cooler eye to what we really want to do next?

Even before we find our forks in the road, how can we know a big decision might or should be coming our way? And, how do we stay current on that never-ending need to accept and plan for the changes we never could  have anticipated?

It's tough at 23, it's super-hard at 30, and, brother, is it ever murder at 50.

Sure, it's a little fruity, but, yeah: you need to write the story you really want to live. Rather than just cobbling together a flattering post-mortem on how you magically ended up where you are.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>productivity, communication, work, barriers, constraints, tools, careers</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/19/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fb2w%2F112&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Taking Pictures 48: $500 and a Lollipop</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/otp/48</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/otp/48</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Bill Wadman &amp; Jeffery Saddoris</author>
      <description>Bill and Jeffery try to iron out the intricacies of copyright and usage, photography as part of a larger, happier life. Photographer and film director Gordon Parks as Photographer of the Week.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/otp/2013/otp-048.mp3" length="44298702" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Bill and Jeffery try to iron out the intricacies of copyright and usage, photography as part of a larger, happier life. Photographer and film director Gordon Parks as Photographer of the Week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.complex.com/tech/2013/03/the-40-hottest-women-in-tech/gina-trapani" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gina Trapani — The 40 Hottest Women in Tech | Complex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://gawker.com/5991978/top-40-hottest-women-in-tech-was-supposed-to-focus-on-their-beautiful-insides?utm_source=gawker.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=recirculation&amp;amp;utm_campaign=recirculation" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Top 40 Hottest Women in Tech Was Supposed to Focus on Their Beautiful Insides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2009/sep/13/business/fi-lazarus13" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Controlling illegal use of copyrighted material on the Web - Los Angeles Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://waxy.org/2011/06/kind_of_screwed/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Kind of Screwed - Waxy.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/61348049#" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;TAKE MY PICTURE on Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wendypaton.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;WENDY PATON PHOTOGRAPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://killingthebuddha.com/mag/exegesis/dear-mr-eggleston/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dear Mr. Eggleston &amp;lt; Killing the Buddha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0300126212/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;William Eggleston: Democratic Camera, Photographs and Video, 1961-2008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gordonparksfoundation.org/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Gordon Parks Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=gordon+parks&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=CLlRUe3dCYeYiAKhmoHABw&amp;amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAQ&amp;amp;biw=1263&amp;amp;bih=758" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;gordon parks - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2006/03/08/arts/design/08parks.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gordon Parks, a Master of the Camera, Dies at 93 - New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B0000DG012/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: American Photography DVD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="" target="_blank"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; Use code PICTURES3 for 30% off.&lt;br /&gt;and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/otp" target="_blank"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; Use the coupon code ‘OTP3’ at checkout to save 10% on your order and get a free domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Bill Wadman &amp; Jeffery Saddoris</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:31:34</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Bill and Jeffery try to iron out the intricacies of copyright and usage, photography as part of a larger, happier life.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Bill and Jeffery try to iron out the intricacies of copyright and usage, photography as part of a larger, happier life. Photographer and film director Gordon Parks as Photographer of the Week.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>photography, camera, images, photos, pictures</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/48/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fotp%2F48&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant Size 18: A Little Flap in the Back (Shannon Wheeler)</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/giantsize/18</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/giantsize/18</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Moisés Chiullan</author>
      <description>Too Much Coffee Man sprang forth from the mind of then-Austinite video clerk Shannon Wheeler. He joins us to discuss his work and the nature of success, whether personal, creative, or financial. Do they have to be separate things?

We also discuss The Bible. The Shannon of 20 years ago wouldn't believe he's working on this unique adaptation/presentation of the classic text.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/giantsize/2013/giantsize-018.mp3" length="28742830" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Too Much Coffee Man sprang forth from the mind of then-Austinite video clerk Shannon Wheeler. He joins us to discuss his work and the nature of success, whether personal, creative, or financial. Do they have to be separate things?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discuss The Bible. The Shannon of 20 years ago wouldn't believe he's working on this unique adaptation/presentation of the classic text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/muchcoffee" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Shannon Wheeler (MuchCoffee) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tmcm.com/tmcm/page/71/#jp-carousel-185" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Shannon Wheeler - Online cartoons since 1995 ? A cartoon-a-day ? Too Much Coffee Man in color on weekends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tmcm.com/tmcm/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Shannon Wheeler - Online cartoons since 1995 ? A cartoon-a-day ? Too Much Coffee Man in color on weekends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.staple-austin.org/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;STAPLE! The Independent Media Expo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bettercomics.com/cc/conventions/conspast_dallasfantasy.htm" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Complex City : Better Comics (c) 2002 : Complex City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dallas_Fantasy_Fair" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dallas Fantasy Fair - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.comixology.com/Too-Much-Coffee-Man-comiXology-Submit-Strips/comics-series/10271" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Too Much Coffee Man: comiXology Submit Strips Digital Comics - Comics by comiXology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://vulcanvideo.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Vulcan Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wages_of_Fear" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Wages of Fear - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pre-Code_Hollywood" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Pre-Code Hollywood - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gFogTD0t5kM" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Flintstones - Winston Cigarette Commerical - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fat_Freddy&amp;#x27;s_Cat" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fat Freddy&amp;#x27;s Cat - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fabulous_Furry_Freak_Brothers" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Life_and_Death_of_Colonel_Blimp" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Life and Death of Colonel Blimp - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chris_Ware" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Chris Ware - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Too_Much_Coffee_Man" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Too Much Coffee Man - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FIzGKhyoYuM" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Too Much Coffee Man - Converse Commercial - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.crumbproducts.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Official R. Crumb Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lupo_the_Butcher" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Lupo the Butcher - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NOMUw2QOkLE" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;LUPO THE BUTCHER - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/From_Hell" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;From Hell - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/O._Henry" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;O. Henry - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code INSERT CODE for 10% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Moisés Chiullan</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>59:06</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Too Much Coffee Man sprang forth from the mind of then-Austinite video clerk Shannon Wheeler. He joins us to discuss his work and the nature of success, whether personal, creative, or financial. Do they have to be separate things?</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Too Much Coffee Man sprang forth from the mind of then-Austinite video clerk Shannon Wheeler. He joins us to discuss his work and the nature of success, whether personal, creative, or financial. Do they have to be separate things?

We also discuss The Bible. The Shannon of 20 years ago wouldn't believe he's working on this unique adaptation/presentation of the classic text.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>comics, art, geek, books</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/46/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fgiantsize%2F18&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screen Time 31: They Solve Space Crimes (Wiley Wiggins)</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/screentime/31</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/screentime/31</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Moisés Chiullan</author>
      <description>Developer/actor/raconteur Wiley Wiggins (Dazed and Confused, Computer Chess, Thunderbeam) joins us to talk about being on various sides of creating independent content. We discuss his passion for true adventure (and programming) above all else.

Did you know that people competed their computer chess programs against each other in the 80's? Now there's a movie about it. Did you know there are tons of free Adventure Time browser-based games available? We talk about them on the show. Ever find yourself reading a show description that asks too many questions? Oh.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/screentime/2013/screentime-031.mp3" length="26436553" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Developer/actor/raconteur Wiley Wiggins (Dazed and Confused, Computer Chess, Thunderbeam) joins us to talk about being on various sides of creating independent content. We discuss his passion for true adventure (and programming) above all else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that people competed their computer chess programs against each other in the 80's? Now there's a movie about it. Did you know there are tons of free Adventure Time browser-based games available? We talk about them on the show. Ever find yourself reading a show description that asks too many questions? Oh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Legend_of_Zelda:_The_Wind_Waker" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gameinformer.com/b/news/archive/2013/01/23/the-legend-of-zelda-wind-waker-hd-coming-to-wii-u-this-fall.aspx" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Legend Of Zelda: Wind Waker HD Coming To Wii U This Fall - News - www.GameInformer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://spelunkyworld.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Spelunky World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.karakasagames.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Karakasa Games ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://wileywiggins.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Wiley Wiggins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://spelunkyworld.com/whatis.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Spelunky World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.whitewhalegames.com/godofblades.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;White Whale Games :: God of Blades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mediamolecule.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Media Molecule - We make games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://fantasticfest.com/arcade" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fantastic Arcade | Fantastic Fest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://fantasticfest.com/news/entry/past_fantastic_arcade_titles_break_into_the_big_time" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Past Fantastic Arcade titles break into the big-time | Fantastic Fest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/wileywiggins/thunderbeam-for-the-ipad" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Thunderbeam! for the iPad by Wiley Wiggins — Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://boingboing.net/2011/05/12/kickstarter-for-thun.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Thunderbeam: a psychedelic, open-ended adventure game for iPad (Kickstarter) - Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://kotaku.com/5801159/1970s-science-fiction-comes-to-life-in-thunderbeam" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;1970&amp;#x27;s Science Fiction Comes to Life In Thunderbeam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://juegosrancheros.com/30/events/fantastic-arcade-thunderbeam/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;juegosrancheros.com — FANTASTIC ARCADE presents JUEGOS RANCHEROS: THUNDERBEAM Edition (w/ bonus J.S. JOUST-ing!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science_Ninja_Team_Gatchaman" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Science Ninja Team Gatchaman - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Captain_Harlock" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Captain Harlock - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.igf.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The 15th Annual Independent Games Festival&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Independent_Games_Festival" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Independent Games Festival - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.adventuretimegamejam.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gamemaking Frenzy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.adventuretimegamejam.com/submissions" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Gamemaking Frenzy | All Submissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.computerchessmovie.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;COMPUTER CHESS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.fortheloveofmovies.net/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;For The Love Of Movies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/wileywiggins" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Wiley Wiggins (wileywiggins) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code INSERT CODE for 10% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Moisés Chiullan</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>54:02</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Developer/actor/raconteur Wiley Wiggins (Dazed and Confused, Computer Chess, Thunderbeam) joins us to talk about being on various sides of creating independent content. We discuss his passion for true adventure (and programming) above all else.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Developer/actor/raconteur Wiley Wiggins (Dazed and Confused, Computer Chess, Thunderbeam) joins us to talk about being on various sides of creating independent content. We discuss his passion for true adventure (and programming) above all else.

Did you know that people competed their computer chess programs against each other in the 80's? Now there's a movie about it. Did you know there are tons of free Adventure Time browser-based games available? We talk about them on the show. Ever find yourself reading a show description that asks too many questions? Oh.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>movies, TV, media, games, HD, entertainment</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/40/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fscreentime%2F31&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 110: They Showed Up Dead</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/110</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/110</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news including: the Dell take over, Jane Goodall's lies,   the Apollo rocket recovery and more. They also discuss who may wear a monocle and the intricacies of men's hats.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-110.mp3" length="27276870" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news including: the Dell take over, Jane Goodall's lies,   the Apollo rocket recovery and more. They also discuss who may wear a monocle and the intricacies of men's hats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/24/michael-dell-may-lose-control-of-pc-maker-after-two-competing-buyout-bids-emerge/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Michael Dell May Lose Control Of PC Maker After Two Competing Buyout Bids Emerge | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dell’s board is looking at two surprise takeover bids from Blackstone Group and billionaire activist investor Carl Icahn, reports Reuters citing sources close to the discussion. A special committee is deciding whether either proposal would trump an existing $24.4 billion buyout offer from the PC maker’s founder Michael Dell and private equity firm Silver Lake.The new bids mean that Michael Dell could potentially lose control of the company he founded in 1984 and that he and Silver Lake will most likely need to reconsider their original proposal to make it more attractive to Dell shareholders, some of whom have complained that its terms undervalue the PC maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/22/783178/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile’s New LTE Network Spotted Being Tested In 8 Major U.S. Cities | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While T-Mobile is more than a bit late to the LTE game, the company confirmed on Monday that their new network would be launching by the end of the month. Where it would launch, however, was kept under wraps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/24/4142082/t-mobiles-new-contract-free-pricing-plans-are-live" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile&amp;#x27;s new contract-free pricing plans are live | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, T-Mobile has pulled the wraps off a new plan structure that eliminates two-year contracts altogether, part of its upcoming "Uncarrier" initiative to streamline pricing. A base price of $50 per month buys you 500MB of high-speed data (with overage-free throttled data after that), unlimited voice minutes, and unlimited texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2013/mar/21/eric-schmidt-blackberry-user" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Surprise! Google chairman Eric Schmidt uses.. a BlackBerry | Technology | guardian.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right: Eric Schmidt uses a BlackBerry. Why? He likes the keyboard, he says. One could question why Schmidt uses a BlackBerry: there are Android phones you can buy now! which offer a keyboard. Here's the Samsung Replenish in the US - though it reminds us of another make (can't think which just now) and only runs Gingerbread 2.3 - you know, from December 2010. Still, the reviews are good. (Plenty more here: tick the "QWERTY keyboard" box under "Style" on the left margin.)What's more, he thinks that Apple's iPad mini - the "small tablet" format that Google and Amazon have both made popular through their Nexus and Kindle Fire offerings - is "too small" compared to the large-format iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/22/4135484/post-office-cant-legally-drop-saturday-mail-service-says-gao" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Post Office can&amp;#x27;t legally drop Saturday mail service, says Congressional oversight office | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government Accountability Office (GAO), which investigates public expenditures for the US Congress, says a Post Office plan to drop Saturday mail delivery doesn't satisfy its legal obligations. In a letter, GAO General Counsel Susan Poling writes that an earlier rule requiring six-day delivery should be considered to extend into 2013, despite the Post Office's argument to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/22/jane-goodall-plagiarizing-wikipedia/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Jane Goodall Apologizes for Plagiarizing Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an age when research is easier than ever and entire sentences can be copied and pasted without second thought, even the most venerable nonfiction writers can find themselves accused of plagiarism.That's appears to be the case with noted author and naturalist Jane Goodall, who was forced to apologize this week after a Washington Post investigation found Goodall's latest book contained more than a dozen passages copied from multiple websites, including Wikipedia.The passages all appear in Goodall's latest book, Seeds of Hope, which was cowritten by Gail Hudson, a writer and researcher who has contributed to two of Goodall's other books in the past. The passages in question range from short phrases to whole sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/22/rovio-opens-angry-birds-space-encounter-exhibit-after-announcing-global-theme-park-plans/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Rovio Opens Angry Birds Space Encounter Exhibit After Announcing Global Theme Park Plans | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rovio is yet again breaking into new businesses with the introduction of the first Angry Birds interactive attraction, as the Kennedy Space Center Visitor Complex is opening an Angry Birds Space Encounter Exhibit.The whole thing measures up to 4,500 square feet of pure Angry Birds wonder. Six stations are set up to let visitors interact with Angry Birds space-related activities and games. This is part of a slow build into Angry Birds-themed consumer attractions for Rovio, who has gone from a mobile game maker to merchandise phenom, with a newly released animated cartoon series being distributed through the games themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/22/google-alerts-dying/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Are Google Alerts Dying?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of Google's killing of Google Reader, power users now have a new fear: Are Google Alerts next?Google Alerts is a service that allows users to receive email notifications of updated Google results for a search query or keyword. This lets users easily monitor an ongoing news story or be alerted of new stories mentioning a brand or individual. Google Alerts are actively used by marketers, social media managers, publicists, journalists and researchers. It's one of Google's oldest tools, and it's also one of the most useful — at least, when it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/22/kickstarter-games-pledges/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Kickstarter: $108 Million Pledged on Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since crowdfunding website and service Kickstarter launched in 2009, a staggering $108.52 million has been pledged to games projects, both video and tabletop. Of that, $90.83 million went towards successful projects — those that met their funding goal and are either already on general release or in development.On the technology side, $47.99 million has been raised by pledges for projects, while $38.33 million of that sum went to successful ventures. In both cases, Kickstarter did not claim the shortfalls.What do these figures tell us? For a start, Kickstarter does rather well as it claims a percentage of each pledge. But more importantly that crowd funding is a very good means to raise capital for a good project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/22/4135754/pepsi-attempts-to-make-its-bottle-more-iconic" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Pepsi attempts to make its bottle more iconic with first redesign in 16 years | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most consumers probably don't think about the design of their beverage bottles, but for a company like Pepsi, it's all part of a global brand image that the company is constantly tweaking. To that end, Pepsi just unveiled a new bottle for its 16 oz. and 20 oz. beverages, the first redesign those bottles have seen in 16 years. As AdAge notes, the new design features a swirled grip — a new design cue that the company hopes it can use to make its bottle a more effective and iconic marketing tool. While a bottle's shape might sound like a mundane detail best left for designers and marketing departments departments to obsess over, the bottle can be just as effective a branding tool as the logo itself — just take a look at Coca-Cola's iconic "contour bottle" design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ewal.net/2012/09/09/slow-wake-for-macbook-pro-retina/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;quot;Fixing&amp;quot; Slow Wake for MacBook Pro w/ Retina Display - Ewal.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is actually happening is that these new MacBook Pro’s (and recent MacBook Air’s) have a new powersaving mode which Apple calls standby. Standby mode kicks in after the laptop has been in normal sleep mode for about an hour. When that happens, the contents of RAM are written to the hard drive and the RAM is powered down to further extend battery life. In theory, the laptop will last up to 30 days in standby mode. The trade off is that, when waking up, it takes a long time to reload 16 GB of RAM from the hard drive (even with SSD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that if the laptop sleeps for less than an hour, then it will wake up nearly instantly. I’ve seen this myself in cases where I close the lid briefly while walking between meetings. This fact is the key to my workaround. It turns out that this 1 hour delay is configurable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/03/22/us-kodak-shutterfly-lawsuit-idUSBRE92L0Z220130322" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Shutterfly sues to shut down Kodak photo app | Reuters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo service Shutterfly Inc has sued to shut down an Eastman Kodak Co app that lets users purchase photo albums made from pictures stored on Facebook Inc's social media network, according to court documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shutterfly bought the Kodak Gallery online photo business for $23.8 million last year, and as part of the deal Kodak agreed not to set up a duplicate business, according to court documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shutterfly said in a complaint filed on Friday with the U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan that the "My Kodak Moments App" violates the sale agreement by setting up a competing business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/24/4141286/windows-blue-screenshots-leak-smaller-live-tiles-options-ui" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Windows Blue leaks online, includes smaller Live Tiles, new side-by-side Snap Views, and IE 11 | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An early build of Windows Blue, the next version of Windows, has leaked online on the same day that Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer celebrates his 57th birthday. Build 9364, a partner version that was originally compiled on March 15th, has been made available on file sharing sites and includes some of the new changes that Microsoft is building into its significant Windows 8 update. Leaked screenshots posted at Winforum show that the company is bringing smaller tile arrangements and even a larger desktop one to its Start Screen, along with greater control over the color personalization options, and a whole lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2013/03/23/apple-acquires-indoor-location-company-wifislam/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Acquires Indoor Location Company WifiSLAM - Digits - WSJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has acquired indoor-GPS company WifiSLAM, a sign that the war over indoor mobile location services is heating up.Apple paid around $20 million for the Silicon Valley-based company, according to a person familiar with the matter who said the deal closed recently.An Apple spokesman confirmed the deal saying the company “buys smaller technology companies from time to time” and generally doesn’t discuss its plans. He declined to comment further. WifiSLAM could not immediately be reached for comment.The two-year-old startup has developed ways for mobile apps to detect a phone user’s location in a building using Wi-Fi signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/03/24/disruptions-f-a-a-may-loosen-curbs-on-fliers-use-of-electronics/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Disruptions: F.A.A. May Loosen Curbs on Fliers&amp;#x27; Use of Electronics - NYTimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to people who work with an industry working group that the Federal Aviation Administration set up last year to study the use of portable electronics on planes, the agency hopes to announce by the end of this year that it will relax the rules for reading devices during takeoff and landing. The change would not include cellphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2013/03/20/apollo-rocket-engines-moon-bezos/2003533/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apollo moon rocket engines raised from Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two giant rocket engines that launched U.S. astronauts to the moon four decades ago have been recovered from the bottom of the Atlantic Ocean off Cape Canaveral by an expedition paid for by Amazon founder Jeff Bezos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The F-1 engines, which powered the first-stage Saturn V boosters that fell back to Earth after their fuel was depleted, were found at a depth of 14,000 feet, Bezos' expedition announced Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recovery, after three weeks at sea, came almost a year after his team used state-of-the-art sonar to locate a debris field of battered, rusted F-1 engines and parts that Bezos described as "gorgeous."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danbenjamin/8539736852/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Me and my Grandfather | Flickr - Photo Sharing!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danbenjamin/8585775375/in/photostream/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dan Benjamin | Flickr - Photo Sharing!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY3 for 30% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>55:55</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news including: the Dell take over, Jane Goodall's lies,   the Apollo rocket recovery and more. They also discuss who may wear a monocle and the intricacies of men's hats. </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news including: the Dell take over, Jane Goodall's lies,   the Apollo rocket recovery and more. They also discuss who may wear a monocle and the intricacies of men's hats.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F110&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 30: Monday, 25 March, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/30</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/30</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>The news for Monday, 25 March, 2013.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-030.mp3" length="5272508" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The news for Monday, 25 March, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>10:25</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>The news for Monday, 25 March, 2013.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>The news for Monday, 25 March, 2013.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F30&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Critical Path 77: Making Sausages</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/criticalpath/77</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/criticalpath/77</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Horace Dediu &amp; Moisés Chiullan</author>
      <description>The more we deconstruct and take apart iTunes, the more we come to respect how it cannot exist independent of the system it's a part of. Its scope and scale and its history and future all indicate that there is more to it than just a store and that it might be a platform in its own right. We get into some more details about all these details and talk about where it came from and where we think it will end up.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/criticalpath/2013/criticalpath-077.mp3" length="40237399" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The more we deconstruct and take apart iTunes, the more we come to respect how it cannot exist independent of the system it's a part of. Its scope and scale and its history and future all indicate that there is more to it than just a store and that it might be a platform in its own right. We get into some more details about all these details and talk about where it came from and where we think it will end up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.asymco.com/2013/03/21/the-conundrum-of-itunes-recognition-of-revenues/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Conundrum of iTunes’ Recognition of Revenues | asymco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.asymco.com/2013/03/22/so-long-break-even/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;So long, break-even | asymco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://5by5.tv/screentime/30" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;5by5 | Screen Time #30: TableTop Day (with Boyan Radakovich)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://tabletop.geekandsundry.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Geek and Sundry | TableTop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code INSERT CODE for 10% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Horace Dediu &amp; Moisés Chiullan</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:23:06</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>The more we deconstruct and take apart iTunes, the more we come to respect how is cannot exist independent of the system it's a part of. Its scope and scale and its history and future all indicate that there is more to it than just a store.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>The more we deconstruct and take apart iTunes, the more we come to respect how it cannot exist independent of the system it's a part of. Its scope and scale and its history and future all indicate that there is more to it than just a store and that it might be a platform in its own right. We get into some more details about all these details and talk about where it came from and where we think it will end up.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>mobile, apple, iphone, ipad, ios, rim, blackberry, nokia, android, google</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/24/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fcriticalpath%2F77&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac Power Users 130: Computing with Kids</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/mpu/130</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/mpu/130</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>David Sparks &amp; Katie Floyd</author>
      <description>David and Katie are joined by Natali Morris to talk about kids and technology. Topics include why it's important to introduce kids to tech, keeping children safe online, monitoring and limiting access and Natali's favorite apps and accessories.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/mpu/2013/mpu-130.mp3" length="45167102" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;David and Katie are joined by Natali Morris to talk about kids and technology. Topics include why it's important to introduce kids to tech, keeping children safe online, monitoring and limiting access and Natali's favorite apps and accessories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://natalimorris.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Natali&amp;#x27;s Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/natalimorris" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Natali on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mommybeta.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mommy Beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/natalimorris/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Natali on Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/2030156/configuring-parental-controls.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Macworld: Configuring Parental Controls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.macworld.com/article/2025807/limiting-your-kids-ios-use.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Macworld: Limiting your kids&amp;#x27; iOS use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.opendns.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.filetransporter.com/how-to/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Transporter How To Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0393339750/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Shallows: What the Internet Is Doing to Our Brains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT5509?viewlocale=en_US&amp;amp;locale=en_US" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;iOS: About Guided Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imore.com/how-use-guided-access-put-your-ipad-or-iphone-guest-user-mode" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;How to put your iPad into &amp;quot;Guest User&amp;quot; mode with Guided Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B006BA8FLO/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Woogie 2!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.luvion.com/baby_monitors/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Luvion Baby Monitors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lorextechnology.com/product/info/Video+baby+monitor+/2000036" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Lorex Baby Monitors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/thesetup/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The OmniFocus Setup Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.smule.com/magicpiano" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Magic Piano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/thesetup/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The OmniFocus Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/sg/app/learn-abcs/id457284432?mt=8" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Learn ABCs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/grandpas-workshop/id555310530?mt=8" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Grandpa&amp;#x27;s Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/counting-bear/id414967966?mt=8" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Counting Bears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apple.com/findouthow/mac/#parentalcontrols" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple Video on Parental Controls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.duckduckmoose.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Duck Duck Moose Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please Support our Sponsors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Omni Group
&lt;a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/powerusers"&gt;We're passionate about productivity for Mac, iPhone and iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Squarespace
&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/?channel=podcast&amp;subchannel=5by5&amp;source=5by5"&gt; Everything you need to create an amazing website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hover
&lt;a href="http://www.hover.com/macpowerusers"&gt;Domain name and email management made simple.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank and Oak
&lt;a href="http://www.frankandoak.com/macpowerusers"&gt;A men’s online clothing store that makes shopping easy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;Use discount code MACPOWER20 at checkout to get 20% OFF your order.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>David Sparks &amp; Katie Floyd</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:33:31</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>David and Katie are joined by Natali Morris to talk about kids and technology. Topics include why it's important to introduce kids to tech, keeping children safe online, monitoring and limiting access and Natali's favorite apps and accessories.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>David and Katie are joined by Natali Morris to talk about kids and technology. Topics include why it's important to introduce kids to tech, keeping children safe online, monitoring and limiting access and Natali's favorite apps and accessories.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>mac, apple, power user, productivity, workflows</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/25/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fmpu%2F130&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Incomparable 132: Kind of Like a Dinosaur</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/incomparable/132</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/incomparable/132</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 18:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jason Snell</author>
      <description>Don't make us angry... you wouldn't like us when we're angry. Our Comic Book Club talks all things Hulk. We begin with a discussion of two She-Hulk series, by John Byrne and Dan Slott, and then move to talk about Proper Hulk, Gray Hulk, Red Hulk, Planet Hulk, Ruffalo Hulk, and more! Plus: What are we reading? (Jason gets really excited about "Hawkeye," who is not a Hulk.) And, other than being green, how is the Hulk like parsley? Channel your inner rage and listen to this episode.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/incomparable/2013/incomparable-132.mp3" length="31536252" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Don't make us angry... you wouldn't like us when we're angry. Our Comic Book Club talks all things Hulk. We begin with a discussion of two She-Hulk series, by John Byrne and Dan Slott, and then move to talk about Proper Hulk, Gray Hulk, Red Hulk, Planet Hulk, Ruffalo Hulk, and more! Plus: What are we reading? (Jason gets really excited about "Hawkeye," who is not a Hulk.) And, other than being green, how is the Hulk like parsley? Channel your inner rage and listen to this episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/Xydqjm" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sensational She-Hulk (Byrne)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/Yz6CSH" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;She-Hulk: Single Green Female&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/14la6iR" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Planet Hulk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/X3miT5" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Hawkeye Vol. 1: My Life as a Weapon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/168RzEG" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Avengers: Avengers World Vol. 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/ZdPTa3" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ultimate Comics Ultimates Vol. 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Jason Snell</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:04:53</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Hulk, She-Hulk, and other Hulks I've known.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Don't make us angry... you wouldn't like us when we're angry. Our Comic Book Club talks all things Hulk. We begin with a discussion of two She-Hulk series, by John Byrne and Dan Slott, and then move to talk about Proper Hulk, Gray Hulk, Red Hulk, Planet Hulk, Ruffalo Hulk, and more! Plus: What are we reading? (Jason gets really excited about "Hawkeye," who is not a Hulk.) And, other than being green, how is the Hulk like parsley? Channel your inner rage and listen to this episode.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>books, movies, tv, comics, sci-fi, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/30/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fincomparable%2F132&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quit! 17: Four Hour Sleep Night</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/quit/17</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/quit/17</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 23:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan is joined by special guest Garrett Dimon to discuss starting and running businesses with less pain and fewer mistakes. Dan takes calls and helps people identify their opportunities and make decisions to redefine their careers.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/quit/2013/quit-017.mp3" length="38131306" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan is joined by special guest Garrett Dimon to discuss starting and running businesses with less pain and fewer mistakes. Dan takes calls and helps people identify their opportunities and make decisions to redefine their careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theonion.com/articles/find-the-thing-youre-most-passionate-about-then-do,31742/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Find The Thing You&amp;#x27;re Most Passionate About, Then Do It On Nights And Weekends For The Rest Of Your Life | The Onion - America&amp;#x27;s Finest News Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://startingandsustaining.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Starting + Sustaining: A book and spreadsheet to help you launch and maintain a web application by Garrett Dimon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://nextupdate.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Next Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://sifterapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sifter - Simple Hosted Bug &amp;amp; Issue Tracking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://garrettdimon.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;GarrettDimon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/garrettdimon" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Garrett Dimon (garrettdimon) on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 10% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:18:53</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan is joined by special guest Garrett Dimon to discuss starting and running businesses with less pain and fewer mistakes. Dan takes calls and helps people identify their opportunities and make decisions to redefine their careers.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan is joined by special guest Garrett Dimon to discuss starting and running businesses with less pain and fewer mistakes. Dan takes calls and helps people identify their opportunities and make decisions to redefine their careers.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>quit, work, job, awesome, garrett dimon, starting, sustaining</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/44/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fquit%2F17&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geek Friday 66: It’s Our Grammar</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/geekfriday/66</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/geekfriday/66</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Faith Korpi &amp; Jason Seifer</author>
      <description>In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith and Jason talk about The Geek Friday Token, hipsters and flip phones, movies on Kickstarter, and much much more.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/geekfriday/2013/geekfriday-066.mp3" length="41853707" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith and Jason talk about The Geek Friday Token, hipsters and flip phones, movies on Kickstarter, and much much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zagg.com/keyboard-cases/index.php#zaggkeys-mini-7+ipad-mini" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;iPad Keyboards, Cases, &amp;amp; Stands | ZAGG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://instagram.com/p/XD8IJ1owXs/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Photo by faitherina • Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.psfk.com/2013/03/oreo-robot-butler.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Robot Butler Separates Oreo Cookies For Its Owner [Video] - PSFK - PSFK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=gBgfpl0lcIo" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;OREO Separator Machine #4 — Creator: Robotic Butler HERB - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.painstaking.co/2013/03/20/the-geek-friday-token/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Geek Friday Token | Painstaking.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0935664/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Alex Winter - IMDb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/underwire/2013/03/exclusive-clip-napster-doc-downloaded/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Exclusive Clip: Relive Napster&amp;#x27;s Big Break in the Documentary Downloaded | Underwire | Wired.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/559914737/the-veronica-mars-movie-project" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Veronica Mars Movie Project by Rob Thomas — Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://science.time.com/2013/03/20/humanity-leaves-the-solar-system-35-years-later-voyager-offically-exits-the-heliosphere/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Report: Humanity Leaves the Solar System — Or Maybe Not | TIME.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4TdczoetXk4" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;&amp;quot;Mario&amp;quot; - SXSW 2011 Film Bumper - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tekken_3" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Tekken 3 - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://faitherina.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Trust Me, I&amp;#x27;m Faith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://schedulingapp.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Make Perfect Work Schedules - Scheduling Employee Scheduling Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://geekfriday.com" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Geek Friday dot com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code IDESOFMARCH for 10% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Faith Korpi &amp; Jason Seifer</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>57:42</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith and Jason talk about The Geek Friday Token, hipsters and flip phones, movies on Kickstarter, and much much more.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>In this episode of Geek Friday, Faith and Jason talk about The Geek Friday Token, hipsters and flip phones, movies on Kickstarter, and much much more.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>technology, tech, geek, tv, movies, comics, music, gear</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/29/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fgeekfriday%2F66&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 109: I Need a Rag!</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/109</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/109</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news and events including the latest in Apple, the evolution of the computer interface, and the most detailed and illegal picture of the internet ever.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-109.mp3" length="28543344" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news and events including the latest in Apple, the evolution of the computer interface, and the most detailed and illegal picture of the internet ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2013/03/21/jony-ive-pushing-for-flat-design-in-ios-7-amid-greater-hardware-software-design-collaboration/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Jony Ive Pushing for &amp;#x27;Flat Design&amp;#x27; in iOS 7 Amid Greater Hardware-Software Design Collaboration - Mac Rumors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last October, Tim Cook tasked Jony Ive with leadership of the company's Human Interface teams in addition to his role as head of Industrial Design. This suggested that the company's hardware and software user interfaces could become more complimentary with one executive in charge of everything that users see and touch. The Wall Street Journal reports that this is indeed the case, with mobile software teams being briefed about new hardware prototypes earlier in the design cycle. Additionally, Ive is now sitting in on the human interface team's review sessions to examine new designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://9to5mac.com/2013/03/21/apple-beefs-up-icloud-apple-id-security-with-two-step-verification/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple beefs up iCloud, Apple ID security with two-step verification | 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Apple has rolled out a new two-step verification service for iCloud and Apple ID users. This functionality greatly enhances the security of Apple accounts because it requires users to use a trusted device and an extra security code.This security code can be sent via SMS or via the Find my iPhone iOS app (if it is installed). Users can now setup two-step authentication on their devices via the Apple ID website. Users need to access the security tab on this website to conduct the setup process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/13/03/21/apple-looks-to-protect-dropped-iphones-by-shifting-their-orientation-mid-flight" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple looks to protect dropped iPhones by shifting their orientation mid-flight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published by the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, Apple's "Protective Mechanism for an Electronic Device" patent filing looks to alleviate some or all of the damage when a device is accidentally dropped. While the invention can be applied to any electronic device with a processor, from a tablet to a laptop, it is most well-suited for those portables that users carry with them on a daily basis. For example, Apple's iPhone is specifically mentioned in the patent language.In order to work, the system needs a sensor or sensor array that can detect when a device is in freefall and how it is positioned relative to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-13579_3-57575626-37/apple-google-google-now-not-submitted-to-app-store/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple, Google: Google Now not submitted to App Store | Apple - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Now has not been submitted yet to Apple's App Store, the iPhone maker told CNET. And Google itself has now confirmed this.Earlier today, Google Executive Chairman Eric Schmidt spoke at the Big Tent Summit in India and was asked when Google Now would be made available to iOS devices. In a coded response, Schmidt stopped short of calling out Apple but did seem to hint that the iPhone maker was playing a role in the app's availability on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.cnet.com/2300-11386_3-10016203.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Stars come out for &amp;#x27;Game of Thrones&amp;#x27; screening (pictures) - CNET News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Game of Thrones" stars talk to the press last night in San Francisco where the red carpet was laid out at the Palace of Fine Arts for a special screening to kick off the series' third season. The hit HBO show held its official premiere earlier this week in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/21/the-science-of-snoozing/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Science of Snoozing [VIDEO]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling a little groggy? Droopy? Dopey? Sleepy? Another 'Seven Dwarfs' syndrome?It may not be because you didn't get enough sleep, but perhaps because you opted for a few extra minutes of it. ASAP Science explains that alarm clocks are really the enemy in the bedroom, because they disrupt your body's natural rhythms and attempts at rousing you awake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/21/4127110/40-years-of-icons-the-evolution-of-the-modern-computer-interface" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;40 years of icons: the evolution of the modern computer interface | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;40 years of icons: the evolution of the modern computer interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/21/4133288/apple-to-finally-stop-accepting-apps-that-use-outdated-udid-device-identifier-may-1st" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple to finally stop accepting apps that use outdated UDID device identifier on May 1st | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple announced it was deprecating the Unique Device Identifier back in August of 2011, and over 18 months later the company will formally start rejecting apps that continue to use it. In a brief post on Apple's Developer website, the company states that it won't accept apps that use UDIDs as of May 1st, and encourages developers to use two other options to provide similar functionality should they need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://motherboard.vice.com/blog/this-is-most-detailed-picture-internet-ever" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;This Is the Most Detailed Picture of the Internet Ever (and Making it Was Very Illegal) | Motherboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a newly published research paper, an unnamed data junkie explains how he used some stupid simple hacking techniques to build a 420,000-node botnet that helped him draw the most detailed map of the Internet known to man. Not only does it show where people are logging in, it also shows changes in traffic patterns over time with an impressive amount of precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/21/4133428/is-google-building-a-smart-watch-of-its-own" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google&amp;#x27;s Android unit reportedly building a smartwatch | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a recent report from The Financial Times, Google might also be getting into the smartwatch game. And unlike Glass, which was developed in the company’s experimental X Lab, the watch (not pictured above) is said to be under development by the Android unit, possibly indicating that Google sees it as a more immediately viable product. According to FT’s source, the Google watch is separate from Samsung’s recently-announced effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/22/fcc-chairman-genachowski-to-step-down/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;FCC Chairman Julius Genachowski will step down &amp;#x27;in the coming weeks&amp;#x27;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julius Genachowski will be stepping down from his position as FCC Chairman "in the coming weeks" according to a brief message on the FCC's webpage. We're expecting more detail in a live announcement at 10am, but this was no big surprise: the Wall Street Journal broke the news yesterday and speculation over Mr. Genachowski's tenure has lingered ever since an awkward exchange where he refused to commit to his future at this year's CES.In his four years at the commission, Genachowski worked to speed up the roll-out of broadband to rural communities, voiced concerns about the current phone unlocking policy and pushed to allocate more spectrum to WiFi use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B003O6E986/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Forza Motorsport 4: Xbox 360: Video Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000Y7U98W/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Sunshine [Blu-ray]: Cillian Murphy, Rose Byrne, Chris Evans, Michelle Yeoh, Troy Garity, Hiroyuki Sanada, Benedict Wong, Mark Strong, Cliff Curtis, Paloma Baeza, Archie Macdonald, Sylvie Macdonald, Alwin H. Küchler, Danny Boyle, Chris Gill, An&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B0013KTGAG/5by5-20" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon.com: Sunshine: Cillian Murphy, Rose Byrne, Cliff Curtis, Chris Evans: Amazon Instant Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danbenjamin/status/315113081430736897/photo/1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter / danbenjamin: The patch panel wire ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY3 for 30% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>58:48</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news and events including the latest in Apple, the evolution of the computer interface, and the most detailed and illegal picture of the internet ever. </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie discuss the latest in tech news and events including the latest in Apple, the evolution of the computer interface, and the most detailed and illegal picture of the internet ever.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F109&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 29: Friday, 22 March, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/29</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/29</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>The news for Friday, 22 March, 2013.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-029.mp3" length="3712266" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The news for Friday, 22 March, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>7:10</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>The news for Friday, 22 March, 2013.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>The news for Friday, 22 March, 2013.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F29&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 108: My Abs Hurt</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/108</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/108</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie are joined late in the afternoon by Myke Hurley and Moises Chiullan to discuss the latest in tech news, deviated septums, and trivia of the 50 United States.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-108.mp3" length="28949598" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie are joined late in the afternoon by Myke Hurley and Moises Chiullan to discuss the latest in tech news, deviated septums, and trivia of the 50 United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2013/03/20/google-launches-evernote-rival-keep-for-the-web-android-4-0-and-above/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google launches Evernote rival Keep for the Web, Android 4.0 and above - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google on Wednesday announced Google Keep, a note-taking service similar to Evernote, for both the Web and Android 4.0  (Ice Cream Sandwich and Jelly Bean) devices. You can try the service out now for yourself at Drive.Google.com/Keep or download the Android app from the Google Play Store. Google describes Keep as a service that lets you “save ideas and organize to-dos the moment they happen by creating notes, lists, photos and voice recordings right from your phone” (don’t worry, it also works on tablets). You can access, edit, and create new notes on the Web from the above website, and furthermore, Google says you’ll be able to do the same directly from your Google Drive account “in the coming weeks.” Keep also lets you speak to it: the service transcribes voice memos for you automatically. Since we’re talking about Google here, there’s also a “super-fast search” function so you can find the note you wrote, read it, and then either archive or delete it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/amazon-on-the-99-kindle-fire-tablet-its-not-happening-2013-3?op=1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon On The $99 Kindle Fire Tablet: &amp;#x27;It&amp;#x27;s Not Happening&amp;#x27; - Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon is not doing a $99 Kindle Fire HD tablet, a company spokesperson tells us: "It's not happening--we are already at the lowest price points possible for that hardware."Previously, TechCrunch had passed along a rumor that Amazon was going to release a $99 tablet, which would have been extremely disruptive.It looks like that's just not feasible right now for Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/19/t-mobile-uncarrier-plans-leak-make-unlimited-talk-and-text-givens/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;T-Mobile &amp;#x27;UnCarrier&amp;#x27; plans possibly leaked, make unlimited talk and text a given (updated)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T-Mobile made much ado at CES of its desire to become the "UnCarrier," with steps away from subsidies and the usual complexities of smartphones. Thanks to tipsters, we have a better sense of what the provider meant. A memo suggests that T-Mobile is revamping plans in the near future to make unlimited talk and text a de facto part of the experience, where data would be the only changeable factor: on Classic tiers , the starter $60 plan would have 500MB of full-speed data with hotspot support built-in, while subscribers could upgrade their service in 2GB increments that cost between $10-20 dollars per month for individuals. You'd still have 'real' unlimited data on Classic from $90, with the hotspot as a bolt-on option. What we've seen doesn't specify a date or price, but T-Mobile happens to have an appropriately-themed event coming up on the 26th&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/youtube-announces-that-it-has-hit-one-billion-monthly-users-which-is-roughly-ten-super-bowl-audiences/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;YouTube Announces That It Has Hit One Billion Monthly Users, Which Is Roughly Ten Super Bowl Audiences | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, YouTube announced that it has hit a billion monthly users, which is an extremely insane metric. We know that YouTube is the go-to place for silly, interesting and important videos, but these numbers are something that even TV networks dream of.The great part for YouTube is that this means that online video ad-spend will go up, since the eyeballs appear to be ready, willing and able. It’s not only advertisers that are rushing YouTube, budding music artists are heading there too, and making a career from the attention that they get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://m.electronista.com/fullarticles/13/03/20/sequester.holding.up.purchase.intended.to.replace.failing.devices/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Exclusive: US DoD to purchase 650,000 iOS devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were told that the breakdown was 120,000 iPads, 100,000 iPad minis, 200,000 iPod touches, and the remaining 210,000 filled by various iPhones. Specific models were not shared, and would likely be specified at the time of the cessation of sequester spending restrictions. Ultimate destinations for the hardware varies, with Electronista being told that "more than half are headed to the battlefield, afloat, and to associated support commands. Most of the rest will stay [at the Pentagon]."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/21/business/media/tonight-show-expected-to-return-to-new-york-with-fallon.html?_r=0" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;‘Tonight’ Show Expected to Return to New York, With Fallon - NYTimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A plan is in the works to bring NBC’s “Tonight” show back to New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the network has yet to complete a deal, it has made a commitment to Jimmy Fallon, the current host of its “Late Night” program, to have him succeed Jay Leno as the next host of “Tonight,” according to several senior television executives involved in the decision. The show would move from Burbank, Calif., back to New York, where it first started in 1954 with Steve Allen as host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some details remain to be worked out, including an exact timetable for the switch, though it is expected to take place by the fall of 2014 at the latest, the executives said in interviews this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NBC has quietly begun work on a new studio in its headquarters building at 30 Rockefeller Plaza as the home for the new “Tonight” show. The studio is part of a general reconstruction of the building being undertaken by Comcast, which this week completed a full takeover of NBC Universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2013/03/20/ad-exec-scott-trattner-returns-to-the-apple-fold-at-media-arts-l/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Ad exec Scott Trattner returns to the Apple fold at Media Arts Lab | TUAW - The Unofficial Apple Weblog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the hiring talk today is about Adobe CTO Kevin Lynch joining up with Apple, but there's been another interesting job switch in the Apple-sphere recently. Ad exec Scott Trattner has returned to work for the Media Arts Lab ad agency, after a short stint working for the design firm 72 and Sunny. The Media Arts Lab is part of ad agency TBWA/Chiat/Day, and the group is responsible for some of the most iconic Apple ads, including the famous Switcher ads, as well as the iPod ads, Think Different and even the classic "1984" commercial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/british-airways-ungrounded/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;British Airways Launches UnGrounded ‘Innovation Lab In The Sky’ To Solve Problems By Putting Techies On Planes Together | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British Airways today announced the first of its “UnGrounded” innovation lab flights that will assemble 100 Silicon Valley luminaries on a flight to London to devise a platform for connecting tech talent with big problems around the world. A partnership with the UN, the inaugural UnGrounded flight will fly on June 12th with 100 leaders from Google, Andreessen Horowitz, RocketSpace and more on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/20/vine-tribeca-film-festival-launch-6secfilms-vine-competition-for-viners-obsessed-with-vining-vines/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Vine, Tribeca Film Festival Launch #6SecFilms Vine Competition For Viners Obsessed With Vining Vines | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vine has steadily made waves ever since its launch in January. First it was a porn scare, and then it was widening growth against competitors like SocialCam and Viddy.And throughout it all, we’ve watched stars like Adam Goldberg vine their hearts out. But with today’s announcement that Vine is powering a new 6-second film contest for the Tribeca Film Festival, the app has most certainly graduated into a new tier of awesomeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chillhour.com/aqua-lung-ocean-wings" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Aqua lung ocean wings-wetsuit that lets you fly underwater | Chill Hour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aqua lung ocean wings is a wetsuit that lets you fly underwater. When we compare human body with the creatures of the sea, we are inefficient underwater.Massive limbs and lack of fins or tails requires a lot of energy to move in the water. Designer Guillaume Binard in cooperation with “Aqua Lung” created “Oceanwings”, a wetsuit with neoprene membranes which gives an incredible feeling to divers who use it in the deep sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/20/att-wireless-home-phone-goes-prepaid/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Wireless Home Phone goes prepaid, emulates landlines on demand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T is wagering that it can overcome some of that hesitance with new prepaid tiers for Wireless Home Phone. Those who plug their wired phones into the $100 cellular hub can now pay only for those times they want pseudo-traditional service, whether it's $20 per month for unlimited US-wide calls or $15 for 1,000 minutes of international long distance. It's hard to make a case for the new Wireless Home Phone option when many of us already have cellphones, but we can see its uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/20/wireless-under-the-skin-implant-can-beam-instant-blood-test-re/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Wireless &amp;#x27;under the skin&amp;#x27; prototype implant beams instant blood test read-outs to your smartphone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new blood-testing subdermal sensor has been developed by a team of scientists in Switzerland. While that may not sound particularly notable, this half-inch prototype can instantly beam several health metrics to smart devices over Bluetooth, monitoring cholesterol, blood sugar levels as well as the impact of medical treatments like chemotherapy using five built-in sensors.The device has already been tested on animals and while the researchers hope to begin testing soon on patients that would typically require a lot of blood tests and monitoring, the module is still several years from a commercial release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/20/4129560/apple-updates-garageband-with-audiobus-support" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple adopts Audiobus iOS multitasking solution with GarageBand update | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has updated GarageBand on iOS with support for Audiobus, a third-party interface that lets you use multiple music creation apps at the same time. Since Audiobus launched late last year, the developers behind several music apps have adopted it as a de facto communication standard for iOS, and it's easy to see why. The simple interface exponentially increases the iPad's value as a music creation tool by letting you do all the recording and sequencing on a single device without complex file imports, as well as enabling apps to talk to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/03/20/174827589/yes-your-new-car-has-a-black-box-wheres-the-off-switch" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Yes, Your New Car Has A &amp;#x27;Black Box.&amp;#x27; Where&amp;#x27;s The Off Switch? : All Tech Considered : NPR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're a vehicle owner and happen to have a car accident in the near future (we hope you don't), it's likely the crash details will be recorded. Automotive "black boxes" are now built into more than 90 percent of new cars, and the government is considering making them mandatory.Dave Wells, a detective at the King County Sheriff's Office in Washington state, specializes in accident reconstruction. That means he's often crouched under steering wheels, looking for the connector that mechanics use to get diagnostic codes. Crash data — moment-by-moment statistics can be saved from a car's most recent collision. There's speed, acceleration, braking — even information from inside the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/google-keepsave-whats-on-your-mind.html?m=1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Official Blog: Google Keep—Save what’s on your mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, if you’re like most people you probably often discover that the desk, fridge or magazine wasn’t such a clever place to leave the note after all...it’s rarely where you need it when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem Google has created Google Keep. With Keep you can quickly jot ideas down when you think of them and even include checklists and photos to keep track of what’s important to you. Your notes are safely stored in Google Drive and synced to all your devices so you can always have them at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://9to5mac.com/2013/03/20/macbook-pro-with-retina-display-problems-in-every-dimension/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;MacBook Pro with Retina display: Problems in every dimension | 9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has built its reputation on quality, craftsmanship, and customer/user experience, but that hasn’t been the case with its latest lineup of MacBooks. What many consumers don’t know is that buying a new Retina MacBook means taking your chances with possibly receiving a unit that is subject to display defects, battery, graphics, and fan-related issues among other major stability problems. These widespread issues have received limited coverage in the press and many consumers claim Apple is failing to sufficiently address the problems by not informing consumers and employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/news/512411/your-next-smartphone-screen-may-be-made-of-sapphire/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sapphire Could Replace Gorilla Glass in the iPhone and other Smartphones | MIT Technology Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manufactured sapphire is incredibly strong and scratch resistant. Now falling costs and technology improvements could make it competitive with glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sapphire, a crystalline form of aluminum oxide, probably won’t ever be as cheap as Gorilla Glass, the durable material from Corning that’s used to make screens on iPhones and other smartphones. A Gorilla Glass display costs less than $3, while a sapphire display would cost about $30. But that could fall below $20 in a couple of years thanks to increased competition and improving technology, says Eric Virey, an analyst for the market research firm Yole Développement. And since sapphire performs better than glass, that price could make it cheap enough to compete, he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/21/4131224/the-new-season-of-game-of-thrones-will-smite-you-with-dragon-fire" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The new season of &amp;#x27;Game of Thrones&amp;#x27; is a slow burn of dragon fire | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HBO's hit series Game of Thrones likes to take its time. From the very beginning, the series has excelled at the slow burn: methodically pitting one character against another, layering betrayal atop betrayal, and finishing each of its two seasons in shocking fashion. Of course, there's also a healthy mix of blood, sex, and dragon fire along the way. If the premiere episode of the program's third season is any indication, it isn't straying too far from that successful combination — and according to the minds behind the show, some of the most satisfying payoffs yet are in store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night HBO and AllThingsD hosted a screening of the episode, followed by a Q&amp;amp;A with author George R.R. Martin as well as executive producers D.B. Weiss and David Benioff. The new season covers roughly half of A Storm of Swords, the third novel in Martin's A Song of Ice and Fire saga. Season four would ostensibly cover the second half of the book — though Benioff cautioned that the show hasn't been picked up for next year just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2013/03/21/new-adware-trojan-targets-os-x-users/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;New adware trojan targets OS X users | TUAW - The Unofficial Apple Weblog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adware attacks against OS X are on the rise this year, says a report by anti-virus company Doctor Web. The Russian firm recently discovered another threat, Trojan.Yontoo.1, which has quickly become the most prominent adware trojan attacking Apple desktops and laptops.The trojan worms its way onto your computer through websites that require you to install a plugin to view the content of the site. The most common vector are movie trailer websites that prompt you to install an HD Video player or similar plugin. Instead of a media plugin, unsuspecting users will download the trojan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danbenjamin/status/314772433066397696/photo/1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter / danbenjamin: Sharing the @MailChimp love ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY3 for 30% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>59:38</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie are joined late in the afternoon by Myke Hurley and Moises Chiullan to discuss the latest in tech news, deviated septums, and trivia of the 50 United States. </itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie are joined late in the afternoon by Myke Hurley and Moises Chiullan to discuss the latest in tech news, deviated septums, and trivia of the 50 United States.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F108&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The News 28: Thursday, 21 March, 2013</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/news/28</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/news/28</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 21:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>The news for Thursday, 21 March, 2013.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/news/2013/news-028.mp3" length="4674410" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The news for Thursday, 21 March, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>9:10</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>The news for Thursday, 21 March, 2013.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>The news for Thursday, 21 March, 2013.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>news, tech, technology, apple, gaming, web, geek</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/42/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fnews%2F28&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ihnatko Almanac 64: Clair Huxtable Syndrome</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/ia/64</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/ia/64</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Andy Ihnatko &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Andy and Dan talk about the Fantastic Four and the Clair Huxtable Syndrome.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/ia/2013/ia-064.mp3" length="26617883" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Andy and Dan talk about the Fantastic Four and the Clair Huxtable Syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heroes_Reborn" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Heroes Reborn - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_The_Cosby_Show_characters#Clair_Huxtable" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;List of The Cosby Show characters - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celestial_(comics)" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Celestial (comics) - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galactus" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Galactus - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Susan_Storm" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Invisible Woman - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/She-Hulk" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;She-Hulk - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LMa3bDyS0WE" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Dirty Jobs-Snake Bite - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Andy Ihnatko &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>54:48</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Andy and Dan talk about the Fantastic Four and the Clair Huxtable Syndrome.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Andy and Dan talk about the Fantastic Four and the Clair Huxtable Syndrome.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>comics, articles, movies, books, tv, music</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/28/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fia%2F64&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic 36: Dalton Caldwell - App.net, Productivity and music</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/systematic/36</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/systematic/36</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Brett Terpstra</author>
      <description>Dalton Caldwell, CEO of App.net, visits Systematic to talk about building platforms, handling email, productivity and some of his favorite music.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/systematic/2013/systematic-036.mp3" length="26936596" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dalton Caldwell, CEO of App.net, visits Systematic to talk about building platforms, handling email, productivity and some of his favorite music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://alpha.app.net/Dalton" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;dalton on App.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://pmarca-archive.posterous.com/the-pmarca-guide-to-personal-productivity" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;The Pmarca Guide to Personal Productivity - pmarca &lt;em&gt;ARCHIVE&lt;/em&gt; - bit.ly/1z2b3V&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ironandwine.com/ghostonghost" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Iron and Wine: Ghost on Ghost Preorder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.maxtannone.com/projects/dcyh/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Doublecheck Your Head | Max Tannone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.andrewbird.net/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Andrew Bird - Hands Of Glory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://bootiemashup.com/halloween/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Halloween Booootie CDs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://bootiemashup.com/blog/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Bootie Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://hypem.com/popular" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Popular MP3 &amp;amp; Music Blog Tracks / The Hype Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://open.spotify.com/app/sifter" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;sifter on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://spaceappschallenge.org/about/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;About | International Space Apps Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://spaceappschallenge.org/location/virtual/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Virtual | International Space Apps Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.overviewthemovie.com/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Overview, the movie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://alpha.app.net/systematic" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;systematic on App.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://join.app.net/from/systematic" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;App.net invites from Systematic! (200 invites, first come, first serve)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week's episode of Systematic is sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (coupon &lt;strong&gt;DANSENTME&lt;/strong&gt;), &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (coupon &lt;strong&gt;IDESOFMARCH&lt;/strong&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (coupon &lt;strong&gt;DANSENTME3&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Brett Terpstra</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>55:23</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle></itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dalton Caldwell, CEO of App.net, visits Systematic to talk about building platforms, handling email, productivity and some of his favorite music.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>productivity, work, creativity, mac, iOS, music, social</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/39/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Fsystematic%2F36&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplified 49: New Overlords</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/amplified/49</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/amplified/49</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Jim Dalrymple &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Jim and Dan talk about Kevin Lynch, the iOS update, Google Reader's demise, leaving Feedburner, Google's priorities, privacy, Dropbox, BlackBerry's claim that the iPhone is "old", learning guitar chords, the line-6 amp, and more.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/amplified/2013/amplified-049.mp3" length="42182430" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Jim and Dan talk about Kevin Lynch, the iOS update, Google Reader's demise, leaving Feedburner, Google's priorities, privacy, Dropbox, BlackBerry's claim that the iPhone is "old", learning guitar chords, the line-6 amp, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mobile.theverge.com/2013/3/13/4101144/google-shuts-down-reader-rss-aggregation-service" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Google Reader to shut down July 1st | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2013/03/19/lynch-bozo" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Daring Fireball Linked List: Exhibit A in the Case That Newly-Hired Apple VP of Technology Kevin Lynch Is a Bozo, a Bad Hire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2013/03/19/exhibit-b" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Daring Fireball Linked List: Exhibit B: Defending/Denying Flash Player&amp;#x27;s Adverse Effect on Battery Life, a Mere Two Years Ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Thoughts on Flash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/membership/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;? Membership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/error.htm?aspxerrorpath=/themes/blogs/generic/post.aspx" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Error&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/dan-lyons-leaves-readwrite/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;ReadWrite Editor-In-Chief Dan Lyons, A.K.A. Fake Steve Jobs, Is Leaving For Hubspot | TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/apple/2013/03/19/apple-credits-evad3rs-jailbreak-team-with-4-of-6-software-bugs-fixed-in-ios-6-1-3/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple credits evad3rs jailbreak team with 4 of 6 software bugs fixed in iOS 6.1.3 - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/13/03/19/why-did-apple-hire-adobe-cto-kevin-lynch/page/1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Why did Apple hire Adobe CTO Kevin Lynch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sapphiretech.com/presentation/media/media_index.aspx?psn=0004&amp;amp;articleID=5083&amp;amp;lid=1" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Sapphire Technology Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/2013/03/18/thorsten-heins-blackberry_n_2901349.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Thorsten Heins, BlackBerry CEO: iPhone Is Getting Old&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But “the rate of innovation is so high in our industry that if you don’t innovate at that speed you can be replaced pretty quickly. The user interface on the iPhone — with all due respect for what this invention was all about — is now five years old.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://line6.com/spideriv75-120-150-hd150/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Advanced Guitar Amp Modeling | Spider IV Guitar Amplifiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://bcrich.com/models/guitars/Kerry%20King/Warlock-Metal-Master-Tribal-Fire/126" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Warlock Metal Master Tribal Fire Guitars - B.C. Rich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://hover.com/dansentme"&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME for 10% off), &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 30% off), and &lt;a href="http://squarespace.com/5by5"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; (use code DANSENTME3 for 10% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Jim Dalrymple &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>1:27:01</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Jim and Dan talk about Kevin Lynch, the iOS update, Google Reader's demise, leaving Feedburner, Google's priorities, privacy, Dropbox, BlackBerry's claim that the iPhone is "old", learning guitar chords, the line-6 amp, and more.</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Jim and Dan talk about Kevin Lynch, the iOS update, Google Reader's demise, leaving Feedburner, Google's priorities, privacy, Dropbox, BlackBerry's claim that the iPhone is "old", learning guitar chords, the line-6 amp, and more.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>apple, mac, ipad, iphone, ios, guitars, music, recording</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/35/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Famplified%2F49&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Frequency 107: Worst Episode Ever</title>
      <link>http://5by5.tv/frequency/107</link>
      <guid>http://5by5.tv/frequency/107</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 16:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</author>
      <description>Dan and Haddie discuss Twitter getting the patent for "Twitter", a redesign of Hulu Plus for the Apple TV, Adobe's CEO is leaving and moving to Apple, the ReadWrite editor-in-cheif Dan Lyons is leaving and moving to Hubspot, and the release of Evernote Food for iOS.
</description>
      <enclosure url="http://d.ahoy.co/redirect.mp3/fly.5by5.tv/audio/broadcasts/frequency/2013/frequency-107.mp3" length="24982964" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Dan and Haddie discuss Twitter getting the patent for "Twitter", a redesign of Hulu Plus for the Apple TV, Adobe's CEO is leaving and moving to Apple, the ReadWrite editor-in-cheif Dan Lyons is leaving and moving to Hubspot, and the release of Evernote Food for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links for this episode:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mobile.theverge.com/2013/3/19/4124888/twitter-gets-a-patent-on-twitter" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Twitter gets a patent on... Twitter | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Twitter famously has a pending patent on the familiar "pull-to-refresh" gesture, the company may have just acquired something more valuable: a patent on the Twitter messaging service itself. The new patent issued today with Twitter founders Jack Dorsey and Biz Stone listed as inventors, and broadly describes a messaging service in which users follow each other and sent messages don't have specific recipients, but are rather sent and displayed to those followers by the system itself. That's exactly how Twitter works, of course — it's definitely more of a broadcasting system than a direct messaging service, and the patent claims explicitly make reference to "broadcasting an update message" several times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter filed for the patent in 2007, but it's doubtful the company will pursue any litigation against competing services with it now that it's in hand — the company has very publicly promised to only use patents defensively, and last year introduced the Innovator's Patent Agreement to codify that promise and require permission from its employees before suing offensively. But competing companies like Facebook will have to evaluate their products carefully against Twitter's very broad claims on virtually any service that allows messages to be sent to a large group of unaddressed recipients who follow the sender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/19/hulu-plus-apple-tv-redesign/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Hulu Plus For Apple TV Gets a Facelift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its blog, Hulu says that it has redesigned the Apple TV Hulu Plus experience "from the ground up," with a focus on finding current TV episodes and content discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content categories are now across the top navigation bar — mimicking the interface Apple uses for the iTunes store — and offering easy access to sections such as TV, Movies, Kids, Latino and the Hulu Queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://gigaom.com/2013/03/19/adobes-cto-heading-to-apple/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Adobe’s CTO leaving the company and heading to Apple — Tech News and Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adobe CTO Kevin Lynch has been wooed away by Apple. CNBC reported Tuesday that Lynch has been hired by Apple but so far there are no details as to what his job title or responsibilities at the company would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/dan-lyons-leaves-readwrite/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;ReadWrite Editor-In-Chief Dan Lyons, A.K.A. Fake Steve Jobs, Is Leaving For Hubspot - TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Lyons, the editor-in-chief at tech blog ReadWrite, is leaving for a position at marketing software company Hubspot. We heard the news from knowledgeable sources, and the part about Lyons’ departure for Hubspot was confirmed by a SAY Media spokesperson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Yes, Dan will be leaving his position as editor-in-chief of ReadWrite effective April 1. He made this decision based on the challenges of telecommuting and the daily distance from his editorial team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still very invested in ReadWrite – it’s an important brand in our portfolio. We’ll continue to invest in and support the team and develop the property as part of our commitment to the future of the brand."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/apple/2013/03/19/apple-credits-evad3rs-jailbreak-team-with-4-of-6-software-bugs-fixed-in-ios-6-1-3/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Apple credits evad3rs jailbreak team with 4 of 6 software bugs fixed in iOS 6.1.3 - The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the release of iOS 6.1.3, Apple has also dropped a security note that details the bugs and issues patched in this version. The note credits the discovery of four of the six bugs fixed to evad3rs, the team behind the evasi0n jailbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/19/evernote-food-ios-update/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Evernote Food for iOS now lets you share recipes, adds support for OpenTable reservations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is an undoubtedly essential part of life -- and, in a rather digital age, some could certainly make the same argument about app updates, right? Well, combining the best of both worlds, today Evernote released a refreshed version of its Evernote Food application on iOS, making it more accessible for hungry users to book a reservation through OpenTable's system and adding some social tidbits that'll let foodies share their recipes by way of email, Facebook or Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.engadget.com/2013/03/19/doj-search-warrant-access-user-email/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;DoJ now in favor of using search warrants to access user email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States Justice Department seems to be listening to cries from Google (among others) that the 1986 ECPA (Electronic Communications Privacy Act) should be revised to reflect the vastly different universe that we now live in. DoJ attorney Elana Tyrangiel testified before the US House Judiciary Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations today, and in a nutshell, she now seems willing to think about the use of search warrants to access all types of email. Previously, the entity wanted the use a far less strict method for gaining access -- giving less privacy to opened emails or emails that were over half a year old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mobile.theverge.com/2013/3/19/4124702/amazon-talks-to-record-labels-about-subscription-music-service" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon in talks with record labels about subscription music service | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscription music services have yet to profit but that hasn't stopped some of the internet's biggest media distributors from jumping into the business. Amazon, the web's biggest retailer, is the latest to inquire with various music companies about starting a subscription service, multiple sources have told The Verge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details are few and the talks have been described as very informal, the sources said. But so far, what Amazon has shown an interest in is an on-demand service that sounds pretty similar to Spotify, generally considered the sector leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/3/19/4123740/supreme-court-upholds-first-sale-rights-abroad" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Supreme Court upholds &amp;#x27;first sale&amp;#x27; right to sell used books or movies, even when bought abroad | The Verge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5inShareThe Supreme Court has ruled that copyright owners cannot legally forbid people who buy their works to sell them in the US, even if the items in question were made outside the US. The decision upheld a geographically unlimited first sale doctrine — a provision which holds that once someone buys a book, DVD, or other work copyrighted in America, they're free to sell or rent it without the copyright holder's permission. In doing so, it created a major precedent for breaking down international sale barriers, granting legal status both to people who simply want to sell items bought abroad and to those who make money by taking advantage of cheap prices outside the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/19/cops-want-text-messages-logs/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Cops Want Wireless Providers to Record and Store Your Text Messages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same day that Google is asking Congress to strengthen privacy protections for Americans' emails, the cops are arguing that U.S. law should require cellphone providers to store text messages logs in the event authorities need to read them in the course of a criminal investigation.According to the proposal, backed by a coalition of law-enforcement associations, wireless companies like AT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2013/03/facebook-preferences-predict-per.html?buffer_share=fdf1e&amp;amp;ref=hp" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook Preferences Predict Personality Traits - ScienceNOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day, millions of people click on Facebook "Like" buttons, boldly declaring their preferences for a variety of things, such as books, movies, and cat videos. But those "likes" may reveal more than they intend, such as sexual orientation, drug use, and religious affiliation, according to a study that analyzed the online behavior of thousands of volunteers. The researchers used data from 58,000 U.S.-based myPersonality volunteers to build a statistical model. Then, they used a sample of myPersonality volunteers to test how well the model could predict personal attributes from likes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/19/us/disposal-of-older-monitors-leaves-a-hazardous-trail.html?pagewanted=all" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Disposal of Older Monitors Leaves a Hazardous Trail - NYTimes.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lots of smaller recyclers are in over their heads, and the risk that they might abandon their stockpiles is very real,” said Jason Linnell of the Electronics Recycling Coordination Clearinghouse, an organization that represents state environmental regulators, electronics manufacturers and recyclers. In February, the group sent a letter to the Environmental Protection Agency asking for immediate help dealing with the rapidly growing stockpiles of the glass, much of which contains lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://mashable.com/2013/03/18/bike-theft-tracker-bikespike/" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;New Theft Tracker Is Like LoJack and OnStar for Your Bike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've ever had your bicycle stolen, you're probably familiar with the frustration of  losing your two-wheeled mode of transport. A Chicago-based startup is addressing that pain point with a gadget that alerts your smartphone when your bike is tampered with and makes it easy to notify the police.The creators at Team BikeSpike developed a beacon of the same name that easily attaches to your bike and tracks its location through your phone or computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2013/03/big_data_means_more_than_big_p.html" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Big Data Means More Than Big Profits - Jim Fruchterman - Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many activities in the social sphere also generate lots of information. Massive amounts of data are collected on the pollution in our cities and the changes in our climate. The more we use technology in our education and health systems, the more data we collect about how people learn and what keeps us healthy or makes us sick. These information-centric areas are built for Big Data — data that if better understood could help provide a pathway to maximize our human potential, instead of maximizing profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2013/03/fixing-the-worst-law-in-technology-aaron-swartz-and-the-computer-fraud-and-abuse-act.html?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pulsenews" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Fixing the Worst Law in Technology: Aaron Swartz and the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act : The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Computer Fraud and Abuse Act is the most outrageous criminal law you?ve never heard of. It bans ?unauthorized access? of computers, but no one really knows what those words mean. Orin Kerr, a former Justice Department attorney and a leading scholar on computer-crime law, argues persuasively that the law is so open-ended and broad as to be unconstitutionally vague. Over the years, the punishments for breaking the law have grown increasingly severe?it can now put people in prison for decades for actions that cause no real economic or physical harm. It is, in short, a nightmare for a country that calls itself free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5gKlyu7mV_3oNhcRyG7P2JKmn9l3Q" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;AFP: S. Korean TV networks, banks under suspect cyber attack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The South Korean military raised its cyber attack warning level Wednesday after computer networks crashed at major TV broadcasters and banks, with initial suspicions focused on North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Korea Internet Security Agency, a state watchdog, said computer networks at three TV broadcasters -- KBS, MBC and YTN -- as well as the Shinhan and Nonghyup banks had been "partially or entirely crippled".
LG Uplus, an Internet service provider, also reported a network crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no immediate confirmation of who or what was behind the multiple shutdown, which occurred around 2:00 pm, but the main finger of suspicion is likely to point at Pyongyang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/cat.mhtml?searchterm=cougar&amp;amp;search_group=&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;search_source=search_form#id=94526785" class="link" target="_blank"&gt;Mid-Adult Blond Woman With Angry Expression And Hands Raised In Claw-Like Gesture, On White Background. Stock Photo 94526785 : Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by &lt;a href="http://shutterstock.com"&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; (use code FREQUENCY3 for 30% off).&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
      <itunes:author>Haddie Cooke &amp; Dan Benjamin</itunes:author>
      <itunes:duration>51:23</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:subtitle>Dan and Haddie discuss Twitter getting the patent for "Twitter", a redesign of Hulu Plus for the Apple TV, Adobe's CEO is leaving and moving to Apple, the ReadWrite editor-in-cheif Dan Lyons is leaving and moving to Hubspot, and the release of Evernote Fo</itunes:subtitle>
      <itunes:summary>Dan and Haddie discuss Twitter getting the patent for "Twitter", a redesign of Hulu Plus for the Apple TV, Adobe's CEO is leaving and moving to Apple, the ReadWrite editor-in-cheif Dan Lyons is leaving and moving to Hubspot, and the release of Evernote Food for iOS.
</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:keywords>frequency, dan benjamin, haddie cooke, news, tech, events, technology</itunes:keywords>
      <itunes:image href="http://icebox.5by5.tv/images/broadcasts/41/cover.jpg"/>
      <atom:link rel="payment" type="text/html" href="https://flattr.com/submit/auto?url=http%3A%2F%2F5by5.tv%2Ffrequency%2F107&amp;user_id=danbenjamin"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
