<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>zenhabits</title>
	<atom:link href="http://zenhabits.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://zenhabits.net</link>
	<description>breathe</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 05:39:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>The Not Knowing Path of Being an Entrepreneur</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/unknowing/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/unknowing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Goals & Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Productivity & Organization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta Lots of people who start businesses try to control outcomes: A vision for your business&#8217;s success. Goals to get you to the successful vision. Try to get the most productive day (out of yourself, or employees). Try to produce certain amounts, or hit certain metrics (pageviews, followers, revenue, sales). Unfortunately, the ability [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Lots of people who start businesses try to control outcomes:</p>

<ol>
<li>A vision for your business&#8217;s success.</li>
<li>Goals to get you to the successful vision.</li>
<li>Try to get the most productive day (out of yourself, or employees).</li>
<li>Try to produce certain amounts, or hit certain metrics (pageviews, followers, revenue, sales).</li>
</ol>

<p>Unfortunately, the ability to control outcomes is an illusion. This is one of the fundamental lessons I&#8217;ve learned in my six years of being in business for myself.</p>

<p>You don&#8217;t really know how things will turn out.</p>

<p>And this is OK.</p>

<p>In fact, it&#8217;s pretty awesome.</p>

<p>Yes, not knowing how things will turn out &#8212; day to day, month to month, year to year &#8212; is crazy scary. I&#8217;m not gonna front. It&#8217;s so scary you might wake up drenched in sweat.</p>

<p>But not knowing is what makes being an entrepreneur more amazing than working a regular desk job with a regular paycheck. We take risks, we fail, we don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen, we not only put our toes into the waters of the unknown &#8230; we dive in, headfirst.</p>

<p>Yes, not knowing is scary. But <strong>if you embrace it</strong>, not knowing can be liberating, and can be an advantage.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s look at how it&#8217;s an advantage, and how to stay present in the middle of the unknown.</p>

<h3>The Advantage of Not Knowing</h3>

<p>Quiz question: What causes us the most anxiety? Million dollar answer: Wanting things to turn out a certain way. Wanting an outcome &#8212; wanting the person you love to love you back, wanting people at your meeting or presentation to like you, wanting a million customers, wanting to be the next Apple or Twitter or Starbucks. This is the cause of our anxiety, because when we want that outcome, we fear that it won&#8217;t come true, and we strive for it to come true, and of course it might not.</p>

<p>There are a million possibilities, and wanting just one of those possibilities is a little crazy. What&#8217;s wrong with the other 999,999? Will our worlds fall apart if that one outcome doesn&#8217;t become a reality? No. We&#8217;ll be just fine no matter what.</p>

<p>Seriously. You&#8217;ll be absolutely fine even if the outcome doesn&#8217;t happen.</p>

<p>So when anxiety comes up, if we learn to let go of needing that outcome, we can then let go of the anxiety.</p>

<p>So advantage #1: <strong>we have less anxiety</strong>. What happens when you have less anxiety? Well, you&#8217;re happier. You are happier when you meet with customers or clients or employees. They feel your happiness. They sense that you&#8217;re cool with how things are going. You are less desperate. You don&#8217;t need things to turn out a certain way &#8212; you don&#8217;t need this one sale. You do your best to make it happen, but you&#8217;re cool even if it doesn&#8217;t.</p>

<p>Other people bet everything on making their outcome happen &#8212; but what if it doesn&#8217;t? Then they&#8217;ve lost everything, with no clear direction of where to go when it fails to happen.</p>

<p>So advantage #2: <strong>we aren&#8217;t as tied to one bet</strong>. That&#8217;s a single point of failure. Not a great idea. Instead, we are OK no matter what happens, and so any outcome of a meeting, a project, a launch &#8230; we are good with that, and no outcome really messes us up. We flow.</p>

<p>Another problem is that people who think they know how things will turn out &#8230; they&#8217;re fooling themselves. No one knows.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s advantage #3: <strong>we are more honest</strong>. Admitting to ourselves that we don&#8217;t know is much more honest than thinking, hoping, things will turn out the way we want. Honesty is important because if we&#8217;re going to act, we should do so with open eyes and a clear assessment of the situation.</p>

<p>Honesty with customers, readers, clients, employees is important too. Admit you don&#8217;t know. They will trust you more, because not only are you telling them you don&#8217;t know, you are clearly OK with that. You don&#8217;t know what will happen, but whatever happens, you&#8217;ll deal with it. That&#8217;s powerful.</p>

<p>Those are just a few advantages, but actually the advantages are many. You don&#8217;t have to plan as much because not knowing means you realize that detailed plans are useless, and actually a waste of your time. You spend less time worrying, more time executing. You aren&#8217;t consumed by the horrible fear that you&#8217;re doing the wrong thing, because you learn that there is never a  perfectly &#8220;right thing&#8221; to do &#8212; not generally for your business, or specifically right now.</p>

<h3>How to Walk the Not Knowing Path</h3>

<p>The Not Knowing Path of an entrepreneur is scary, but honestly, what path isn&#8217;t?</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s how to walk the path:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Admit you don&#8217;t know</strong>. This is obviously the first step, but it&#8217;s hard because we often want to think we know, or at least that we can make certain things happen the way we want them to. We think we can will things to happen. That&#8217;s not true. Many things fail despite Herculean efforts to make them succeed. We don&#8217;t control the future, we can&#8217;t know the future. We don&#8217;t know. Admit it to ourselves, and to others.</li>
<li><strong>Watch for anxiety</strong>. When you start feeling anxious (and that will always happen, probably numerous times a day), look inward for the source of the anxiety. What are you hoping will happen that&#8217;s making you anxious? This awareness is the key to everything.</li>
<li><strong>Tell yourself you&#8217;ll be OK</strong>. You become aware of an outcome you&#8217;re hoping for &#8230; now tell yourself that it doesn&#8217;t matter if that outcome happens. It really doesn&#8217;t matter, even if we&#8217;ve made up this story for ourselves that all depends on it happening. It doesn&#8217;t matter, and no matter what happens, we&#8217;ll be OK. Life-and-death situations are possibly the only exception to this, though I&#8217;m of the mind that even death is an outcome that I&#8217;d be OK with.</li>
<li><strong>Consider worst-case scenarios</strong>. What&#8217;s the worst thing that could happen? Someone doesn&#8217;t like you, doesn&#8217;t think as highly of you as you&#8217;d like, a meeting ends in anger, a sale doesn&#8217;t happen, the business fails. How bad is this worst-case scenario? How likely is it to happen? How would you cope if it did? Honestly, I think you&#8217;d be fine no matter what.</li>
<li><strong>Know your principles</strong>. Take some time to think about what should guide you, if you aren&#8217;t guided by trying to make something specific happen. If you&#8217;re not tied to an outcome or vision of the future you can&#8217;t control, what would guide you? Step back, reflect. What drives you? Why do you do what you do? For example, some of my guiding principles are wanting to help others, wanting to act compassionately, wanting to do things I love, and building trust by doing those things.</li>
<li><strong>Act on principles, not goals or detailed plans</strong>. Once you have your guiding principles, let them guide you on a day-by-day basis, moment-to-moment. You don&#8217;t know how something will turn out when you act, but you do know whether this action is in line with your principles.</li>
<li><strong>Breathe, and smile</strong>. In the end, not knowing can be scary, but liberating and profound. You are in the midst of a turbulent sea, and are afloat without knowing where anything will go. But that&#8217;s always true, even of people who don&#8217;t admit it to themselves. So enjoy the ride. Look at the amazing place you&#8217;re in, and smile. Because this path of not knowing &#8230; it is the path of life itself.</li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;If you realize that all things change, there is nothing you will try to hold on to. If you are not afraid of dying, there is nothing you cannot achieve.&#8217; <strong>~Lao Tzu</strong></p>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/unknowing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Change Your Life: A User&#8217;s Guide</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/change/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13388</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;You will never change your life until you change something you do daily.&#8217; ~Mike Murdock By Leo Babauta Start with a simple statement: what do you want to be? Are you hoping to someday be a writer, a musician, a designer, a programmer, a polyglot, a carpenter, a manga artist, an entrepreneur, an expert at [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;You will never change your life until you change something you do daily.&#8217; <strong>~Mike Murdock</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Start with a simple statement: what do you want to be?</p>

<p>Are you hoping to someday be a writer, a musician, a designer, a programmer, a polyglot, a carpenter, a manga artist, an entrepreneur, an expert at something?</p>

<p>How do you get there? Do you write your intention on a piece of paper, and put it in a bottle and launch it to sea, hoping it will manifest? No. The universe isn&#8217;t going to make this happen. You are.</p>

<p>Do you set yourself a big goal to complete by the end of the year, or in three months? Sure, but that doesn&#8217;t get the job done. In fact, if you think back on most examples in your life, setting big long-term goals probably doesn&#8217;t work very often. How many times has this strategy been successful?</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to lay down the law here, based on many many experiments I&#8217;ve done in the last 7 years: <strong>nothing will change unless you make a daily change</strong>.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve tried weekly action steps, things that I do every other day, big bold monthly goals, lots of other permutations. <em>None of them work except daily changes</em>.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re not willing to make it a daily change, you don&#8217;t really want to change your life in this way. You only like the idea of learning to draw/speak Japanese/play guitar/program in php/etc. You don&#8217;t really want to do it.</p>

<p>So make a daily change. Let&#8217;s dig into how it&#8217;s done!</p>

<h3>How to Turn an Aspiration Into a Daily Change</h3>

<p>Let&#8217;s name a few aspirations:</p>

<ul>
<li>lose weight</li>
<li>write a book</li>
<li>stop procrastinating</li>
<li>fall in love</li>
<li>be happy</li>
<li>travel the world</li>
<li>drink more water</li>
<li>learn Spanish</li>
<li>save money</li>
<li>take more pictures</li>
<li>read more books</li>
</ul>

<p>How do you turn those lofty ideas into daily changes? Think about what you could do every day that would make the change happen, or at least get you closer to the goal. Sometimes that&#8217;s not always easy, but let&#8217;s look at some ideas:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>lose weight</strong> &#8211; start walking every day, for 10 minutes at first, then 15 after a week, then 20 &#8230; once you are walking for 30-40 minutes a day, make another change &#8212; drink water instead of soda.</li>
<li><strong>write a book</strong> &#8211; write for 10 minutes a day.</li>
<li><strong>stop procrastinating</strong> &#8211; I can already hear the ironic (and original!) jokes about how people will deal with procrastination later (har!). Anyway, a daily action: set a Most Important Task each morning, then work on it for 10 minutes before opening your browser/mobile device.</li>
<li><strong>fall in love</strong> &#8211; go somewhere each day and meet/social with new people. Or do daily things that make you a fascinating person.</li>
<li><strong>be happy</strong> &#8211; do something each day to make the world better, to help people.</li>
<li><strong>travel the world</strong> &#8211; save money (see next item). Or start selling your stuff, so you can carry your belongings on a backpack and start hitchhiking. </li>
<li><strong>save money</strong> &#8211; start cutting out smaller expenses. Start cooking and eating at home. Sell your car and bike/walk/take the train. Start looking for a smaller home. Do free stuff instead of buying things.</li>
<li><strong>drink more water</strong> &#8211; drink water when you wake up, then every time you take a break (once an hour).</li>
<li><strong>learn Spanish</strong> &#8211; study Spanish sentences in Anki and listen to Pimsleur tapes 10 minutes a day.</li>
<li><strong>take more pictures</strong> &#8211; take pictures at lunch (but dear jeebus, not of your lunch) and post them to your blog.</li>
<li><strong>read more books</strong> &#8211; read every morning and before you go to bed.</li>
</ul>

<p>You get the idea. Not all of these are perfect ideas, but you could come up with something that works better for you. Point is, do it daily.</p>

<h3>How to Implement Daily Changes</h3>

<p>This method is fairly simple, and if you really implement it, nearly foolproof:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>One Change at a Time</strong>. You can break this rule, but don&#8217;t be surprised if you fail. Do one change for a month before considering a second. Only add another change if you were successful at the first.</li>
<li><strong>Start Small</strong>. OK, I&#8217;ve said this two bajillion times. No one ever does it, though. Start with 10 minutes or less. Five minutes is better if it&#8217;s a hard change. If you fail at that, drop it to 2 minutes.</li>
<li><strong>Do it at the same time each day</strong>. OK, not literally at the same minute, like at 6:00 a.m., but after the same trigger in your daily routine &#8212; after you drink your first cup of coffee in the morning, after you arrive at work, after you get home, after you brush your teeth, shower, eat breakfast, wake up, eat lunch, turn on your computer, first see your wife each day.</li>
<li><strong>Make a huge commitment to someone</strong>. Or multiple people. Make sure it&#8217;s someone whose opinion you respect. For example, I made a commitment to studying/coding PHP at least 10 minutes each day to my friend <a href="http://tynan.com/">Tynan</a>. I&#8217;ve made commitments to my wife, to other friends, to readers of this blog, to readers of a newspaper on Guam, to my kids, and more.</li>
<li><strong>Be accountable</strong>. Taking my programming example with Tynan &#8230; each day I have to update a Google spreadsheet each day showing how many minutes I programmed/studied each day, and he can (and does) check that shared spreadsheet. The tool you use doesn&#8217;t matter &#8212; you can post to Facebook or Twitter, email someone, mark it on a calendar, report in person. Just make sure you&#8217;re accountable each day, not each month. And make sure the person is checking. If they don&#8217;t check on you, you need to find a new accountability partner or group.</li>
<li><strong>Have consequences</strong>. The most important consequence for doing or not doing the daily habit is that if you don&#8217;t, the people will respect you less, and if you do, they&#8217;ll respect you more. If your accountability system isn&#8217;t set up this way, find another way to do it. You might need to change who you&#8217;re accountable to. But you can add other fun consequences: one friend made a promise to Facebook friends that he&#8217;d donate $50 to Mitt Romney&#8217;s campaign (this was last year) each time he didn&#8217;t follow through on a commitment. I&#8217;ve made a promise to eat whale sushi (I won&#8217;t fail, because eating a whale is repugnant to me, like eating a cow or a child). I&#8217;ve promised to sing a Japanese song in front of strangers if I failed. The consequences can also be positive &#8212; a big reward each week if you don&#8217;t miss a day, for example. Make the consequences bigger if you miss two straight days, and huge if you miss three.</li>
<li><strong>Enjoy the change</strong>. If you don&#8217;t do this, you might as well find another change to make. If the daily action feels tedious and chore-like, then you are doing it wrong. Find a way to enjoy it, or you won&#8217;t stick to it long. Or find some other change you enjoy more.</li>
</ol>

<p>That&#8217;s it. Seven pretty simple steps, and you&#8217;ve got a changed life. None of these steps is impossible &#8212; in fact, you can put them into action today.</p>

<p>What daily change will you make today?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;A year from now you will wish you had started today.&#8217; <strong>~Karen Lamb</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Note</strong>: I have a program designed to help you make changes in this way, with built-in accountability and step-by-step plans each month &#8212; the <a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/">Sea Change Program</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Your Family On Board with Life Changes</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/family-changes/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/family-changes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 16:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance & Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13382</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;Men learn while they teach.&#8217; ~Seneca the Younger By Leo Babauta It is a curious phenomena that when we try to change our habits &#8212; simplify our clutter, eat healthier, start exercising &#8212; the other people in our life don&#8217;t instantly want to be changed in the same way. It&#8217;s as if they had their [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;Men learn while they teach.&#8217; <strong>~Seneca the Younger</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>It is a curious phenomena that when we try to change our habits &#8212; simplify our clutter, eat healthier, start exercising &#8212; the other people in our life don&#8217;t instantly want to be changed in the same way.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s as if they had their own minds!</p>

<p>Horrible as that might sound, it&#8217;s the reality we have to deal with if we have a family (or friends, roommates, coworkers, etc.). They often resist changes we make, or their possibly unhealthy habits stand in our way.</p>

<p>You&#8217;re trying to eat only whole foods, and yet your daughter eats goldfish crackers and pizza and Oreos. And she doesn&#8217;t seem to want to munch on asparagus instead!</p>

<p>So what&#8217;s a habit changer to do? Abandon all attempts at change? No. Force change on family members? Tempting, but not effective.</p>

<p>The answer is that there is no simple answer. I&#8217;ll share what has worked for me, but that won&#8217;t work for everyone. When you&#8217;re single and living alone, it&#8217;s easy to make whatever changes you want to make &#8212; but if you&#8217;re married, you have to make compromises. You live in the space that is common between the two of you, and that is negotiated space. When you add kids to your life, you now live in a space that is common between all of you, also a negotiated space.</p>

<p>What works? Let&#8217;s take a look at some strategies. Try one, try two, or try them all, and figure out what works in your negotiated space.</p>

<h3>Getting Others On Board</h3>

<p>Here&#8217;s a common scenario: you&#8217;ve read about some interesting challenge or change someone else has made, or perhaps read a magazine article or book on the topic, and have been giving it some thought, and finally arrived at the decision to make the change &#8230; and then you spring it on your significant other or entire family. They somehow aren&#8217;t as enthused as you&#8217;d like!</p>

<p>That&#8217;s because you have gone through an entire thinking process to arrive at the decision, and they are being asked to come in only at the end &#8212; after the decision has been made. That&#8217;s not fair to them, because they haven&#8217;t had time to go through the same thinking process, to consider the reasons, to find the motivation, to be included in the decision.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve found a more effective method is to get all the people who will be affected in on the thinking process as early as possible. Don&#8217;t talk to them about it when you&#8217;re near the decision-making point &#8230; talk to them when you first hear or read about the idea. Talk about why it&#8217;s appealing to you. Get their input. Ask whether they&#8217;d consider that kind of change. Talk about your motivation. Include them every step of the way, until the decision is made, and even after.</p>

<p>What people don&#8217;t like is being forced to change, against their will. So never make people feel that way. Don&#8217;t ask them to change &#8230; ask them to help you change, once you&#8217;ve gotten to the decision. Say that their support is really important to you, and while they are welcome to join you (you&#8217;d love that!), they don&#8217;t have to change. Just help you make your change. Ask them to be your accountability buddy, someone to call on when you&#8217;re having trouble, someone to report problems and successes to.</p>

<h3>Setting the Example</h3>

<p>While not everyone will be instantly on board with your ideas for change, I&#8217;ve found the best method of persuasion is being a good model for change.</p>

<p>When I started exercising, most of my family wasn&#8217;t doing it. I tried to convince people, but I wasn&#8217;t as good at persuasion as I thought. When they saw me exercising, at first they thought I was a bit kooky. Then they saw the changes in me, and how much I enjoyed it, and I would share how great it was, and over time, it inspired some to think about it.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s what you can do &#8212; inspire people to consider something they wouldn&#8217;t normally consider, just by setting a good example. No one else will do yoga with you? That&#8217;s OK &#8230; keep doing it, and share your experiences. Do it in front of them as they watch TV. Try not to be annoying, though.</p>

<h3>Making Changes on Your Own</h3>

<p>If others won&#8217;t get on board with your changes, ask for a minimum amount of support: ask that they give you the space to make the change on your own, without their help. This isn&#8217;t a small thing sometimes &#8212; often people are threatened when someone in their life makes changes, or they don&#8217;t like the disruption of their routine of doing things with you (eating junk food together, for example). You doing something on your own is a big change for them.</p>

<p>Ask for the space to do it alone, and ask that they not criticize or otherwise make it hard on you. If they are resentful, this makes it more difficult, but you&#8217;ll have to make an effort to show that this is something that will make you happy, and you will do your best not to disrupt things for them. If that means you don&#8217;t spend mornings together because you are out running, then try to create other time together, like in the evenings or on weekends.</p>

<p>When you make changes on your own, without the support of others, it&#8217;s more difficult. You need to find other encouragement &#8212; I&#8217;ve joined running groups online, a smoking cessation group, and other similar groups. Facebook and other social networking tools can also be helpful in finding online support. Often there are groups in your area where you can meet people in person who are going through the same changes.</p>

<h3>Family Challenges</h3>

<p>One of my more successful strategies is creating challenges for my family. They aren&#8217;t required to do the challenges, of course, but sometimes people like the opportunity to rise to a challenge. And they like making changes with others.</p>

<p>My wife and I have created eating challenges to do with each other (we call them Lean Out Challenges, usually after we go on a trip and gorge ourselves on unhealthy food). With the kids, I&#8217;ve challenged them to do pushups, handstands, running, vegetarian experiments, daily drawing, and more.</p>

<p>Challenges are fun if you do them together. It can be fun to do it as a competition, or to offer rewards for people who complete the challenge.</p>

<h3>Notes on Eating Habits</h3>

<p>Eating changes can be especially difficult if your family isn&#8217;t doing it with you, because they can be eating junk food right in front of your face as you try to much on celery. Tough stuff.</p>

<p>Here are some notes from my experiences:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you do the cooking, cook food for the family, and cook your meals separately. Eva &amp; I often cook our healthy food in bulk and eat the same food for days, while the kids eat other things. For some reason they&#8217;re not big kale and quinoa fans. Kids.</li>
<li>Kids can change their taste buds, but slowly. They won&#8217;t instantly like big green salads, but you can introduce vegetables slowly, in soups and other dishes they might be used to. Dice carrots and kale can be added to chili and spaghetti sauce if you cut them small enough and add them when you&#8217;re cooking onions/garlic.</li>
<li>Kids will eat nearly anything if you add some baked fries to the dish.</li>
<li>If the kids are going to eat something especially tempting (pizza), I try to make myself scarce so I don&#8217;t have temptations. It&#8217;s too hard to avoid junk that I enjoy eating, if it&#8217;s right in front of me, so I&#8217;ll go for a run or go to my room to do some work &#8212; keep busy.</li>
<li>We try to find restaurants that has healthy food that the kids will like.</li>
<li>When I went vegetarian, Eva &amp; the kids weren&#8217;t vegetarian. I did get them to try some dishes, which they generally liked, and then would just eat my food separately from them. If I made my food especially delicious, it would be tempting for them to at least try.</li>
<li>Kids will go to any restaurant if there&#8217;s dessert at the end.</li>
<li>Many people don&#8217;t like the idea of vegan food, even if they&#8217;ve never tried it. Making delicious vegan cupcakes will often win them over, at least to try it. I recommend <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Vegan-Cupcakes-Take-Over-World/dp/1569242739">Vegan Cupcakes Take Over the World</a>. Truly amazing.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Supporting Their Changes</h3>

<p>If you want others to support your changes, you should also support theirs. When my kids or wife express a desire to make some change, I do my best to help them achieve that:</p>

<ul>
<li>I share my experiences and what worked for me, and how I overcame some obstacles.</li>
<li>I share websites and books that help with that change, and often will buy books to help them.</li>
<li>I&#8217;ll do a project with them, or create a challenge we can do together.</li>
<li>I run and workout with my wife, and created a workout log to help her track her fitness.</li>
<li>I share vegetarian recipes with my wife (who is now vegan), and with my daughter, who decided to try vegetarianism</li>
</ul>

<p>There are more possibilities, but these are a few examples. When they see you supporting them, they now have a model for how to act when you want to make changes in the future. It&#8217;s not an overnight change that you&#8217;ll see in your family, but slow gradual long-term changes. Play the long game when it comes to changing the culture of a family.</p>

<h3>Learn by Teaching</h3>

<p>The best way to make changes yourself is to help others. That means supporting them when they want to make changes, sharing the changes you&#8217;ve made and teaching them what you&#8217;ve learned, showing someone how to do something cool after you&#8217;ve learned how to do it.</p>

<p>You are teaching by making changes and sharing those changes with your family. They might not care about learning at first, but they will, over time. And when you teach, you learn more and more. As I am now, sharing with you.</p>

<h3>Mindful + Entrepreneur Seminar</h3>

<p>In other news, I&#8217;m holding a 3-hour seminar next week (March 21) with Jesse Jacobs of Samovar Tea Lounge. In this seminar, I&#8217;ll share my biggest mistakes in growing Zen Habits and building an online business, and what I&#8217;ve learned along the way. Jesse will share his story and lessons in building Samovar Tea Lounge and building an amazing environment for people to disconnect in order to connect.</p>

<p>Join us in a fireside chat over tea and chocolate and learn our secrets. We&#8217;re hosting a live seminar on <a href="http://shop.samovarlife.com/product-p/12mien01.htm?mc_cid=9ccf452e0c&#038;mc_eid=[UNIQID]">March 21 from 3-6pm</a> at Yerba Buena Samovar Tea Lounge for just 25 participants so that we share the view from from the inside, field all your questions and have a lively conversation.</p>

<p>This event won&#8217;t be streamed to the Internet. It will only be available live to this small group, as we share tea and chocolate.</p>

<p>In this 3-hour seminar you will:</p>

<ul>
<li>taste great tea and chocolate: learn how to be an expert taster</li>
<li>talk with me (Leo Babauta) and Jesse jacobs, founder of Samovar Tea Lounge (3 locations and ~100 employees)</li>
<li>learn to focus mindfully</li>
<li>learn to savor life more</li>
<li>find calm throughout the work day</li>
<li>learn how—and why—to single-task</li>
<li>learn how to deal with distraction</li>
<li>try some simple meditation techniques</li>
<li>create focused task lists</li>
<li>learn the key to effective fundraising</li>
<li>become good at change and discomfort</li>
<li>learn how to create the right habits</li>
<li>discuss the fundamentals of building an online and retail business</li>
<li>learn about how I created Samovar, and how Leo created Zen Habits</li>
<li>talk about our main sources of revenue</li>
<li>discuss some of the lessons we’ve learned in building our businesses</li>
<li>ask us your burning questions questions so you don’t make the mistakes we made</li>
</ul>

<p>We’re keeping this intentionally small with room for just 25 participants so that we can go broad and deep. People have been asking us for a program like this for years, so it&#8217;s likely to sell out fast. If you are starting a new venture, or contemplating it, this could be the boost you’ve been waiting for. Knock down obstacles, meet an amazing group of like-minded peers, and give the world the art you know you have inside.</p>

<p><strong>Find focus. Build a business. The world is waiting for you.</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://shop.samovarlife.com/product-p/12mien01.htm?mc_cid=9ccf452e0c&#038;mc_eid=[UNIQID]">Learn more→</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/family-changes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Stick to a Habit When Life Falls Apart</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/bumps/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/bumps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 17:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happiness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;If you’re going through hell, keep going.&#8217; ~Winston Churchill By Leo Babauta We&#8217;d like to think that making positive life changes is a straight line from beginning to where we want to go. But life has taught us differently. Experience shows us that you can start a new habit (let&#8217;s say working out) and things [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;If you’re going through hell, keep going.&#8217; <strong>~Winston Churchill</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>We&#8217;d like to think that making positive life changes is a straight line from beginning to where we want to go.</p>

<p>But life has taught us differently.</p>

<p>Experience shows us that you can start a new habit (let&#8217;s say working out) and things go great for awhile, and then life gets in the way. Things get messy. Things fall apart. We have a few bad days, or a huge project to work on at work, or relationship problems, or a family crisis, or we get sick.</p>

<p>What do we do when life gets messy and our habits fall to the wayside? Well, give up, obviously.</p>

<p>Actually, I take that back. We tend to give up, because when things get in the way and we mess up on our habits, it&#8217;s a little discouraging, even depressing.</p>

<p>But it doesn&#8217;t have to be. There are a few things you can do instead:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Breathe</strong>. Pause for a moment, breathe, focus on the breath. Know that you are OK, in this moment. Give yourself a moment&#8217;s space to think about what&#8217;s going on in your life, and who you are.</li>
<li><strong>Give yourself a break</strong>. If things like relationship problems get in the way of your habits, allow yourself to pause the habits until you get your life in order and let your mind rest. Rest is important. Get plenty of sleep &#8212; this is important, because when stressful things are happening in our lives, our bodies and minds need plenty of rest to heal.</li>
<li><strong>Know that every habit has bumps in the road</strong>. There&#8217;s never a perfectly smooth path with no bumps. Seriously, no habit goes on a perfectly straight line &#8212; at least, none that I&#8217;ve created, and none that anyone I know has created. Expect the bumps, and don&#8217;t let them end everything.</li>
<li><strong>Allow yourself to experience the messy.</strong> Things will always come up, life gets messy, painful things happen. That&#8217;s OK. Give yourself the space to experience the pain with the joy, the mess with the beauty.</li>
<li><strong>Find a friend to help you get on track</strong>. It&#8217;s great if you can do habits by yourself, but it&#8217;s even better if you can find a friend who will do it with you, or at least hold you accountable, and help you get things back on track once things clear up for you.</li>
<li><strong>Keep smiling!</strong>. That&#8217;s the most important thing. Smile, and you&#8217;re doing it right.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/bumps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zen Mind in the Middle of Chaos &amp; Stress</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/zm/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/zm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 15:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Happiness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta What do you do when your job, or your personal life, is a constant source of busy-ness, rushing, nose-to-the-grindstone work, and stress? Or what do you do if your life is simple and relatively stress-free, but something blows up and you are in the middle of chaos and high stress all of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>What do you do when your job, or your personal life, is a constant source of busy-ness, rushing, nose-to-the-grindstone work, and stress?</p>

<p>Or what do you do if your life is simple and relatively stress-free, but something blows up and you are in the middle of chaos and high stress all of a sudden?</p>

<p>This is when we could use a dose of Zen Mind, or the <strong>Art of Letting Go</strong>.</p>

<p>What is this Zen Mind? To be honest, I&#8217;m still learning what that is, but what I&#8217;ve been practising is a constant letting go. Let&#8217;s take an example:</p>

<p>I have a major deadline approaching. It is stressing me out, man! But what is the source of the stress? It&#8217;s not the work, which is just a series of actions. It&#8217;s not the deadline, which is just a time constraint. It&#8217;s my reaction to those external events &#8212; my fear that I&#8217;m not going to make it, that I&#8217;ll mess up, that I&#8217;ll look stupid or incompetent. This fear that is causing my stress reaction is rooted in my wanting things to turn out a certain way &#8230; wanting to meet the deadline and get things perfect and look good.</p>

<p>What if I could let go of wanting things to turn out that way? This is a fantasy, an ideal, that I&#8217;m holding onto. It might turn out that way, sure, but it could turn out a dozen other ways, and the truth is I don&#8217;t have complete control over how it&#8217;ll turn out. All I can do is do the work, and the fantasy, the fear and the stress are only getting in the way. So if I can let go of this ideal, this fantasy, I can let go of the fear, and the stress.</p>

<p>This is the Zen Mind that I&#8217;m learning about. It&#8217;s simply letting go, and in doing so, you attain a peace of mind no matter what chaos and seemingly stressful event are going on around you. Again, I&#8217;m not good at this yet, but I&#8217;m learning. I&#8217;ll share what I know with you.</p>

<h3>The Art of Letting Go</h3>

<p>So these are the steps to letting go:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Notice why you&#8217;re stressed</strong>. What external event is stressing you? Why is it stressing you out? What fear do you have?</li>
<li><strong>Notice what you&#8217;re holding onto</strong>. If your response is fear, it&#8217;s because you&#8217;re holding onto something. It&#8217;s probably a fantasy/ideal, or wanting to control something, wanting something to turn out a certain way, wishing things would meet the expectations you have. If you&#8217;re saying, &#8220;He should do this&#8221; or &#8220;It should be like this&#8221; then you&#8217;re holding onto an ideal/expectation/outcome.</li>
<li><strong>Realize that it&#8217;s not real</strong>. This fantasy, this expectation, this wishing you could control things &#8230; it&#8217;s just made up in your head. To be fair, we all do it. But it&#8217;s not a real thing &#8212; and it can be let go of.</li>
<li><strong>See that it&#8217;s hurting you</strong>. This thing you&#8217;ve made up is causing you stress, which is shortening your life, and making what short life you have less enjoyable. It&#8217;s causing pain in your life. Realize this.</li>
<li><strong>Let go</strong>. If something you&#8217;ve made up is causing pain, why hold onto it? It&#8217;s not worth it. By letting go, you release the pain, and are just left with you and the work you need to do.</li>
</ol>

<h3>Zen Mind in the Middle of Chaos</h3>

<p>So you work long hours and are stressed out. It&#8217;s work you love, perhaps, but still hard work, and still lots of stressors. Maybe you get to take some good breaks during the day, maybe you take weekends off, maybe you get some great vacations.</p>

<p>But the fact remains: no matter what kind of breaks and vacations you take, much of your life is spent doing the hard work, and stressed out. You need to be able to simultaneously work <em>and</em> be on vacation. This is the practice of Zen Mind that we&#8217;re talking about &#8212; letting go and being able to breathe and smile in the middle of a stressful workday.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s only stressful, of course, because of stuff we&#8217;re making up in our heads. So if we can create a constant practice of awareness and letting go, we constantly let go of the stress.</p>

<p>Your boss dumps a new project on you with a close deadline. Yikes! You&#8217;re instantly stressed. Notice, and let go. Breathe. Feel the stress floating away as you let go of an ideal and an expectation. You are now free, and you can just do the first task &#8212; after all, that&#8217;s all you can ever do.</p>

<p>Your coworker or client is mad at you, and yelling at you. This is highly stressful. Until you realize that they are probably yelling for some problem that&#8217;s not really about you &#8212; they are stressed out, they are having a bad day, they have problems dealing with stress. And you are holding onto the expectation that everyone around you should behave perfectly, which of course is an absurd fantasy. You let go of that, and reach out in your heart to this fellow human being who isn&#8217;t happy. How can you make things better for this person, with an open heart?</p>

<p>Your son is stressing you out because he&#8217;s not doing what he should be doing. You&#8217;re mad! Why can&#8217;t he just do what you ask? Of course, this is a fantasy. Your kids (or friends, or spouse) are not going to live up to these expectations you have of how they should behave &#8212; these expectations aren&#8217;t anything real, just fantasies. You can&#8217;t control their behavior &#8212; wanting to do so just stresses you out. So let go of that expectation and the desire to control, and the stress goes away. Instead, open your heart, and be open to who they are.</p>

<p>OK, so that&#8217;s all easier said than done. In the real world, it takes a lot of practice. We often forget about this process when things hit the fan. That&#8217;s OK. Life is a constant practice. Keep practicing, and let go of wanting to be perfect at it. Just in the attempt, you&#8217;re already perfect.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/zm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Create a Sacred Space in Your Heart</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/sacred/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/sacred/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Happiness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13306</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;Drink your tea slowly and reverently, as if it is the axis on which the world earth revolves &#8211; slowly, evenly, without rushing toward the future.&#8217; ~Thich Nhat Hanh By Leo Babauta Yesterday I had tea with a Daoist tea monk who said for tea to change you, you have to create a sacred space [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;Drink your tea slowly and reverently, as if it is the axis
  on which the world earth revolves &#8211; slowly, evenly, without
  rushing toward the future.&#8217;
  <strong>~Thich Nhat Hanh</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Yesterday I had tea with a <a href="http://www.lifeoftea.com/?page_id=2">Daoist tea monk</a> who said for tea to change you, you have to create a sacred space in your heart for the tea.</p>

<p>Imagine that space for a moment. How does it feel? What can reside in that sacred space? How different is it from mechanically drinking tea, without paying attention to it?</p>

<p>Now think about the difference between just drinking tea, as if you were drinking anything and not really paying attention &#8230; and drinking tea with that sacred space in your heart for that tea. It&#8217;s profoundly different, and it changes everything.</p>

<p>You can do that for anything, not just tea. Anything that&#8217;s important to you.</p>

<p>If you create a sacred space in your heart for something, it changes how you do it. It changes you, at the molecular level.</p>

<p>We crank through things these days &#8212; email, social networks, news, work tasks, calls, meetings, deadlines &#8212; and then the day is gone. This is a waste of a miracle, the day that we&#8217;ve been given.</p>

<p>Instead, create a sacred space for that which matters most:</p>

<ul>
<li>meditation, yoga, tea</li>
<li>reading at bedtime with your child</li>
<li>having tea with your spouse</li>
<li>a daily walk</li>
<li>writing</li>
<li>your most important and creative work</li>
</ul>

<p>Perhaps every moment should have a sacred space in our hearts, but we have to start somewhere. Pick something small but important, and create that space today.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Tea is drunk to forget the din of the world.&#8217; <strong>~T&#8217;ien Yiheng</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>Mindful + Entrepreneur: A Seminar with Leo</h3>

<p>In other news, I&#8217;m holding a 3-hour seminar here in San Francisco with my friend Jesse Jacobs (creator of the <a href="http://www.samovarlife.com/ubg/">Ultimate Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Tea</a>):</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://shop.samovarlife.com/product-p/12mien01.htm">Mindful + Entrepreneur Seminar</a>
</strong>
The seminar will be held at Samovar Tea Lounge at the Yerba Buena Gardens in San Francisco on March 21, 2013. Join us!</p>

<p>n this 3-hour seminar you will:</p>

<ul>
<li>taste great tea and chocolate: learn how to be an expert taster</li>
<li>talk with Jesse Jacobs, founder of Samovar Tea Lounge, and Leo Babauta, founder of the Zen Habits website</li>
<li>learn to focus mindfully</li>
<li>learn to savor life more</li>
<li>find calm throughout the work day</li>
<li>learn how&#8211;and why&#8211;to single-task</li>
<li>learn how to deal with distraction</li>
<li>try some simple meditation techniques</li>
<li>create focused task lists</li>
<li>become good at change and discomfort</li>
<li>learn how to create habits</li>
<li>discuss the fundamentals of building an online and retail business</li>
<li>learn about how Jesse created Samovar, and how I created Zen Habits</li>
<li>talk about our main sources of revenue</li>
<li>discuss some of the lessons we&#8217;ve learned in building their businesses</li>
<li>ask us your burning questions questions so you don’t make the mistakes they made</li>
</ul>

<p>The seminar will be broken into two sessions: mindfulness, and entrepreneurship. A selection of Samovar Tea Lounge’s handcrafted teas and chocolates will be provided.</p>

<p>This intimate and unique seminar is limited to 25 participants.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://shop.samovarlife.com/product-p/12mien01.htm">Mindful + Entrepreneur Seminar</a>
</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/sacred/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meditation: The Most Fundamental Habit</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/fundameditate/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/fundameditate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13261</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216; To meditate does not mean to fight with a problem. To meditate means to observe.&#8217; ~Thich Nhat Hanh By Leo Babauta It&#8217;s no secret that I advocate meditation as a great way to start your day, deal with stress, live in the present and more. But what many people don&#8217;t realize is that meditation [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216; To meditate does not mean to fight with a problem.<br />
  To meditate means to observe.&#8217;<br />
  <strong>~Thich Nhat Hanh</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>It&#8217;s no secret that I advocate meditation as a great way to start your day, deal with stress, live in the present and more.</p>

<p>But what many people don&#8217;t realize is that meditation is perhaps the most important habit if you want to change other habits.</p>

<p>Recently I wrote about the <a href="http://zenhabits.net/habitses/">Four Habits That Form Other Habits</a> &#8212; and you might recall Habit 2:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Be Mindful of Negative Thoughts</p>
</blockquote>

<p>How do you learn to be mindful of your negative thoughts? Simple: you practice. And how do you practice mindfulness of your thoughts? By far the best method I&#8217;ve found is meditation.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s look at why meditation is so good for helping to change your habits, and how to form the meditation habit.</p>

<h3>How Meditation Helps Habits</h3>

<p>When we are unaware of our thoughts and urges, which arise in the back of our mind mostly unnoticed, they have a power over us. We are unable to change if these unbidden thoughts control us. But when we learn to observe them, we can then release their power over us.</p>

<p>Meditation is practice for observing those thoughts, for being more mindful of them throughout the day.</p>

<p>I will give you several examples in my own life, though actually there are dozens:</p>

<ol>
<li>When I quit smoking, I would get an urge to take just one drag on a cigarette, and it would get so strong I had a hard time beating it. At the same time, I had these rationalizing thoughts: &#8220;It&#8217;s OK to smoke just one &#8212; one cigarette doesn&#8217;t hurt you&#8221;, or &#8220;Why are you making yourself suffer like this? It&#8217;s not worth it!&#8221; And those thoughts and urges would have beat me if I let them, but I watched them. I didn&#8217;t act, I just watched. And the would rise and crest and then fade, and I would be OK.</li>
<li>When I started running, I wanted to stop when things got uncomfortable. But I learned that it was just a scared part of my mind that wanted to stop, a part of me that shied away from discomfort. I would watch that scared part of me, that makes me quit anything hard, and not let it control me.</li>
<li>When I write, I often get the urge to go do something else. When this urge goes unnoticed, I just act on it, and procrastinate. When I am mindful of this urge (and the accompanying rationalizations that come if I don&#8217;t act on the urge), then I can <a href="http://zenhabits.net/pause/">pause</a> and watch the urge and let it go, and return to the writing.</li>
</ol>

<p>This same process helped me <a href="http://zenhabits.net/7y/">change my eating habits</a>, run a marathon, <a href="http://zenhabits.net/zero/">change my clutter habits</a>, and <a href="http://zenhabits.net/my-story">much more</a>.</p>

<p>But none of that would have been possible if I didn&#8217;t learn to watch, to be mindful of my urges and rationalizations and negative thoughts that told me I couldn&#8217;t do it.</p>

<p>How did I learn to watch and be mindful? Meditation. It is the one habit where all you&#8217;re doing is practicing this mindful observing, where everything else is stripped away in a beautiful simplicity that leaves just you and your thoughts and the present moment.</p>

<h3>How to Form the Meditation Habit</h3>

<p>It&#8217;s pretty simple, but the doing is everything:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Commit to just 2 minutes a day</strong>. Start simply if you want the habit to stick. You can do it for 5 minutes if you feel good about it, but all you’re committing to is 2 minutes each day.</li>
<li><strong>Pick a time and trigger</strong>. Not an exact time of day, but a general time, like morning when you wake up, or during your lunch hour. The trigger should be something you already do regularly, like drink your first cup of coffee, brush your teeth, have lunch, or arrive home from work.</li>
<li><strong>Find a quiet spot</strong>. Sometimes early morning is best, before others in your house might be awake and making lots of noise. Others might find a spot in a park or on the beach or some other soothing setting. It really doesn’t matter where — as long as you can sit without being bothered for a few minutes. A few people walking by your park bench is fine.</li>
<li><strong>Sit comfortably</strong>. Don’t fuss too much about how you sit, what you wear, what you sit on, etc. I personally like to sit on a pillow on the floor, with my back leaning against a wall, because I’m very inflexible. Others who can sit cross-legged comfortably might do that instead. Still others can sit on a chair or couch if sitting on the floor is uncomfortable. Zen practitioners often use a zafu, a round cushion filled with kapok or buckwheat. Don’t go out and buy one if you don’t already have one. Any cushion or pillow will do, and some people can sit on a bare floor comfortably.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on your breath</strong>. As you breathe in, follow your breath in through your nostrils, then into your throat, then into your lungs and belly. Sit straight, keep your eyes open but looking at the ground and with a soft focus. If you want to close your eyes, that’s fine. As you breathe out, follow your breath out back into the world. If it helps, count … one breath in, two breath out, three breath in, four breath out … when you get to 10, start over. If you lose track, start over. If you find your mind wandering (and you will), just pay attention to your mind wandering, then bring it gently back to your breath. Repeat this process for the few minutes you meditate. You won’t be very good at it at first, most likely, but you’ll get better with practice.</li>
</ol>

<p>And that’s it. It’s a very simple practice, but you want to do it for 2 minutes, every day, after the same trigger each day. Do this for a month and you’ll have a daily meditation habit.</p>

<h3>Meditation Habit in March</h3>

<p>If you&#8217;d like help creating this fundamental habit, I&#8217;ve created a Meditation module for the <a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/">Sea Change Program</a> in March.</p>

<p>In the module, you&#8217;ll get:</p>

<ul>
<li>A few articles about the meditation habit</li>
<li>Reminder emails every 2-3 days</li>
<li>A live webinar with me in the middle of the month about the habit</li>
<li>A forum and accountability teams to help you stick to the habit</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Bonus</strong>: On Monday (March 4, 2013), <a href="http://www.samovarlife.com/">Jesse Jacobs of Samovar Tea Lounge</a> will be doing a live webinar for Sea Change members on the meditation of tea. <a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/">Sign up to get details</a>.</p>

<p>Please note that this is a monthly membership program of $10/month, but you can quit anytime. You can also join anytime, not just at the beginning of the month, and start your habit whenever you want. <a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/">Sign up here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/fundameditate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating the Genuine Connections We Long For</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/connect/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/connect/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 15:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Happiness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13232</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta We all long for genuine human connections, and even in a busy life with lots of people around us, these genuine connections can be hard to find. We socialize online, but that&#8217;s not very genuine (why I quit Facebook). We work with people, but often that&#8217;s task-oriented and not human connection-oriented. We [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>We all long for genuine human connections, and even in a busy life with lots of people around us, these genuine connections can be hard to find.</p>

<p>We socialize online, but that&#8217;s not very genuine (why I <a href="http://zenhabits.net/fb/">quit Facebook</a>). We work with people, but often that&#8217;s task-oriented and not human connection-oriented. We might have family and friends in our lives, but when we are busy or distracted by the online world, those connections might fade.</p>

<p>In the last year or two, I&#8217;ve made it a point to have fewer friendships, but with deeper connections &#8230; while also being open to the miracle of a random encounter with another human being. This philosophy has paid off in more genuine connections with my family and friends, but less busy-ness.</p>

<p>Today I&#8217;ll share a few reasons for creating genuine connections, and my strategies for creating them.</p>

<h3>Why Genuine Connections Are Important</h3>

<p>There are many reasons, but these are the ones that strike me as important:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>We need it to be happy and fulfilled</strong>. All the money in the world, and the best job in the world, and all the material possessions in the world &#8230; won&#8217;t matter much if you&#8217;re alone and have no genuine human connections. We have a human need for this kind of connection, and there&#8217;s no doubt that it makes us happier, even if it complicates our lives a bit.</li>
<li><strong>It boosts creativity</strong>. I find that working in solitude is the <a href="http://zenhabits.net/creative-habit/">best way to create</a>, and <a href="http://zenhabits.net/solitude/">having some time for solitude</a> is important for reflecting on ideas &#8230; but having a genuine discussion with someone is really important for expanding on those ideas. When I get together with a friend, or talk something over with my wife, I inevitably walk away with several new (or reinvigorated) ideas that excite me.</li>
<li><strong>It creates opportunities</strong>. I am not in favor of &#8220;networking&#8221;, but when you make a connection with someone, new opportunities for collaboration and creation emerge that weren&#8217;t there before. For example, before I met Jesse Jacobs of <a href="http://www.samovarlife.com/">Samovar Tea Lounge</a>, I wasn&#8217;t a big tea guy. But after we became friends, I became interested in tea, and we sat down and recorded some lessons on tea (where I was the beginner student) and that turned into the excellent new <a href="http://www.samovarlife.com/ubg/">Ultimate Beginner&#8217;s Guide to Tea</a>. That wasn&#8217;t a realistic possibility before we connected. This has happened to me numerous times &#8212; I met <a href="http://liveyourlegend.net/">Scott Dinsmore</a> and later contributed to his new course, <a href="http://howtoconnectwithanyone.com/joinus/official-launch-2013/">Connect With Anyone</a> &#8230; I met Susan O&#8217;Connell of <a href="http://www.sfzc.org/">San Francisco Zen Center</a> and co-created the Zen of Work course with her &#8230; I met <a href="http://thinktraffic.net/">Corbett Barr</a> and contributed to his fantastic platform for people creating online businesses, <a href="http://fizzle.co/">Fizzle</a> &#8230; and so on and so on.</li>
</ol>

<p>Life is better when you make genuine connections. You are happier, less isolated, more creative, with new opportunities.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s look at how to make these important connections.</p>

<h3>How to Make Genuine Connections</h3>

<p>Here&#8217;s the thing &#8230; you can&#8217;t just force a connection to be what you want it to be. Many people make this mistake in different ways: they try to create a connection with someone who doesn&#8217;t want it, or hope the person responds in a certain way, or want the other person to be something they&#8217;re not, and so on. The key to an unforced, genuine connection is openness.</p>

<p>So here&#8217;s what works for me:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Be open to random connections</strong>. While I accept fewer invitations these days than I did a couple years ago, when I randomly meet someone, I try not to be closed to them. This means opening up, wondering who they are and setting aside any prejudgements that happen, sharing who I am openly and with a smile. I don&#8217;t know if this will be a connection to last a lifetime, but it can be one to brighten a moment.</li>
<li><strong>Make time for the important relationships</strong>. For me, this starts with my wife and kids. While work is important, it&#8217;s important to me to make time each day for them. Even just reading a book, or taking a walk, or sitting down and talking about something &#8212; if the relationship is important, I&#8217;ll make time most days for it. But it also extends to a small circle of friends who I might not see every day, or even every week &#8212; if I can, I&#8217;ll make time for them. We get together for tea or a workout usually.</li>
<li><strong>Be open to who they are</strong>. Try to notice your expectations of the other person, and let them go. Don&#8217;t pigeon-hole them, don&#8217;t try to make them someone they&#8217;re not &#8230; just explore who they are without knowing what you&#8217;ll find. Be curious. You&#8217;ll find the real them this way, and it&#8217;s much better than finding what you hoped to find.</li>
<li><strong>Be open to what happens</strong>. Many people go into a meeting with someone else with an agenda, and try to get that done. Like it&#8217;s a task that needs to be accomplished. But it&#8217;s not &#8212; a connection with someone else isn&#8217;t about productivity or goals. It&#8217;s about connection. It&#8217;s two very different human beings spending time together and merging their random personality traits into one experience. That&#8217;s true even if it&#8217;s a business meeting. Let your personality come out, and allow theirs to come out, and see what happens. It could be talking about a project, but it could be random topics and ideas, it could be a discussion of what&#8217;s been going on in your lives and what you have in common, it could be helping one or the other of you with a problem that you have, it could be a debate of ideas, and so on. Don&#8217;t try to force it.</li>
<li><strong>Be open about yourself</strong>. Often we try to present a certain good side of ourselves. We try to come across as competent, knowledgeable, interesting, accomplished, funny, smart, etc. But that&#8217;s  a front. It&#8217;s only a part of who we are &#8212; the good part. If it&#8217;s true at all. Why bother trying to connect with someone when we&#8217;re just going to give them a false identity, just a façade? Might as well stay home. Much better is to open yourself up, to show the real you. This is scary. It means <a href="http://liveyourlegend.net/create-trust-with-anyone/">being vulnerable</a>, and being willing to be embarrassed. That&#8217;s a huge amount of trust to put into a human being, especially if it&#8217;s not someone you know well. But it&#8217;s totally worth it. When you become vulnerable, you risk a lot, but you also get much, much more. You get trust from the other person. You get a deeper connection. You get a better friendship. They open up more too. And when you&#8217;ve done this a few times, you realize &#8212; there isn&#8217;t that much risk, because it never really ends up in a bad way. It&#8217;s pretty much all upside.</li>
</ol>

<p>There&#8217;s more to creating genuine connections, but you don&#8217;t want to read a book. If you do, I recommend you check out Scott Dinsmore&#8217;s new course, <a href="http://howtoconnectwithanyone.com/joinus/official-launch-2013/">Connect With Anyone</a>. This is not an affiliate link or ad, just a recommendation of a great resource that also happens to feature my story of how I overcame my introvertedness, and more.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/connect/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tremors of Psychitude: One Little Trick to Find Purpose and Motivation</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/help/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/help/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 17:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Goals & Motivation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta Today when I asked people what was bothering them, the two most common responses were related to: Finding meaning and purpose Finding motivation As it turns out, those two things can be solved with one little step. Here&#8217;s the step: help someone else. This sounds exceedingly simple, but it&#8217;s the shift in [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Today when I <a href="https://twitter.com/zen_habits/status/306090491265564672">asked people what was bothering them</a>, the two most common responses were related to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Finding meaning and purpose</li>
<li>Finding motivation</li>
</ul>

<p>As it turns out, those two things can be solved with one little step.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the step: <strong>help someone else</strong>.</p>

<p>This sounds exceedingly simple, but it&#8217;s the shift in focus that really makes a difference. Let&#8217;s say I was having trouble finding the motivation to write &#8230; to solve that, I might tweet something asking people what problems they&#8217;re having. Then I move from &#8220;how do I solve my problem (of not being motivated)&#8221; to &#8220;how can I help these people&#8221;?</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not bogged down by my own distractions or guilt or laziness anymore &#8230; I&#8217;m focused on doing something good for someone else. Now I&#8217;m excited! The words just pour out of me. This is a hypothetical scenario, of course.</p>

<h3>Finding Meaning and Purpose</h3>

<p>If you feel stuck in your life, or confused, because you don&#8217;t have a clear direction and have no way of finding that direction &#8230; shift your focus from yourself.</p>

<p>Instead of thinking, &#8220;What should I be doing?&#8221; or &#8220;What could I do to give my life purpose?&#8221; &#8230; try asking:</p>

<ul>
<li>What could I do to help people in need?</li>
<li>What pain are other people feeling that I could help with?</li>
<li>Who do I care most about, and what problems do they have?</li>
<li>Who are my current customers, and what can I do to help them more?</li>
<li>What problems are out there that strangers might have, that my particular skillset could solve?</li>
</ul>

<p>When you start asking these kinds of questions, your focus shifts from your confusion and problems, to the confusion and problems of others. And when you start solving them, you have purpose. It&#8217;s gratifying to help others. It fills you with a sense of meaning and appreciation.</p>

<p>It sounds too easy, but it works 100% of the time. I will give you your money back if it doesn&#8217;t.</p>

<h3>Getting Pumped with Psychitude</h3>

<p>We might move through the day as if in a fog of blueness, slogging through mud, in a slump, feeling no motivation to do anything useful. This is a problem I imagine people of yore didn&#8217;t deal with as much. I&#8217;m not sure what in our modern condition causes this lack of motivation, but when I figure it out, I will write a poem about it for you.</p>

<p>But the cure is simple and pure and lovely: help others.</p>

<p>Can&#8217;t get off your butt to do something useful to your career and life in general? OK. So forget about your life, your career, your little set of problems. That&#8217;s a self-focus that doesn&#8217;t do anything for you.</p>

<p>Instead, move your focus to others. What pain are other people feeling? Can you help in some small way? Can you ease their suffering just a little? Can you put a smile on someone&#8217;s face? Can you change someone&#8217;s life?</p>

<p>When you change someone&#8217;s life for the better, even just a little, you feel amazing.</p>

<p>This shift in focus &#8230; it rocks your world. It sends tremors of psychitude throughout your body and mindbrain. It&#8217;s quite nice.</p>

<h3>A Few Other Steps</h3>

<p>OK, I know I said just one step is needed, but a few other little things to consider:</p>

<ul>
<li>Simplify your day. Do less. Pick just one thing to focus on.</li>
<li>Clear distractions. Shut off the Internet. Turn off notifications.</li>
<li>Move in one small step. Don&#8217;t tackle the whole damn project. <a href="http://zenhabits.net/starting/">Just get started</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://zenhabits.net/rockabye/">Get more sleep</a>. Lack of sleep, too little water, too much stress, and too much caffeine are causing your headaches.</li>
</ul>

<p>Good. Do those few steps, and shift your focus to others, and your mind and entire being will be rocked with psychitude like never before.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/help/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Create the Habits of Being Lean, in 7 Years</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/7y/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/7y/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 21:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health & Fitness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13181</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta People want to lose weight really fast (myself included). We fantasize about having a flat stomach, a leaner body, in just weeks. Two weeks would be ideal. Search for &#8220;weight loss&#8221; in Amazon and you&#8217;ll find books that will show you how to &#8220;lose weight fast&#8221; or in a certain number of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>People want to lose weight really fast (myself included). We fantasize about having a flat stomach, a leaner body, in just weeks. Two weeks would be ideal.</p>

<p>Search for &#8220;weight loss&#8221; in Amazon and you&#8217;ll find books that will show you how to &#8220;lose weight fast&#8221; or in a certain number of weeks, like 8 weeks, 4 weeks, even 2 weeks.</p>

<p>Of course, that&#8217;s bunk.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s take a closer look at what it would take to lose weight in 4 weeks:</p>

<ul>
<li>About 2/3 of American adults are overweight or obese, and have more than 20 lbs. to lose. If you&#8217;re trying to lose 20 lbs. in 4 weeks, that&#8217;s 5 lbs. a week. But for most people, it&#8217;s much better to lose 1-2 lbs. per week than 3-5 lbs.</li>
<li>A big drop in weight (like 10 lbs. in the first two weeks) often happens if you drastically change your diet. Most of this is water weight &#8212; only a few of those 10 lbs. will be actual fat. This water weight is deceiving, because 1) it&#8217;s unsustainable, because after the first couple weeks you won&#8217;t lose much water weight and your rate of weight loss will drop to a more sustainable 1-2 lbs. per week, which will be disappointing if you hoped to keep losing weight that fast, and 2) the water weight comes back on really quickly if you change your diet back later.</li>
<li>What you&#8217;re really doing is going on a short-term drastic diet (and probably some intense exercise) but in your mind, you&#8217;re only doing it for 4 weeks, and you think you just need to get through this short-term suffering in order to achieve the weight loss. This is wrong. You&#8217;ll lose weight, then go back to your old habits, and then gain the weight back and more.</li>
</ul>

<p>So losing a lot of weight in 4 weeks is possible, but it&#8217;s more sustainable to lose it slowly, and to build long-term habits, and much of the weight you lose is water weight that will come right back on when you return to old habits.</p>

<p>And so, losing weight fast is a bad idea.</p>

<p>What&#8217;s a better way? Changing your actual eating and exercise habits, which is much harder than most people realize. Let&#8217;s take a look at me as a case study.</p>

<h3>Leo&#8217;s 7-Year Weight Loss Story</h3>

<p>Calling it my &#8220;weight loss story&#8221; is deceiving, because this story really isn&#8217;t about weight. It&#8217;s about changing old habits.</p>

<p>I started off about 60 lbs. heavier than I am now, and I had years of bad eating and exercise habits. I ate lots of meat, junk food, sweets, fast food, party food, and drank soda, beer, fatty coffee drinks and more. And I almost never did active stuff. But that&#8217;s just the start of my health habits, as it turns out.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what happened:</p>

<ol>
<li>I started by quitting smoking. This taught me a lot about habits, and got the ball rolling down the road to becoming healthier.</li>
<li>I started running to relieve stress. If you relieve stress by smoking, drinking, or eating unhealthy food, you&#8217;ll need to find a healthier stress coping habit. Running became that habit for me, though now I have others: meditation, socializing in a healthy way, drinking tea, and various thinking habits.</li>
<li>I could barely run, and so I started small and progressed gradually.</li>
<li>I learned that quitting smoking and running made me feel healthy and great, but eating junk food made me feel worse. So I started trying to eat healthier food, which meant learning to eat vegetables. I didn&#8217;t like it much at first, but I learned to like veggies, and now I love them. This taught me that by gradually introducing healthy foods, I could train my tastebuds and learn to like things I didn&#8217;t like at first. I&#8217;ve now done this with dozens of foods.</li>
<li>I became vegetarian. This cut out a ton of unhealthy fatty meats that I was eating, and I ate more vegetables instead. I missed the meats at first, but soon learned that I didn&#8217;t need them anymore. I started losing a good amount of weight at this point &#8212; maybe 30 lbs. in my first year.</li>
<li>I ran a marathon. This took a year of building up my mileage. I was still overweight at this point, but definitely lighter.</li>
<li>I started eating fewer sweets. This is a weak point for me, as I love sweets and still indulge now and then. It&#8217;s been a long road of learning why I eat sweets, and eating other things instead (fruits, especially berries, and a little dark chocolate are my favorites &#8212; also some raisins or dried cranberries).</li>
<li>I learned to eat healthier snacks. Fruits and nuts, veggies and hummus, salads.</li>
<li>I started to learn other ways to be active, like riding bikes, swimming, playing sports, lifting weights. One at a time.</li>
<li>I learned that doing activities with others, like my wife, kids, sister, friends, was more fun and motivating. I learned about using challenges to keep myself motivated and to make active-ness more fun.</li>
<li>I developed social coping skills so I could be a vegetarian in the midst of meat eaters and unhealthy friends/relatives.</li>
<li>I learned to watch myself eating when I was eating socially. This is still something I&#8217;m working on, as it&#8217;s not a habit you face every day.</li>
<li>I learned to eat healthier at restaurants.</li>
<li>In the 2nd year of fitness, I did a couple of short triathlons (I was just a beginner really). In my 3rd year I did a couple more marathons.</li>
<li>I became vegan, gradually. I&#8217;ve only been 100% vegan for about 5 months now, but was 95% vegan for a couple years.</li>
<li>I learned to eat fewer processed grains, fewer convenience foods, less sugar.</li>
<li>Last year I finally dropped sugar from my coffee.</li>
<li>I started building a little muscle, slowly, in the last few years, through weights.</li>
<li>I backtracked a bunch of times, overeating during travel or social occasions, gaining fat. Then I&#8217;d set a little challenge for myself and lose fat again.</li>
</ol>

<p>This is just the broad strokes overview, actually. Learning what habits I&#8217;d developed over the years was the big part, and then slowly changing them one by one, has been the main process. Again, I&#8217;ve backtracked a number of times, but watching myself do that has been a learning process, and learning to get back on track with healthy habits even after I slipped up has been a great skill to learn.</p>

<p>It hasn&#8217;t been a linear progression. I&#8217;ve gone up and down, learned a lot along the way, and am still changing my habits. Today I am happy with my body, and fairly lean for my age. I don&#8217;t look like an underwear model, but I don&#8217;t feel like I need to, and am really happy with my healthy habits. This is where I should be, and if I keep an eye on my habits, I&#8217;m likely to stay this way for years.</p>

<h3>So You Want to Form Lean Habits</h3>

<p>Give up the idea of quick weight loss, and focus on building sustainable habits. Yes, it will take longer, but it will also last longer. Yes, it will take some work, but it&#8217;s fun, and you learn a lot about yourself in the process.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what I recommend:</p>

<ul>
<li>Start with a really easy habit. Just a small step, like drinking more water or eating a fruit a day or going for a short walk (or walk/run if that&#8217;s too easy) or doing a few pushups. You&#8217;ll learn about forming habits as you do so.</li>
<li>Stick with easy habits for awhile, and if you&#8217;re successful at them, then you can gradually progress. You&#8217;ll be amazed at how much you can progress &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t exercise for 10 minutes when I started, but in 2011 I completed the GoRuck Challenge, which was 13 hours of hard exercise.</li>
<li>Watch yourself as you eat. Why are you eating? What need are you fulfilling? Can you find a healthier replacement habit?</li>
<li>Change your tastebuds. Most people think things like, &#8220;I can&#8217;t give up meat&#8221; or &#8220;I hate vegetables&#8221; or &#8220;I could never give up ____&#8221; (cheese, sweets, chocolate, pizza, etc.). I&#8217;m not asking you to give it up, but if you really want to learn the habits of being lean, change your tastebuds to healthier things. Eat a vegetable every day &#8212; before long, you&#8217;ll like it. Try brown rice instead of white, or whole grains instead of white flour, or fruits instead of sweets, or tempeh instead of meat, or quinoa or kale or dark chocolate or chard. They&#8217;re all delicious, if you give them a chance.</li>
<li>Make activity a social thing. Do something fun with other people. Join a running club. Walk with your spouse. Get your coworkers to join a challenge. Be accountable to each other.</li>
<li>Sign up for a race or other fitness challenge.</li>
<li>Learn to socialize without eating unhealthy things.</li>
<li>Learn healthy strategies for when you go to a social gathering or restaurant or travel.</li>
<li>When you fail, forgive yourself, and learn. Get better. Keep doing it.</li>
<li>Be proud of little progress. Enjoy the journey. I mean every single step &#8212; don&#8217;t keep your eye on the end goal, but on where you are, and how amazing it is.</li>
</ul>

<p>That should get you started. If you do those things for a few years, you&#8217;ll know what else you need to do by then.</p>

<p>Good luck, my friends. This journey might be longer than a sprint, but that&#8217;s what makes it worthwhile. If you set yourself down this path, you are one of the courageous, the joyous, the lucky.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/7y/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 1.042 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-26 05:51:05 -->
