<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>zenhabits</title>
	<atom:link href="http://zenhabits.net/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://zenhabits.net</link>
	<description>breathe</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 15:33:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>A Guide to Practical Contentment</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/contentment/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/contentment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 15:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13587</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta A lot of people search for ways to find happiness, but I&#8217;ve found the idea of contentment to be more important than happiness. Why contentment over happiness? A couple of important reasons: Happiness can go up or down each day (or moment), but contentment is something more stable. We tend to seek [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>A lot of people search for ways to find happiness, but I&#8217;ve found the idea of contentment to be more important than happiness.</p>

<p>Why contentment over happiness? A couple of important reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li>Happiness can go up or down each day (or moment), but contentment is something more stable.</li>
<li>We tend to seek to increase happiness by adding things (food, excitement, a warm bath, time with a loved one) but contentment is a skill that allows you to subtract things and still be content.</li>
<li>Contentment can actually be a good place to start as you make changes (changes and contentment might seem paradoxical to some, but hear me out).</li>
</ol>

<p>What is contentment? For me, it&#8217;s really about being happy with who you are. Which I wasn&#8217;t for many years, and I think most people are not.</p>

<p>In my life, I&#8217;ve learned to be better at the skill of contentment (not that I&#8217;m perfect, but I&#8217;ve learned). I am happy with my life. I am happy with myself. I&#8217;m happy with where I am professionally, and don&#8217;t seek to add more readers or pageviews or income. I&#8217;m happy wherever I am.</p>

<p>And while many might say, &#8220;Sure, you can say that now that you&#8217;ve reached a certain level of success,&#8221; I think that&#8217;s wrong. Many people who achieve success don&#8217;t find contentment, and are always driven to want more, and are unhappy with themselves. Many people who are poor or don&#8217;t have a &#8220;successful&#8221; career have also found contentment. And what&#8217;s more, I think finding contentment has actually driven any success that I&#8217;ve found &#8212; it helped me get out of debt, it helped me change my habits, it has made me a better husband, father, friend and collaborator, perhaps even a better writer.</p>

<p>Worst of all, with the attitude of &#8220;you can be content because you&#8217;re successful&#8221;, is that people who say this are dismissing the path of contentment &#8230; when it&#8217;s something they can do right now. Not later, when they reach certain goals or a certain level of financial success. Now.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at the path of contentment, how it&#8217;s a good place for habit change, and how to get started down the path.</p>

<h3>The Path of Contentment</h3>

<p>We start out in life thinking that we&#8217;re awesome. We can dance in public as 5-year-olds, and not care what others think of us. By the time we&#8217;re adults, that&#8217;s been driven out of us, by peers and parents and the media and embarrassing situations.</p>

<p>As adults, we doubt ourselves. We judge ourselves badly. We are critical of our bodies, of ourselves as people, of our lack of discipline, of all our faults. We don&#8217;t like our lives.</p>

<p>As a result, we try to improve this lacking self, try to get better because we suck so much. Or, we doubt our ability to get better, and are very unhappy. Or we sabotage our attempts at change, because we don&#8217;t really believe we can do it.</p>

<p>This self-dislike results in worse relationships, a stagnant career, unhappiness with life, complaints about everything, and often unhealthy habits like eating junk food, drinking too much alcohol, not exercising, shopping too much, being addicted to video games or the Internet.</p>

<p>So what&#8217;s the path to being content with yourself and your life?</p>

<p>The first problem is if you don&#8217;t trust yourself. That&#8217;s an important area to work with.</p>

<p><b>Your relationship with yourself is like your relationship with anyone else. If you have a friend who is constantly late and breaking his word, not showing up when he says he will, eventually you&#8217;ll stop trusting that friend.</b> It&#8217;s like that with yourself, too. It&#8217;s hard to like someone you don&#8217;t trust, and it&#8217;s hard to like yourself if you don&#8217;t trust yourself.</p>

<p>So work on this trust with yourself (I give some practical steps in the bottom section below). Increase it slowly, and eventually you&#8217;ll trust yourself to be awesome.</p>

<p>The second problem is that you judge yourself badly. You compare yourself to an unreal ideal, in all areas. You want a beautiful model&#8217;s body. You want to achieve certain goals, personally and professionally. You want to travel the world and learn languages and learn a musical instrument and be an amazing chef and have an amazing social life and the perfect spouse and kids and incredible achievements and be the fittest person on the planet. Of course, those are <em>completely</em> realistic ideals, right?</p>

<p>And when we have these ideals, we compare ourselves to them, and we always measure up badly.</p>

<p>The path to contentment, then, is to stop comparing ourselves to these ideals. Stop judging ourselves. Let go of the ideals. And gradually learn to trust ourselves.</p>

<p>Read on for the practical steps.</p>

<h3>Changing Habits and Contentment</h3>

<p>Before we get to the practical steps, let&#8217;s talk about contentment and change. Many people think that if you&#8217;re content, you&#8217;re just going to lay on a beach doing nothing all day. Why do anything if you&#8217;re content with the way things are?</p>

<p>But actually contentment is a way better place to start making changes than unhappiness with who you are.</p>

<p>Most of us are driven by the need or desire to improve ourselves, to fix certain things about ourselves that we don&#8217;t like. While that can definitely be a place for driving some changes, it&#8217;s not a good place to start from with those kinds of changes.</p>

<p>If you feel there&#8217;s something wrong with you that needs to be improved, you&#8217;re going to be driven to improve yourself, but you may or may not succeed. Let&#8217;s say you fail in your habit change. Then you start to feel worse about yourself, and you&#8217;re then on a downward spiral where every time you try to improve, you fail, and so you feel worse about yourself, and then you&#8217;re on the downward spiral. You start to self-sabotage your changes, because you really don&#8217;t believe that you can do them. Based on past evidence, you don&#8217;t trust yourself that you can do it. And that makes you feel worse.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s if you fail. But let&#8217;s say you happen to succeed, and you&#8217;re really good at succeeding. So you succeed &#8212; maybe you lose weight, and so maybe you don&#8217;t feel as bad about your body now.</p>

<p><strong>But what happens is, if you start in this place of fixing what&#8217;s wrong with you, you keep looking for what else is wrong with you, what else you need to improve.</strong> So maybe now feel like you don&#8217;t have enough muscles, or six pack abs, or you think your calves don&#8217;t look good, or if it&#8217;s not about your body, you&#8217;ll find something else.</p>

<p>So it&#8217;s this never-ending cycle for your entire life. You never reach it. If you start with a place of wanting to improve yourself and feeling stuck, even if you&#8217;re constantly successful and improving, you&#8217;re always looking for happiness from external sources. You don&#8217;t find the happiness from within, so you look to other things.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re externally looking for happiness, it&#8217;s easy to get too into food, or shopping, or partying, or overwork, to try to be happy.</p>

<p>If instead, you can find contentment within and not need external sources of happiness, then you&#8217;ll have a reliable source of happiness. I find that to be a much better place to be than relying on external sources of happiness.</p>

<p>A lot of people wonder, &#8220;If you find contentment, won&#8217;t you just lay around on the beach, not improving the world, not doing anything?&#8221; But I think that&#8217;s a misunderstanding of what contentment is.</p>

<p>You can be content and lay around, but you can also be content and want to help others. You can be content and also compassionate to others, and want to help them. You can be happy with who you are, but at the same time want to help other people and ease their suffering. And that way, you can offer yourself to the world and do great works in the world, but not necessarily need that to be happy.</p>

<p>Even if for some reason, your work was taken away from you, you&#8217;d still have that inner contentment.</p>

<h3>Practical Steps Contentment</h3>

<p>The question is how to get there. How to go from being unhappy with yourself to being content?</p>

<p>The path is learning a few crucial skills:</p>

<p>1. <strong>Build self-trust</strong>. The only way to fix a lack of trust is in small steps. If you the unreliable friend wants to rebuild trust with you, the right way is not for him to say, &#8220;Now, trust me with your life&#8221; &#8212; instead, it&#8217;s to start building trust in small steps. Do little things, and see if the trust is held up. Over time, you open yourself up more and more.</p>

<p>What I usually do to build trust is to start with small things that I&#8217;m totally certain I can do &#8212; drinking a glass of water every day is an easy example. I want to drink more water, so I set a bunch of reminders to drink a glass of water when I want to wake up. If you can keep that up for a week or two, it helps you trust yourself. Most people try to change hard stuff, fail, and then the trust is gone. So start with the small stuff.</p>

<p>2. <strong>Notice your ideals</strong>. The other problem for finding contentment is that we&#8217;re constantly feeling bad about ourselves, because the reality of ourselves does not meet some ideal we hold. That ideal could come from mass media, looking at magazines and movie stars. Or it could just come from some idea about how perfect we should be. When it comes to productivity or how our bodies should look.</p>

<p><strong>The truth is, the reality of ourselves is not bad, it&#8217;s only in bad in relation to the ideal that we have about ourselves. When we let go of the ideal, we&#8217;re left with the reality that can be judged as perfectly great.</strong> It&#8217;s a unique human being who is beautiful in its own way.</p>

<p>So ask if you&#8217;re feeling bad about who you are and how you did. If so, it&#8217;s because of the ideal. To recognize that takes awareness first. Notice your ideals.</p>

<p>3. <strong>Let go of the ideals</strong>. Once we notice the ideals, we need to stop comparing ourselves to them. Let go of the ideal. The only way to let go of the ideal is to see the pain that it&#8217;s causing in yourself and realize you want to end that pain, and letting go of an ideal that&#8217;s hurting you is self-compassion. Watch the pain. Be compassionate with yourself and stop causing pain in yourself with this process of comparing yourself with ideals.</p>

<p><strong>Note that this article is based on an interview I did with <a href="http://sebastianmarshall.com/">Sebastian Marshall</a> for his charity, <a href="http://givegetwin.com/">GiveGetWin</a>,  where I&#8217;m <a href="http://givegetwin.com/products/practical-action-oriented-contentment-with-leo-babauta">offering a class for up to 10 people</a>&nbsp;to learn about some practicalities of contentment, action-oriented compassion, trusting yourself, and meditation.</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/contentment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Practice of Work Mind &amp; Vacation Mind, Simultaneously</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/zenwork/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/zenwork/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 19:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Productivity & Organization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13581</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta Imagine being on vacation: you can laze around, sipping on margaritas, not worrying about what you have to do today, not worrying about the time, just being without all the anxiety. Now imagine being busy at work: you are doing one task while worrying about others, worrying that you&#8217;re not doing the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Imagine being on vacation: you can laze around, sipping on margaritas, not worrying about what you have to do today, not worrying about the time, just being without all the anxiety.</p>

<p>Now imagine being busy at work: you are doing one task while worrying about others, worrying that you&#8217;re not doing the right task, thinking about all the other things on your schedule and task list, interrupted by others, filled with anxiety.</p>

<p>Vacation mind, work mind.</p>

<p>They are two different things, and yet, what if we could have the vacation mind while working? We&#8217;d have to toss out the lazing around and the margaritas, but the mindset could be the same. The result would be a saner way of living, where we aren&#8217;t &#8220;working for the weekend&#8221; or looking forward to the little vacation time we have, but instead are happier throughout the week.</p>

<p>How can this be done? It&#8217;s a few small mindset habits, which can be practiced and learned over time.</p>

<h3>What Vacation Mind is Like at Work</h3>

<p>Work mind is often full of anxiety: anxiety for what we need to do, for deadlines, for irritating or angry co-workers/bosses, for all the information coming in, for whether we&#8217;re doing the right thing right now, for whether we&#8217;re missing out on something important.</p>

<p>Vacation mind lets that anxiety go, and is just present in the current moment. Time is less important, enjoying yourself is the priority.</p>

<p>So what does it look like when you apply vacation mind to work? You let go of the anxiety. You aren&#8217;t worried about getting it all done, or doing the right thing right now, or all the things you have to do later. You are immersed in enjoying whatever you&#8217;ve chosen to do right now.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s say you decide to write something right now &#8212; you have a long list of things to do, but you decide this is the thing you want to work on at the moment. Could there be other things you should be doing instead? Of course &#8212; there always are. There&#8217;s no way to know the perfect thing to do &#8212; so just pick something, and do it.</p>

<p>You have other things to do, but instead of worrying about those things, you immerse yourself in the current task. You aren&#8217;t worried about getting it done quickly, but more focused on enjoying yourself as you do it.</p>

<p>Now and then you mentally step back, take a look at the bigger picture, and then return back to immersion in the task.</p>

<p>And you can do this when you talk with a co-worker or client. You can do this with an important email, or processing paperwork/small tasks, designing something, programming, creating art, helping a patient or student.</p>

<p>Pick something to do, immerse yourself, let go of worrying about other things, and just do. Enjoy yourself. Once in awhile, come up for air and look at the big picture.</p>

<h3>The Vacation Mind Practices</h3>

<p>You might have noticed the key elements in the description above &#8212; they&#8217;re the practices to be developed if you want to have vacation mind at work.</p>

<p>Note that you can&#8217;t just flip a switch and be good at these things today &#8230; they take practice, like any other skill. I can say that they&#8217;re worth practicing, even if you never master them, because they can transform your relationship with work.</p>

<p>Here are the practices &#8212; I recommend practicing a little each day:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Pick something, immerse yourself</strong>. On vacation, you might decide to go for a swim. So you do, and fully enjoy the feeling of the cool water on your skin, the exertion of the swim, the taste of the water in your mouth. You can do this at work too: pick something to do, forget about whether it&#8217;s the right thing to do at the moment (there&#8217;s no such thing), and just do it. Be fully in it. Enjoy the experience of doing it. Notice the feeling, the exertion, the taste.</li>
<li><strong>Let go of anxieties</strong>. This takes practice. It&#8217;s noticing when anxiety comes up, then noticing the source of the anxiety, which is some kind of outcome you hope will happen (looking good in front of others, being perfectly productive, not messing up, controlling a situation, etc.). Realize that this outcome is only a fantasy, and that other outcomes are OK too. Realize that holding on to this fantasy outcome is hurting you (causing anxiety). Be compassionate with yourself and let go of the unnecessary fantasy that&#8217;s hurting you.</li>
<li><strong>Step back and see the big picture</strong>. Immersing yourself is great, but it&#8217;s also useful to be able to un-immerse yourself, and take an assessment of what&#8217;s going on around you. This might mean what&#8217;s going on physically around you &#8212; people who are nearby, how you&#8217;re sitting (and whether you&#8217;re sitting too long), etc. But it could mean taking a look at your work situation, as it is right now (something that&#8217;s always changing) &#8212; is there an appointment you should get to, another task you should jump into instead, someone who needs your attention, some anxiety that&#8217;s come up? See the big picture, then go back into immersion.</li>
<li><strong>Be less worried about time</strong>. There are times when time matters &#8212; showing up on time for an appointment to be considerate of the other person/people you&#8217;re meeting, meeting a deadline, having to bill for the time you spend. But a lot of the time we worry about time for no real good reason. It&#8217;s not healthy. Immerse yourself in the task, step back to see the big picture, and immerse yourself again (in the same task or another). The time of day isn&#8217;t relevant to this process.</li>
</ol>

<p>Is it possible to be on permanent vacation, so that you&#8217;re doing your work but also in the relaxed, enjoyable mindset that&#8217;s brought on by margaritas on the beach? I think so, but there&#8217;s only one way to find out. Practice.</p>

<h3>The Zen of Work Course</h3>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in a little Zen mind in your work life, I&#8217;ve teamed up with San Francisco Zen Center to create the 2nd incarnation of the <a href="http://zenofwork.com/">Zen of Work online course</a>.</p>

<p>The course is taught by me and Zen priest Robert Thomas, with a number of other Zen teachers contributing lessons.</p>

<p>It will run for four weeks, starting May 5, 2013.</p>

<p><a href="http://zenofwork.com/">Learn more and register for the course now</a>!</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/zenwork/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Eat Real Food Without Spending Hours in the Kitchen</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/fastreal/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/fastreal/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health & Fitness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13420</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Editor&#8217;s Note: This is a guest post from Jules Clancy of Stonesoup. Are you eating real, whole food as much as you&#8217;d like? If you&#8217;ve been following Zen Habits for any length of time, you&#8217;ve probably been inspired by Leo&#8217;s story. My favorite part is how he went from being an overweight junk food eater [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6><strong>Editor&#8217;s Note</strong>: This is a guest post from Jules Clancy of <a href="http://thestonesoup.com/">Stonesoup</a>.</h6>

<p>Are you eating real, whole food as much as you&#8217;d like?</p>

<p>If you&#8217;ve been following Zen Habits for any length of time, you&#8217;ve probably been inspired by Leo&#8217;s story. My favorite part is how he went from being an overweight junk food eater to a lean, plant-food-loving machine.</p>

<p>Like Leo, I&#8217;m a big believer that for optimum health it&#8217;s best to eat real, whole food as much as possible. Preferably prepared at home.</p>

<p>The good news is, it doesn&#8217;t need to take as much time as you&#8217;d think.</p>

<p>When I was writing my book &#8217;5 Ingredients 10 Minutes&#8217;, one of the things that kept surprising me was how I could make healthy, home cooked meals in not very much time.</p>

<p>So today I wanted to share with you 7 tips for eating real food without spending hours in the kitchen.</p>

<h3>1. Start small.</h3>

<p>When I was learning to meditate as part of Leo&#8217;s <a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/" target="_blank">Sea Change program</a>, one of the biggest lessons for me was to set small, achievable goals.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s all about making it as easy as possible for yourself to take the first step.</p>

<p>The same applies to cooking for yourself. Its so much easier to start with one night a week and build from there.</p>

<p>Making it achievable also means you&#8217;re less likely to end up with a fridge full of vegetables that make you feel guilty when they go bad and you throw them out.</p>

<h3>2. Learn some quick and easy recipes.</h3>

<p>Having a little collection of easy recipes that focus on speedy cooking techniques is half the battle. Especially when you&#8217;re just getting into cooking real food.</p>

<p>If a recipe has an ingredients list as long as your arm, or has instructions like &#8216;simmer for 30 minutes&#8217; it&#8217;s best to save them for weekend cooking when you have loads of time.</p>

<p>Look for simple stir frys, hearty salads or one pot meals. If you&#8217;re stuck for inspiration there&#8217;s a collection of &#8216;<a href="http://thestonesoup.com/blog/2011/06/50-healthy-10-minute-meals/" target="_blank">50 healthy 10 minute meals</a>&#8216; over on my blog to get you started.</p>

<h3>3. Experiment with different ingredients.</h3>

<p>Avoid getting stuck in a food rut by swapping different ingredients into your favourite speedy meals.</p>

<p>For example, if you normally make a stir fry with tofu and kale, try it instead with bok choy or broccoli. Same goes for flavourings. If you normally use garlic, try ginger or a new spice.</p>

<h3>4. Skip the peeling.</h3>

<p>I&#8217;ve never been a big fan of peeling vegetables. It takes ages and you lose the nutrients close to the skin. These days I just rinse or scrub and move on to the next step.</p>

<p>You won&#8217;t notice the difference for veg with thin skins like carrots or sweet potatoes. For things like butternut squash or beets, I roast with the skins on. It&#8217;s easy to slip the cooked skins off but often I leave them on because they&#8217;re delicious.</p>

<h3>5. Try it raw.</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m far from being a raw food purist, but I do try to include some raw vegetables in my diet every day. Not only is this beneficial for getting extra enzymes and heat-sensitive vitamins, it&#8217;s also much quicker than cooking.</p>

<p>For example, it takes a fraction of the time to finely slice a bunch of broccoli and toss it in a dressing than it takes to steam it. (see recipe below)</p>

<p>Think about finely slicing or grating veg and serving them raw. Some of my favorites are shaved raw broccoli or grated raw cauliflower to serve in place of steamed rice with curries or stir frys. I also love shaved fennel or cabbage in salads and finely sliced kale or raw bok choy &#8211; which has a surprisingly moreish crunchy texture.</p>

<h3>6. Use convenient ingredients.</h3>

<p>The &#8216;real food police&#8217; aren&#8217;t going to arrest you because you haven&#8217;t prepared everything yourself from scratch. So don&#8217;t be afraid to cheat and use pre-prepared veg when it makes sense for you.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m a big fan of things like pre-washed salad leaves and scrubbed potatoes. I usually don&#8217;t like paying extra for pre-chopped veg, but if it works for you, go for it. I do use grilled veg from the deli from time to time.</p>

<p>Also try convenient ingredients as a flavor highlight or sauce. Think about commercial hummus, pesto, salsa, soy sauce, curry pastes or olive tapenade.</p>

<h3>7. Don&#8217;t forget about frozen veg.</h3>

<p>I once asked a nutritionist friend her thoughts about frozen veg. She said that freezing is probably the best method for preserving veg without losing much of the nutrition. In fact, frozen veg picked at its best will often have more nutrients than old &#8216;fresh&#8217; vegetables that are past their prime.</p>

<p>Frozen veg are especially beneficial if your schedule is variable because they will sit in the freezer waiting for you to be ready for them. They also save you loads of prep time. Compare sitting down to shell a giant bowl of peas with the time it takes to open the packet and pour them into a pot.</p>

<p>Frozen peas are a pantry essential in our house but also consider things like frozen spinach, collard greens, broad beans, broccoli, cauliflower, or even frozen veg ready to stir fry in your wok.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7061/6883602859_c5018f89ec_z.jpg" width="640" height="448" alt="broccoli &amp; feta salad"></a></p>

<h3>Raw Broccoli &#038; Feta Salad</h3>

<p><em>Raw broccoli salads are very popular in my house. At least once a week or so, some sort of raw broccoli dish turns up for lunch.  If you do prefer your broccoli cooked, however, this salad is just as delicious with steamed broccoli.</em></p>

<blockquote>enough for 2:
1 tablespoon seeded mustard
1 tablespoon rice wine vinegar
1 head broccoli
100g (3.5oz) feta
handful pine nuts</blockquote>

<ol>
<li><p>Combine mustard, vinegar and 2 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil in a medium bowl. Taste. Season.</p></li>
<li><p>Finely slice the broccoli stems and chop the florettes into tiny bite sized trees. Toss in the dressing.</p></li>
<li><p>Crumble feta and sprinkle over the salad with the pine nuts.</p></li>
</ol>

<p><strong>VARIATIONS</strong>
<strong>vegan / dairy-free</strong>  &#8211; replace the feta with an avocado, flesh scooped into chunks.</p>

<p><strong>nut-free</strong> &#8211; replace the pine nuts with sesame seeds or finely diced red capsicum (bell pepper) or red onion.</p>

<p><strong>herby</strong> &#8211; serve sprinkled with fresh herbs such as coriander (cilantro), parsley, mint or basil.</p>

<p><strong>more substantial</strong> &#8211; increase the amount of feta and/or toss in a drained can of chickpeas or white beans.</p>

<p><strong>Jules Clancy blogs about meals in minutes over at <a href="http://www.thestonesoup.com" target="_blank">www.thestonesoup.com</a>. Her new book <a href="http://5ingredients10minutes.com/" target="_blank">&#8217;5 Ingredients 10 Minutes&#8217;</a> is now available. </strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/fastreal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quitting Your Habits</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/quitting/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/quitting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13424</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Editor&#8217;s Note: This is a guest post from Tynan of Tynan.com. Posts about habits are both my favorite posts to write, and my favorite posts to read on sites like Zen Habits. I believe managing your habits is the practical equivalent of molding who you are and who you will become. Today, though, I&#8217;m going [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6><strong>Editor&#8217;s Note</strong>: This is a guest post from Tynan of <a href="http://tynan.com">Tynan.com</a>.</h6>

<p>Posts about habits are both my favorite posts to write, and my favorite posts to read on sites like Zen Habits. I believe managing your habits is the practical equivalent of molding who you are and who you will become. Today, though, I&#8217;m going to write about the destruction of habits.</p>

<p>Throughout my life I&#8217;ve implemented thousands of habits. Some are simple habits that could very well last my entire life, like meditating for five minutes before I check my email in the morning. Others, like my three month experiment with polyphasic sleep, are all-consuming. In between are habits like eating healthy, going to the gym, and writing daily. These habits often produce outsize rewards for the effort they require, but they do require a significant amount of effort. If I continued every one of my habits indefinitely, I would need five hundred hours each day to fit them all in.</p>

<p>So how do we decide when to give up a habit to make room for a new one, to accommodate growing responsibilities, or to just free up some time and focus?</p>

<p>I have a hard-and-fast answer that I use myself, which you may also find useful: I only quit habits when I don&#8217;t want to quit them anymore.</p>

<p>Liking a habit is the surest sign that you&#8217;ve spent enough time on the habit to get properly adjusted to it and to start reaping the benefits of it. Without hitting those two waypoints, it&#8217;s impossible to objectively assess whether a habit should be removed or not.</p>

<p>Three months ago I began working out. The first workout was fun, because I got that feel-good rush that rewards me for doing something good for myself. That high had worn off by third gym session. On the way home I was mentally drafting an email to my trainer, giving him several solid reasons I should quit.</p>

<p>All of my reasons were legitimate downsides of working out. It took a lot of time out of my day, caused me to sleep more, and made meal preparation a hassle. I have a lot of stuff going on, and those are serious concerns. The reason they&#8217;re invalid is because they&#8217;re not being properly weighed against the benefits. I was adjusting to a new routine, which is always difficult, and hadn&#8217;t gained any muscle yet.</p>

<p>Today these drawbacks still exist. I&#8217;ve gotten faster at meal preparation and have somewhat adjusted my sleep schedule, but the impact on my time is still significant. The reason I&#8217;m not mentally (or physically) drafting emails to explain why I&#8217;m quitting is because I now have the benefits to counteract the costs of working out. I&#8217;ve gained fifteen pounds, most of it muscle, have improved all of my lifts by significant amounts, and have strengthened my willpower.</p>

<p>I wouldn&#8217;t say that I like working out now, but I like the overall impact it has on my life. I genuinely want to keep doing it. If something should come up that requires me to sacrifice some of my time-consuming habits, I won&#8217;t mind putting exercise up for consideration, because I can be objective about the pros and cons. If I did quit for some reason, I&#8217;d also be leaving on a high note, making it easier to decide to get back into it later.</p>

<p>The opposite, quitting when you want to, is a terrible strategy. You end up putting in work, getting no results, quitting, and then moving on to the next thing. Your lasting impression of each habit is an unfair one which prejudices you against every trying it again. So stick with things when you don&#8217;t want to stick with them, and only consider quitting when you don&#8217;t want to quit. It may not sound like it, but you&#8217;ll be happier that way.</p>

<p><strong>Read more from Tynan about changing your life, minimalism and more at <a href="http://tynan.com">Tynan.com</a>. Tynan is also the creator of a new <a href="http://sett.com/">blogging platform called SETT</a>.</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/quitting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 38 Best Methods of Successful Exercisers</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/fit-habit/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/fit-habit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13483</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta How do you form the exercise habit &#8212; really make it stick? Take the first step. Then take another. Make each step so important that you can&#8217;t miss it. And enjoy each step. That&#8217;s my method, honed from eight years of forming the exercise habit. It works, for me. But everyone has [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>How do you form the exercise habit &#8212; really make it stick?</p>

<p>Take the first step.</p>

<p>Then take another. Make each step so important that you can&#8217;t miss it. And enjoy each step.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s my method, honed from eight years of forming the exercise habit. It works, for me.</p>

<p>But everyone has a different method, and it&#8217;s inspiring and massively useful to learn from others who&#8217;ve successfully created the habit themselves.</p>

<p>Today, we&#8217;ll look at a great list of those methods, submitted by folks on Twitter who have overcome the odds and successfully formed the exercise habit.</p>

<p>First, thank you, to everyone who submitted their successful methods. It was more than I&#8217;d hoped for, and incredibly powerful reinforcement of what works. But there were so many submissions that I had to whittle it down, tossing out good ideas and picking others that I thought were more universally applicable. Many of the ones listed here were echoed many times over in the submissions.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s dive in!</p>

<p>I asked people who had successfully created the exercise habit &#8212; what worked for them? They answered (note &#8211; ones without a name after them were submitted anonymously):</p>

<ol>
<li>Stop looking at it as a habit and instead as a lifestyle and an important part of my self-care. ~Lara Rininger</li>
<li>Work out first thing in the morning. You get it out of the way and it provides you with an abundance of energy for the rest of the day. ~Jen Zeman</li>
<li>Crank up your favorite music! I often see suggested play lists for workouts, but just listen to what excites you. It will get you moving. ~Jen Zeman</li>
<li>When I started running I started out at .5 miles and increased in .25 increments (I usually average 4 mile runs). It didn&#8217;t happen overnight &#8211; give your lungs and muscles time to adjust. Same with weight training &#8211; start light and build your way up. Results will start to show in about 3-4 weeks. ~Jen Zeman</li>
<li>Making it my #1 priority and doing it first thing in the morning.        </li>
<li>30 day yoga challenges for myself that I then give updates on my Blog. Accountability. ~Kira Elliott</li>
<li>If I workout in the morning, before my day starts, I &#8220;earn: chocolate/beer/carb later in the day. Otherwise, no treats for me!</li>
<li>No excuses. I never miss more than 2 days. You have to insist on it and protect it.</li>
<li>Also: just put your workout clothes on. Once you do that it feels silly not to start. Just commit to 10 minutes. You will probably do more.</li>
<li>Also: no one ever regrets working out. Is there anything else in the world you can do, and know 100% you won&#8217;t regret it?</li>
<li>This is the one that&#8217;s helped the most: I&#8217;ve made a point to really, really, REALLY notice how much better I feel now that I exercise regularly; I&#8217;m sleeping better, my mood is better, I&#8217;m much less sluggish. It took about 3-4 weeks to see it, but it&#8217;s helped a lot. ~Polly</li>
<li>Make it a habit, don&#8217;t rely on motivating yourself to workout, consciously think of it as just something you do after &#8216;x&#8217;. This was a huge aha moment for me. ~Mark Feinholz</li>
<li>On that note, do it in the morning, habits are much easier to establish in the morning. the triggers are much more dependable (finish cup of coffee &#8211; put on gym shorts). Morning triggers are always there and the day has not polluted your plans yet. </li>
<li>A daily morning ritual to mark the beginning of training. In my case, tying up my bandana on my head meant &#8216;It&#8217;s running time&#8217;. ~Alfonso Acosta</li>
<li>I started running consistently the month before I got divorced. In theory it was the lowest part of my life &#8212; but I&#8217;d never felt better. I couldn&#8217;t get over that. I was sold on exercise, though it took me a while to make running the nonnegotiable part of my schedule it is now. After I got married again and when our daughter was a baby I used to run at the high school track near our house. I&#8217;d pretend the bleachers were filled with people cheering me on. “Good job!” I imagined them hollering. “Way to go!” And, “It’s great you’re leaving the baby with Dad for a while on this beautiful summer evening to do something nice for yourself.” Well, nice &#8212; and hell. It was hell. I wasn’t in shape, I didn’t want to miss a second with our new baby, and that was that. The pretend cheerleaders must’ve helped. Certainly they didn’t hurt. Because eventually, through a series of learning and unlearning and relearning the importance of exercising, it’s what I do. No discussion. No bargaining out of workouts unless I’ve made them up in advance. It’s soothing, really. There are no decisions to be made about exercise. I just do it. To the extent anything else good happens, I attribute it to this: running is magic. ~Maureen Anderson</li>
<li>Fixed a time of the day that HAS to be the workout time. Cleared away tasks around that time to make sure I don&#8217;t get stuck with something else. ~Elle Kaiye</li>
<li>Mentally preparing myself during the day for the evening workout helped.Mental preparation was important to prevent talking myself out of workout on the pretext of being &#8220;&#8221;exhausted&#8221;" or having &#8220;&#8221;more important stuff to do&#8221;". ~Elle Kaiye</li>
<li>Sometimes even looking at the pictures of Victoria&#8217;s Secret Angels helped ;) ~Elle Kaiye</li>
<li>I don&#8217;t have a workout buddy now but that had helped me to stay on track in the past. Support from my Mom helped me a lot! ~Elle Kaiye</li>
<li>Doing a sport that you love and try new types of exercise/sports. ~Chris B.</li>
<li>Do it a few days in a row, you &#8211; your body and mind- will get used to it. ~Chris B.</li>
<li>Enter a race or contest. ~Chris B.</li>
<li>I had to stop setting goals &#8211; as is advised by pretty much every source out there! I just got discouraged that I wasn&#8217;t moving as fast as the &#8216;programme&#8217;, or that I still felt no closer to running a marathon I seriously didn&#8217;t want to.
>What works instead: feeling great about just turning up. I do what I feel able to when I&#8217;m there, and if it&#8217;s not much or not as much as last time &#8211; fine. I showed up. I get to say &#8220;I went to the gym&#8221; which impresses on its own, without me detailing what I did! ~Sarah</li>
<li>A lot of people take days off when they&#8217;re exercising, which I think is great and important for your body to recover. However, I&#8217;ve found the habit of going to the gym (or wherever you go to workout) is important for me to do EVERY DAY. I run and do some strength training most days, but when it&#8217;s time for a recovery day I still go to the gym- to play racquetball, take an easy walk, shoot a few baskets, whatever. ~Dave Hall</li>
<li>What worked for me was strong commitment to myself that I do exercise on these days on this time NO MATTER WHAT. I do not accept situations I wouldn&#8217;t exercise on my planned day if for example I felt tired, or couples of friends invited me for a meeting, or it was raining (running is essential part of my routine) or anything else. These are all small excuses that we have to actually struggle with. They are too small to prevent us from fulfilling the plan. I only omit my exercise session if I&#8217;m on vacation or if I&#8217;m seriously ill. In other cases there is no way to break the habit. ~Przemyslaw</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t think about it, just do it. Even though I&#8217;ve consistently worked for over 15 years, it doesn&#8217;t mean I don&#8217;t have days that I just don&#8217;t feel like working out. I do have those days, but I push through it and do the work out anyway. ~Caroline</li>
<li>Schedule time for exercise and keeping to it like you would any other appointment or meeting. ~Katie</li>
<li>First I picked some awesome skills I wanted do be able to do from <a href="http://www.beastskills.com/tutorials/">this website for motivation</a>. While working towards them I basically only had a single goal: Do at least a single exercise every day, one pushup, pullup, sit up, &#8230; If I didn&#8217;t feel like it, wouldn&#8217;t do more, just a single one. Now I&#8217;m can do one armed pushups, one legged squads, l-seats and quite a few pullups. What also probably helped was that I didn&#8217;t need a single piece of equipment. ~Michael</li>
<li>I exercise every single day. Every. Single. Day. That&#8217;s my secret. I don&#8217;t give myself the choice of whether to exercise or not. Every time that you give yourself a choice, you give yourself the opportunity to decide not to do something. ~Mark Cancellieri</li>
<li>Sleep in my exercise gear (makes me feel mentally ready for action the next day). ~Ruth Seatter</li>
<li>Plan to exercise with a friend (running or gym class etc). $20 wager if you don&#8217;t make it. ~Ruth Seatter</li>
<li>Make it into a game or do it as a social activity with a friend. the more enjoyable it is the likelier you are to continue it. ~Matthew</li>
<li>Accountability. I am a very lazy person and I hate being answerable to people. I like to do things at my pace which is why I never stick to anything for long. But this time when it came to eating healthy and losing weight, I made myself answerable and accountable to my cook! I asked my cook to keep a check on what I eat and not offer me any junk or fried. So each time I entered to kitchen to grab some snacks, I saw him standing there and to avoid answering to his questions, I would step out with eating. This worked for me and now I am used to &#8216;not&#8217; eating when I am not hungry. ~Surabhi Surendra</li>
<li>Focus on effort: Set yourself goals around effort, not around results. ~Chiranth</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t let weather deter you. Once you do one or two runs in the rain you&#8217;ll see that they are liberating. ~Patty</li>
<li>I started very small. Starting small cancelled any excuse not to practice daily. I have refrained from overdoing in the first two weeks. This left me more energy to become more stable in practicing daily. I have committed with my girlfriend on a feasible outcome in a medium term, like being fit for our summer vacations. After some weeks the reason of my motivation shifted from being willing to satisfy the external source (girlfriend&#8217;s expectations) to being more confident and happy with myself. Starting one single habit is giving me the confidence to change other habits and the clarity to identify which other habits do I want to develop. ~Niccolo&#8217; Stamboglis</li>
<li>No more than 1 day off in a row. Find an exercise you really enjoy (I love lifting weights!). Try new types of exercise. You will be tired when beginning a new exercise program so eat well to fuel exercise and get enough sleep. Religiously stick with it for the first two weeks, then you will begin to notice an improvement in your energy levels that is very motivating. ~Patty</li>
<li>I joined a sports team (soccer), which is a fun way to exercise and ride my bike to work daily. This way I am physically active without really realizing it. I lack motivation to do exercises on my own. I almost need a team or coach or class to do well. (i.e. if I go to the gym solo, I get less results than if I joined a class). ~Bradlinn</li>
</ol>

<h3>The Exercise Habit in April</h3>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for help to form the exercise habit, I recommend my Sea Change Program &#8212; it&#8217;s a monthly membership program focused on helping you make changes in your life, and in April we&#8217;re doing an <strong>Exercise Habit Module</strong>.</p>

<p>Each month we do a module focused on a different habit (procrastination, healthy eating, and meditating so far), and in April, we&#8217;re tackling the exercise habit!</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what you get, for $10/month:</p>

<ol>
<li>A plan to help you form the habit.</li>
<li>Email reminders every 2-3 days.</li>
<li>A live webinar each month where you can ask me questions.</li>
<li>A forum to ask questions of other members.</li>
<li>Accountability teams within the forum.</li>
<li>2-3 articles to help guide you and answer your questions.</li>
</ol>

<p><a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/">Learn more→</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/fit-habit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Make It Impossible To Fail</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/impossible/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/impossible/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Goals & Motivation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13421</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Editor&#8217;s Note: This is a guest post from Maneesh Sethi of Hack the System. It’s funny how long two minutes can be. Just a few weeks ago, a package arrived: a Sonicare EasyClean Toothbrush. The toothbrush has an automatic timer which dings every thirty seconds until two minutes have passed. It’s a strange thing, the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6><strong>Editor&#8217;s Note</strong>: This is a guest post from Maneesh Sethi of <a href="http://hackthesystem.com">Hack the System</a>.</h6>

<p>It’s funny how long two minutes can be.</p>

<p>Just a few weeks ago, a package arrived: a Sonicare EasyClean Toothbrush. The toothbrush has an automatic timer which dings every thirty seconds until two minutes have passed.</p>

<p>It’s a strange thing, the mental passage of time. The first thirty seconds feel like a millennium&#8212;when the heck is this brush going to ding? By the second ding, I’ve begun walking, or pacing, or thinking, but it still feels like an eternity.</p>

<p>The third ding? I barely even notice it. And the fourth feels like barely an instant.</p>

<p>Of course, each ding really takes exactly thirty seconds, but time doesn’t always act like it should. Just like how the first five minutes of a jog feel longer than the rest, or how the first sentence of an article takes hours &#8212; but the rest seems to take minutes.</p>

<p>The Sonicare toothbrush, however, is an example of a <i>Failure-Proof Environment</i>. Once you decide to start brushing, once you hit that on-switch, the brush won’t stop until two minutes have passed. When I use a regular toothbrush, I usually quit after twenty seconds or less, but by constructing a failure-proof environment&#8212;in this case, by buying a fancy toothbrush&#8212;I <i>built a system</i> that forces me to succeed. Building this system&#8212;this failure-proof environemnt&#8212;is the key to any habit change.</p>

<p>So, how can you build a failure proof environment? How can you force yourself to build better habits?<b> </b></p>

<h3>How to Construct a Failure-Proof Environment</h3>

<p>Think about this: how many times have you promised yourself to eat better? It’s easy for your sane-superego to make a promise on January 1. But you know the rest: a couple days later, someone hands you a cookie. Your insane-emotional-id-self takes over, and forgets what the real you wants. All it can say is “cookie cookie cookie.”</p>

<p>Damn lizard brain.</p>

<p>The good news? There is a way to short-circuit this process. The secret is called <b>precommitment</b>.</p>

<p>Precommitment is the process of making a promise, when you are in your sane state, that will prevent your tempted insane-emotional-id-self from doing something bad. Imagine that on January 1<sup>st</sup>, you decide to take a flight to a deserted island, one without cookie-trees. It’s not so hard to say no to a cookie when they are impossible to find.</p>

<p>My first experience with precommitment was during a <a href="http://www.boss-inc.com/course_28-day-field_56.html">28 day trek</a> through the wilderness. I had no access to cookies, Facebook, or any other distraction. And I lost <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/blog/how-to-lose-23-lbs-in-28-days-hint-it-requires-radical-system-hacking/">23 lbs in 28 days</a> &#8212; my first experience with a drastic environment change. For five days in a row, I was <a href="http://www.theminimalists.com/maneesh">alone in a cave</a> — just myself, a pen, and a notebook. Without access to distractions, there was no choice. I wrote more in those five days than I had written in the previous year.</p>

<p>Precommitment is the process of creating an enviroment that <b>forces</b> you to succeed.</p>

<p>You might not be able to find a month to hike in the wilderness, but there are still ways to use precommitment in your normal life. Let’s take a look at some examples.</p>

<h3>Precommitting via the Bet Switch Mechanism</h3>

<p>What’s another way to force yourself to stop eating that cookie?</p>

<p>After I returned from the wilderness, I quickly noticed the weight returning. I needed to get back in shape for a TV show I was filming, but I couldn’t just run away into a forest this time. So what did I do? I used the <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/blog/the-bet-switch-mechanism-the-one-simple-tactic-that-will-make-you-lose-weight-eat-right-and-get-in-the-best-shape-of-your-life/">Bet Switch Mechanism.</a></p>

<p>The Bet Switch Mechanism is simple: you precommit to something using a bet. In the case of weight loss, I promised my friend that for every non-paleo-diet item I ate, I would pay $50 / item. In other words, that cookie wasn’t just a tasty dessert—it was $50. Instantly, my cravings disappeared. I no longer would use the excuse &#8216;let me just have one&#8230;&#8217; before engorging on a mountain of chocolate and ice cream and Love Actually.  I lost 15 lbs in 4 weeks. The incident worked so well that I <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/minimalist-guide">created a guide to help others hack their habits</a>.</p>

<p>I used the same tactic with Leo Babauta &#8212; for a week, I had to write for thirty minutes at 9am. Failure? $50. And <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/blog/how-to-write-4x-more-words-than-you-ever-have-before-or-why-i-paypal-ed-leo-babauta-25/">Leo ended up getting paid</a>.</p>

<p>I use this tactic all the time. Heck, if I don’t finish the article you are reading now by 11:59 PST, I owe a friend $250 :p</p>

<p>Are you trying to finish something, but just not finding the motivation to do so? Find a friend to bet with. It doesn’t have to be money—one of my female friends puts her favorite dress on the line.</p>

<p>You can use <a href="http://stickk.com/">stickk.com</a> to find someone to bet with, if you don’t have someone nearby to work with.<b> </b></p>

<h3>Precommitting using the Craigslist Slapper Technique</h3>

<p>Still not feeling motivated? Precommit by hiring someone to force you to work.</p>

<p>A few months ago, I hired someone on Craigslist to sit down next to me. Her job was specific: every time I used Facebook, she was required to <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/blog/why-i-hired-a-girl-on-craigslist-to-slap-me-in-the-face-and-why-it-quadrupled-my-productivity/">slap me in the face</a>.</p>

<p>Sure, it sounds stupid, but the act of hiring someone makes you much more likely to actually DO something. With my slapper, my productivity increased by 4x.</p>

<p>Today, when I have a project I just <b>have</b> to finish, I hire someone to sit next to me and force me to work. This way, even if my stupid lizard-brain wants to check Facebook and use Twitter, my slapper &#8212; my most powerful failure-proof precommitment tool &#8212; keeps me in check.</p>

<p>In the same vein, do you want to start going to the gym? Precommit by hiring a personal trainer for two months in advance. You will probably miss the gym on your own, but you won’t miss an (expensive) appointment with a trainer.</p>

<p>The key here is <b>set an appointment with someone else</b>. It’s easy to not show up to the gym alone, but you’re much less likely to do so if it means disappointing your trainer or friend.</p>

<h3>Putting it all together</h3>

<p>At the end of the day, it comes down to a decision &#8212; are you going to change your habits? Or are you going to live the same way you always have?</p>

<p>If you’ve made the decision to change, check out my <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/minimalist-guide">Minimalist Guide to Hacking Your Habits</a>. It’s a guide and set of worksheets that will show you the specific processes of habit change, and guide you along the way.</p>

<p>A year from now, you’ll wish you had started today.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p><strong>Maneesh Sethi has spent the last five years as a digital nomad—traveling the world and building businesses . He created a <a href="http://hackthesystem.com/minimalist-guide">minimalist guide</a> for Zen Habits readers to help build better habits. Get the guide and check out <a href="http://hackthesystem.com">Hack the System</a>.</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/impossible/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Not Knowing Path of Being an Entrepreneur</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/unknowing/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/unknowing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Goals & Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Productivity & Organization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Leo Babauta Lots of people who start businesses try to control outcomes: A vision for your business&#8217;s success. Goals to get you to the successful vision. Try to get the most productive day (out of yourself, or employees). Try to produce certain amounts, or hit certain metrics (pageviews, followers, revenue, sales). Unfortunately, the ability [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Lots of people who start businesses try to control outcomes:</p>

<ol>
<li>A vision for your business&#8217;s success.</li>
<li>Goals to get you to the successful vision.</li>
<li>Try to get the most productive day (out of yourself, or employees).</li>
<li>Try to produce certain amounts, or hit certain metrics (pageviews, followers, revenue, sales).</li>
</ol>

<p>Unfortunately, the ability to control outcomes is an illusion. This is one of the fundamental lessons I&#8217;ve learned in my six years of being in business for myself.</p>

<p>You don&#8217;t really know how things will turn out.</p>

<p>And this is OK.</p>

<p>In fact, it&#8217;s pretty awesome.</p>

<p>Yes, not knowing how things will turn out &#8212; day to day, month to month, year to year &#8212; is crazy scary. I&#8217;m not gonna front. It&#8217;s so scary you might wake up drenched in sweat.</p>

<p>But not knowing is what makes being an entrepreneur more amazing than working a regular desk job with a regular paycheck. We take risks, we fail, we don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen, we not only put our toes into the waters of the unknown &#8230; we dive in, headfirst.</p>

<p>Yes, not knowing is scary. But <strong>if you embrace it</strong>, not knowing can be liberating, and can be an advantage.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s look at how it&#8217;s an advantage, and how to stay present in the middle of the unknown.</p>

<h3>The Advantage of Not Knowing</h3>

<p>Quiz question: What causes us the most anxiety? Million dollar answer: Wanting things to turn out a certain way. Wanting an outcome &#8212; wanting the person you love to love you back, wanting people at your meeting or presentation to like you, wanting a million customers, wanting to be the next Apple or Twitter or Starbucks. This is the cause of our anxiety, because when we want that outcome, we fear that it won&#8217;t come true, and we strive for it to come true, and of course it might not.</p>

<p>There are a million possibilities, and wanting just one of those possibilities is a little crazy. What&#8217;s wrong with the other 999,999? Will our worlds fall apart if that one outcome doesn&#8217;t become a reality? No. We&#8217;ll be just fine no matter what.</p>

<p>Seriously. You&#8217;ll be absolutely fine even if the outcome doesn&#8217;t happen.</p>

<p>So when anxiety comes up, if we learn to let go of needing that outcome, we can then let go of the anxiety.</p>

<p>So advantage #1: <strong>we have less anxiety</strong>. What happens when you have less anxiety? Well, you&#8217;re happier. You are happier when you meet with customers or clients or employees. They feel your happiness. They sense that you&#8217;re cool with how things are going. You are less desperate. You don&#8217;t need things to turn out a certain way &#8212; you don&#8217;t need this one sale. You do your best to make it happen, but you&#8217;re cool even if it doesn&#8217;t.</p>

<p>Other people bet everything on making their outcome happen &#8212; but what if it doesn&#8217;t? Then they&#8217;ve lost everything, with no clear direction of where to go when it fails to happen.</p>

<p>So advantage #2: <strong>we aren&#8217;t as tied to one bet</strong>. That&#8217;s a single point of failure. Not a great idea. Instead, we are OK no matter what happens, and so any outcome of a meeting, a project, a launch &#8230; we are good with that, and no outcome really messes us up. We flow.</p>

<p>Another problem is that people who think they know how things will turn out &#8230; they&#8217;re fooling themselves. No one knows.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s advantage #3: <strong>we are more honest</strong>. Admitting to ourselves that we don&#8217;t know is much more honest than thinking, hoping, things will turn out the way we want. Honesty is important because if we&#8217;re going to act, we should do so with open eyes and a clear assessment of the situation.</p>

<p>Honesty with customers, readers, clients, employees is important too. Admit you don&#8217;t know. They will trust you more, because not only are you telling them you don&#8217;t know, you are clearly OK with that. You don&#8217;t know what will happen, but whatever happens, you&#8217;ll deal with it. That&#8217;s powerful.</p>

<p>Those are just a few advantages, but actually the advantages are many. You don&#8217;t have to plan as much because not knowing means you realize that detailed plans are useless, and actually a waste of your time. You spend less time worrying, more time executing. You aren&#8217;t consumed by the horrible fear that you&#8217;re doing the wrong thing, because you learn that there is never a  perfectly &#8220;right thing&#8221; to do &#8212; not generally for your business, or specifically right now.</p>

<h3>How to Walk the Not Knowing Path</h3>

<p>The Not Knowing Path of an entrepreneur is scary, but honestly, what path isn&#8217;t?</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s how to walk the path:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Admit you don&#8217;t know</strong>. This is obviously the first step, but it&#8217;s hard because we often want to think we know, or at least that we can make certain things happen the way we want them to. We think we can will things to happen. That&#8217;s not true. Many things fail despite Herculean efforts to make them succeed. We don&#8217;t control the future, we can&#8217;t know the future. We don&#8217;t know. Admit it to ourselves, and to others.</li>
<li><strong>Watch for anxiety</strong>. When you start feeling anxious (and that will always happen, probably numerous times a day), look inward for the source of the anxiety. What are you hoping will happen that&#8217;s making you anxious? This awareness is the key to everything.</li>
<li><strong>Tell yourself you&#8217;ll be OK</strong>. You become aware of an outcome you&#8217;re hoping for &#8230; now tell yourself that it doesn&#8217;t matter if that outcome happens. It really doesn&#8217;t matter, even if we&#8217;ve made up this story for ourselves that all depends on it happening. It doesn&#8217;t matter, and no matter what happens, we&#8217;ll be OK. Life-and-death situations are possibly the only exception to this, though I&#8217;m of the mind that even death is an outcome that I&#8217;d be OK with.</li>
<li><strong>Consider worst-case scenarios</strong>. What&#8217;s the worst thing that could happen? Someone doesn&#8217;t like you, doesn&#8217;t think as highly of you as you&#8217;d like, a meeting ends in anger, a sale doesn&#8217;t happen, the business fails. How bad is this worst-case scenario? How likely is it to happen? How would you cope if it did? Honestly, I think you&#8217;d be fine no matter what.</li>
<li><strong>Know your principles</strong>. Take some time to think about what should guide you, if you aren&#8217;t guided by trying to make something specific happen. If you&#8217;re not tied to an outcome or vision of the future you can&#8217;t control, what would guide you? Step back, reflect. What drives you? Why do you do what you do? For example, some of my guiding principles are wanting to help others, wanting to act compassionately, wanting to do things I love, and building trust by doing those things.</li>
<li><strong>Act on principles, not goals or detailed plans</strong>. Once you have your guiding principles, let them guide you on a day-by-day basis, moment-to-moment. You don&#8217;t know how something will turn out when you act, but you do know whether this action is in line with your principles.</li>
<li><strong>Breathe, and smile</strong>. In the end, not knowing can be scary, but liberating and profound. You are in the midst of a turbulent sea, and are afloat without knowing where anything will go. But that&#8217;s always true, even of people who don&#8217;t admit it to themselves. So enjoy the ride. Look at the amazing place you&#8217;re in, and smile. Because this path of not knowing &#8230; it is the path of life itself.</li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;If you realize that all things change, there is nothing you will try to hold on to. If you are not afraid of dying, there is nothing you cannot achieve.&#8217; <strong>~Lao Tzu</strong></p>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/unknowing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Change Your Life: A User&#8217;s Guide</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/change/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13388</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;You will never change your life until you change something you do daily.&#8217; ~Mike Murdock By Leo Babauta Start with a simple statement: what do you want to be? Are you hoping to someday be a writer, a musician, a designer, a programmer, a polyglot, a carpenter, a manga artist, an entrepreneur, an expert at [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;You will never change your life until you change something you do daily.&#8217; <strong>~Mike Murdock</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>Start with a simple statement: what do you want to be?</p>

<p>Are you hoping to someday be a writer, a musician, a designer, a programmer, a polyglot, a carpenter, a manga artist, an entrepreneur, an expert at something?</p>

<p>How do you get there? Do you write your intention on a piece of paper, and put it in a bottle and launch it to sea, hoping it will manifest? No. The universe isn&#8217;t going to make this happen. You are.</p>

<p>Do you set yourself a big goal to complete by the end of the year, or in three months? Sure, but that doesn&#8217;t get the job done. In fact, if you think back on most examples in your life, setting big long-term goals probably doesn&#8217;t work very often. How many times has this strategy been successful?</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to lay down the law here, based on many many experiments I&#8217;ve done in the last 7 years: <strong>nothing will change unless you make a daily change</strong>.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve tried weekly action steps, things that I do every other day, big bold monthly goals, lots of other permutations. <em>None of them work except daily changes</em>.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re not willing to make it a daily change, you don&#8217;t really want to change your life in this way. You only like the idea of learning to draw/speak Japanese/play guitar/program in php/etc. You don&#8217;t really want to do it.</p>

<p>So make a daily change. Let&#8217;s dig into how it&#8217;s done!</p>

<h3>How to Turn an Aspiration Into a Daily Change</h3>

<p>Let&#8217;s name a few aspirations:</p>

<ul>
<li>lose weight</li>
<li>write a book</li>
<li>stop procrastinating</li>
<li>fall in love</li>
<li>be happy</li>
<li>travel the world</li>
<li>drink more water</li>
<li>learn Spanish</li>
<li>save money</li>
<li>take more pictures</li>
<li>read more books</li>
</ul>

<p>How do you turn those lofty ideas into daily changes? Think about what you could do every day that would make the change happen, or at least get you closer to the goal. Sometimes that&#8217;s not always easy, but let&#8217;s look at some ideas:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>lose weight</strong> &#8211; start walking every day, for 10 minutes at first, then 15 after a week, then 20 &#8230; once you are walking for 30-40 minutes a day, make another change &#8212; drink water instead of soda.</li>
<li><strong>write a book</strong> &#8211; write for 10 minutes a day.</li>
<li><strong>stop procrastinating</strong> &#8211; I can already hear the ironic (and original!) jokes about how people will deal with procrastination later (har!). Anyway, a daily action: set a Most Important Task each morning, then work on it for 10 minutes before opening your browser/mobile device.</li>
<li><strong>fall in love</strong> &#8211; go somewhere each day and meet/social with new people. Or do daily things that make you a fascinating person.</li>
<li><strong>be happy</strong> &#8211; do something each day to make the world better, to help people.</li>
<li><strong>travel the world</strong> &#8211; save money (see next item). Or start selling your stuff, so you can carry your belongings on a backpack and start hitchhiking. </li>
<li><strong>save money</strong> &#8211; start cutting out smaller expenses. Start cooking and eating at home. Sell your car and bike/walk/take the train. Start looking for a smaller home. Do free stuff instead of buying things.</li>
<li><strong>drink more water</strong> &#8211; drink water when you wake up, then every time you take a break (once an hour).</li>
<li><strong>learn Spanish</strong> &#8211; study Spanish sentences in Anki and listen to Pimsleur tapes 10 minutes a day.</li>
<li><strong>take more pictures</strong> &#8211; take pictures at lunch (but dear jeebus, not of your lunch) and post them to your blog.</li>
<li><strong>read more books</strong> &#8211; read every morning and before you go to bed.</li>
</ul>

<p>You get the idea. Not all of these are perfect ideas, but you could come up with something that works better for you. Point is, do it daily.</p>

<h3>How to Implement Daily Changes</h3>

<p>This method is fairly simple, and if you really implement it, nearly foolproof:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>One Change at a Time</strong>. You can break this rule, but don&#8217;t be surprised if you fail. Do one change for a month before considering a second. Only add another change if you were successful at the first.</li>
<li><strong>Start Small</strong>. OK, I&#8217;ve said this two bajillion times. No one ever does it, though. Start with 10 minutes or less. Five minutes is better if it&#8217;s a hard change. If you fail at that, drop it to 2 minutes.</li>
<li><strong>Do it at the same time each day</strong>. OK, not literally at the same minute, like at 6:00 a.m., but after the same trigger in your daily routine &#8212; after you drink your first cup of coffee in the morning, after you arrive at work, after you get home, after you brush your teeth, shower, eat breakfast, wake up, eat lunch, turn on your computer, first see your wife each day.</li>
<li><strong>Make a huge commitment to someone</strong>. Or multiple people. Make sure it&#8217;s someone whose opinion you respect. For example, I made a commitment to studying/coding PHP at least 10 minutes each day to my friend <a href="http://tynan.com/">Tynan</a>. I&#8217;ve made commitments to my wife, to other friends, to readers of this blog, to readers of a newspaper on Guam, to my kids, and more.</li>
<li><strong>Be accountable</strong>. Taking my programming example with Tynan &#8230; each day I have to update a Google spreadsheet each day showing how many minutes I programmed/studied each day, and he can (and does) check that shared spreadsheet. The tool you use doesn&#8217;t matter &#8212; you can post to Facebook or Twitter, email someone, mark it on a calendar, report in person. Just make sure you&#8217;re accountable each day, not each month. And make sure the person is checking. If they don&#8217;t check on you, you need to find a new accountability partner or group.</li>
<li><strong>Have consequences</strong>. The most important consequence for doing or not doing the daily habit is that if you don&#8217;t, the people will respect you less, and if you do, they&#8217;ll respect you more. If your accountability system isn&#8217;t set up this way, find another way to do it. You might need to change who you&#8217;re accountable to. But you can add other fun consequences: one friend made a promise to Facebook friends that he&#8217;d donate $50 to Mitt Romney&#8217;s campaign (this was last year) each time he didn&#8217;t follow through on a commitment. I&#8217;ve made a promise to eat whale sushi (I won&#8217;t fail, because eating a whale is repugnant to me, like eating a cow or a child). I&#8217;ve promised to sing a Japanese song in front of strangers if I failed. The consequences can also be positive &#8212; a big reward each week if you don&#8217;t miss a day, for example. Make the consequences bigger if you miss two straight days, and huge if you miss three.</li>
<li><strong>Enjoy the change</strong>. If you don&#8217;t do this, you might as well find another change to make. If the daily action feels tedious and chore-like, then you are doing it wrong. Find a way to enjoy it, or you won&#8217;t stick to it long. Or find some other change you enjoy more.</li>
</ol>

<p>That&#8217;s it. Seven pretty simple steps, and you&#8217;ve got a changed life. None of these steps is impossible &#8212; in fact, you can put them into action today.</p>

<p>What daily change will you make today?</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;A year from now you will wish you had started today.&#8217; <strong>~Karen Lamb</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Note</strong>: I have a program designed to help you make changes in this way, with built-in accountability and step-by-step plans each month &#8212; the <a href="http://zenhabits.net/membership-signup/">Sea Change Program</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Your Family On Board with Life Changes</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/family-changes/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/family-changes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 16:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Finance & Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13382</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;Men learn while they teach.&#8217; ~Seneca the Younger By Leo Babauta It is a curious phenomena that when we try to change our habits &#8212; simplify our clutter, eat healthier, start exercising &#8212; the other people in our life don&#8217;t instantly want to be changed in the same way. It&#8217;s as if they had their [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;Men learn while they teach.&#8217; <strong>~Seneca the Younger</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>It is a curious phenomena that when we try to change our habits &#8212; simplify our clutter, eat healthier, start exercising &#8212; the other people in our life don&#8217;t instantly want to be changed in the same way.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s as if they had their own minds!</p>

<p>Horrible as that might sound, it&#8217;s the reality we have to deal with if we have a family (or friends, roommates, coworkers, etc.). They often resist changes we make, or their possibly unhealthy habits stand in our way.</p>

<p>You&#8217;re trying to eat only whole foods, and yet your daughter eats goldfish crackers and pizza and Oreos. And she doesn&#8217;t seem to want to munch on asparagus instead!</p>

<p>So what&#8217;s a habit changer to do? Abandon all attempts at change? No. Force change on family members? Tempting, but not effective.</p>

<p>The answer is that there is no simple answer. I&#8217;ll share what has worked for me, but that won&#8217;t work for everyone. When you&#8217;re single and living alone, it&#8217;s easy to make whatever changes you want to make &#8212; but if you&#8217;re married, you have to make compromises. You live in the space that is common between the two of you, and that is negotiated space. When you add kids to your life, you now live in a space that is common between all of you, also a negotiated space.</p>

<p>What works? Let&#8217;s take a look at some strategies. Try one, try two, or try them all, and figure out what works in your negotiated space.</p>

<h3>Getting Others On Board</h3>

<p>Here&#8217;s a common scenario: you&#8217;ve read about some interesting challenge or change someone else has made, or perhaps read a magazine article or book on the topic, and have been giving it some thought, and finally arrived at the decision to make the change &#8230; and then you spring it on your significant other or entire family. They somehow aren&#8217;t as enthused as you&#8217;d like!</p>

<p>That&#8217;s because you have gone through an entire thinking process to arrive at the decision, and they are being asked to come in only at the end &#8212; after the decision has been made. That&#8217;s not fair to them, because they haven&#8217;t had time to go through the same thinking process, to consider the reasons, to find the motivation, to be included in the decision.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve found a more effective method is to get all the people who will be affected in on the thinking process as early as possible. Don&#8217;t talk to them about it when you&#8217;re near the decision-making point &#8230; talk to them when you first hear or read about the idea. Talk about why it&#8217;s appealing to you. Get their input. Ask whether they&#8217;d consider that kind of change. Talk about your motivation. Include them every step of the way, until the decision is made, and even after.</p>

<p>What people don&#8217;t like is being forced to change, against their will. So never make people feel that way. Don&#8217;t ask them to change &#8230; ask them to help you change, once you&#8217;ve gotten to the decision. Say that their support is really important to you, and while they are welcome to join you (you&#8217;d love that!), they don&#8217;t have to change. Just help you make your change. Ask them to be your accountability buddy, someone to call on when you&#8217;re having trouble, someone to report problems and successes to.</p>

<h3>Setting the Example</h3>

<p>While not everyone will be instantly on board with your ideas for change, I&#8217;ve found the best method of persuasion is being a good model for change.</p>

<p>When I started exercising, most of my family wasn&#8217;t doing it. I tried to convince people, but I wasn&#8217;t as good at persuasion as I thought. When they saw me exercising, at first they thought I was a bit kooky. Then they saw the changes in me, and how much I enjoyed it, and I would share how great it was, and over time, it inspired some to think about it.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s what you can do &#8212; inspire people to consider something they wouldn&#8217;t normally consider, just by setting a good example. No one else will do yoga with you? That&#8217;s OK &#8230; keep doing it, and share your experiences. Do it in front of them as they watch TV. Try not to be annoying, though.</p>

<h3>Making Changes on Your Own</h3>

<p>If others won&#8217;t get on board with your changes, ask for a minimum amount of support: ask that they give you the space to make the change on your own, without their help. This isn&#8217;t a small thing sometimes &#8212; often people are threatened when someone in their life makes changes, or they don&#8217;t like the disruption of their routine of doing things with you (eating junk food together, for example). You doing something on your own is a big change for them.</p>

<p>Ask for the space to do it alone, and ask that they not criticize or otherwise make it hard on you. If they are resentful, this makes it more difficult, but you&#8217;ll have to make an effort to show that this is something that will make you happy, and you will do your best not to disrupt things for them. If that means you don&#8217;t spend mornings together because you are out running, then try to create other time together, like in the evenings or on weekends.</p>

<p>When you make changes on your own, without the support of others, it&#8217;s more difficult. You need to find other encouragement &#8212; I&#8217;ve joined running groups online, a smoking cessation group, and other similar groups. Facebook and other social networking tools can also be helpful in finding online support. Often there are groups in your area where you can meet people in person who are going through the same changes.</p>

<h3>Family Challenges</h3>

<p>One of my more successful strategies is creating challenges for my family. They aren&#8217;t required to do the challenges, of course, but sometimes people like the opportunity to rise to a challenge. And they like making changes with others.</p>

<p>My wife and I have created eating challenges to do with each other (we call them Lean Out Challenges, usually after we go on a trip and gorge ourselves on unhealthy food). With the kids, I&#8217;ve challenged them to do pushups, handstands, running, vegetarian experiments, daily drawing, and more.</p>

<p>Challenges are fun if you do them together. It can be fun to do it as a competition, or to offer rewards for people who complete the challenge.</p>

<h3>Notes on Eating Habits</h3>

<p>Eating changes can be especially difficult if your family isn&#8217;t doing it with you, because they can be eating junk food right in front of your face as you try to much on celery. Tough stuff.</p>

<p>Here are some notes from my experiences:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you do the cooking, cook food for the family, and cook your meals separately. Eva &amp; I often cook our healthy food in bulk and eat the same food for days, while the kids eat other things. For some reason they&#8217;re not big kale and quinoa fans. Kids.</li>
<li>Kids can change their taste buds, but slowly. They won&#8217;t instantly like big green salads, but you can introduce vegetables slowly, in soups and other dishes they might be used to. Dice carrots and kale can be added to chili and spaghetti sauce if you cut them small enough and add them when you&#8217;re cooking onions/garlic.</li>
<li>Kids will eat nearly anything if you add some baked fries to the dish.</li>
<li>If the kids are going to eat something especially tempting (pizza), I try to make myself scarce so I don&#8217;t have temptations. It&#8217;s too hard to avoid junk that I enjoy eating, if it&#8217;s right in front of me, so I&#8217;ll go for a run or go to my room to do some work &#8212; keep busy.</li>
<li>We try to find restaurants that has healthy food that the kids will like.</li>
<li>When I went vegetarian, Eva &amp; the kids weren&#8217;t vegetarian. I did get them to try some dishes, which they generally liked, and then would just eat my food separately from them. If I made my food especially delicious, it would be tempting for them to at least try.</li>
<li>Kids will go to any restaurant if there&#8217;s dessert at the end.</li>
<li>Many people don&#8217;t like the idea of vegan food, even if they&#8217;ve never tried it. Making delicious vegan cupcakes will often win them over, at least to try it. I recommend <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Vegan-Cupcakes-Take-Over-World/dp/1569242739">Vegan Cupcakes Take Over the World</a>. Truly amazing.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Supporting Their Changes</h3>

<p>If you want others to support your changes, you should also support theirs. When my kids or wife express a desire to make some change, I do my best to help them achieve that:</p>

<ul>
<li>I share my experiences and what worked for me, and how I overcame some obstacles.</li>
<li>I share websites and books that help with that change, and often will buy books to help them.</li>
<li>I&#8217;ll do a project with them, or create a challenge we can do together.</li>
<li>I run and workout with my wife, and created a workout log to help her track her fitness.</li>
<li>I share vegetarian recipes with my wife (who is now vegan), and with my daughter, who decided to try vegetarianism</li>
</ul>

<p>There are more possibilities, but these are a few examples. When they see you supporting them, they now have a model for how to act when you want to make changes in the future. It&#8217;s not an overnight change that you&#8217;ll see in your family, but slow gradual long-term changes. Play the long game when it comes to changing the culture of a family.</p>

<h3>Learn by Teaching</h3>

<p>The best way to make changes yourself is to help others. That means supporting them when they want to make changes, sharing the changes you&#8217;ve made and teaching them what you&#8217;ve learned, showing someone how to do something cool after you&#8217;ve learned how to do it.</p>

<p>You are teaching by making changes and sharing those changes with your family. They might not care about learning at first, but they will, over time. And when you teach, you learn more and more. As I am now, sharing with you.</p>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/family-changes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Stick to a Habit When Life Falls Apart</title>
		<link>http://zenhabits.net/bumps/</link>
		<comments>http://zenhabits.net/bumps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 17:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zenhabits</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happiness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenhabits.net/?p=13325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;If you’re going through hell, keep going.&#8217; ~Winston Churchill By Leo Babauta We&#8217;d like to think that making positive life changes is a straight line from beginning to where we want to go. But life has taught us differently. Experience shows us that you can start a new habit (let&#8217;s say working out) and things [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>&#8216;If you’re going through hell, keep going.&#8217; <strong>~Winston Churchill</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<h6>By <a href="http://leobabauta.com">Leo Babauta</a></h6>

<p>We&#8217;d like to think that making positive life changes is a straight line from beginning to where we want to go.</p>

<p>But life has taught us differently.</p>

<p>Experience shows us that you can start a new habit (let&#8217;s say working out) and things go great for awhile, and then life gets in the way. Things get messy. Things fall apart. We have a few bad days, or a huge project to work on at work, or relationship problems, or a family crisis, or we get sick.</p>

<p>What do we do when life gets messy and our habits fall to the wayside? Well, give up, obviously.</p>

<p>Actually, I take that back. We tend to give up, because when things get in the way and we mess up on our habits, it&#8217;s a little discouraging, even depressing.</p>

<p>But it doesn&#8217;t have to be. There are a few things you can do instead:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Breathe</strong>. Pause for a moment, breathe, focus on the breath. Know that you are OK, in this moment. Give yourself a moment&#8217;s space to think about what&#8217;s going on in your life, and who you are.</li>
<li><strong>Give yourself a break</strong>. If things like relationship problems get in the way of your habits, allow yourself to pause the habits until you get your life in order and let your mind rest. Rest is important. Get plenty of sleep &#8212; this is important, because when stressful things are happening in our lives, our bodies and minds need plenty of rest to heal.</li>
<li><strong>Know that every habit has bumps in the road</strong>. There&#8217;s never a perfectly smooth path with no bumps. Seriously, no habit goes on a perfectly straight line &#8212; at least, none that I&#8217;ve created, and none that anyone I know has created. Expect the bumps, and don&#8217;t let them end everything.</li>
<li><strong>Allow yourself to experience the messy.</strong> Things will always come up, life gets messy, painful things happen. That&#8217;s OK. Give yourself the space to experience the pain with the joy, the mess with the beauty.</li>
<li><strong>Find a friend to help you get on track</strong>. It&#8217;s great if you can do habits by yourself, but it&#8217;s even better if you can find a friend who will do it with you, or at least hold you accountable, and help you get things back on track once things clear up for you.</li>
<li><strong>Keep smiling!</strong>. That&#8217;s the most important thing. Smile, and you&#8217;re doing it right.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenhabits.net/bumps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced

Served from: zenhabits.net @ 2013-04-15 05:20:28 -->