<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dr. Pepper Schwartz: The Secrets We Keep From Our Partners</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-pepper-schwartz/secrets-and-relationships_b_3112488.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3112488</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-19T02:34:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Secrets and lies are commonplace in relationships, not only in the United States, but in the world. 43 percent of men and 33 percent of women say they keep major secrets from each other.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Pepper Schwartz</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-pepper-schwartz/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: large;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/frank-warren/postsecret-500000-secrets_b_3111905.html?1366337703" target="_hplink"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to read an original op-ed from the TED speaker who inspired this post and watch the TEDTalk below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently did a study that, among other things, looked at the secrets and lies that people keep from their spouse or committed partner. You know, the person who we share vows with, the person who we say "I love you" to, the person we share a bed and a life with -- that person.  The national and international study of 80,000 people, part of which appears in &lt;em&gt;The Normal Bar&lt;/em&gt; (with Chrisanna Northrup and Jim Witte) indicates that secrets and lies are commonplace in relationships, not only in the United States, but in the world. 43 percent of men and 33 percent of women say they keep major secrets from each other -- in fact, 27 percent of people who said they were in an "extremely happy relationship" also admitted to having major secrets from their partner.( In France and Italy , big secrets seem to be a way of life; approximately 75 percent of men and women there said they had them.) As for lies, 75 percent of our men, and 71 percent of the women said they occasionally lie to their partner-and that was even  true for 69 percent of the happiest couples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We know that the façade we present, not only to the world -- but to each other, does not include the whole truth of who we are, what we think, and what we do or have done.&lt;small&gt; - Dr. Pepper Schwartz&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whats going on here? Where's the highly vaunted open communication and intimacy that American therapists and self-help books urge as the core of every marriage and life-long commitment? The truth is revealed in Frank Warren's postcards and in our own fascination with the backstage lives of celebrities: we know that real relationships are not as one-dimensional as wedding photos or Christmas letters. We know that the façade we present, not only to the world -- but to each other, does not include the whole truth of who we are, what we think, and what we do or have done. We have not only told white lies- we have told some whoppers. There are spouses who do not know their partner never finished college, never really had an orgasm, never really stopped seeing their high school sweetheart. They do not know that their partner was never actually in combat or that their loving mate has had a crush on their best friend for 20 years. To lesser and greater extents, each life is an orchestrated mix of fiction and non-fiction. People cannot face what they believe would be the reaction to the whole truth, and nothing but the truth, even from the person who has professed love, acceptance and devotion to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our knowledge of our own secrets makes us more than a little curious about the secrets of others. If the secret warrants a tabloid or newspaper headline, it may even have the effect of making us feel better. Our secret, compared to the one that made the headlines is not so bad.  On the other hand, if we are a candidate for the cover of the National Enquirer, the public's thirst for uncovering secrets is genuinely scary -- but it seems not so scary that we stop behavior that puts us in jeopardy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I think is most interesting however, is the drive for absolution, the need that Warren tapped into, of needing to tell one's own secret to someone -- anyone! The Catholic Church figured that out a long time ago. By having little private rooms where a tiny or terrible secret can be told- without public consequence, the church has given its faithful a way to expunge the heavy burden of secret-keeping. Modern therapy can be the secular equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secret keeping does weigh on the majority of people, but not always, mind you, because of guilt. No sometimes, an unfaithful partner is just dying to brag about a particularly flattering conquest- and they need someone safe to receive this "guilty pleasure." Other times, the secret does create true angst; either because the guilty party has violated his or her own values, or the possibility of exposure and disgrace mounts up over time. Why else do cellmates tell one another about their true culpability when doing so exposes them to legal vulnerability-even the death penalty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there is a need to tell, and a need to hide. We can be in both categories. We may also want to know other people's secrets, even as we guard our own. But guard them, we do. Secrets are secret for a reason. We could lose respect, love, even freedom, if all our secrets were known. But as Frank Warren's Secrets site and The Normal Bar data show, the likelihood that all secrets will be known, is slim. And that is not just true in the workplace or in politics: it also true for even our most intimate, our most trusted relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ideas are not set in stone. When exposed to thoughtful people, they morph and adapt into their most potent form. TEDWeekends will highlight some of today's most intriguing ideas and allow them to develop in real time through your voice! Tweet #TEDWeekends to share your perspective or email &lt;a href="mailto:tedweekends@hufﬁngtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;tedweekends@hufﬁngtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt; to learn about future weekend's ideas to contribute as a writer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/frank_warren_half_a_million_secrets.html?zone=huffpost" width="450" height="252" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094592/thumbs/s-SECRET-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Joelle Fraser: 'I Lived A Double Life'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/joelle-fraser/my-double-life-the-biker-_b_3088824.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3088824</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-19T05:45:29Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-19T05:44:20Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What I've learned is to focus on what's in front of you: love for your child, balance of work and play, and a fierce pursuit of that which gives you peace of mind. If you insist on these things, and your lover agrees, then you can make your way forward together.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Joelle Fraser</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/joelle-fraser/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The Biker was just what I wanted -- young, handsome, the right kind of wild -- and easy to leave when the thrill wore off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met at a friend's summer BBQ. I was a recently divorced mother of a five-year-old boy, and like a hothouse flower after a long cold spell, ready to be a woman again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was I didn't know how to date as a single mom. More importantly: it was tough enough for me to let someone in, and now I had a child to protect as well? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, because I had 50-50 custody, I sidestepped the issue altogether: I'd be a mother half the week, a lover the other half. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually pulled it off for a while. Although I introduced the Biker and my boy Dylan to each other after a few months (carefully, and at a gathering of a dozen people), and we had lunch together now and then, I kept them at arm's length for half a year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why not? Dylan already had a terrific father. I wasn't looking to create a family while still grieving for the one that was gone. Neither was the Biker, also bruising from a failed marriage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's different after divorce. There's no map anymore, no yellow brick road. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I went on long, fast rides on the Harley, letting the wind rip away any doubts. I wore the biker chick costume of tight jeans, tank top and sexy braids and danced to southern rock bands under the stars. On Sundays I rushed home to don sweatpants, pack lunches and take nature walks with my son. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, lust turned to love. Real love. Gradually, my "double life" began to wear on me. There was always someone to miss. I also began to feel the unique loneliness of the parent who parents alone. For the Biker, I was holding back an essential part of myself: being a mother. With my son, I never felt wholly present -- especially when the Biker left on a weekend ride. Worry shadowed my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following summer, we finally began doing things "as a family" -- camping, going to matinees, taking day trips -- but the three of us formed a tense triangle, with me at the top, trying like a domestic juggler to make everyone happy. I let Dylan get away with too much while The Biker, who had no kids -- who'd never even dated anyone with kids -- followed my uncertain lead. It was like the blind leading the blind. What we did share was our own childhood baggage as children of divorce, which made us so cautious all we could do was stumble. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I blamed the tension on the Biker's lack of bonding with Dylan, it took me months to realize my own part in it all: the way I'd subtly discouraged him from coming to Dylan's t-ball practices, even though they were just down the block from his house. Six months later, I felt the same discomfort as I went alone to Dylan's school Christmas pageant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underneath it all, I was afraid of more heartache, more undoing. The Biker was too young, too drawn to the open highway. We were doomed ... weren't we? How could I start my son along the same twisting path of dead ends that my parents had led me along? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit the wall, and took a long break, which gave us both time to see what we missed, and what we wanted. Turns out what we wanted was each other, but balance too. He realized that the family time gave him a purpose he'd never felt before, but he needed direction and to feel welcome. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, when he asked if he could shop for Easter gifts, I said yes, and my son's joy that morning, seeing the brimming basket of toys and chocolate, is an image I won't forget. Later, they assembled kites and we watched them sail into the sky. I've learned to get out of the way so they can enjoy each other. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my memoir, &lt;em&gt;The Forest House&lt;/em&gt;, I wrote about the geography of divorce -- which for most is a dark, alien place where it takes months, years, to get your bearings -- only to find the world's shifted again, like a land riddled with fault lines. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I've learned is to focus on what's in front of you: love for your child, balance of work and play, and a fierce pursuit of that which gives you peace of mind. If you insist on these things, and your lover agrees, then you can make your way forward together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it doesn't have to be so hard. Kids love people who love them -- who take an interest in them. Why limit a child's life out of fear of the unknown? We can't predict what will happen, and thus vainly try to prepare by controlling who cares for whom and how much and for how long. It doesn't help to shut out love today out of worry that, eventually, it'll fade. Who knows -- maybe, this time, it won't.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094556/thumbs/s-DOUBLE-LIFE-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Denise Albert: Divorce Diaries: The New Family Vacation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/denise-albert/family-vacations-after-divorce_b_3065780.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3065780</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-19T00:21:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-19T00:21:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The most incredible things that I have witnessed through my kids eyes have been in the past year, since I separated from their dad. And that's because now I can fully enjoy being a mom on a mission doing and enjoying every journey we take.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Denise Albert</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/denise-albert/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'll be chronicling my new life as I go through the divorce process and I hope you'll follow my journey. If you're looking for me to bash my ex, that won't happen. But if you're looking for a woman and mom excited for a new life, if you find it interesting to read about the roller coaster of emotions and all of the things that come with starting over... then join me here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always remember when I was a kid my mom saying she loved seeing things through my eyes. I never fully understood that expression until I had kids of my own, now especially that they are old enough to enjoy experiences I present them with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most incredible things that I have witnessed through my kids eyes have been in the past year, since I separated from their dad. And that's because now I can fully enjoy being a mom on a mission doing and enjoying every journey we take. To me now, there's nothing I can't do. There's no task too big, there's not a thing I can't accomplish as a parent on her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, any chance I get, I plan adventures for my two boys and myself. Whether it's little things around our city, like touring a new neighborhood, ice-skating at Wollman Rink, taking the kids on the subway to a Brooklyn Nets game or a walking tour of Wall Street, we are always on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it's the bigger excursions and adventures that have surprised me the most. When I started to plan my first vacation on my own with my boys, I couldn't decide what to do. With the boys only four and eight, I couldn't figure out what kind of trip would be the easiest to do as a single parent. Should it be a beach trip or something a little more active? Would it be hard for me to keep them busy all day with swimming and playing or should I be more adventurous? I finally decided a mixture of the two would be a successful trip so we headed out west. The planned stay at the Loews Santa Monica would be perfect. Part beach, part boardwalk, part in the middle of a town with things to do. It was perfect except that I didn't plan for the 50-degree weather so instead of the beach and water activities, we mixed it up with day trips to tourist locations around Los Angeles. When we spent the afternoon visiting the Hollywood Walk of Fame, Chinese Mann Theater and the Hollywood sign, I became my mother 30 years ago looking at the same locations through my eyes.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The visions continued as we drove down the coast in our Audi blasting Disney Radio and singing over and over again to Justin Bieber as we went to meet friends at the Aviarra Hyatt just outside San Diego for the second part of our trip to Legoland. (If only my parents had Disney Radio, it would have made that same trip years ago so much more manageable.)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop proved to be planned perfectly. I wasn't quite ready to take on Disneyland on my own, so we met friends to take on Legoland. What a perfect choice. With just the three of us, there would have been an odd man out so now with another family of three we were six and everyone had a ride partner.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my initial trepidations, the trip was a great success, and I felt like I won the Superbowl. Next "We're going to Disney...."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was the plan until my friends asked if we wanted to go skiing with them. By now I successfully had a six-hour flight &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/denise-albert/divorce-diaries-have-you-_1_b_2415311.html" target="_hplink"&gt;(with a little disastrous detour)&lt;/a&gt; under my belt and a part beach, part tourist, part theme park vacation under my belt; so why not try a ski trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It never crossed my mind that we're not skiers, so off to the Montage in Deer Valley, Utah we went. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was scared long before we ever arrived. Friends asked how I would do it. "There's so much equipment," "How will you carry both of their boots and skis," "Wow, good luck, that's a lot of work." Everyone thought I was crazy. A non-skiing mom and two boys who have never skied before trekking across the country to ski every day, all day, for five days. What if the boys hated skiing? "Bribery," I was told. "Have chocolate on the way in, and chocolate waiting on the way out."  Sounded good to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a disaster I thought!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how wrong everyone turned out to be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It couldn't have gone smoother. All dressed in layers, ready to face the day. No problem. Snacks packed -- no problem; boots, skis and poles -- no problem. Ski school... best invention ever.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With tears rolling down my face (hopefully hidden by my sunglasses), I dropped the boys off for ski school at 10 a.m. the first day. By 1:00 p.m., my spying served its purpose. I knew we would all enjoy the trip. In less than three hours, my boys were standing on skis and smiling. I picked them up by 3:30 every afternoon to hugs, smiles and enthusiasm for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of ski school for the kids meant moments of beauty and freedom for me. I may not have had a spouse to take turns with or pass the kids off to, but ski school served that purpose for me.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the best part about the trip wasn't the just the skiing, the swimming or the daily smores outside the hotel with our friends. The best part went back to my mother's saying, and this time even deeper.  It was not only the seeing my kids experience something new, but also the joy and confidence this new skill brought them.  The drive and determination to get back out there to keep learning, to keep improving and to thoroughly enjoy something so new for all of us.  And that is a vision I will never forget and one I will continue to create for my boys.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094562/thumbs/s-SKIING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Why This Couch Is Cursed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/funny-divorce_n_3111547.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111547</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T23:32:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-19T05:43:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There's no shortage of weird objects to be found on Craigslist. Who doesn't need a Free VCR with a porno video stuck in it? Or...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There's no shortage of weird objects to be found on Craigslist. Who &lt;em&gt;doesn't&lt;/em&gt; need a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/26/free-craigslist-ads-theres-a-reason-its-free_n_2190902.html#slide=1569224" target="_hplink"&gt;Free VCR&lt;/a&gt; with a porno video stuck in it? Or a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/05/12/apartment-16-cats_n_861161.html" target="_hplink"&gt;furnished apartment that comes with 16 cats&lt;/a&gt;? (Hint: We don't.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we bring you a new, ridiculous Craigslist ad, this one advertising a "divorce couch." What, exactly, is a "divorce couch"? Just ask &lt;a href="http://imgur.com/gallery/sGbEW" target="_hplink"&gt;Imgur user angelradness&lt;/a&gt;, who tried to pawn off the couch on Craigslist after it brought bad relationship luck to her and its past owners. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Single-handedly responsible for 3 divorces and one long term relationship breakup," she wrote. "Successfully kept one divorcee single for two years. A proven track record!" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the full ad below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class="imgur-album" width="100%" height="550" frameborder="0" src="http://imgur.com/a/sGbEW/embed"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unhappily married couples, we have found the couch for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you think of this anti-love seat below, then click through the slideshow below for some of the most ridiculous ads we've ever come across on craiglist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--2683--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094106/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-COUCH-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Biggest Thing Missing From The Divorce Process</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/the-most-important-thing-_n_3112416.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112416</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T22:09:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:07:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Divorce has become so common place in our society that when we hear of a neighbor or friend divorcing we have a tendency to shrug...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>divorcesupport.about.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Divorce has become so common place in our society that when we hear of a neighbor or friend divorcing we have a tendency to shrug it off as just another divorce. I know that before I went through my own divorce, I didn't give much thought to the experiences of those I knew who were divorcing or had divorced.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094356/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How To Co-Parent When You Can't Stand Your Ex</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/five-tips-for-coparenting_0_n_3112613.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112613</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T22:08:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:07:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The process of divorce is hard enough, but when you have to co-parent with an ex who has become the bane of your existence, things...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.goodtherapy.org</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The process of divorce is hard enough, but when you have to co-parent with an ex who has become the bane of your existence, things can get worse. Some parents become better at being caregivers after divorce because they find their own voice and style outside the relationship. Others transform into an unrecognizable version of themselves, making parenting a horribly intolerable experience. Either way, when you can’t stand the person you are parenting with, life can become a drag, and the battle becomes exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094413/thumbs/s-FIGHTING-FAMILY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Truth About Being A Single Mom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/the-truth-about-being-a-s_n_3112633.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3112633</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T22:08:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T22:07:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>AS a five-year veteran of the single mom gig, I’ve been on a constant emotional rollercoaster—feeling like queen of the universe for potty-training my son...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.businessmirror.com.ph</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;AS a five-year veteran of the single mom gig, I’ve been on a constant emotional rollercoaster—feeling like queen of the universe for potty-training my son in a month, panicking at 3 am as I nurse his 104-degree fever, and even doing a happy dance after dropping him off at day care. I’m free, I think...even though I’m headed straight to work. Then there’s the sinking guilt of raising my son without his father and the exhaustion of having to do it all. Being a single mom is pretty much as tough as it’s cracked up to be, but that doesn’t mean I don’t love it.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094428/thumbs/s-SINGLE-MOM-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dr. Jane Greer: Jane Seymour and James Keach: Twenty Years Married, Why Doesn't It Get Easier?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-jane-greer/jane-seymour-and-james-ke_b_3103119.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3103119</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T21:00:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:00:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Sometimes enough is enough, and it takes a lot of courage to end a marriage after so many years together. One way to avoid reaching that point is to make sure those trust issues that appeared in the earlier years of your marriage don't go unchecked or ignored.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Dr. Jane Greer</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-jane-greer/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;After two decades of marriage, actress Jane Seymour and her husband, director James Keach, have decided to part ways. Seymour, a former Bond girl and star of Dr. Quinn Medicine Woman, has been married three times before. Keach had been married twice before. The two wed in 1993 and have 17-year-old twin sons. While neither have stated reasons for the separation, confirming only that they are living apart and negotiating a settlement, reports suggest it may have something to do with his infidelity.&lt;em&gt; The Daily Mail&lt;/em&gt; reported that a source close to the couple said, "James is a very charismatic man, but he's a flirt and has a wandering eye. They've been having trust issues."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, trust issues. Let me first begin by saying it is always a jolt when a couple has been married for a long time and then decides to end it. It is unnerving and hard to understand why and how they prevailed for so long but didn't ultimately succeed at their union. Shouldn't marriage get easier as time goes on? Certainly by now they must have figured out how to adjust to each other's needs and make things work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This takes me back to the trust issues. Sometimes there are problems that surface early in a marriage that are simply swept under the rug. Maybe the couple tried to deal with whatever was in question, but they were busy, with new careers and perhaps with kids. Life was coming at them full throttle and they might not have had the energy or focus needed to get to the foundation of the trouble. They were probably also quite hopeful that this person they chose to spend the rest of their life with was the right choice. And they were pretty committed to proving that fact, for the sake of their lives together and for their family -- the one that might already existed or the one they dreamt about creating in the future. So they let unresolved issues go by, even excusing some questionable behavior. And thus at least momentarily they jumped the hurdle of whatever they were upset about. But if that problem was not fully resolved, to its core, it can sink deep and take root where it can smolder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flash forward fifteen or twenty years. Imagine that those unresolved issues have been there all that time, beneath that argument they have over and over about the thermostat or keeping the car clean. In my book&lt;em&gt; What About Me? Stop Selfishness From Ruining Your Relationship,&lt;/em&gt; I talk about The Never Ending Fight in which a couple has the same heated disagreement over and over and over. Every time it crops up it is open warfare. The years have gone by, but the issues are the same, and now each person doesn't have quite the hope or the tolerance they did at the beginning of their marriage. In addition to that, the time they have shared has only served to clarify the odds between them. It gets to the point where they have hit their last nerve, and so the marriage finally begins to crumble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn't funny, but it does remind me of a joke. Bessy and Sam go to see a marriage counselor after 50 years of marriage. Bessy says she wants a divorce. The marriage counselor asks her why, after all these years, is she making that decision now? And Bessy answers, "Because enough is enough!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes enough is enough, and it takes a lot of courage to end a marriage after so many years together. One way to avoid reaching that point is to make sure those trust issues that appeared in the earlier years of your marriage don't go unchecked or ignored. Take the time then to work through them. More than anything people want to feel they are safe in their union and they can trust their spouse. But if that remains elusive, and you are truly unhappy, don't let the amount of time that you have shared hold you back from making an important change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please tune in to "Let's Talk Sex" which streams live on HealthyLife.net every last Tuesday of the month at 2 PM EST, 11 AM Pacific. We look forward to listener call-in questions, dealing with relationships, intimacy, family, and friendships, at 1.800.555.5453.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connect with Dr. Jane Greer on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/DrJaneGreer" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and be sure to follow @DrJaneGreer on Twitter for her latest insights on love, relationships, sex, and intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on Dr. Greer, visit http://www.drjanegreer.com.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1019423/thumbs/s-JANE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jennifer Ball: Growing Pains: A Tale of Forgiveness</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-ball/growing-pains-a-tale-of-f_b_3091188.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3091188</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:50:24Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:50:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I have forgiven. I forgave him, and I didn't even realize it. Oh how I fought it. Tooth and nail, I did. I looked like a dog being dragged into the veterinarian's office, probably. Claws dug into the floor, neck straining against the pull of the leash.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jennifer Ball</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-ball/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;You know how, when you were little and you'd approach your mom or dad with some sort of mystery ailment? "Mommy, my legs hurt!" you'd exclaim, offering up your little shins for their inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Sweetheart... those are growing pains" they would say, giving you a comforting touch or kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder, if I were to go to doctor today with these odd maladies I'm experiencing, what they would say. When I presented them with my symptoms: a twinge in my heart now and then, an odd pulled feeling in my soul... would they, too, offer me the same prognosis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh, Jenny. No worries. Those are growing pains, my dear."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I think I'm growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the first symptoms not too long ago. The kids would mention something about their dad, or something about the mistress-turned-stepmom or their little half-brother. And instead of snarling or feeling sick or thinking something awful about it, I felt... nothing. Okay, maybe that's exaggerating. I still felt a little bit of the old hurt, the scar from the knife wound in my back would throb just the tiniest bit, but still. It was becoming almost imperceptible. The conversation would come and go and we'd be onto the next dozen subjects before it would occur me: "It doesn't feel so bad anymore."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started a rage-y and ranting essay about the subject of forgiveness, and why I hate that word and all that it implies. How offended I am whenever I am told that it's my job to forgive, how my life will change oh-so-much when I finally, finally forgive my ex-husband for all the wrongs, for all of the grievous injuries he has inflicted upon me and our kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was about a third of the way through that post when it dawned on me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have forgiven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forgave him, and I didn't even realize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh how I fought it. Tooth and nail, I did. I looked like a dog being dragged into the veterinarian's office, probably. Claws dug into the floor, neck straining against the pull of the leash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Forgive him? Seriously? Look what he's done, look at this mess he's left behind. How am I supposed to forgive him?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind, forgiving him was akin to presenting him with a "Get Out of Jail Free" card. It was offering him absolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, just this morning, I finally realized that the card isn't for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That anger, that hurt, that grief... it was necessary, I believe. Necessary and natural. Who wouldn't wail and moan after being hurt so deep? It got me through the darkest of days and it fueled me when I ran out of other resources to just.keep.going. It motivated me and spurred me along and kept shooting imaginary bullets at my feet just to keep them moving. To keep me dancing this slow waltz of recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would read other tales of forgiveness and feel shame because I didn't have that capacity, nor did I have the desire, to forgive. I didn't want to let go of the red blanket of rage that I had snuggled with for so long. Its heat kept me warm. It gave me desperately needed security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until I didn't need it anymore. I am marching forward now, taller and stronger than ever before. I know that what I've been through has sucked and at times, almost killed me. But I wouldn't be where I am today without it. For every tear shed, there has been a laugh or a hug or a smile. For every time I cursed the man who left me, there has been a sweet, shadowy memory of the man he once was, the best friend I once had. And for that, I'm grateful. Grateful that the hate and anger didn't wipe out those old images of him, nor did they squelch my ability to love and be loved in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll never forget what has happened. I don't think I could, even if I wanted to. I still drive past my old street and feel fresh tears threatening when I catch a glimpse of the little house I lost. I still get mad when I'm single-handedly dealing with a petulant, angry teenager and I picture my ex-husband playing with his toddler, singing "The Wheels on The Mother-Effing Bus." I still feel all of that, and so much more. But the feelings come, they flit around behind my eyes for just a bit. And then they go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't have any secret recipes for forgiveness, no mantra or step-by-step how-to instructions. Maybe I had to wait until we had our last meeting in court. Maybe it had to grow at its own slow-as-molasses pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know this: once you've forgiven, you will know. You will feel it, like a growing pain... in your heart, in your mind, and in your soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And only then can you get on with your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm using my Get Out of Jail free card now, folks. I'm busting out. And it feels good.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/845656/thumbs/s-FORGIVENESS-mini.jpg?4" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jane Seymour: Divorce Is 'Devastating'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/jane-seymour-james-keach-_n_3111069.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111069</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:39:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:13:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>On Thursday, actress Jane Seymour sat down with the "The View" co-hosts to talk candidly about her recent split from actor/director James Keach -- her...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;On Thursday, actress Jane Seymour &lt;a href="http://beta.abc.go.com/shows/the-view/video/PL5554876/_m_VD55298006" target="_hplink"&gt;sat down with the "The View" co-hosts &lt;/a&gt;to talk candidly about her&lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691269,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt; recent split from actor/director James Keach&lt;/a&gt; -- her &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691269,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;husband of 20 years&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Obviously, it's really devastating," &lt;a href="http://beta.abc.go.com/shows/the-view/video/PL5554876/_m_VD55298006" target="_hplink"&gt;the former Bond girl said&lt;/a&gt;. "It did happen a while ago. It was sort of kept quiet." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, Seymour's rep &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691269,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;confirmed to People magazine&lt;/a&gt; that the estranged pair had been &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691269,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;separated for several months&lt;/a&gt; and were now in the process of &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691269,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;negotiating the terms of their divorce.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But unlike &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/12/celebrities-who-dissed-exes_n_2456593.html" target="_hplink"&gt;many celebrity splits&lt;/a&gt;, the breakup of their marriage seems to be anything but acrimonious. Just one day after&lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/jane-seymour-marriage-over-kicks-husband-out-malibu-mansion/" target="_hplink"&gt; reports of their split&lt;/a&gt; began circulating, Seymour and Keach &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2309198/Jane-Seymour-estranged-husband-James-Keach-reunite-announcing-divorce-charity-event.html#ixzz2QYGNN7Fe" target="_hplink"&gt;appeared together on the red carpet&lt;/a&gt; at her &lt;a href="http://www.openheartsfoundation.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;Open Hearts Foundation&lt;/a&gt; charity event.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On "The View," she confirmed that &lt;a href="http://www.orlandosentinel.com/entertainment/blogs/tv-guy/os-jane-seymour-on-divorce-its-life-it-happens-20130418,0,779739.post" target="_hplink"&gt;she and Keach remain friends&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We open our hearts to one another. We respect one another," &lt;a href="http://beta.abc.go.com/shows/the-view/video/PL5554876/_m_VD55298006" target="_hplink"&gt;Seymour said&lt;/a&gt;. "We've been together 22 years, and we will be together the rest of our lives raising our children and doing things like the Open Hearts Foundation."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former couple has a pair of &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20691269,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;17-year-old twin boys &lt;/a&gt;together. This will be the &lt;a href="http://www.express.co.uk/news/showbiz/391939/Bond-actress-Jane-Seymour-62-in-divorce-number-4" target="_hplink"&gt;fourth divorce&lt;/a&gt; for Seymour and the &lt;a href="http://news-briefs.ew.com/2013/04/13/jane-seymour-james-keach-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;third for Keach&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href="http://beta.abc.go.com/shows/the-view/video/PL5554876/_m_VD55298006" target="_hplink"&gt;"The View"&lt;/a&gt; to watch Seymour's interview. Then, click through the slideshow below to see photos of the actress throughout the years. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--208843--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1093897/thumbs/s-JANE-SEYMOUR-JAMES-KEACH-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Do Open Relationships Work?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/open-relationship_n_3111130.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111130</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:38:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:37:31Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Are open marriages ever a good idea? That's the question HuffPost Divorce blogger Vicki Larson considered in a blog post Monday. Since so many "romances...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Are open marriages ever a good idea? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the question HuffPost Divorce blogger &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/vicki-larson/whats-so-wrong-with-an-op_b_3032948.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Vicki Larson considered in a blog post Monday.&lt;/a&gt; Since so many "romances end because of cheating," Larson says she wonders why more couples aren't more transparent about the sometimes-difficult realities of monogamy -- and why they're so scared of the idea of an open relationship. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Why is the idea of an open relationship so threatening," &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/vicki-larson/whats-so-wrong-with-an-op_b_3032948.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Larson writes,&lt;/a&gt; "especially when it's clear that many are having nonmonogamous relationships anyway while pretending they're monogamous?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were curious to know if our readers agreed with Larson's take on open marriage, so we asked them to share their thoughts on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce?ref=tn_tnmn" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Click through the slideshow below to see some of the most interesting responses, then head to the comments to share your opinion on open relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--292768--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094031/thumbs/s-OPEN-MARRIAGES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Is He Cheating? Answer Depends On One Thing...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/is-he-cheating_n_3111712.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111712</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T20:37:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:54:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What constitutes cheating? Cristen Conger, co-host of the "Stuff Mom Never Told You" podcast, recently tackled that topic along with her professor boyfriend Chris. Using...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ashley Reich</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ashley-reich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;What constitutes cheating?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.howstuffworks.com/author/cconger/" target="_hplink"&gt;Cristen Conger&lt;/a&gt;, co-host of the "Stuff Mom Never Told You" podcast, recently tackled that topic along with her professor boyfriend Chris. Using a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/22/what-is-cheating_n_2743853.html" target="_hplink"&gt;University of Michigan study&lt;/a&gt; entitled "&lt;a href="http://www.epjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/EP11159171.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;Was That Cheating? Perceptions Vary by Sex, Attachment Anxiety, and Behavior&lt;/a&gt;" as a jumping off point, the pair examined several behaviors that &lt;a href="http://live.huffingtonpost.com/r/segment/512b22e402a76028490008e4" target="_hplink"&gt;may or may not count as cheating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up for discussion? Hugging someone of the opposite sex for more than 10 seconds, spending the night in the same bed, sending naked pictures to one another and other questionable behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above for their take, then click through the slideshow below for behaviors our readers &lt;em&gt;don't&lt;/em&gt; consider cheating. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--247370--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094293/thumbs/s-CHEATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>George Lopez Is Back</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/george-lopez-show-fx-saint-george_n_3111722.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3111722</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T19:56:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T20:16:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There's a new George Lopez show on the way! FX has picked up Lopez's half-hour sitcom "Saint George," which he co-created and will star in....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jaimie Etkin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jaimie-etkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There's a new &lt;a href="http://www.nickatnite.com/shows/george-lopez/" target="_hplink"&gt;George Lopez show&lt;/a&gt; on the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FX has picked up Lopez's half-hour sitcom "Saint George," which he co-created and will star in. The new &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Lopez_(TV_series)" target="_hplink"&gt;Lopez show&lt;/a&gt; marks the comedian's first starring TV role since "George Lopez" ended its six-season run on ABC in May 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Saint George" will be a multi-camera ensemble comedy that centers on the chaotic life of a recently divorced working class Mexican-American turned successful entrepreneur (Lopez). He struggles to balance his demanding ex-wife, his 11-year-old son, his overbearing mother who just moved in, and his uncle, as well as his new role as a philanthropist “giving back” by teaching history once a  week at a night school.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm excited about my new show, couldn't think a better group of people or better place to create than FX," Lopez said in a statement. "Now to get ready ... Back to Pilates!" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FX ordered "Saint George" under the 10/90 model: Ten episodes will be made and if the series earns a certain level of ratings succes over it first 10-episode run, FX will order an additional 90 episodes. The model has been successful in recent history with another FX series "Anger Management" and Tyler Perry’s "House of Payne" and "Meet The Browns" on TBS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“George Lopez is an incredibly gifted actor-producer and one of the most talented comedians in the business,” Chuck Saftler, FX's executive vice president, said in a statement. "The 10/90 model requires a unique individual who has the ability to pull off this kind of daunting schedule. George is that guy and we couldn’t be happier that he chose FX as the home for his new project.”&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Matt Williams and his Wind Dancer Films partner David McFadzean co-created "Saint George" with Lopez. The trio will serve as executive producers and will also co-write the first episode of the series. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Production on &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0310460/" target="_hplink"&gt;Lopez's new show&lt;/a&gt; is set to begin in August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/28/george-lopez-new-sitcom_n_1307519.html&lt;br /&gt;
" target="_hplink"&gt;News of Lopez's new series first broke in February 2012&lt;/a&gt; and though "Saint George" marks Lopez's return to sitcoms, it's not his first time back on TV. The comedian had a late-night run on TBS with "Lopez Tonight," which ran from 2009 to 2011, and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/06/08/take-me-out-george-lopez-flirty-thirty-dating-show-video_n_1579830.html" target="_hplink"&gt;hosted Fox's dating game show "Take Me Out"&lt;/a&gt; in the summer of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think about &lt;a href="http://www.deadline.com/2013/04/fx-picks-up-new-george-lopez-sitcom-in-1090-deal-with-lionsgatedebmar-mercury/" target="_hplink"&gt;Lopez's upcoming show&lt;/a&gt;? Will you watch? Sound off in the comments!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094159/thumbs/s-GEORGE-LOPEZ-SHOW-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: The Perfect Color For Small Spaces</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/maxwell-ryan-apartment-therapy-video_n_3109749.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3109749</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T19:32:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T19:30:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It can fool your eyes into thinking the room is much bigger. </summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelle-manetti/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you're living in a home that's 500 square feet or less, it can be difficult to make it feel anything but tiny. So, when &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/maxwellat" target="_hplink"&gt;Maxwell Ryan&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;a href="http://apartmenttherapy.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Apartment Therapy&lt;/a&gt;, joined our very own &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brie-dyas/" target="_hplink"&gt;Brie Dyas&lt;/a&gt; on HuffPost Live, our readers were  curious to learn some &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/martha-stewart-small-space-decorating_n_3085607.html" target="_hplink"&gt;small space tips&lt;/a&gt; that could help to open up a teeny home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan suggested removing unnecessary doors, especially those that are &lt;a href="http://www.homedepot.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/Navigation?&amp;N=5yc1vZ1xr5Z1erZ1z13yjj" target="_hplink"&gt;accordion-style&lt;/a&gt;. According to Ryan, old houses often have non-functional doors that can cause clutter, making the space look smaller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also recommended painting walls white, while keeping floors dark by either staining them or adding an accent rug. Ryan said the brighter the walls, the bigger the space will look. "If [the space] is light, bright and expansive, you'll have the feeling of bigness, even if the square footage is relatively small." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above to hear what else Ryan had to say about the topic. And be sure to click through our slideshow to see tips on &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/15/sabrina-soto-spring-home-makeover_n_2883914.html" target="_hplink"&gt;how to decorate a small space&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--292079--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1094101/thumbs/s-MAXWELL-RYAN-APARTMENT-THERAPY-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Kim Kardashian's Not Going To Like This...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/18/kim-kardashians-ugly-cry_n_3101881.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3101881</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-18T16:13:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-18T21:01:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We love a good ugly cry -- especially when it's Kim Kardashian who's shedding the tears. Sure, it's a rare person who looks attractive when...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;We love a good ugly cry -- &lt;em&gt;especially &lt;/em&gt;when it's Kim Kardashian who's shedding the tears. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it's a rare person who looks attractive when the waterworks come on, but if seven seasons of "Keeping Up With the Kardashians" have taught us anything, it's that the 32-year-old reality star has a tendency to look a little less than perfect when crying. Who could forget the mascara-stained tears that rolled down her face when she admitted that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/01/27/kim-kardashian-divorce-ki_n_1237338.html" target="_hplink"&gt;her marriage to Kris Humphries hit the skids?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, &lt;a href="http://www.sugarscape.com/main-topics/lol/841735/kim-kardashians-top-5-ugly-cry-faces-lol" target="_hplink"&gt;that infamous divorce breakdown&lt;/a&gt; is immortalized in the form of an iPhone case &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kim-Kardashian-Crying-IPhone-Case/dp/B00AT75K8Q" target="_hplink"&gt;for sale on Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="kim kardashian iphone case" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1092401/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price of the case itself? $15.99. Seeing Kim K's crying face every time you pick up your phone? Priceless. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you think of the case in the comments, then click through the slideshow below for 23 celebrities, including Kardashian, getting their cry on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--269158--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1092530/thumbs/s-KIM-KARDASHIAN-UGLY-CRYING-FACE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
