<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marni Battista: What To Look For In Your Next Husband</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marni-battista/what-to-look-for-in-a-hus_b_2879685.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2879685</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T06:01:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T06:01:26Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When you're looking for a serious relationship after divorce, remember that like attracts like. Working on your own happiness is a great first step in moving to toward a healthy, loving relationship.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marni Battista</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marni-battista/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When you're finally ready to remarry post-divorce, you need to know what characteristics to look for in a husband. Although you've been married previously,  we're willing to guess that you didn't have a checklist before you took your vows! To help when you're looking for a long lasting, serious(ly) fun relationship that has the possibility of leading to marriage, here are five traits you should look for in a guy: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His actions match his words.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most important traits to look for in a long-term mate is that what they do is consistent with what they say they're going to do. If he calls when he says he's going to call, arrives when he says he's going to arrive, and is consistent over time, you can safely assume that this type of behavior will continue throughout the course of your relationship. When you decide to commit to each other, having someone who you can count on to do what he says he's going to do is &lt;em&gt;crucial&lt;/em&gt; and will contribute to a happy, healthy relationship (provided you do the same).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He has strong communication skills.&lt;/strong&gt;  Guys who are able to identify their feelings, express them appropriately andnmanage them will most likely have an easier time being in a relationship with a mature woman who has the same skills. Although it can be attractive at first when a guy is closed off and mysterious, as time goes on you're probably going to get frustrated. Having important conversations about commitment, kids and finances is going to be extremely difficult if your guy can't tell you his opinion. When you find a guy who can tell you clearly how he feels and is someone you can agree and disagree with in a healthy way, he might be the guy you want to put a ring on your finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He can take charge and make decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;  When you get married, having a spouse who can handle a difficult situation makes all the difference in the world. This doesn't mean you should look for someone who orders for you (or orders you around!), but if you find a guy who can masterfully solve a problem or protect you from a threat (even if it's just a pushy salesman), it's an amazing trait that you will want your long-term mate to have in his arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He has a great sense of humor.&lt;/strong&gt;  Any man who can see the lighter side of a somewhat serious situation is a great catch -- provided he does it in an appropriate way, of course. Finding a guy with a solid sense of humor moves him closer to the husband material category. If he makes you laugh when you're feeling down or helps lighten up your mood, you may have struck upon a diamond in the rough. Don't let this guy get away too fast; laughter can keep relationships fun and exciting, and a good belly laugh always makes any day better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He shares a similar value set.&lt;/strong&gt; When you're looking for "the one" -- the person you're likely to be with forever (or at least for a long time) -- sharing the same values is  make-it-or-break-it. Perhaps it's common religious beliefs, if that means a lot to you, or even having the same views on family or raising kids if you decide to have them. Sharing values will not only bring you closer together, but it will also help to solidify your bond in the long term. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you're looking for a serious relationship after divorce, remember that like attracts like. Working on your own happiness is a great first step in moving to toward a healthy, loving relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050500/thumbs/s-WHAT-TO-LOOK-FOR-IN-NEXT-HUSBAND-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jamie McGonnigal: Husband Threatens Custody Suit After Ex-wife Befriends 'Known Homosexual'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jamie-mcgonnigal/custody-suit-ex-wife-gay-friend_b_2926903.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2926903</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T22:16:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T22:16:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kelly's friend Chris has no record of being a child predator, or really any criminal record whatsoever, but the lawyer's letter also threatens to pursue criminal proceedings against him merely for babysitting Kelly's son.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jamie McGonnigal</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jamie-mcgonnigal/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Here's one for the books. A Roman Catholic father in Maryland has asked his lawyer, Paul C. Sullivan, to pen one of the most horrific pieces of undeniable bigotry that I have seen in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed Taylor and Kelly Robertson were married, had two sons and then divorced (as has been known to happen). Kelly was awarded custody of the children, with visitation rights for Ed. Since then, it seems that Kelly has become friends with a gay man, Chris. Kelly has since remarried, and she sometimes asks Chris to babysit her kids (as has been known to happen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, that's not OK with ultra-Catholic Ed. The following letter was sent to Kelly with regard to her parenting. In the letter, Paul Sullivan engages in a homophobic tirade ignorantly linking being gay with being a child predator, claiming that by having a gay person around the house, Kelly is "encouraging a homosexual lifestyle," and threatening investigations and custody trials should Kelly not reverse the child's dangerous course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the lawyer and father have been in communication with the sheriff, the county commissioners, the vice principal and the guidance counselor of the middle school that Kelly's son attends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly's friend Chris has no record of being a child predator, or really any criminal record whatsoever, but the lawyer's letter also threatens to pursue criminal proceedings against him merely for babysitting Kelly's son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this were 1950, I might understand some of the homophobic and vitriolic things being claimed here by Paul Sullivan, but it's 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the full text of the letter, followed by images of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Dear Mrs. XXXXXX
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;I have been retained by Mr. XXX again to address parenting issues related to your two (2) sons. As you know, there has been considerable difficulty recently related to your refusal to support and encourage the children's Roman Catholic faith and certain biblical precepts related to lifestyle choices. It appears as if you are encouraging a homosexual lifestyle for the children and allowing your eldest, XXXX at age 13 to be placed in an environment where he could, and likely would, be exposed to a child predator.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;As you know this case was previously assigned to Judge Kenneth long who is currently the administrative judge for the Washington County Circuit Court in Hagerstown. In the event you continue the destructive parenting that encourages XXXX' exploration of decadent choices in behavior, we will have no alternative but to file to obtain sole legal custody and sole physical custody of both children. We have been in communication with Sheriff XXXX, the vice principal of XXXX Middle School, the guidance counselor at XXXX Middle School and the president of the XXXX County Commissioners, seeking their assistance and support in helping XXXX change the path which you seem to be encouraging.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;It may be necessary for us to file a CINA petition, because the actions taken at his school related to detention do not seem to be having any corrective effect. This child appears to be out of control because of your refusal to co-parent with Mr. XXXX on Saturday, March 16th at 8:30 PM as ordered by the court. It is our understanding that you allowed XXXX to stay overnight at the home of a known homosexual whose probable intentions related to XXXX are suspect. Further investigation may lead to the request for criminal charges against that individual due to XXXX minority.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;We're attempting to obtain additional assistance to help XXXX abate the current course you have encouraged him to travel. You seem not to understand the eventual adverse consequences that may occur for XXXX and which could adversely affect him for a lifetime.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;If, however, you would be taking the position in court that you are not encouraging XXXX in the way it is believed you are, and are in fact unable to adequately discipline XXXX or institute and enforce parental boundaries that are needed, you certainly have the option to enter into a consent decree allowing Mr. XXXX to have sole legal and sole physical custody of the children so that he will have the authority, within the bounds of law, to take the corrective action needed to safeguard the best interests of the children.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Please do not hesitate to contact me if you have any questions concerning this matter. If you are agreeable to the entry of a consent order as suggested above, please call me at your earliest convenience and I will prepare it for your review and signature.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Thank you and kindest regards,
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Very truly yours,
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;Paul C. Sullivan&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHOTOS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-392930_10200966632633571_559762508_n.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-392930_10200966632633571_559762508_n.jpg" width="600" height="825" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-21-580977_10200966632793575_1531958428_n.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-21-580977_10200966632793575_1531958428_n.jpg" width="600" height="825" /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some further research and a conversation with Kelly has brought some more information to light. It turns out that Ed has released some videos about his wife, "&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JUbOhjSUXzw" target="_hplink"&gt;The Drug Slut&lt;/a&gt;," and it turns out that their son's "behavior problems" include getting detention for talking in class and simply not wanting to participate in the extreme dogma that his father tries to force upon him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ed's organization, Maryland's Fathers Rights League, is also known for lobbying against the &lt;a href="http://wn.com/righteous_anger_of_exiled_fathers,_the_only_sane_response" target="_hplink"&gt;Violence Against Women Act&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050342/thumbs/s-EDTAYLORCUSTODYSUITLETTER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The 30 Best Things About Being A Single Parent </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/single-parents_n_2925671.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925671</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T21:43:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T21:42:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Happy National Single Parent Day! Did you even know it was a holiday? In 1984, President Ronald Reagan officially designated March 21 as the day...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Happy &lt;a href="http://www.reagan.utexas.edu/archives/speeches/1984/32184d.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;National Single Parent Day&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you even know it was a holiday? In 1984, President Ronald Reagan &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/march-21-national-single-parent-day-fragrance-day-210600839.html" target="_hplink"&gt;officially designated March 21&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; day to acknowledge the hard work of single parents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the day never received the same level of recognition as Mother's Day, or those other Hallmark card-endorsed holidays, we think it's high time it did. After all, there are nearly &lt;a href="http://parenting.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/05/21/single-dads-are-different/" target="_hplink"&gt;14 million single parents doing double duty in the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the holiday, we took a page from Kerri Zane and her &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kerri-zane/5-reasons-its-better-to-b_b_2854313.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;blog post on the perks of being a single parent&lt;/a&gt; and asked our readers what they liked best about parenting solo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to see what they had to say, then head to the comments and share what you think is the best thing about single parenting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287672--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049854/thumbs/s-SINGLE-PARENT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Billionaire Romney Backer Embroiled In Record-Setting Divorce Battle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/harold-hamm-divorce_n_2926784.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2926784</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T20:39:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T20:49:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By Brian Grow and Joshua Schneyer ATLANTA/NEW YORK (Reuters) - Continental Resources chief executive Harold Hamm, one of America's wealthiest and most influential businessmen, is...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Reuters</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jillian-berman/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;By Brian Grow and Joshua Schneyer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATLANTA/NEW YORK (Reuters) - Continental Resources chief executive Harold Hamm, one of America's wealthiest and most influential businessmen, is embroiled in a contentious divorce that could lead to a record financial settlement and threaten his control of America's fastest-growing oil company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sue Ann Hamm, Harold Hamm's second wife and a former executive at Continental, filed for divorce on May 19, 2012, Oklahoma court records show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documents in the case are sealed. But in a March 7, 2013 filing obtained by Reuters, Sue Ann Hamm alleges that Harold "was having an affair" that she discovered in 2010, prompting her to later file for divorce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harold Hamm, 67, is a leading force behind the U.S. oil boom and served as the senior energy adviser to Republican presidential candidate Mitt Romney's campaign. Time magazine named him one of the most influential people in the world, and Forbes listed him last year among the 50 richest Americans. Ranked No. 35, Hamm is worth $11.3 billion, the magazine estimated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His estranged wife, Sue Ann Hamm, 56, has held key posts at Continental. She has led oil-industry trade groups in Oklahoma, testified to Congress on behalf of Continental and created Continental's oil and gas marketing units. She is no longer with the company, her lawyer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hamms were married in April 1988 and have two adult children, Jane and Hilary. Harold Hamm has three children from a prior marriage that ended in divorce in 1987.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether the Hamms signed a prenuptial agreement is unclear. Legal analysts who reviewed court filings said that without one, the case could lead to a record-breaking financial settlement - one that could exceed the $1.7 billion paid by News Corp. founder and chairman Rupert Murdoch to ex-wife Anna in 1999. One outcome could be a split of "marital property" that may include dividing Harold Hamm's controlling 68 percent stake in Continental, currently worth $11.2 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't know of anything that's ever been this big," said Barbara Atwood, professor emeritus of family law at the University of Arizona. "There's just so much money involved."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continental was subpoenaed in the case last summer, and it was ordered by the Oklahoma court to hand over documents late last year. Four other companies controlled by Hamm also were subpoenaed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A review of Continental's Securities and Exchange Commission filings and company statements shows no mention of the divorce proceedings. Although corporate governance scholars said Continental had no legal obligation to disclose the Hamms' divorce proceedings to shareholders, "It's a lawsuit that involves a potential impact on the controlling shareholder," said Charles Elson, director of The Weinberg Center for Corporate Governance at the University of Delaware. "Certainly, it would be relevant to an investor if there is going to be or could be a shift in control."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After receiving inquiries from Reuters, Continental put out a news release acknowledging the divorce case. The fight, the company said, "is not anticipated to have any impact or effect on the company's business or operations."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spokeswoman Kristin Miskovsky didn't respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An attorney for Sue Ann Hamm declined to comment, citing a confidentiality agreement governing the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continental shares were trading down 2.1 percent at $86.86 by 3:16 p.m. EDT. They fell as low as $85.85 after the divorce proceedings were acknowledged by Hamm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamm, the 13th child of Oklahoma sharecroppers, started his career at age 20, scrubbing scum out of oil barrels. A few years later, he drilled a 75-barrel-a-day gusher in his home state, helping pay for university classes in geology. He founded Continental in 1967, two decades before he and the former Sue Ann Arnall were married. She is an economist and a lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamm's biggest breakthrough came in the 1990s, when he helped discover the Bakken field of North Dakota, the largest new U.S. oil prospect since the 1960s. The discovery helped Continental lead a resurgence in U.S. oil production, using the controversial drilling method known as hydraulic fracturing, or fracking. The technique pumps water laden with sand and chemicals underground to release previously unreachable oil reserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the Bakken yields nearly 700,000 barrels a day, roughly 10 percent of American output. Continental controls more than 1 million acres in the formation, which stretches from North Dakota to Montana. The firm also owns oil and gas rights in several other states, including Oklahoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continental has said the entire Bakken field - being developed by several companies - may contain 24 billion barrels of oil. That would be enough to meet U.S. oil demand for more than three years. Drilling by Continental alone added 649 million barrels to the company's proved oil reserves between 2008 and 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The firm says it controls drilling leases to more oil-rich Bakken acres than any other company, helping to make Hamm the largest oil baron in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamm directly controls 126.3 million shares, or 68 percent, of Oklahoma City-based Continental and more through family trusts. Those shares alone are worth at least $11.2 billion. Continental shares have risen 21 percent this year and closed on March 20 at $89.15, down 0.6 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But his stake in Continental could change significantly as a result of a divorce settlement. The firm's massive growth occurred during the marriage. Its share price has surged nearly 500 percent in the five years since an initial public offering in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Oklahoma family law, wealth accrued through the efforts of either spouse during a marriage would typically be subject to "equitable distribution" between the parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"A court in Oklahoma may look closely at what each party has contributed," said legal specialist Atwood. "But it sounds to me like both spouses here were working hard in the business."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Where there are concerns about company control in a settlement, a spouse would usually get paid the value of the shares," she said. "This is going to be really interesting."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Court records show that Sue Ann Hamm petitioned for divorce in May 2012. But earlier Oklahoma court records suggest the Hamms' relationship has been rocky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1998, Harold Hamm filed for divorce and demanded that Sue Ann undergo a psychological evaluation. He later withdrew the divorce petition and the case file was ordered destroyed this year, on February 13, according to Oklahoma court records. What prompted the destruction of the file is unclear. In 2005, Sue Ann Hamm subsequently filed for divorce; that case also was dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her 2005 divorce filing is now a key issue in the Hamms' divorce battle, according to a court document reviewed by Reuters. Indeed, it could play a pivotal role in determining how property - including interest in Continental - will be divided, legal analysts said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Harold Hamm, the couple "actually separated in the fall of 2005 and have lived separate lives ever since," the court document says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Sue Ann Hamm's attorneys counter that the Hamms "continued to reside together (although they do own four homes), travel together, attend public functions together, raise their children together, file joint tax returns, and work together."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2012, for instance, Harold and Sue Ann Hamm jointly hosted a fundraiser for Republican presidential candidate Romney at their $3 million mansion in Nichols Hills, Oklahoma, according to photos and media reports. The event raised more than $2 million for the Romney campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last September, Reuters reported that Harold Hamm had made political contributions that exceeded federal legal limits by as much as 41 percent during the 2011-2012 election period. Continental said at the time that the donations were made from an account held jointly by Harold and Sue Ann Hamm and were intended to be split between Hamm and his wife, which would have kept the donations within legal limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Harold and Sue Ann Hamm also jointly gave $20 million to a diabetes center at the University of Oklahoma named for Harold Hamm, who has Type II diabetes. The same year, the couple signed up for Warren Buffett and Bill Gates' Giving Pledge initiative, indicating their intention to dedicate most of their wealth to philanthropy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a court filing two weeks ago, Sue Ann Hamm's attorneys say the Hamms agreed "to engage in marriage counseling sessions in an effort to save their marriage" in November 2010, after Sue Ann Hamm concluded that her husband had been unfaithful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether the Hamms separated in 2005 or more recently is crucial as the court determines how Harold Hamm's assets will be divided, legal analysts said. Under Oklahoma family law, the increase in the value of an asset during marriage is considered part of the total pool of "marital property."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"In general, if you own property prior to the marriage and you bring it to the marriage, it is separate," said Marianne Blair, a professor of family law at the University of Tulsa. "But that separate property can increase in value. To the extent the increase was due to marital efforts or marital funds," it can be divided by the court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamm divorced his first wife, Judith Ann, in 1987, according to Oklahoma court records. A document filed by Sue Ann Hamm's attorneys in the current case shows they received access to marital records in the prior divorce in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attorneys for both Hamms will present evidence about when the couple separated and the resulting "date of valuation of (the) business" on May 20, according to the court docket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's decided could help determine whether their divorce settlement rivals the largest reported divorce settlement to date - the $1.7 billion paid by Murdoch to his ex-wife Anna in 1999. That settlement, in California, directly affected shareholders of News Corp. because it awarded Murdoch's three eldest children stakes in the voting shares of the company. Reports of the Murdoch divorce sent News Corp. shares lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Jaffe, a family law attorney in Beverly Hills, California who represented Anna Murdoch, declined to discuss the Murdoch case. But after reviewing the court docket and document obtained by Reuters in the Hamm case, he said Sue Ann Hamm's decades of work for Continental was unique compared with most divorce cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"She has a leg up because she worked for the company and she can claim that a portion of her efforts went into making the company what it is today," Jaffe said. "She was married to him when the value of the company went up. She has got to be looking for a couple of billion dollars."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Reporting by Brian Grow in Atlanta and Joshua Schneyer in New York; additional reporting by Jeanine Prezioso; editing by Blake Morrison and Michael Williams.)&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050121/thumbs/s-HAROLD-HAMM-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: A Wife's Revenge Against Her Cheating Husband?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/cheating-husband-billboard_n_2924419.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2924419</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T20:26:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T21:33:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A scorned wife in North Carolina appears to have borrowed Mastercard's "priceless" campaign in order to call out her cheating husband on a billboard in...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/katherine-bindley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A scorned wife in North Carolina appears to have borrowed Mastercard's "priceless" campaign in order to call out her &lt;a href="http://myfox8.com/2013/03/20/a-wifes-billboard-revenge-on-battleground-ave/" target="_hplink"&gt;cheating husband on a billboard&lt;/a&gt; in Greensboro, WGHP reports.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Story continues below)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="cheating husband billboard" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049496/thumbs/o-CHEATING-HUSBAND-BILLBOARD-570.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is the sign too good to be true? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local newspaper The News &amp; Record noted that the &lt;a href="http://www.news-record.com/home/941590-63/greensboro-billboard-revenge-against-cheating#continue" target="_hplink"&gt;cheating husband billboard &lt;/a&gt;is owned by Outdoor Signage. When the news outlet asked the company about the sign's legitimacy, they were referred to Marty Kotis at Kotis Properties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marty Kotis did not immediately respond to The Huffington Post's request for comment, but a brief look into the &lt;a href="http://www.snopes.com/love/revenge/emily.asp" target="_hplink"&gt;history of scorned ex-wife billboards&lt;/a&gt; suggests that such displays have been used in the past as marketing ploys. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As myth-debunking site Snopes previously noted, a similarly themed message from a woman named Emily went up in 2006. That billboard was directed at a man named Steven, and said: "Do I have your attention now? I know all about her, you dirty, sneaking, immoral, unfaithful, poorly-endowed slimeball, Everything's caught on tape."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message was signed, "Your (soon-to-be-ex) Wife, Emily." &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The billboard received so much attention that ABC's "Good Morning America" reportedly wanted Emily to come on the show, according to Snopes. However, the message turned out to be marketing material for a reality television show on Court TV. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, not all revenge billboards are gimmicks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signs paid for by a woman named YaVaughnie Wilkins turned out to be legit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilkins claimed to have had an eight-year relationship with a man named Charles Phillips, the New York Post previously reported. However, after he decided to stay with his wife, the &lt;a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/news/national/she_did_whaaat_CTz3l7zyyaJKLywTNaVSrO" target="_hplink"&gt;woman spent about $250,000 advertising their affair&lt;/a&gt; on billboards in multiple locations across the country, including Times Square.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow for five more stories of exes who acted out post-split:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--257277--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch the full news segment below:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script src="http://player.ooyala.com/iframe.js#ec=hoOTZjYToGF_ZfMcJ4V2uMoOD1bPLvNz&amp;pbid=d8f58704137d45e392883052ae837773"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049496/thumbs/s-CHEATING-HUSBAND-BILLBOARD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Daughter Pays Tribute To Single Mom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/single-parent_n_2925670.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925670</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T20:19:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T21:22:20Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In honor of National Single Parent Day on March 21, we wanted to show some appreciation for those parents going at it alone. What better...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;In honor of &lt;a href="http://news.yahoo.com/march-21-national-single-parent-day-fragrance-day-210600839.html" target="_hplink"&gt;National Single Parent Day&lt;/a&gt; on March 21, we wanted to show some appreciation for those parents going at it alone. What better way to do that than by showcasing a thank-you message from someone raised by a single mother?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video above, Olivia Joy Stinson, the founder of &lt;a href="http://penpalsbookclub.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;PEN Pals Book Club For Children of Incarcerated Parents,&lt;/a&gt; praises her mom for "always [making] it work." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I can say that we've never gone without and we've always had everything we've needed. Everything I needed and, on top of that, everything I wanted. I'd see the Barbie this, Barbie that and at Christmas I always had it. No idea how it would happen, but I always had it," she said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stinson -- a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/olivia-stinson/" target="_hplink"&gt;Charlottle, N.C. native&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/olivia-stinson/" target="_hplink"&gt;Winston-Salem State University student&lt;/a&gt; -- runs a charitable organization that &lt;a href="http://penpalsbookclub.org/" target="_hplink"&gt;aims to improve literacy&lt;/a&gt; among kids whose parents are incarcerated and prevent those children from following down the same bad path by &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/olivia-stinson/pen-pals-book-club-and-su_b_2370902.html" target="_hplink"&gt;getting them involved in the community. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above for more on Stinson's tribute to her mother. Then, click through the slides below to see what single parenting looks like to our readers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--260764--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049900/thumbs/s-SINGLE-PARENT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What If Marriage Were Temporary? </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/what-if-marriage-were-tem_n_2925456.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925456</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T20:11:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T20:11:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In Jonathan Swift's 1726 classic Gulliver's Travels, he describes a race of people, the Struldburgs, who are afflicted with the pesky inconvenience of immortality. If...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.theatlantic.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;In Jonathan Swift's 1726 classic Gulliver's Travels, he describes a race of people, the Struldburgs, who are afflicted with the pesky inconvenience of immortality. If two Struldburgs are to marry each other, "of course" the marriage is dissolved, by courtesy of the kingdom, as soon as the younger partner hits 80, "for the law thinks it a reasonable indulgence, that those who are condemned...to a perpetual continuance in the world, should not have their misery doubled by the load of a wife."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1049670/thumbs/s-TEMPORARY-MARRIAGES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kathleen B. Connell: How Divorce Could Complicate Your Tax Filing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kathleen-b-connell/preparing-your-taxes-in-t_b_2911023.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2911023</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T16:04:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T16:03:51Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As if taxes aren't complicated enough, it can get worse during a divorce or separation. There are certain things that individuals going through the divorce process -- or who are recently divorced -- should keep in mind when preparing their taxes.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kathleen B. Connell</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kathleen-b-connell/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;As if taxes aren't complicated enough, it can get worse during a divorce or separation. There are certain things that individuals going through the divorce process -- or who are recently divorced -- should keep in mind when preparing their taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you are going to need to consider your filing status (i.e. "Married Filing Jointly," "Married Filing Single,'' "Head of Household," etc.) The IRS only cares about one day in terms of whether you are married or not, and that is December 31. If you are married on December 31, then it is as if you are married for the whole year -- whether you married on New Year's Eve, or 20 years prior. Likewise, if you get divorced by December 31, it is as if you are divorced for the whole year. So, if your divorce was final by December 31, 2012, then you do not have the option of filing as a married person for your 2012 taxes. Your filing status options are "Head of Household" or "Single."&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Typically, "Head of Household" is going to provide a slight tax advantage over "Married Filing Single" or "Single." However, one should make sure that the requirements to file as "Head of Household" are met:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Whether the taxpayer paid more than one-half of the housing costs during the year;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether the taxpayer lived apart from his or her spouse during the second half of the tax year in question; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whether dependent child(ren) lived in the home for at least one-half of the year.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
 
Another important consideration for the newly or soon-to-be divorced taxpayer is which spouse will claim the child(ren) as the dependant(s). The IRS regulations are clear that the parent with whom the child spends more time may claim the child as his/her dependent. That means that if you look at the custody schedule, and one parent has greater than 50 percent of the year with the child(ren) (even if it is only one day), that particular parent may claim the child as his/her dependent.

&lt;p&gt;However, taxpayers can negotiate and contract around this requirement. In other words, the parent with more than 50 percent of the custodial time may elect to let the other parent claim the child as his/her dependent, but must do so in writing and must execute the required IRS form (Form 8332). If the parents did not negotiate or otherwise come to an agreement on who would claim the child as a dependent, then both parents must file the IRS regulations using "time with the child" as the decision-maker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about paying support (child or spousal)? Regularly, my clients ask about the deductibility of child support. I hate to break it to them, but the IRS will not accept a deduction for paying for the support of one's own children. In the agency's eyes, it is a parent's legal obligation to financially support his/her child. However, under many circumstances, alimony -- or, spousal support -- is tax deductible to the paying spouse and taxable to the receiving spouse. There are certain clawbacks to look out for and a laundry list of requirements, so consult your licensed CPA, but there is potential for a tax deduction and/or the creation of taxable income related to alimony or spousal support that should be investigated.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The transfer of property from one spouse to the other -- whether it is real estate, an investment account, a retirement account, cash, or personal propert -- if made pursuant to a divorce, is not a taxable event. This also includes gift taxes. As the law sees it, you are not making a gift to your spouse or former spouse, you are simply giving him/her their share of the marital estate. The property transferred will retain its original basis for tax purposes so that when it is sold, cashed in, or otherwise disposed of at some point in the future, the tax basis is the same as it was with the spouse who originally held title to that asset. For example, if a husband transfers one-half of his brokerage account to his wife, pursuant to a divorce, the initial transfer is not a taxable event for either individual. However, if the wife starts to liquidate the investments down the road, she will have to pay taxes on those investments based on the original basis in the stocks, bonds or other investments just as if the husband had sold them himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any loss carried forward that the taxpayers have been utilizing will remain available to the taxpayer who held title to the asset. In the event the loss was a result of a jointly titled asset, the IRS presumes that each party gets one-half of any remaining loss carry forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxes can be complicated in any year, but in the year of divorce -- and even subsequent years -- when marital assets are sold or otherwise disposed of or alimony is paid or/received, the tax consequences can be more complicated. Any person who is divorced or thinking about getting divorced should certainly consult with a CPA to ensure that the tax affect related to marital assets and support is taken into account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kathleen B. Connell is a partner and family law attorney with Boyd Collar Nolen &amp; Tuggle, LLC (Atlanta). She serves clients involved in a variety of family law matters, including divorce, custody arrangements, pre- and post-nuptial agreements, and related services. In addition, her financial background - she holds both undergraduate and master's degrees in accounting - enables her to provide guidance on general questions impacting her clients' financial health. She may be reached at &lt;a href="mailto:kconnell@bcntlaw.com" target="_hplink"&gt;kconnell@bcntlaw.com&lt;/a&gt; or (770) 953-4300.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1048358/thumbs/s-TAX-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The New Book That Could Help Simplify Your Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/making-marriage-simple_n_2917305.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2917305</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T15:32:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T16:31:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Incompatibility is grounds for marriage" isn't relationship advice you hear often, but Harville Hendrix, Ph.D. and Helen LaKelly Hunt, Ph.D. are convinced it is exactly...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Huff/Post50</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebecca-klein/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"Incompatibility is grounds for marriage" isn't relationship advice you hear often, but Harville Hendrix, Ph.D. and Helen LaKelly Hunt, Ph.D. are convinced it is exactly the type of thing that couples need to hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Incompatibility plays a crucial role in preparing you and your partner to meet each other’s needs," wrote Hendrix and Hunt in their recent book “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Making-Marriage-Simple-Changing-Relationship/dp/0770437125" target="_hplink"&gt;Making Marriage Simple: 10 Truths For Changing The Relationship You Have Into The One You Want&lt;/a&gt;." "…Honestly, compatibility is grounds for boredom."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Making Marriage Simple" contains the basic truths authors Hendrix and Hunt, ages 77 and 64 respectively, have learned about marriage throughout 30 years together. They found inspiration for the book after overcoming a rough patch, which almost threatened to tear the couple apart 15 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We tried like five therapists, the fifth therapist even called us the couple from hell," said Hunt, whose work in philanthropy got her elected to the &lt;a href="http://www.greatwomen.org/women-of-the-hall/search-the-hall/details/2/81-Hunt" target="_hplink"&gt;National Women’s Hall Of Fame&lt;/a&gt;. “But eventually we mastered [marriage]. We learned how to talk to each other -- we still had issues, but learned how to deal with it in a way so that we still feel intimate at the end of the day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hendrix and Hunt, who &lt;a href="http://www.imagocounseling.com/harville-hendrix-and-helen-lakelly-hunt/" target="_hplink"&gt;now counsel couples around the world&lt;/a&gt;, say negativity was one of the problems that once plagued their marriage. To fix the problem, they made a daily chart that was filled with either a smiley or frown face, depending upon if they made it through the day without negative actions. The idea that "negativity is invisible abuse," is now among one of the basic truths listed in their book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Negativity is like putting toxins in a relationship," said Hendrix. "We made a deliberate attempt to remove the pattern of negativity from our relationship and that was what made the [it] safe again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the other truths espoused in their book are that couples should embrace their incompatibilities and that marriage should be funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Helen is more expressive, emotional and intuitive, while I’m more logical and detached," said &lt;a href="http://www.harvillehendrix.com/index.php" target="_hplink"&gt;Hendrix&lt;/a&gt;, a pastor who has written several other books including, "&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Getting-Love-You-Want-Anniversary/dp/0805087001" target="_hplink"&gt;Getting the Love You Want&lt;/a&gt;." "But instead of looking at [these things] as differences and asking 'how come you’re so emotional?' … [look at them as] stimulants for growth."  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunt and Hendrix also believe that although all relationships have serious issues, the issues should not be treated seriously. They try to relay that couples should maintain lightheartedness by filling their book with cartoons and putting polka dots on its cover. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Knowing when to be lighthearted is an art form … many couples find themselves working so hard on their relationship, that they forget to actually have fun together," wrote Hunt and Hendrix. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several other truths listed in the book are: "romantic love is a trick," "conflict is growth trying to happen," and "being present for each other heals the past."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hendrix wants readers to understand that these truths are not difficult to attain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It’s not rocket science, it’s not easy, but it's simple. Leave negative stuff out, leave positive stuff in, and do that until your relationship is safe and you have the marriage of your dreams,” said Hendrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Everyone can have the marriage of their dreams, don't give up hope," added Hunt.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1047737/thumbs/s-MAKING-MARRIAGE-SIMPLE-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kim Kardashian Testifies Her Love For Kris Humphries Was Real</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/21/kim-kardashian-divorce-deposition_n_2923274.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2923274</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T13:31:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T20:05:44Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kim Kardashian's divorce trial is fast approaching and the reality star is dead-set on maintaining that her marriage to Kris Humphries wasn't a fraud, as...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Stephanie Marcus</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/stephanie-marcus/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Kim Kardashian's divorce trial is fast approaching and the reality star is dead-set on maintaining that her marriage to Kris Humphries wasn't a fraud, as he claims. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, the 32-year-old &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/21/kim-kardashian-deposition-kris-humphries-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;was "secretly" deposed, according to TMZ,&lt;/a&gt; and testified under oath that when Humphries proposed to her, and when they actually tied the knot, she was really in love with him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources revealed that the deposition took place at the pregnant reality star's attorney Laura Wasser's office and lasted a whopping nine hours to complete her testimony. Insiders told TMZ that the Brooklyn Nets forward's lawyer grilled Kim for evidence that she defrauded the athlete, &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20671810,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;by marrying him only for publicity and to boost ratings on her reality show&lt;/a&gt; -- but her testimony reportedly hasn't helped her ex's case at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps what's most surprising is that sources told the website that Humphries' lawyer didn't press Kim much about her reality show, and whether it was staged. In the past, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/13/kim-kardashian-kris-humphries-divorce_n_2676946.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Humphries' legal team has used threats of exposing the Kardashians' reality show as nothing but a sham&lt;/a&gt;, as evidence that his client was defrauded into marrying Kim. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of questioning is especially surprising, since "Keeping Up With The Kardashians" producer Russell Jay reportedly gave damning testimony when he was deposed last month.  According to Life &amp; Style, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/14/kim-kardashian-proposal-reshot_n_2876766.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Jay admitted that at least two scenes depicting Humphries were scripted, reshot or edited. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jay reportedly testified that Kardashian not only knew about Humphries' "surprise" proposal before it actually happened, but it was &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2012/01/kris-humphries-kim-kardashian-planned-his-wedding-proposal/" target="_hplink"&gt;reshot because the reality star didn't like her reaction the first time around&lt;/a&gt;. And while it's not uncommon for a reality show to do re-shoots, he also claimed that a scene where Kim confesses she's having doubts about her marriage, to her mother, was not shot on a trip to Dubai as shown, but at a &lt;a href="http://www.realitytea.com/2012/01/14/photos-proof-that-kim-kardashians-reality-show-is-fake-scene-with-kris-jenner-was-staged/" target="_hplink"&gt;later date on a Los Angeles sound stage&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously it was believed that Humphries had little chance at proving his marriage to Kardashian was a fraud, and even &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/kris-humphries-divorce-lawyer-quits-just-before-kim-kardashian-court-hearing-2013152" target="_hplink"&gt;parted ways with one of his divorce lawyers &lt;/a&gt;who though it would be impossible to prove. The producer's testimony appeared to be the basketball player's best shot at proving fraud, but as TMZ pointed out, &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/13/kim-kardashian-kris-humphries-divorce-if-marriage-was-scam-he-was-in-on-it/" target="_hplink"&gt;it also could have hurt Humphries' case&lt;/a&gt;. The site points out that since the 27-year-old agreed to re-shoot his proposal, he was in on everything, making it much harder to argue that he was duped by Kardashian. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former couple was married for a mere 72 days, before &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/10/31/kim-kardashian-to-file-fo_n_1067424.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kardashian filed for divorce on Oct. 31, 2011&lt;/a&gt;. More than a year later,  Kardashian and Humphries' divorce trial is set to begin May 6 -- let the games begin. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1048836/thumbs/s-KIM-KARDASHIAN-DIVORCE-DEPOSITION-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kerri Zane: 5 Reasons It’s Better To Be A Single Parent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kerri-zane/5-reasons-its-better-to-b_b_2854313.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2854313</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-21T06:13:40Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-21T17:26:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Yes, it can be very stressful, but there are actually a lot of benefits too.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kerri Zane</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kerri-zane/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Although the gold standard in child rearing has traditionally been a dual family unit, being a single parent has a myriad of benefits. Rather than navigating the treacherous territory of constant parental compromise, you can independently make choices for your children that you feel is best. Eleven years ago, when my former husband and I split, I saw my divorce as a glorious opportunity to parent solo. No more discussing the finer points of gymnastics vs. volleyball. I didn't have to debate dessert after dinner vs. never ever letting sugar touch lips. And there was no longer a lengthy discussion over the reason my daughters needed braces.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the state of rock-steady marital bliss in this country continues to falter, more and more adults are joining the ranks of contented uncoupled family units. In fact, based on the latest Census Bureau statistics, there are over &lt;a href="http://www.lifesitenews.com/news/the-number-of-children-living-in-single-parent-homes-has-nearly-doubled-in/" target="_hplink"&gt;14 million single parent households&lt;/a&gt; with children under the age of 18. That is a lot of people and a good reason to celebrate. Which is why, March 21 has been designated as National Single Parent's Day. A time to honor all those tenacious individuals who do what they do, day in and day out, to support, nurture and care for their kids. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a single mom advisor and author of&lt;a href="http://kerrizane.com/appearances-events/win-a-free-getaway/" target="_hplink"&gt; It Takes All 5&lt;/a&gt;, I would like to honor the day and offer you five solid reasons why it's better to be a single mom or dad then half of a parenting pair.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	No Negotiations Necessary:&lt;/strong&gt; While your married counterparts continue to disagree on the state of their children's welfare, you get to make unilateral choices, which in the long run is better for your offspring's well-being. A child's behavior can be negatively affected by adult arguing. It will either leave them crying their eyes out or running for cover. With no one else in the house to challenge your choices, you may continue to be the cozy constant security blanket your children need. Granted, there is a financial price to pay when you are the sole provider, but children need to learn that sometimes we can't give them everything they want. And oftentimes what they thought was a "must-have," really isn't. Ultimately if it is that important, you will find a way. Payment plans were designed for the single parent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.	Stellar Independent Role Model:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the best gifts I was able to give my two daughters was the knowledge that they can make it on their own. Change a light bulb without a dad in the house -- snap Mom. Swoop a stylish up-do for your teen with no mom in sight -- yeah Dad. You embody the the idea that it's better to "want" to be in a relationship because there is a loving bond rather than you "need" to be in a relationship because there is stuff to be done or procured. When your child sees you as a completely whole and independent adult, they will learn to emulate your healthy behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.	Relationship Options May Vary:&lt;/strong&gt; Our society is shifting away from the bonds of matrimony. &lt;a href="http://www.pewsocialtrends.org/2011/12/14/barely-half-of-u-s-adults-are-married-a-record-low/" target="_hplink"&gt;A recent Pew study&lt;/a&gt; revealed that just over half of adult Americans are married, the lowest rate in decades. Children will be enlightened and possibly relieved that they are no longer tied to that traditional lifestyle. Marriage is optional and sometimes not applicable. Long-term relationships without wedding bands can be stronger. My idols in this arena are Kurt Russell and Goldie Hawn; they've been together for nearly 30 years. These lessons are particularly important for girls, who were raised on the fictitious belief that Prince Charming would sweep them of their feet to live happily ever after, only to become enormously disappointed when their fairytale ending turns into a hardcore courtroom reality. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.	Bed Sharing Not Required: &lt;/strong&gt;Married couples may have more sex, but it isn't nearly as much fun. While they constantly have to "spice it up" in the bedroom, the nature of being single and switching partners does all the cooking for us. We tease, experiment and explore the bawdy awareness of every new lover. Researchers at the University of Pisa found that &lt;a href="http://healthyliving.msn.com/health-wellness/men/13-surprising-facts-about-testosterone-1" target="_hplink"&gt;testosterone levels&lt;/a&gt;, in both men and women, make the sex hotter during the first two years of a relationship. My favorite part of becoming single again was the choice to have, or not to have, a mate in my bed. The National Sleep Foundation reported that &lt;a href="http://www.saga.co.uk/health/mind/sleepmatters.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;sleeping two to a bed&lt;/a&gt; could cause you to lose 49 minutes of sleep per night. That's a lot! On the nights when no one is next to me to snuggle with, I lay diagonally across the mattress, relishing the cool crisp sheets on "his side." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.	Building a Better Body: &lt;/strong&gt;Marriages are like your freshman year in college. You have the tendency to pack on the pounds. &lt;a href="http://www.match.com/magazine/article/6320/" target="_hplink"&gt;One study found&lt;/a&gt; that women could gain five to eight pounds in the first few years of their wedded bliss and a whopping 54 pounds by the ten-year mark, while their single counterparts stay slim. Most of us have an overriding desire to want to be attractive to prospective mates of the opposite sex. The result of a divorce? A slimmer, trimmer you -- aka the Divorce Diet. Take a look at Tom Cruise who reportedly lost 15 pounds after splitting with Katie. Jennie Garth lost 20 and Demi Moore has been stick thin since the departure of her sweetheart, Ashton Kutcher. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many reports will tell you that being a single parent is stressful. It is. But no more stressful than being a married parent. Ultimately, we all want to step into our own with confidence and take every curveball life throws us with our independent spirit intact. The best way to handle the inevitable life shifts is to stay positive, reach out for support from your friends and family, relish the time you spend with your children and most importantly, create a daily space for some much deserved me-time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy National Single Parents Day to you!&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1048356/thumbs/s-SINGLE-PARENT-DAY-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lee Block: Why We Should Stop Teaching Our Kids About 'Happily Ever After'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lee-block/the-fairy-tale-demystifyi_b_2878967.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2878967</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-20T21:20:40Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T21:20:22Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The myth of the princess wedding with the big dress, tons of flowers, bridesmaids, flower girls and the prince waiting at the end of the aisle prevails, and is what many girls perceive to be the American dream.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lee Block</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lee-block/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I loved princesses who let down their hair, got kissed awake by princes and fit into glass slippers. I dreamed of being saved from the dragon, the evil stepmother or the wicked witch by a dashing prince on the white horse. I planned the elaborate fairytale fantasy of marriage &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt;, but the reality was that I was not a princess, just a housewife and a mom and it is damn hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would happen if we taught our daughters that prince charming wasn't going to whisk them away to a fabulous castle filled with blue birds that sang and teapots that danced? Would we shatter their dreams, or would be we be teaching them facts that would prepare them for the realities of motherhood and marriage? Because, let's face it, life isn't a fairy tale and happily every after is harder to achieve as divorce becomes easier to obtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Do We Learn From Fairy Tales?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll admit that some fairy tales teach good morals, but other than that, what do we actually learn from them? That the stepmothers are all evil? Seriously? We all know that is a bunch of bull, and not only that, but it is a stigma that all stepmothers have had to fight since the onset of Cinderella. Thank you to Charles Perrault for starting that lovely rumor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, not everything we learn from fairy tales is bad. For instance Snow White taught us not to eat apples at Halloween because they might be poisoned or have razor blades stuck in them. On the other hand, Snow White did go off with seven strangers and live with them, and I don't think that is something we would want our children to emulate when we tell them daily about "stranger danger".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Princess Myth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't know any little girls that haven't gone through  the "princess" phase, where they pull out the Disney costume of their favorite princess and wear it all day, every day and even sleep in it. No matter what you do, you can't get them to take it off. Does it damage them to wear it? No. Is it irritating? Yes. Does it teach them anything? No. Do we want them to grow up thinking that they will be princesses? No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of life is that unless you are born into royalty or marry into royalty, you will not be a princess, and even princesses' lives aren't like those in the fairy tales -- except for maybe the castle part. But the myth of the princess wedding with the big dress, tons of flowers, bridesmaids, flower girls and the prince waiting at the end of the aisle prevails, and is what many girls perceive to be the American dream. When the wedding is over, the dream becomes the white picket fence with a perfect house and two gorgeous kids and the best dog that is perfectly trained -- utter bliss every single day. Those of us that have been there know that this is not reality. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demystifying the Myth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we demystify the myth without tainting our children or leaving them feeling bereft, with no hope for a future filled with love? It seems to me that putting more emphasis on the marriage and less emphasis on the wedding is a perfect place to start. The wedding is a couple of hours and the marriage is a lifetime. Isn't it more productive to spend more time planning the marriage than the wedding? It seems so obvious, yet so few people -- if any -- actually do it. Perhaps this may explain high divorce rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, would we be doing our daughters a disservice by demystifying the myth of the fairy tale by letting them in on the real secret to a happy ending -- which is that marriage is not all rainbows and flowers but hard work and compromise? Or should we continue to allow them to figure it out for themselves? How do we think that has been working for us? Or better yet, how has that worked for you? It didn't work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>6 Sports Stars Who Dated Fellow Athletes After Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/20/lindsey-vonn-dating-tiger-woods_n_2917234.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2917234</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-20T20:31:54Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T20:32:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There's a new power couple in the sports world. On Monday, Tiger Woods announced on Facebook that he was dating newly single skier Lindsey Vonn....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;There's a new power couple in the sports world. On Monday, Tiger Woods &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152697837415121.1073741826.164825930120&amp;type=1" target="_hplink"&gt;announced on Facebook &lt;/a&gt; that he was &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/18/tiger-woods-lindsey-vonn-dating-announcement_n_2901686.html?utm_hp_ref=sports" target="_hplink"&gt;dating newly single skier Lindsey Vonn. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vonn, who &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/09/lindsey-vonn-and-thomas-v_n_2443308.html" target="_hplink"&gt;finalized her divorce&lt;/a&gt; from husband Thomas Vonn in January 2012, took to her &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151508174969728&amp;set=a.10150905357679728.428648.89975379727&amp;type=1" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; to share the same news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I guess it wasn't a well-kept secret but yes, I am dating Tiger Woods," the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10151508174969728&amp;set=a.10150905357679728.428648.89975379727&amp;type=1" target="_hplink"&gt;Olympic gold medalist wrote&lt;/a&gt;. "Our relationship evolved from a friendship into something more over these past few months and it has made me very happy."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So can we expect the sports stars' romance to go the distance? Only time will tell, but in the meantime, click through the slideshow below for five other athletes who dated -- and in some cases, married -- fellow sports stars after divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287423--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1047693/thumbs/s-TIGER-WOODS-LINDSEY-VONN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Vonn Mocked Tiger's Sex Scandal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/20/lindsey-vonn-mocked-tiger-woods-scandal_n_2917613.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2917613</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-20T20:06:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T20:17:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When Tiger Woods and Lindsey Vonn made their relationship Facebook official earlier this week, both superstar athletes asked for privacy. If people do talk about...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Greenberg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-greenberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;When Tiger Woods and Lindsey Vonn &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/18/tiger-woods-lindsey-vonn-dating-announcement_n_2901686.html" target="_hplink"&gt;made their relationship Facebook official&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week, both superstar athletes asked for privacy. If people do talk about the sports power couple, however, Vonn, 27, may understand. After all, she couldn't help but joke about Woods' sex scandal back in 2010. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I guess it wasn't a well-kept secret but yes, I am dating Tiger Woods. Our relationship evolved from a friendship into something more over these past few months and it has made me very happy," Vonn posted on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/LindseyVonnUSA" target="_hplink"&gt;her Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; on Monday. "I don't plan on addressing this further as I would like to keep that part of my life between us, my family and close friends. Thank you for understanding and your continued support!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woods, 37, posted a very similar statement on &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/Tiger" target="_hplink"&gt;his Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; and the couple shared a four photos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back when Woods' marriage to Elin Nordegren was very publicly coming undone and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/tiger-woods-mistress/" target="_hplink"&gt;alleged mistresses&lt;/a&gt; were coming forward in shocking numbers, Vonn couldn't help but joke about her future boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As chronicled in an article by Time magazine from February 2010, Vonn mocked Woods' sex scandal and subsequent &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/02/19/tiger-woods-press-confere_n_468722.html" target="_hplink"&gt;confessional press conference&lt;/a&gt; during her downtime at the Vancouver Olympics. The decorated ski champion even outlined her idea for a "Saturday Night Live" sketch that would make light of Woods' apology and admission of infidelity. In the idea she described for Time magazine, to the reported delight of her entourage, Vonn would appear at a podium quite like Woods had in that same month and say "There's something you don't know about me. Tiger, you're like my idol, and I too have a sex problem."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STORY CONTINUES BELOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287003--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Described by Time as coming "across as ingratiatingly anti-Woods," Vonn was also asked how she dealt with the pressures of being a celebrity athlete. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Well, I'm married, so I don't have that problem," Vonn, who was married to her coach at the time, responded. "But, um, I guess [Woods] is married too."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.time.com/time/specials/packages/article/0,28804,1963484_1963490_1966894,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;CLICK HERE&lt;/a&gt; to read full Time article. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Both &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/08/23/tiger-woods-divorce-final_n_691486.html#s81031" target="_hplink"&gt;Woods&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/09/lindsey-vonn-and-thomas-v_n_2443308.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Vonn have divorced&lt;/a&gt; since his press conference and her wisecracks. Rumors that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/25/tiger-woods-lindsey-vonn-dating_n_2551604.html" target="_hplink"&gt;they were dating&lt;/a&gt; began late in 2012 and continued until Woods and Vonn confirmed their relationship status this week. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1047930/thumbs/s-LINDSEY-VONN-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mike And Ike Getting Back Together After Messy Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/20/mike-ike-geting-back-together_n_2885982.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2885982</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-20T19:45:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-20T21:48:43Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Remember the tragic news last year that Mike and Ike were heading for divorce? Fear not, candy fans -- The Huffington Post has learned from...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carey-polis/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Remember the tragic news last year that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/04/12/mike-ike-divorce_n_1421498.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Mike and Ike were heading for divorce&lt;/a&gt;? Fear not, candy fans -- The Huffington Post has learned from Mike and Ike themselves that things are on the mend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is the duo getting back together, its namesake candy brand is getting reformulated. That means new flavors, new packaging and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital campaign on their divorce has been ongoing for about a year now -- with Ike working on his art while Mike spent time on his music. The divorce schtick included everything from peeks at &lt;a href="http://mikeandikebrand.tumblr.com/tagged/art" target="_hplink"&gt;Ike's art&lt;/a&gt;, to actually involving a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_s8JOqP18ns" target="_hplink"&gt;negotiator throughout the "divorce" proceedings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"We've been having a lot of fun," Donald Houston, senior category manager for the candy's parent company, Just Born, said about the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fans of the candy didn't seem to grow tired of hearing about the failing relationship, following updates on the Mike and Ike &lt;a href="http://mikeandikebrand.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/mikeandike" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; pages. "It's actually been pretty impressive how engaged people have been," Houston said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the divorce campaign, the company has had its highest sales in 10 years -- sales of the original fruit flavor are up 9.3 percent from the previous fiscal year, Houston said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those following closely may have noticed that in the past few weeks there have been reported sightings of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=NbMvajM1AuE" target="_hplink"&gt;Mike &amp; Ike together&lt;/a&gt;. Love is in the air, people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In honor of Mike and Ike getting back together, Just Born is launching a new flavor called Strawberry Reunion, which will roll out in stores starting next week. Take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-18-Screenshot20130318at4.05.44PM.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-18-Screenshot20130318at4.05.44PM.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-18-Screenshot20130318at4.05.44PM-thumb.png" width="570" height="316" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the new flavor, all of the Mike and Ike boxes underwent a redesign -- especially important considering the versions in stores for the past year had either "Mike" or "Ike" crossed out (no one said divorce was pretty!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-18-mikeandike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-18-mikeandike.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-18-mikeandike-thumb.jpg" width="570" height="380" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To really push the new incarnation of Mike and Ike, there will be billboard ads, radio spots, in-store displays, a relaunched website and more. But the biggest part of the launch is the Mike and Ike movie trailer that will air on national television starting in early June. It's...dramatic. Take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt; var src_url="https://spshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?playList=517716998&amp;height=411&amp;width=570&amp;sid=577&amp;origin=undefined&amp;relatedMode=2&amp;relatedBottomHeight=60&amp;companionPos=&amp;hasCompanion=false&amp;autoStart=false&amp;colorPallet=%23FFEB00&amp;videoControlDisplayColor=%23191919&amp;shuffle=0&amp;isAP=1"; src_url += "&amp;onVideoDataLoaded=HPTrack.Vid.DL&amp;onTimeUpdate=HPTrack.Vid.TC"; if (typeof(commercial_video) == "object") { src_url += "&amp;siteSection="+commercial_video.site_and_category; if (commercial_video.package) { src_url += "&amp;sponsorship="+commercial_video.package;  } } document.write('&lt;scr' + 'ipt type="text/javascript" src="'+src_url+'"&gt;&lt;/scr' + 'ipt&gt;');&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;A hearty congratulations to Mike and Ike -- we wish them many more years of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos courtesy of Mike and Ike&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1048194/thumbs/s-MIKE-IKE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
