<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: 66 Inspirational Quotes About Marriage Equality</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/gay-marriage-quotes_n_2947825.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2947825</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:37:54Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:38:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Two cases will go before the Supreme Court regarding the legality of same-sex marriage in the United States, one on March 26 and the other...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Noah Michelson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/noah-michelson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Two cases will go before the Supreme Court regarding the legality of same-sex marriage in the United States, one on March 26 and the other the following day, March 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, the Justices will hear arguments regarding Proposition 8, the legislation which made gay marriage illegal in California in 2008. And on Wednesday, the Court will consider the constitutionality of the Defense of Marriage Act, which was signed into law in 1996 and federally defines marriage as the legal union of one man and one woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've seen an incredible amount of progress on the marriage equality front in the last 10 years -- including a huge push that came in just the last few months when same-sex marriage was made legal in Washington, Maryland and Maine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we nervously watch and wait to see how the Supreme Court rules on these two historic cases, we thought now was a good time to showcase some inspiring quotes about the fight for marriage equality. We've chosen 66 great quotes from queer people and their allies and featured them in the slideshow below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a favorite quote that isn't featured? Tell us in the comments section, along with your thoughts on what you think is going to happen regarding the Prop 8 and DOMA cases.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054004/thumbs/s-GAY-MARRIAGE-QUOTES-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Intimacy Intervention: 'Help! I Can't Stop Sleeping With My No-Good Ex'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/abiola-abrams-intimacy-intervention-cant-stop-sleeping-with-ex_n_2933883.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933883</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:22:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:15:30Z</updated>
    
    <summary> Passionate Living Coach Abiola Abrams gives love, dating and self-esteem advice on the CW's Bill Cunningham Show and all over the web through her...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Cumberbatch Anderson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-anderson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="essence logo1" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051757/thumbs/r-ESSENCE-LOGO1-medium260.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passionate Living Coach Abiola Abrams gives love, dating and self-esteem advice on the CW's Bill Cunningham Show and all over the web through her hit web series AbiolaTV. Now she wants to help you keep things spicy and fresh between the sheets. Are you in need of an intimacy intervention? Just ask Abiola!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear Abiola,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep sleeping with my ex. He was my first and I’m ready to move on but I just can’t. We have been best friends since childhood, so I never thought he would treat me this way. He’s driving me crazy! I thought we were soul mates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our six years together, there was so much infidelity. He got married to someone else behind my back even though it was not legal because his divorce was not final. He was living with me for 11 months when he left the house one morning to get married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time photos of him with other women pop up on my Facebook timeline I go crazy. I have gained weight, I’m depressed and in a rut. Now I just started having sex with him again and I don’t know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help me get out of this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signed,&lt;br /&gt;
Ex-hausted in Ex-cruciating Pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ex-uberantly About to Move Forward,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goddess sister, it is time for an ex-orcism. First of all, you have my deepest sympathy. I say that because the only way to get past this is to grieve the death of the relationship, as off base as it was, heal your self-worth and move forward like the queen you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is not driving you crazy, sis. You are willingly showing up in your party pants and paying for the bus ticket to get there. You’re not alone. A recent YourTango Breakup Survey shows that more than half of single people say that thinking about their exes keeps them from finding new love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sleeping with” with this man is only ex-acerbating the situation. We are creatures of habit but to put it bluntly, having sex with this ex is like eating your vomit. The meal might have tasted great at one time but now it can just make you ill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to abruptly ex-purge. Cut off contact. Unfriend him on all social media. You don’t need to see “Loser is now in a relationship with Rachet” pop up on her timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why you are having trouble walking away: when we are sexually intimate our brains blast us with feel-good chemicals like oxytocin, dopamine and endorphins. Your adrenaline also starts going. As women, we can find ourselves deluded about the prospects of a defunct relationship because we have recharged our attachment bonds. Every time you are intimate with him and your body hits you with more oxytocin, you reinforce this. If you are trying to move forward, romping with him keeps you stuck in the same place. It’s a matter of physics and inertia. You can’t evolve while still actively engaged with someone who continues to treat you like less than a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ex is an unscrupulous human being. I’m sure both of his wives would agree. You cannot be soul mates when one partner is lacking a soul. A relationship works between two whole healthy people. This “man" is neither whole nor healthy. You are trying to make right with your body what you could not make work with your clothes on. You need to rebuild trust in yourself by making better choices because not only has this man betrayed you, but you have betrayed yourself. Take full responsibility for your actions. I say this not to beat up on you, but if you make only him responsible, then only he can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main issue is what I like to call “deservability.” You deserve much better than to have a man who would leave your house to marry someone else. That is emotional abuse. It’s time to woman up and become your own best friend. Breakup pain is awful but there’s no getting around that. On the other side there is wholeness, healing and freedom, promise. The only way to reclaim your joy and power is to go through the fire, love and forgive yourself, learn the lessons and then move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day you’ll look back and wonder, what was I thinking? It’s okay, princess. We all do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abiola Abrams is the founder of The Bombshell Academy blog, online school and web series over at AbiolaTV. Follow her on Twitter to continue the discussion about this week's hot topic, and then email her your burning questions now. Anything you send will be posted anonymously, promise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052200/thumbs/s-ABIOLA-ABRAMS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>3 Ways Sex Changes For Men After 50</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/sex-over-50-men_n_2925739.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925739</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T11:29:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:02:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When it comes to how sex over 50 for men, all interested parties seem to focus on erections -- or, more specifically, the increased difficulty...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Anthonia Akitunde</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/anthonia-akitunde/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;When it comes to how &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/12/sex-over-50-not-having-sex_n_1561339.html" target="_hplink"&gt;sex over 50&lt;/a&gt; for men, all interested parties seem to focus on erections -- or, more specifically, the increased difficulty to get and/or maintain an erection that goes with age. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sex for men over 50 changes in other ways besides a higher likelihood of dealing with&lt;a href="http://www.webmd.com/erectile-dysfunction/default.htm" target="_hplink"&gt; erectile dysfunction&lt;/a&gt;, according to certified sex and relationship expert Joe Kort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Men have their own midlife crisis," Kort said. "They're bodies, their hair, their erections... their masculinity is starting to change. It's really about their virility as a man. Some of it is that they want to feel more like a man. They have to wrestle with their own masculinity."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kort spoke with Huff/Post50 about three ways sex changes for men over 50. Have you experienced these differences? Tell us your thoughts in the comments section or via Twitter @HuffPost50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;1. Men feel closer to their sexual partners.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common stereotype of men being distant after having sex is based on biology, Korte said. While men and women have the same levels of &lt;a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/basics/oxytocin" target="_hplink"&gt;oxytocin&lt;/a&gt;, the so-called "love hormone" that is responsible for&lt;a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=be-mine-forever-oxytocin" target="_hplink"&gt; bonding to partners&lt;/a&gt; and children, men have more testosterone, which is a hormonal distancer, Korte explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Men's testosterone starts dropping in the 40s and really starts lowering in their 50s," he said. But because their oxytocin levels remain the same, men over 50 find themselves attaching more to their partners after sex, a complete 180 from how men typically feel after intercourse, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They're shocked themselves at how much they can attach," Korte said. This attachment bore out in a 2012 study where &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/11/study-oxytocin-the-love-hormone-makes-men-in-relationships-want-to-stay-away-from-other-women/265314/" target="_hplink"&gt;monogamous men who received a nasal spray of oxytocin&lt;/a&gt; were more likely to keep their distance from an attractive female and avoid sending romantic interest signals compared to single men. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;2. Men become more open to expressing their sexuality in different ways.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women tend to be more open about their sexual fantasies, going beyond the mechanics of sex to explore different scenarios and ways to express intimacy, Kort said. But that changes for men over 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They have a fluidity with what they want sexually, because their erections can't work," meaning they have to find new ways to be sexual, he said. "They're doing things, wanting things because they aren't so rigid." (No pun intended.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men over 50 become more vocal about their sexual fantasies, and begin to broaden their ideas of what turns them on, considering "even fantasies they wouldn't have imagined before," Kort told Huff/Post50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The defenses aren't as strong anymore," he said. "Maybe they're more bored with their fantasies, [maybe] it doesn't get them to the edge like it used to. [But] they're more open-minded to different things because they're older."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;3. Men become driven by fear.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call it little red Corvette syndrome -- but when men hit 50, that desire for a new, younger model becomes overwhelming, Kort said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"There is research that supports you're looking for someone who can bear your children," he said. "So there is some biology behind it. Women have it too, but it's not as prominent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They really start wanting the ideal that they always wanted," Kort explained. "It's not an issue of right or wrong, they're just panicked. Internally, they get scared and they act on it because their time is running out. [They think], 'I'm never going to attract a woman like this again, and I want it'."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053782/thumbs/s-SEX-OVER-50-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Sandy Weiner: 4 Things Men Should Never Do On A First Date</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sandy-weiner/advice-for-guys-4-tips-fo_b_2916383.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2916383</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T05:39:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T06:11:40Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The bottom line is that first impressions matter in dating. If you want a great relationship with someone special, you need to put your best self forward.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Sandy Weiner</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sandy-weiner/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;This is for all you newly single men out there. Are you fed up with first dates that don't lead to a second date? Do you sometimes scratch your head and ask yourself, "Why didn't she want to go out with me again? I thought things were going well." I want to help you understand women better. I want you to have more success in getting that second date. So, I'm going to reveal some dating tips based on my personal experiences, plus those shared by my divorced friends and the clients I coach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are, if you felt that a date went well but she never wants to date you again, you might have said or done something that turned her off. You probably didn't even realize it. The following tips could mean the difference between a lonely Saturday night in front of the TV with a beer or another great date with that lovely woman. Here are the four things men should &lt;em&gt;never &lt;/em&gt;do on a first date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't talk about sex.&lt;/strong&gt; Not on the first phone call or the first date. Confident, self-respecting women don't want to be objectified. It's not that women are not interested in sex. Quite the contrary -- most of us love sex! But don't talk about your sexual conquests with us on a first date. Please take time to get to know us. Like us for our intelligence, warmth, kindness, creativity and wit. Do &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; us that you're physically attracted to us, but don't make it the primary focus of why you're into us. When you ease into the physical relationship, most of us respond better.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't be negative.&lt;/strong&gt; Please don't talk about what sucks in your life. We're sorry that you lost your job. We understand that your kids are driving you crazy. We feel bad that you don't have much of an appetite since your wife left you. You've lost weight. You've gained weight. You're in debt. You have kidney stones or irritable bowel syndrome. Listen up: we all have "stuff" that frustrates or overwhelms us. There is a time and place to share the big stuff of our lives; the first date is not it. We don't know you well enough yet. It feels overwhelming and inappropriate to us. If we end up in a relationship with you, by all means, share it all with us. We'll care about you and want to support you then. But this is only the first date, so please stay positive.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't discuss your ex.&lt;/strong&gt; Your relationship with your ex was terrible. She threw you out of the house. You were blindsided. She took all your money. She has full custody of your kids. We get it, divorce is hard, and sometimes the ex has done very hurtful things. But we don't want to hear about it -- not on a first date or a first phone call. Maybe later. We want to talk about what's going on for you now. What are your dreams? Your passions? Stay in the present, and we'll both enjoy the date much more. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't be rude.&lt;/strong&gt; If you're unkind to the waiter, doorman, toll collector, or any other person you come in contact with on that first date, we will judge you as unkind. We want to be in a relationship with someone who is considerate, compassionate and warm. Go out of your way to be nice, and chances are, you'll get that second date.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that first impressions matter in dating. If you want a great relationship with someone special, you need to put your best self forward. You're judging us as much as we're judging you. I'm sure we're doing or saying things that are turning you off, too. We want to understand you guys better. We want to improve our dating success, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's start communicating here about what we can do to bring about more healthy, loving relationships. Please share your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And you're invited to sign up &lt;a href=" http://eepurl.com/w3bHv" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for my brand new FREE report, &lt;strong&gt;"The Top 3 Mistakes Midlife Daters Make &amp; How to Turn Them Around to Find Love Now!"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052531/thumbs/s-MALE-DATING-TIPS-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Rosalind Sedacca: How To Talk To Your Children After Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rosalind-sedacca/talk-to-not-at-your-child_b_2903747.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2903747</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T17:28:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T17:27:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Too often, busy parents find themselves talking "at" their children, but not "to" them. And most especially, not "with" them.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rosalind Sedacca</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rosalind-sedacca/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Therapists are always reminding parents to talk to their children. Unfortunately, many parents need just such a reminder -- especially in today's mega-paced culture in which just sitting down to a family dinner together seems to be a major accomplishment. Too often, busy parents find themselves talking "at" their children, but not "to" them. And most especially, not "with" them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, of course, is problematic in any family trying to raise socially, emotionally and spiritually healthy children. However, it is especially dangerous if that family is facing the challenges of divorce or separation.  If your parent-child communication skills and rapport is not optimal before discussions about divorce or family lifestyle changes come up, the likeliness of a peaceful, successful outcome is dramatically jeopardized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason, more than ever before, parents need to create a bond of trust and support with their children when the family is facing any level of upheaval.  If that respectful bond and trust is broken or tenuous, children are much more likely to feel abandoned, neglected and fearful about their safety and security in the face of separation of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is never too late to bridge that gap and start authentic communication with your children. Honesty is always important in any parent-child relationship, but it becomes extremely significant at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all communication must be age-appropriate. And these talks are never a license for a dumping session about your soon-to-be ex or former spouse. Whining, complaining, sarcasm, disrespect and related behaviors are not healthy forms of communication, especially with sensitive children. They don't want you to air your dirty laundry with them. They want to feel safe, loved, secure and supported as they move into a transition in life that they did not desire or create. Insulting or criticizing their other parent affects them to their core. Your children are innocent and many parents need to remind themselves of this fact again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has never been a better time than now to boost your level of communication with your children, regardless of your marital status. Share some of your own feelings and experiences with life's challenges before you start asking them questions about their life. Knowing that you personally deal with fears, anxieties, doubts and related emotions gives your children permission to talk about those they are experiencing. It makes them feel more okay about their own insecurities. And it encourages them to talk more frankly with you about challenges they face in all facets of their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't wait for a special occasion to start honestly and candidly talking to your children. Determine to make sincere communication with your children a regular part of your family life. You will never regret it and you will come to reap surprising rewards in the months and years ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosalind Sedacca, CCT is author of How Do I Tell the Kids about the Divorce? A Create-a-Storybook Guide to Preparing Your Children - with Love! For more information about this innovative new approach to that tough conversation, visit &lt;a href="http://www.childcentereddivorce.com/kids/" target="_hplink"&gt;howdoitellthekids.com&lt;/a&gt;. For Rosalind's free ebook on Post-Divorce Parenting: Success Strategies for Getting It Right, other articles and valuable resources for parents, visit &lt;a href="http://www.childcentereddivorce.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;childcentereddivorce.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052525/thumbs/s-KIDS-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Tammy Nelson, Ph.D.: What To Do When You Discover Your Spouse Is Cheating</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/can-i-get-over-an-affair-_b_2911106.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2911106</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T09:24:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T09:23:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The immediate response after discovering a spouse's affair is commonly disbelief, anger, sadness, loss or grief.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tammy Nelson, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted from &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy; Redefining Your Relationship After Infidelity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immediate response after discovering a spouse's affair is commonly disbelief, anger, sadness, loss or grief. It can take several years before the betrayed spouse is ready to even consider forgiveness, even if the partner who cheated begs for it. And through the cheating partner may immediately feel remorse and repeat "I'm sorry" over and over again, that apology may not get past the betray'ed partner's outer layer of hurt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is possible to move on and rebuild after infidelity. I have identified three distinct phases of recovery from an &lt;a href="http://janisaspring.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;affair&lt;/a&gt;: the crisis phase, the understanding (or insight) phase, and the vision phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crisis Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first phase of affair recovery, the crisis phase, happens when an affair is disclosed or discovered. The initial shock and deep betrayal can rock your confidence, and make you feel like everything you have ever known is collapsing.  It is important in this phase of the recovery after an affair to recognize that this is a phase -- you will get through this. This really difficult time will pass, and you will move into another stage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't make any decisions now about what to do with your relationship.  Take care of yourself and your family and hold onto those major decisions for a while. When the chaos has slowed down enough for you to breathe and look around, you may start to think more about whether or not you want to stay together and start a new monogamy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially after infidelity, it can be difficult for you to envision a new, shared future. The one person you turned to in the past for support when you were in pain is now the person causing you pain. It can seem as if there's no one to turn to. You may now think of your relationship as a liability instead of your strength. You may feel lonely and confused. You may long for the partner who always served as the support system in your life, and that time of innocence before you discovered the affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a time lapse in the grief process. The person who had the affair has known about the infidelity ever since it began. If you are just now discovering the affair, you are at a totally different point in the process than your partner is. You have only begun to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Role of Grief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A &lt;a href="http://www.stages-of-grief-recovery.com/kubler-ross-stages-of-grief.html" target="_hplink"&gt;grieving&lt;/a&gt; process is normal after an affair. As you move through the grieving process, many emotions will emerge, possibly including anger, fear, denial, and eventually acceptance. You can feel as if you are grieving a death, and in many ways, you are. You are grieving the old vision of your marriage or relationship. This is true whether you decide to stay together or move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both partners must grieve their losses if they are to build a new marriage. Grief is triggered by the loss of the future you thought you were headed toward together. Whatever ideas you had about how you would grow old as a couple, retire, have grandchildren, rock on the front porch together, or travel the world, the affair has now challenged that vision of a shared future. Grief is a process of letting go of that vision. And, interestingly, grief has a way of making room for a different future if you choose to create that possibility going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Understanding (or Insight) Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The second phase of affair recovery is the understanding (or insight) phase, and you will recognize when you are entering this phase when you start to look at how the affair happened. This second phase of affair recovery comes after the crisis has ebbed and you are moving past your intense anger and confusion. Although it can be a difficult time, this phase will help you to experience empathy for each other and can give you hope for the future if you decide you want to stay together. You may still not know whether you want to make things work for the long run, but you will be able to do some of the work on your past to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the affair and how it happened will help you to get clearer about what led you both to this point in your lives. This means you both need to explore the meaning of the affair. During this second phase of affair recovery, you may begin to wonder where your responsibility lies for what happened in your relationship. This is not about assigning blame, but a time to deconstruct the affair and the history of your marriage or relationship, to find out where the roots of the infidelity began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting to understand the affair can answer many of the questions that you may feel are still unanswered. Some of your frustration may be relieved at that point, and you may be ready to make some decisions about your relationship going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moving Past Blame&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If both partners are willing and ready to move into healing, you will notice a shift happening. Instead of feeling polarized into the good spouse and the bad spouse, the two of you will begin to realize that you each share responsibility for what happened in your relationship before the affair. There was most probably a dynamic in your marriage that contributed to the affair. When you start becoming aware of this shared dynamic, the recovery process becomes a shared experience between the two of you. The affair may even eventually move from being "his affair" or "her affair" to being "our affair."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start to feel this shift, it means you are moving into the next stage of your affair recovery. You are moving from the Insight phase into the Vision phase, where you are ready to look at a new future and a new monogamy, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vision Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you reach the third phase of affair recovery, the vision phase, it is time to make some decisions about staying together, or letting go and moving on.  Here you can decide about whether or not it is possible to create a new future together. To do this, you should be clear about what your new monogamy will look like. In my new book, &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt;, there are distinct steps for developing that new relationship, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt; challenges the common view that an affair has to mean the end of a relationship. Monogamy as we know it is changing in our world and in our culture. Our ability to remain monogamous is becoming more difficult in an age when cheating is easier than ever. Marriage as we know it will be totally different by the end of this century. The couples that manage to stay together and make it work will be the ones who decide to create fluidity and flexibility in their partnerships, and find ways to make monogamy work for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information, &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed" target="_hplink"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.drtammynelson.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Dr. Tammy Nelson&lt;/a&gt; is a world renowned sex and relationship expert and the author of &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/getting-the-sex-you-want-book/" target="_hplink"&gt;Getting the Sex You Want&lt;/a&gt;.   She can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.drtammynelson.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;drtammynelson.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052524/thumbs/s-INFIDELITY-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>4 Major Red Flags You Should Never Ignore </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/red-flags_n_2934838.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934838</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:58:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T19:20:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>You know what they say: hindsight is 20/20. But it's not until you've been through divorce or a tough breakup that you begin to realize...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;You know what they say: hindsight is 20/20. But it's not until you've been through divorce or a tough breakup that you begin to realize how much truth that platitude actually holds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take it from the folks on Reddit. On Thursday night, the thread &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/1arkti/divorcees_of_reddit_what_things_did_your_ex_do/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Divorcees of Reddit, what things did your ex do before your marriage that, in hindsight, you should have known not to marry him/her?"&lt;/a&gt; blew up on the social network, with both men and women weighing in with the pre-marriage warning signs they ignored. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what were some of the most ominous red flags? For one man, it started with meeting the folks: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/intensenerd" target="_hplink"&gt;intensenerd&lt;/a&gt;: When I arrived, there were two men leaving their home wearing suits and driving a rental car.
When I asked who they were, her mom explained that it was 2 producers from the Jerry Springer show. They were there to interview her grandfather and her big brother.

&lt;p&gt;The episode they were invited to appear on was called "Grandpa stole my wallet and my girlfriend."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her brother couldn't go because his probation officer didn't want him leaving the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also found out right before we got married that she was cheating on her boyfriend with me... A man she then left me for again and is now divorced from.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yikes. Down-thread, one woman said a shady office relationship should have been warning enough: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/OfTheBegin_Ning" target="_hplink"&gt;OfTheBegin_Ning&lt;/a&gt;: He had an uncomfortably close “friendship” with a girl he worked with, and it was practically a weekly thing for me to ask if he was involved with her. He always denied it up and down. Yeah, they’re married now.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last straw for this Redditor? When her husband asked for an open marriage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For another woman, the pre-marriage warning sign was her boyfriend's utter lack of compassion when her grandfather died. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/Valeskatriona" target="_hplink"&gt;Valeskatriona:&lt;/a&gt; The day my grandfather died, I was crying on the front porch and he just stood there with his arms crossed and stared at me. I had to ask for a hug. He also did not come to the funeral and when I was with my family afterwords he sent me several text messages asking why I wasn't home already. When I got home he guilt tripped me, because I wasn't home earlier for him to comfort me. Yeah... I was an idiot. Needless the say, the marriage did not last.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But perhaps the most glaringly obvious red flag mentioned on the thread? &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/butthead_is_my_cat" target="_hplink"&gt;butthead_is_my_cat's&lt;/a&gt; partner's tendency to refer to their marriage as a "starter marriage." Eek. Live and let live, we guess? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now we want to hear from you: What's the one thing your ex did before you married that should have tipped you off that the marriage wouldn't work out? Head to the comments to share your story or tweet us &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPost Divorce&lt;/a&gt;, then click through the slideshow for more relationship red flags. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--243162--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052058/thumbs/s-ASHAMED-MAN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Trey Anthony: Still Holding On to Anger About an Ex? Let it Go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/trey-anthony/forgiving-an-ex_b_2929154.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2929154</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:04:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T21:33:03Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I am friends with all my exes! Many people find this very strange. Many years ago I had an extremely bad break up, and because there was so much hurt between us we decided to not speak. This was one of the most difficult and challenging times of my life. But as I get older I have little time for bitterness, anger, or hurt. If there is an ex in your life whom you feel anger towards or cannot speak to them, let them go.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Trey Anthony</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/trey-anthony/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I am friends with all my exes! Many people find this very strange. I also talk quite regularly to most of my exes and each one of them always calls me to wish me happy birthday! At my last birthday party, my ex came with her new partner, who I adore and we all had a grand old time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like receiving regular updates on my exes and I'm very close with most of them! Some of my exes have even flown or driven 15 hours to come to visit me in my new home and we have shared delightful conversations, giggling like school girls way into the night! I truly adore all of my ex partners and I think they are wonderful, amazing, brilliant people! I'm so glad that I have chosen wisely.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it's hard for me to comprehend loving someone so deeply and intimately and then pretending as if they never existed! Many years ago I had an extremely bad break up, and because there was so much hurt between us we decided to not speak. This was one of the most difficult and challenging times of my life. It kept me up at night. I went to therapy about it, and could not rid myself of the anger and hurt! I was filled with rage and took no responsibility for the role that I played in the demise of our relationship. I cried about it often. I told everyone I could the list of offences by my ex! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet even though I was angry, I just couldn't understand how someone I loved so deeply could act as if we never were... I was so sad that we were not able to come together to talk it out or even be in the same room without some sort of "drama" unfolding! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, time does heal all wounds and five years after our break up, I swallowed my pride and realized that I didn't need to be "right" I just wanted to be at peace. So I swallowed my pride and I sent a "peace" email and we agreed to meet. At that meeting we both shed tears of joy and hurt. We were able to talk and work things out. We both realized we needed to be in each other lives. There was so much more we needed to learn from each other, and much more growing that we needed to do as well. There was too much love there for us to just walk away -- too much herstory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get older and I become more committed to my spiritual path, I have little time for bitterness, anger, or hurt. I'm a person who loves passionately and loves deeply. I'm loyal. And if I tell you I love you, I will love you for life! You become my family. I pray often for all my exes, wishing them joy, love and laughter all the things I wish for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realize that everyone who comes into your life is a reflection of you. You chose them, they are mirrors of who you are, and you attracted them. So for me, every one of my partners have been beautiful learning lessons. I have loved them all differently. Learnt different things. And they have truly shaped the womyn I am, and slowly evolving to be. I loved them and I still love them all in my own special way. I want each one of them to be happy and live inspired lives! And I truly thank each and everyone of them for loving me fiercely.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my lesson to to everyone today is, I truly encourage you, to let go of anger, hurt and blame. If there is an ex in your life whom you feel anger towards or cannot speak to them, let them go...let them go with love.  Daily bless them and pray for them. Don't hold on to anger it's not good. Write them a letter, send it, or maybe don't send it. Maybe send them a peace email, reach out in a loving way or silently release them in your heart. But you must let go of the anger, remember that you use to love them.... and love is a gift -- always choose to unwrap it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Love is a gift of one's inner most soul to another so both can be whole."  -Buddhist quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namaste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--259411--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052289/thumbs/s-BREAKUP-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Do I Adopt My Stepchild? </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/ask-the-attorney-steppare_n_2934362.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934362</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:54:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:54:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Q: For years, I have filled the role of a parent to my stepchild, and I would like that relationship to be legally recognized. How...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>canon-mcmillan.patch.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Q: For years, I have filled the role of a parent to my stepchild, and I would like that relationship to be legally recognized. How do I go about adopting my stepchild, as a stepparent?&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051924/thumbs/s-ADOPT-STEPCHILD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Common Is Infidelity?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/how-common-is-cheating--i_n_2934394.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934394</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:54:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:53:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Sometimes I worry that society is becoming immune to infidelity and cheating in a romantic relationship. We hear things like, “Half of all marriages end...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>psychcentral.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Sometimes I worry that society is becoming immune to infidelity and cheating in a romantic relationship. We hear things like, “Half of all marriages end in divorce” and “Half of people in a relationship admit to cheating.” We become desensitized and perhaps a bit pessimistic by hearing these disheartening statistics repeated over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051931/thumbs/s-CAUGHT-CHEATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Well That's One Way To Show You're Single...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/funny-sticker_n_2934119.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934119</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:21:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T23:59:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Ever get tired of seeing those stick-figure family decals on the back of minivans? If the answer is yes, then this post might warm your...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Ever get tired of seeing those &lt;a href="http://minnesota.cbslocal.com/2013/02/20/good-question-how-did-family-stick-figures-become-so-popular/" target="_hplink"&gt;stick-figure family decals&lt;/a&gt; on the back of minivans? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer is yes, then this post might warm your cold, cold heart. On Friday, Reddit user HollahAtAllah &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/rva/comments/1asyo9/saw_this_little_nugget_in_church_hill_somebodys/" target="_hplink"&gt;posted a photo&lt;/a&gt; of one slightly embittered Hyundai Veloster owner's rear window. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/QSwUotI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/QSwUotI.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that's one way to make your relationship status known. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you think of the window display, then click through the slideshow below for some of the funniest bumper sticker parodies we've ever seen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--287936--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051916/thumbs/s-STICK-FIGURE-FAMILY-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Inside Kevin Hart's Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce_n_2933725.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933725</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:17:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:17:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Actor and comedian Kevin Hart's bank account is thanking him right now. According to TMZ, although Hart is worth a reported $9 million, his ex-wife...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Actor and comedian Kevin Hart's bank account is thanking him right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;According to TMZ&lt;/a&gt;, although Hart is worth a &lt;a href="http://www.celebritynetworth.com/richest-celebrities/richest-comedians/kevin-hart-net-worth/" target="_hplink"&gt;reported $9 million&lt;/a&gt;, his ex-wife Torrei Hart received a relatively small sum in their divorce -- &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;a settlement of just $175,000.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2011/01/exclusive-documents-comedian-kevin-hart-files-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;filed for divorce &lt;/a&gt;from his wife of nearly eight years in February 2011. In the filing, he requested that the court not grant Torrei &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2011/01/exclusive-documents-comedian-kevin-hart-files-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;any spousal support.&lt;/a&gt; They &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;finalized their split&lt;/a&gt; in November 2011. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the divorce wasn't an entirely negative experience for the "Real Husbands of Hollywood" star, who recently opened up about how he's&lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/393704/kevin-hart-covers-ebony-talks-getting-serious-his-quot-lying-period-quot-and-why-he-never-makes-gay-jokes?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_hplink"&gt; changed for the better&lt;/a&gt; since the split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"When I was married, I definitely went through a lying period," he said in the &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/393704/kevin-hart-covers-ebony-talks-getting-serious-his-quot-lying-period-quot-and-why-he-never-makes-gay-jokes?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_hplink"&gt;April issue of Ebony magazine&lt;/a&gt;. "I just turned into a liar, but you learn from your mistakes. Being that guy once upon a time has helped me develop into the man I am now, and I approach relationships in a completely different manner."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Harts have &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2011/01/exclusive-documents-comedian-kevin-hart-files-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;two children together&lt;/a&gt; -- an 8-year-old daughter and a 5-year-old son. Kevin will reportedly pay his ex &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;$19,785 a month in child support.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to test your knowledge of other celebrity divorce settlements:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--233083--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051765/thumbs/s-KEVIN-HART-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Natalie Gregg: The Biggest Myth About Child Custody</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-gregg/fathers-rights-in-divorce_b_2903819.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2903819</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T18:04:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T18:03:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary>During divorce proceedings, the level of past parental involvement is the most critical factor in determining both the level of access that each spouse will receive and the amount of child support that will be provided, if any.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Natalie Gregg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-gregg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;In my practice as a &lt;a href="http://nataliegregg.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce lawyer&lt;/a&gt;, the vast majority of the fathers whom I have represented want to remain actively involved as parents after their divorce has been settled. Very few want to sever ties with their children, even when they cannot stand the sight of their ex-wives.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
In fact, I am seeing an increasing number who are fighting to be named the primary conservator -- or the parent who determines where the children live and has majority of the access. This is especially true when both spouses are working full-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a working mom, and I benefit from a marriage in which parenting duties are truly split 50/50. However, having worked with over 600 divorcing clients, I can say that our relationship is an exception to the rule.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Even in dual income households, one spouse typically bears a disproportionate level of the parenting responsibilities. During divorce proceedings, the level of past parental involvement is the most critical factor in determining both the level of access that each spouse will receive and the amount of child support that will be provided, if any.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
From my perspective, the courts should not arbitrarily favor mothers over fathers. I believe firmly that the spouse who has served as the primary parental figure should remain in that role after the divorce has been finalized. And as such, they should receive a corresponding amount of the post-divorce estate. This is the case &lt;em&gt;regardless of the gender&lt;/em&gt; of the primary conservator.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As a marketing ploy, some family law firms tout themselves as "father's rights" firms. The truth is that, while some judges may arbitrarily favor the traditional model of a family with the mother as the primary caretaker and the father as the sole breadwinner, their decision of who will serve as primary managing conservator generally rests on the level of each spouse's involvement in the children's lives. If both spouses were working full-time and they shared parenting duties 50/50, then the father has just as solid an opportunity to be named the primary managing conservator as the mother.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The key consideration is whether the father was equally (or more) involved in the children's lives and took a vested interest on a &lt;em&gt;daily basis&lt;/em&gt; in parenting. Examples include the following: taking the children to school, attending PTA meetings, making meals for the children, managing doctor appointments, choosing extracurricular activities and the like. Here, the court seeks to maintain what is closest to continuity for the children.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And as a divorcing parent, you should also seek to maintain as much strength in the foundation of your children's lives as possible. The worst behavior that I see in my practice is when divorcing spouses treat their children like property rather than people. Fighting over them is not the same as arguing over who gets the house or the car or the timeshare: when it comes to determining conservatorship, access and child support, your primary focus should be to build the most effective co-parenting relationship possible.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As I often tell my clients, "You can love your kids or hate your ex-spouse; but you &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-gregg/how-to-tell-your-children_1_b_1792700.html" target="_hplink"&gt;cannot do both&lt;/a&gt; at the same time."&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And now, for my fellow mothers who are reading this article:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I understand that we share a special bond with the children who grew within us for nine months before they met their fathers. However, when it comes to deciding their future, we truly need to focus on what is best for them (and which, at heart, is truly what is best for us). That could very well be having the father named as the primary conservator. You are no less of a mother to that child just because they now live with their father more than with you. In parenting, what matters most is the quality of the time that children receive from both of their parents.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This article neither constitutes nor is intended to be legal advice. Please be advised that if you need legal counsel, you should consult an attorney regarding your individual situation.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Georgianna Donadio, MSc, Ph.D., D.C.: Loving Again After Loss</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/georgianna-donadio-msc-phd/loving-again-after-loss_b_2883053.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2883053</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T17:33:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T17:33:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Losing love by breakup or death is one of the most profound and stressful things we as human beings can experience.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Georgianna Donadio, MSc, Ph.D., D.C.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/georgianna-donadio-msc-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships, belonging and love are essential to our health, happiness and what we want, need and desire. It is one of psychologist Abraham Maslow's Hierarchy of Human Needs and the one of the most frequently conflicted areas of human interaction. The willingness to be vulnerable to love again after things go badly in an intimate relationship requires both courage and resilience to transverse the landscape of such profound emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing love by breakup or death is one of the most profound and stressful things we as human beings can experience. The loss of love can literally "break our hearts" and can even undermine our will to live. Sigmund Freud, MD, the well-known father of modern psychoanalysis, many decades ago stated that we "are never as hopelessly unhappy as when we lose love."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is what sustains our lives; so much so that research shows the impact of grief on the development and exacerbation of unresolved grief, and how it can result in the development of serious illness or fatal heart disease. The loss of love is something many of us fear and something many of us can't imagine happening when, on the surface, things in our relationship seem to be on an even keel. Yet, for most of us at one time or another, we experience the crushing pain of losing love and the almost obsessive reaction we have to try and regain that love, or find a way to end the pain and sense of emptiness that can often accompany such loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with a small press literary publication, The Sun, you may not have read this poignant essay, published in that magazine, written by Poe Ballantine. He provides insight to the necessity of trust within love. Trust is the element of love which provides the safe place necessary to share our lives and hearts with others. Trusting, and dealing with the loss of trust within love, requires great courage to be able to move beyond the loss and love again. It is interesting that we are inundated from many sources these days with information about wellness and how to prevent illness, when what many of us need is information about how to create more fulfilling and healthy relationships and prevent the heartbreak of losing love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ballantine's essay tells a story about his father:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"He kept a close ritual of coffee, then work, dinner, his television shows and his cigarettes. The newspaper stayed on the table open to the personals. He had opened them the first day she had left him, like the reflex of a man covering a wound after being shot. His face was gray from survival. He was a man who could not allow himself to break. The despair stretched out. The music from the stereo could not fill the emptiness. Our conversations were automatic, clock talk. His single guiding hope was that she would return."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What had happened to my father - he never believed it would happen to him. He was fifty years old, settled, comfortable, secure. His children were raised. He had worked hard all his life and now he could relax. I understood why my mother had left him, but I still condemned her for leaving - for taking the easy way out. My father and I played cards and watched private-eye dramas on television. He looked in the personals, called once at something that looked right, but cancelled soon after; it just wasn't in him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"One Sunday afternoon I heard him crying in the bedroom. I didn't know what to do with a father who cried. He taught me all I knew, the important things: honesty, loyalty, firm handshake, the love beyond self-love, the duty of a man. Trust was his only religion and it was failing him and in turn it was the failure of the world."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The one thing a human being asks for on this earth is to be loved. Why should it be impossible?"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trusting, loving and the resilience to come back from the loss of love may be the next "health frontier." Nutrition, one of the more popular health topics, is not just about nourishing our tissues. Nourishing our hearts, which are hungry for love and acceptance, is another skill we need to learn. If we should be mindful of what we eat, how mindful should we become about how and who we love? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/cancerlibrary/epeco/selfstudy/module-4-pdf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/3684749&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dad Who Posted Money Pics On Facebook Busted For Child Support: Cops</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/christopher-robinson-facebook-money_n_2934348.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934348</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T17:25:19Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:10:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Christopher Robinson may have to pick that money off the floor and give it to his ex after cops used his Facebook photos of him...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Simon McCormack</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/simon-mccormack/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/03/facebook-money-pics-bust-dad-for-allegedly-dodging-child-support/" target="_hplink"&gt;Christopher Robinson may have to pick that money&lt;/a&gt; off the floor and give it to his ex after cops used his Facebook photos of him posing with cash to bust him for allegedly failing to pay child support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABC News reports that the Milwaukee man is charged with &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/03/facebook-money-pics-bust-dad-for-allegedly-dodging-child-support/" target="_hplink"&gt;three felony counts of failure to support his 3-year-old child,&lt;/a&gt; after he allegedly didn't make a single monthly child support payment for three years. He was supposed to pony up $150 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What we do in these types of cases is we try to find out from other family members whether there is other information we may not be able to know about,” Milwaukee County Chief Deputy District Attorney Kent Lovern told ABCNews.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lovern told WDJT his office often uses Facebook to build cases against &lt;a href="http://www.cbs58.com/news/local-news/Father-Flaunts-Cash-on-Facebook-Busted-for-Child-Support-198868891.html" target="_hplink"&gt;suspected child support scofflaws.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's a great investigative tool for us because it gives us a glimpse into their real lives that our targets may be living," Lovern said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stir's Nicole Fabian-Weber tries to understand what would posses someone to post photos of themselves with money when they are &lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/technology/153004/child_support_avoiding_dad_busted" target="_hplink"&gt;delinquent on child support payments.&lt;/a&gt; She comes to the conclusion that it has something to do with the constant need for attention that Facebook engenders and feeds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It's awfully easy to get caught these days, thanks to Facebook. People want to be seen! They want to be heard! And clearly, that's predominantly what's on their minds. I mean, bailing out on three years of child support, then uploading a photo of cash. That's just dumb. And that, my Friends, is being drunk on Facebook.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/03/facebook-money-pics-bust-dad-for-allegedly-dodging-child-support/" target="_hplink"&gt;ABC News reports&lt;/a&gt; that Robinson was served with an arrest warrant in February, but since he failed to appear, the warrant is still active. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051787/thumbs/s-CHRISTOPHER-ROBINSON-FACEBOOK-MONEY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
