<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Meg Buck: 10 Lessons I Learned About Marriage From Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/meg-buck/what-i-know-about-marriag_b_2951150.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2951150</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T06:29:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T06:28:40Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I married my first love when I was 22. We'd been together for four years and I was having his baby, so it seemed like the right thing to do. It turns out that I was wrong -- we ended up getting divorced after less than a year of marriage. Here's what I learned from the experience.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Meg Buck</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/meg-buck/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I married my first love when I was 22. We'd been together for four years and I was having his baby, so it seemed like the right thing to do. It turns out that I was wrong -- we ended up getting divorced after less than a year of marriage. Here's what I learned from the experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don't get married because it seems like a good idea.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
We were very much in love, but we hadn't faced any extreme ups or downs in our dating relationship and saw no reason married life would be any different. We didn't consider the additional stress of a newborn, let alone how much life changes as one continues to grow, get older, and take on greater responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Being in love is not going to cut it. You need more.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
My marriage to husband #1 fell apart within a year. We held expectations of one another that we never communicated, and this led to some pretty deep-seated resentments. We didn't turn to each other or depend on one another during the rocky times. The wedge between us grew until we didn't relate to each other at all. It got to the point that I didn't even want him coming home at night, never mind any idea of having sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We co-existed for a short while until I knew things had to change. I told him I wanted to get counseling, but he told me there was nothing wrong. &lt;em&gt;What? &lt;/em&gt;Nothing wrong? We don't talk! We're unhappy! At least I was unhappy. I felt hurt that that wasn't reason enough to seek help to rebuild our relationship. I didn't think I could face fighting for my marriage by myself. I felt like a total failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your marriage is not you. Marriage is not a measure of your worth or value to others.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Our divorce was awful. We were angry and hurt, and lashed out at each other.&lt;br /&gt;
I was consumed by my anger. I had put my trust in husband #1 and he failed me. At least, that's what I told myself. I felt like he had done something to me by not being the husband I wanted him to be. It took years of hard work for us to make our way out of this morass of upset and resentment. But we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then came husband #2. I was determined to make this relationship work. Between divorcing #1 and meeting #2, I'd met and dated a dozen men. I resolved to make this relationship different than the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The state of your relationship has something to do with you, not just the other person.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
When #2 and I met, we lived nearly 500 miles from one another. Our relationship began with a conversation that looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Should we do this?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't know. I don't know how to have a long distance relationship that works."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't know how to do it either. But I think we can do it together."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You're right. Let's do it. Let's do whatever it takes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Do whatever it takes. Make that your commitment, not just to your partner but to your relationship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 It wasn't long before I was pregnant. Number-two and I spent three days discussing our options. Both aborting and going through with the pregnancy would change our lives forever. An abortion meant feelings we couldn't imagine for we didn't know how long. Having the baby meant his moving 500 miles to create a family with me and I wasn't willing to ask him to do that. If he was going to move, it was because he wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Share your feelings, fears, concerns, commitments and goals with your partner. Listen to your partner's feelings, fears, concerns, commitments and goals. Let their feelings be as important as yours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We realized that the only reason we were considering aborting was because we were afraid of what life would look like if we decided to keep the baby, and we didn't want to live lives of, or make decisions from, fear. So we decided to have the baby, and in the process turn upside down everything we knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Go with the flow. It's so much easier to accept and roll with the punches than to wish earnestly for something else to happen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since we met, #2 and I have seen a lot of transition and change: we have moved three times and I chose to give up custody of my older son instead of fighting a custody battle with #1. Not to mention our son was born. Some days our saving grace was simply being able to talk to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Tell your partner what you need. Be as honest as you possibly can, every day &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number-two did not propose right away. We had agreed that we would not get married until we were certain it was what we both wanted. I'd jumped that gun before and was not about to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Trust your partner implicitly. They have pledged their life to you too. They're in this too. They want it to work too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early in our engagement, my older son asked me when we were going to get divorced. I realized that all he knew was divorce. I told him that his soon-to-be stepfather and I were not going to get divorced. He asked how I knew. I told him that divorce isn't an option for us. We are committed to doing whatever it takes to stay together. Marriage may not always be easy, look pretty, or feel nice. And that is okay. Life isn't always easy, doesn't always look pretty or feel nice. And that is okay, too. His father and I hadn't known these things. And that was okay too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Focus on the good, in your partner and in your relationship. Focus on the good in life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For a pre-wedding gift, my mother-in-law gave us a small, heart-shaped plaque. I hung it in our bathroom so we both can see it every day. It says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marriage is like a Garden &lt;br /&gt;
it takes a lot of love &lt;br /&gt;
&amp; a little work &lt;br /&gt;
each day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn't have said it better myself.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057486/thumbs/s-MARRIAGE-LESSONS-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How To Win Over Your Stepkids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/stepparent-advice-how-to_n_2951878.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2951878</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T22:38:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T22:39:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's a rare stepparent who hasn't tried, in their own way, to win over their stepkids. Whether it was snapping up two Justin Bieber concert...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's a rare stepparent who hasn't tried, in their own way, to win over their stepkids. Whether it was snapping up two Justin Bieber concert tickets or attempting to bond over hot wings during a stepsons-only guy's night out, it's hard to resist trying to fast-track a solid relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as any member of a blended family can tell you, relationships can't be forced. So how can you stop stressing over winning over your step-kids -- and actually get them to like you? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recenty asked five experts (and HuffPost bloggers) to share with us the three things they think stepparents need to know to create a healthy, unhurried relationship with their stepkids. Click through the slideshow below to read their advice, then &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostDivorce&lt;/a&gt; the three things &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think new stepparents need to know to forge a better relationship with their spouse's kids. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288355--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055534/thumbs/s-STEPPARENT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Inside Porsha &amp; Kordell's (Former) Happy Home</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/porsha-kordell-stewart-divorce_n_2958193.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2958193</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:38:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:37:56Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We're wondering who gets this place in the divorce. </summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michelle-manetti/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The internet is abuzz about "&lt;a href="http://www.bravotv.com/the-real-housewives-of-atlanta" target="_hplink"&gt;Real Housewives of Atlanta&lt;/a&gt;" star &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/kordell-stewart-divorce-porsha_n_2955815.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Porsha Williams and NFL star Kordell Stewart's reported divorced&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we have to say, we're a bit surprised ourselves. Especially after seeing the couple's amazing &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/house-tour" target="_hplink"&gt;house&lt;/a&gt; that was featured on &lt;a href="http://www.bravotv.com/the-real-housewives-of-atlanta/rhoa-house-tours" target="_hplink"&gt;BravoTV.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video, the gorgeous two-story house is covered in photos of the duo in almost every room. Williams even talks about how she designed it after the &lt;a href="http://www.starwoodhotels.com/stregis/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;St. Regis Hotel&lt;/a&gt;, the location where they got married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally we're wondering who will end up with this ritzy Atlanta abode with features like pretty French doors, glamorous furniture and built-in kitchen seating. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the clip above to see the complete house tour, then click through our slideshow to see photos of the "Real Housewives of Atlanta" cast. Read more about the&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/kordell-stewart-divorce-porsha_n_2955815.html" target="_hplink"&gt;state of their marriage.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--252051--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057377/thumbs/s-PORSHA-KORDELL-STEWART-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Is Putting Your Children First Bad For Marriage?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/marriage-problems_n_2957477.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2957477</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T21:35:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:10:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Do good moms make bad wives? That's the charged question blogger Jackie Morgan MacDougall asked Tuesday in a HuffPost Divorce blog on the need for...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Do good moms make bad wives? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the charged question blogger Jackie Morgan MacDougall asked Tuesday in a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jackie-morgan-macdougall/7-tips-to-save-your-marri_b_2909724.html" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost Divorce blog&lt;/a&gt; on the need for parents to prioritize their marriages to stave off divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm not saying to neglect the kids, but they won't exactly suffer by seeing their parents put each other at the top of the list, instead serving as relationship role models," MacDougall wrote. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MacDougall is hardly the first person to make the case for putting your spouse before your kids. Author and mother-of-four Ayelet Waldman &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-solod-warren/whos-your-bad-mother-ayel_b_195824.html" target="_hplink"&gt;famously elicited boos&lt;/a&gt; from an "Oprah" show audience for admitting that she &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2005/03/27/fashion/27love.html?_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;loved her husband more than her own kids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to know what our readers thought, so with MacDougall's piece in mind, we posed this question to our &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce?ref=tn_tnmn" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; communities: Is putting your children first bad for a marriage? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to read their responses, then head to the comments to weigh in with your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288519--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1056945/thumbs/s-MARRIAGE-PROBLEMS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Every Woody Allen Stammer From Every Woody Allen Movie</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/every-woody-allen-stammer_n_2936067.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2936067</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T16:15:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T16:51:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Here is every Woody Allen stammer ever from every Woody Allen movie ever. Brace yourselves..... Edited by Ben Craw and Oliver Noble...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Oliver Noble</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/oliver-noble/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Here is every Woody Allen stammer ever from every Woody Allen movie ever. Brace yourselves.....&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Edited by Ben Craw and Oliver Noble&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052451/thumbs/s-EVERY-WOODY-ALLEN-STAMMER-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Barry Finkel: The Best Way To Protect Yourself From Infidelity?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barry-finkel/infidelity-clauses-protec_b_2903812.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2903812</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T16:13:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T16:12:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Can a marriage be protected from infidelity? Some spouses and divorce lawyers believe the infidelity clause is the antidote to adultery.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Barry Finkel</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/barry-finkel/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Infidelity can often be the death knell of a marriage. One spouse cheats on the other, causing anger, threats of financial retribution and hostility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, can a marriage be protected from infidelity? Some spouses and divorce lawyers believe the infidelity clause is the antidote to adultery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An infidelity clause is a component of a prenuptial agreement stating that if one party is proved to have been involved in an extramarital affair, the aggrieved spouse will receive a financial award from the cheating spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infidelity clauses came to the forefront in &lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/2013/01/17/tiger-woods-proposes-to-ex-wife-elin-nordegren-report-says/" target="_hplink"&gt;January&lt;/a&gt;, and again in &lt;a href="http://www.examiner.com/article/tiger-woods-elin-nordegren-togetherness-rekindles-remarriage-rumors" target="_hplink"&gt;February&lt;/a&gt;, when Tiger Woods was rumored to be seeking back ex-wife Elin Nordegren (&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/20/lindsey-vonn-dating-tiger-woods_n_2917234.html" target="_hplink"&gt;He since announced&lt;/a&gt; that he's dating skier Lindsay Vonn.) At the time, Nordegren reportedly countered with a demand for a prenup and infidelity clause with a $350 million financial penalty should Woods stray again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though rare, the infidelity clause is not unheard of. In most cases, they're requested by a prospective spouse who loves her partner (it's most often the wife asking for the clause), but may know of or suspect a history of cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one case, I represented the husband-to-be in the drafting of a prenuptial agreement. It was both spouses' second marriage and both were in their 40s. The wife's attorney inserted the infidelity clause demanding she get my client's restaurant if he were found to have cheated on her. Given he had no history of an affair in his previous marriage, we struck that from the prenup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another situation, the wife asked for a doubling of all alimony settlement figures from $150,000 to $300,000 if her husband had an affair. Given the husband in this case also had no history of cheating, again, the language was removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While neither attempt was a "deal-killer" for the marriage, in both cases the husbands-to-be were disheartened that the wife would make such a request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therein lies one pitfall of a infidelity clause. Such a request could raise doubt or mistrust where none is warranted. For a couple where neither has any history of cheating, the clause might be cause for resentment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the legal issues and concerns regarding infidelity clauses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infidelity clauses are binding.&lt;/strong&gt; Like prenuptial agreements themselves, they are contractual agreements entered into by the two parties and found enforceable in most states. So neither should have any expectation of excusal from the agreement should he or she transgress.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's hard to define "infidelity." &lt;/strong&gt;For example, is it flirting with a co-worker? A husband's trip to a gentlemen's club or strip bar? Is kissing another women a betrayal? Is oral sex? Or is sexual intercourse the sole actionable offense? Interpretation -- and mere suspicions -- must be avoided. The agreement must clearly define what constitutes infidelity, and proof thereof.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What constitutes proof of an affair?&lt;/strong&gt; Cash withdrawals, credit card receipts, cell phone records, even toll transponders can point to errant spending or travel patterns. Are one's suspicions worth hiring a private investigator to dig deeper? That may be required to get to the truth.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many family law attorneys advise pursuing infidelity clauses only when the other party has a proven history of cheating or extra-marital affairs. Where none are known or suspected, the clause goes beyond what couples are often trying to accomplish in a prenup -- that is, a reasonable protection of one's interests.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055563/thumbs/s-INFIDELITY-CLAUSE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lisa Copeland: Is This Why Alpha Women Are Still Single?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-copeland/dating-over-50-alpha-males_b_2923679.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2923679</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T11:52:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T11:54:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The problem is when we want an alpha male, we are threatening the ingrained role in men's DNA from caveman days of needing to be the provider. An alpha male looks at Katie and doesn't know how to play the provider role of being able to give to Katie in a way that will make her happy.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa Copeland</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-copeland/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;After 15 years of being single, Katie Couric recently said she was ready for a relationship that could lead to marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Katie has to do is look around and she'll find herself in great company with less than famous boomer women who are in the same situation she's in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is happening here? Why are these dynamic, powerhouse women still single so many years after their marriages ended?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katie and many women our age look great. They lead successful lives. And I'm sure (just as your friends say to you) Katie is probably told over and over again how she's such a great catch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And she is. Katie has been a role model personally and professionally for many of us for decades now. We love her style, we admire her parenting and we feel like she could be a best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is happening here? Why can't Katie, and so many powerful women of our generation, find a man to marry? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powerful women like Katie usually want to date a man who is just like she is -- smart, successful and respected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the alpha male to whom Katie is attracted does not want to marry a woman who is a clone of himself. More than likely, this man is looking for a woman who will let him give, who will appreciate everything he does for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women of our generation were rarely advised on how to receive from a man. If anything, we were taught we didn't need men in our lives. We were encouraged to become strong and independent women and we learned to take care of ourselves with or without a man's presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've spent years fighting our way to the top of the corporate ladder becoming successful, powerful and influential women in our fields. We are used to making decisions and we know how to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the president at work and we are used to being the president at home. And we don't know how to turn that feeling off when it comes to men. We want equality in all areas of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is when we want an alpha male, we are threatening the ingrained role in men's DNA from caveman days of needing to be the provider. An alpha male looks at Katie and doesn't know how to play the provider role of being able to give to Katie in a way that will make her happy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inability for boomer women to receive from a man is why boomer men often turn to younger women for companionship. It's not necessarily the eye candy he's looking for. It's the appreciation he craves that younger women give to him by joyfully receiving his gifts. Something women our age don't always do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An alpha male wants to cherish his woman by showing her he can protect her financially, emotionally and physically to the best of his ability. This role makes a woman like Katie feel safe and protected. In theory, she likes his decisiveness, but in reality she often has a hard time letting him be the leader. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the alpha man might love her mind but will quickly tire of competing with her for the leadership role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is a powerful woman to do? A beta male is a better fit for Katie and other alpha women out there. These men will respect their alpha female and let her make the major decisions in the relationship. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In return, a woman of authority will cherish a man who doesn't mind taking a backseat. He may not have the job or status alpha females are used to, but he will have other qualities to offer the relationship that can be beneficial, like the ability to emotionally support in a way an alpha man can't. Wouldn't that be nice after a hard day at work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do you think? Tell us your thoughts in the comments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055502/thumbs/s-DATING-OVER-50-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jackie Morgan MacDougall: Do Good Moms Make Bad Wives?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jackie-morgan-macdougall/7-tips-to-save-your-marri_b_2909724.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2909724</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T07:10:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T15:46:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What you might not realize about that "perfect" mother who's always volunteering in the classroom.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jackie Morgan MacDougall</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jackie-morgan-macdougall/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Every classroom has one. Maybe she's even you. She's the mom who lives and breathes all things motherhood, using every ounce of energy to provide the precious little ones with the ultimate childhood experience. She bakes from scratch, has dinner on the table every night at 5:00 p.m. sharp and can whip together homemade costumes for the entire 5th grade cast of Wizard of Oz faster than you can say "And your little dog, too."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't even get me started on her crafting skills. While I try to avoid eye contact when I see that my son's teacher needs tiny fall trees cut out, that lady knows her way around a glue gun like nobody's business. She's like a cross between Martha Stewart and MacGyver, using pipe cleaner and a rock to create memorable holiday gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, most of us struggle with the simple task of juggling homework and soccer practice -- there's no shame in that, right? Nope, not her. She not only gets it all done but heads up the carnival committee and organizes the next class party at the same time. I want to scream at her "My God, woman, don't you sleep?" But I'm starting to think that if you showed up at her house in the middle of the night, you'd see her put away on a shelf with the rest of the wind-up robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for every other mom who thinks that she's perfect, setting the bar the rest of us can't even come close to, there's a certain someone who's anything but impressed... her husband. Because while she's spending sleepless nights frosting cupcakes and sewing costumes, he's feeling neglected and going to bed alone. Which brings me to my question...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do good moms make bad wives?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica is no stranger to the good mom, bad wife question. In a recent conversation, she revealed to me that she believes her dedication to the kids was a major contributing factor in the recent demise of her marriage, creating resentment, competition and feelings of neglect in her husband. "He hated that [I always volunteered] because it set into the time that should've been fed into him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But was he partially responsible for leading her to a life of extreme motherhood in the first place? Jessica admits that throughout her marriage, she's often felt unappreciated and not supported emotionally, leaving her with unmet needs. Using her time with the kids to fill those needs was good for the kids and her. "Because I needed validation and emotional gratification that he wasn't providing, the kid stuff was easy to take on. I always get a 'thank you.' Volunteering is very validating for me; it's rewarding and fulfilling."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think almost anyone who's walked into their young child's classroom can relate. The feeling you get when your kid notices your arrival can be pretty intoxicating, and knowing you're making an impact is exhilarating. But what happens in a few years when your kid begs you not to come and refuses to be seen with you? After years letting your marriage run on auto pilot, I wouldn't be so sure your spouse will be waiting with open arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.healthymarriageinfo.org/couples/lists-for-couples/index.aspx#6" target="_hplink"&gt;National Healthy Marriage Resource Center&lt;/a&gt; cites spending time together, showing respect and exploring common interests as a few of their 10 tips to having a healthy marriage. I'm no therapist, but I've got my own tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call each other names. &lt;/strong&gt;There's nothing worse than hearing a couple call each other "mommy" and "daddy" when there are no kids in a 100-yard radius. Referring to each other by name is a tiny, yet effective, way to recall the person you loved pre-kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just say no.&lt;/strong&gt; Say it with me... "I can't volunteer to run the bake sale this time." Say it, own it, live it. I promise you, if you utter those words, you will not die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just say yes.&lt;/strong&gt; Rumor has it, men often lose interest in alone time after hitting a certain age. Turn him down time after time and I guarantee he'll lose it with you much earlier. Just sayin'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize. &lt;/strong&gt;Listen, I'm not saying you shouldn't be involved with the kids. Volunteering and running the activities show is a positive thing and helps connect you with the kids. But do you really think Groundhog Day requires individually-wrapped holiday gift bags filled with pencils and Punxsutawney Phil-shaped erasers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forsake all others.&lt;/strong&gt; That's right, it's in the vows. Somewhere between sickness and health and richer/poorer, you agreed to forsake all others. While we think about staying faithful to our partner in the biblical sense, vows were about putting each other first. I'm not saying to neglect the kids, but they won't exactly suffer by seeing their parents put each other at the top of the list, instead serving as relationship role models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop making excuses.&lt;/strong&gt; I know I can be the first to suggest skipping date night in order to save a little cash. But the price of dinner and a sitter is nothing compared to the cost of divorce. So put on some lipstick and get your butt out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skip the crayons.&lt;/strong&gt; Here's a date night rule to live by: If there's a play area in the restaurant, find somewhere else to eat. Chain restaurants are packed with screaming kids and stressed-out parents, not the atmosphere to encourage kid-free conversation and romance. I know you love your never-ending breadsticks, but save Olive Garden for family night, OK?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you a better mom or wife? Share your tips to a healthy marriage and how you balance both!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055560/thumbs/s-GOOD-MOM-BAD-WIFE-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: The Messy Way One Woman Got Back At Her Cheating Husband </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/cheating-husband_n_2951322.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2951322</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T22:52:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:51:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One woman's response to having her heart broken by her cheating husband? Breaking his stuff. On Monday, Reddit user jennny55 shared a photo of her...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;One woman's response to having her heart broken by her cheating husband? Breaking his stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1azhlr/my_neighbor_caught_her_husband_cheating/" target="_hplink"&gt;Reddit user jennny55 shared a photo&lt;/a&gt; of her neighbor's belongings thrown out on the lawn after his wife discovered he had cheated. Take a look at the scene here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/LzLxr8E"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LzLxr8E.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who needs moving boxes, anyway? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head to the comments to share your thoughts on the wife's response, then click through the slideshow for five more stories of exes who got revenge post-split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--257277--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055503/thumbs/s-REVENGE-INFIDELITY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dennis Quaid And Wife Back Together... Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/dennis-quaid-divorce_n_2950257.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950257</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T22:40:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:35:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary>UPDATE: According to E! News, Dennis Quaid and Kimberly Buffington-Quaid still plan to go through with their divorce. "[Reports that they are reconciling are] not...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/401336/dennis-quaid-not-reconciling-with-wife-kimberly-after-filing-for-divorce-says-rep" target="_hplink"&gt;According to E! News&lt;/a&gt;, Dennis Quaid and Kimberly Buffington-Quaid still plan to go through with their divorce. "[Reports that they are reconciling are] not true," &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/401336/dennis-quaid-not-reconciling-with-wife-kimberly-after-filing-for-divorce-says-rep" target="_hplink"&gt;Quaid's rep told E! News&lt;/a&gt;. "They are divorcing." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREVIOUSLY: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dennis Quaid and estranged wife Kimberly Buffington-Quaid are reportedly getting back together... again.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/367701/dennis-quaid-files-for-divorce-asks-for-joint-custody-of-twins" target="_hplink"&gt;filing for divorce &lt;/a&gt; in November 2012, &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/23/dennis-quaid-wife-kimberly-back-together-divorce-filing/" target="_hplink"&gt;TMZ reports&lt;/a&gt; that the couple has reconciled. But there is one big issue: the pair already signed the divorce documents, &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/23/dennis-quaid-wife-kimberly-back-together-divorce-filing" target="_hplink"&gt;which means the split is set to become final soon.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://www.raoulfelder.com/clients.html" target="_hplink"&gt;celebrity divorce lawyer Raoul Felder&lt;/a&gt;, the couple's next move depends on whether or not a judge has already signed the divorce papers.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"If the judge did not sign the divorce order, then they can simply say they withdraw it, sign a stipulation to withdraw it and that's the end of it," Felder told HuffPost Divorce. "But if the judge did sign the order, they would have to go to court to get a new order to vacate the prior judgment of divorce."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn't the first time that the pair has split up and reconciled. In March 2012, Buffington-Quaid &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2012/03/09/dennis-quaid-divorce-kimberly-buffington/#.T1pTgXLLyRk" target="_hplink"&gt;filed for divorce&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000598/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Vegas" actor&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/313991/dennis-quaid-s-wife-stops-divorce-explosive-couple-trying-to-make-it-work-source-says" target="_hplink"&gt;withdrew the petition&lt;/a&gt; just two months later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The couple -- who are parents to &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/367701/dennis-quaid-files-for-divorce-asks-for-joint-custody-of-twins" target="_hplink"&gt;5-year-old twins&lt;/a&gt;  -- &lt;a href="http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,661042,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;tied the knot &lt;/a&gt; in July 2004. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quaid has been &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/dennis-quaids-wife-kimberly-buffington-quaid-files-for-separation-20121910" target="_hplink"&gt;married twice before&lt;/a&gt; -- first to actress PJ Soles and later to actress Meg Ryan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to test your knowledge of eight other celebrities who reconciled with an ex post-split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--209534--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055017/thumbs/s-DENNIS-QUAID-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>14 Ways To De-Stress When Your Ex Has the Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/divorce-stress_n_2950800.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950800</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T21:14:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T21:17:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One surprising silver-lining to divorce? Having time to yourself when your ex has the kids. You miss them, of course, but once you've adjusted to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;One surprising silver-lining to divorce? Having time to yourself when your ex has the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You miss them, of course, but once you've adjusted to the quiet -- and the complete lack of Nick Jr. on your TV -- that uninterrupted "me time" can be exactly what you need after a long week of soccer practices, doctor's appointments and carpooling to school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just ask HuffPost Divorce readers. From morning yoga classes, to well-earned naps, click through the slideshow below to see how our readers de-stress when the ex has the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287666--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055206/thumbs/s-NAP-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Elisabeth Moss Opens Up About Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/elisabeth-moss_n_2950149.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950149</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T20:44:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:47:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Mad Men" actress Elisabeth Moss doesn't mince words when it comes to discussing her 8-month marriage to "Saturday Night Live" funnyman Fred Armisen. A year...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"Mad Men" actress Elisabeth Moss doesn't mince words when it comes to discussing her 8-month marriage to "Saturday Night Live" funnyman Fred Armisen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year after saying that the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/03/08/elizabeth-moss-fred-armisen_n_1332911.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"greatest impersonation [Armisen] does is that of a normal person,"&lt;/a&gt; the 30-year-old actress gave more insight into what she learned from her marriage to the comedian in an interview with &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/magazine/elisabeth-moss-on-what-peggy-wont-do-this-season-on-mad-men.html?src=dayp&amp;_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh, God. I learned so much," &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/magazine/elisabeth-moss-on-what-peggy-wont-do-this-season-on-mad-men.html?src=dayp&amp;_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;Moss told the Times in early March&lt;/a&gt;. "Not to be at all Oprah on you, but it is one of those things where you are kind of glad to have learned those lessons at an early age -- to get them out of the way." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moss and Armisen married &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20315431,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;in October 2009&lt;/a&gt; and  &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/08/13/elisabeth-moss-fred-armis_n_681825.html" target="_hplink"&gt;split in May 2010&lt;/a&gt;. Less than a week after their split, Armisen was reportedly &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/08/18/fred-armisen-abby-elliott_n_687102.html " target="_hplink"&gt;dating SNL co-star Abby Elliott&lt;/a&gt;. His relationship with Elliott &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20532202,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;ended in September 2011&lt;/a&gt;. Moss has recently been linked to &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20605313,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Australian cinematographer Adam Arkapaw. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2013, Armisen admitted to Howard Stern that he was a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/08/fred-armisen-elisabeth-moss-marriage_n_2433188.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"terrible husband"&lt;/a&gt; to Moss. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want it all ... fast," &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/08/fred-armisen-elisabeth-moss-marriage_n_2433188.html" target="_hplink"&gt;he told Stern&lt;/a&gt;. "I want to be married, I want to live together ... and then somewhere around a year or two years, I get freaked out. I freak out emotionally and then I actually feel like 'Oh my God, who's this stranger in my house?'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they aren't the first celebrity exes to dish about their relationship after a split. Click through the slideshow below to read more shocking statements celebs have made post-divorce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--238408--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054899/thumbs/s-ELISABETH-MOSS-FRED-ARMISEN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Austin Blood: The Truth About Infidelity Today</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/austin-blood/social-media-booty-call_b_2908531.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2908531</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T17:06:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T23:16:52Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Whereas twenty years ago a married man might have to go to a bar or romance a co-worker for an extramarital booty call, today he can save himself all that hassle with just a few mouse clicks.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Austin Blood</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/austin-blood/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Unless you've been living on the moon for the past couple of years, you've noticed the massive surge in the number of websites dedicated to online dating. Along with old standbys like eHarmony and Match.com, hundreds of new sites now cater to every kink, taste and fetish imaginable. If that's your thing, smile your best Cheshire grin. It's a brand new day on the world wide web and you're only a few mouse clicks away from finding your first love or "dating" an incarcerated felon. Anything you want is there for the taking if you're so inclined; all you need is an internet connection and a little time on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New dating websites are blasting their way into every home in America with the cultural equivalent of an atomic bomb. The shockwaves they're leaving behind are resonating through the landscape with permanent and irreversible effects. Many online dating sites now offer an unprecedented opportunity to find that perfect match... even if you already have a significant other. As proof, one need look no further than AshleyMadison.com. Last year, this notoriously naughty website for married people seeking affairs signed up its ten-millionth member. That's the number "1" with &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; zeros, my friend! Traditional values have long been under siege, but never like this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this scenario....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late one evening while you're asleep, your husband clicks over to AshleyMadison out of curiosity. The kids are in bed and he's had a lousy day. He's stressed out about work and finances and the two of you aren't connecting like you used to. He heard about this website from a co-worker but just can't believe it until he sees it. He tells himself, "There's no harm in just checking it out...I would never have an affair."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click. Click. Click. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later he's chatting with a woman across town. (Yes, it really is that easy) She's cute. &lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; cute. And lonely. Soon messages are flying back and forth like a flurry of ping pong balls. He likes her. She likes him. It's exciting, so he'll likely return tomorrow night for some more "innocent" chat. After you've gone to sleep, of course. Over time they agree to meet for the "harmless" lunch. And before you know it...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BOOM!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Monogamy takes one in the nuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of extramarital booty calls, can you guess the number one site for online hookups? The site that puts even Mistress Madison to shame? If you said Facebook, you're correct. The same scene is repeated thousands of times across America every evening. Suburban housewife. Mother of two. Happily married... or so she tells herself. Late one night she's uploading family photos on Facebook when a message icon pops up in the corner of her screen. It's Dave, an old fling from high school. "Hey Cutie," he says. Completely harmless... right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrong! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the next several months, she unknowingly and unintentionally heads down the most slippery of slopes. It all starts innocently enough. At first, it's just surface talk. Family, career, kids and life in general. As the weeks pass, she begins to look forward to their evenings together online. With her glass of wine in hand and her husband and kids asleep, her time with Dave becomes her happy place and the escape she so badly needs. Dave is easy on the eyes and a fantastic listener. And unlike her husband, he really seems to understand her.  Over time, she begins to feel alive again. Not since her early 20's has she felt this vibrant. What began as simple online chat session eventually explodes into a blaze of passion she thought long extinguished. Before you know it, they begin to share details intimate enough to make a porn star blush. And it's all downhill from there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another blow to Mr. Monogamy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer number of people on Facebook now make it the easiest place to start down the path to an extramarital sheet shuffle. In fact, the American Academy of Matrimonial Lawyers says &lt;a href="http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/tech/news/2010-06-29-facebook-divorce_N.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;sixty-six percent of their lawyers&lt;/a&gt; now cite Facebook as the primary source of evidence in their divorce proceedings. With stats like these, it's clear that everyday folks from all walks of life are going online in droves and meeting up with old and new flames alike. For the lonely wife or horny husband, the web is now a category five tempest of temptation swirling with opportunities that didn't exist even a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now before we go any further, let me be very clear on one point: the websites themselves aren't the real issue here. Their popularity is purely symptomatic of deeper sociological matters beyond the scope of this article. The websites don't make people cheat any more than cars force people to drive drunk. What the technology does is make it substantially &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; by creating or facilitating the opportunity. Whereas twenty years ago a married man might have to go to a bar or romance a co-worker for an extramarital booty call, today he can save himself all that hassle with just a few mouse clicks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for society at large?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contend the infidelity rate will continue to increase exponentially, for married and unmarried couples alike. It's simply too damn easy to have an affair in the new millennium. This in turn will have an immense social impact on our culture as the concept of traditional marriage as a viable union takes a blow to the balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't believe me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For countless couples, marriage after the ten-year mark is already synonymous with boredom, loneliness and sometimes plain ol' misery. By almost any metric, traditional marriage is on the skids if modern statistics are to be believed. For starters, the divorce rate is higher than the Empire State Building and more couples than ever are opting instead for cohabitation and open lifestyle choices. And that was before this new wave of technology made it easier than ever to sneak around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those times I feel compelled to share the cold, hard truth of reality. Particularly given that my sworn mission is to be an advocate for all women and a critical part of this charge is creating awareness of issues with life-altering potential in a woman's world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues for better or for worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-19-signature.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-19-signature.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-19-signature-thumb.png" width="80" height="27" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a href="www.AustinBlood.com" target="_hplink"&gt;www.AustinBlood.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fan Page: &lt;a href="www.Facebook.com/TheAustinBlood" target="_hplink"&gt;www.Facebook.com/TheAustinBlood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marcy Miller: A Simple Way To Begin Moving On Post-Split </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marcy-miller/the-joy-of-nesting_b_2935535.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935535</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T16:54:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T16:54:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary>After discovering that my husband was cheating and kicking him out of our home, I was left with a broken heart, anxiety and angst, and a house full of reminders of him</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marcy Miller</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marcy-miller/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;After discovering that my husband was cheating and kicking him out of our home, I was left with a broken heart, anxiety and angst, and a house full of reminders of him. It was very painful to see his clothes in the closet, toiletries in the bathroom, tools in the garage and smiling pictures of us from happier days staring at me in every room. The memories were overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something needed to be done quickly to give me peace in my own home. I needed to reclaim my space and inject a bit of estrogen to comfort me. First, I loaded boxes of shoes, books, knick-knacks, memories, sweaters,  jeans and other non-hanging clothes and moved them carefully to my clean and dry garage. I then bought garment bags and a coat rack and hung his shirts, suits, sport coats and slacks in these, which I moved to the garage as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I had the pictures to deal with. I stored our wedding album and pictures from the reception in a box in the garage, and I tore up the pictures in the frames and spent quality time culling through pictures of friends and family to replace them. It felt like a breath of fresh air to walk into the room and see familiar, loving, smiling faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I still felt my soon-to-be-ex's presence, and I needed a clean start. So I decided to re-paint the bedroom. I had originally chosen a very neutral light pastel green on the walls, but it was time to shake up the place. I chose a deep purple/gray to change the atmosphere completely.  And what a difference a few coats of paint can make!  It lifted my spirits and helped me to forget the years of sleeping in the same bed with him. I also bought new sheets and pillows, and started to sleep in the middle of the bed instead of on "my side."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it was time to reorganize and shed all the clothes that I had been keeping in my closet but had not had the time or energy to cull. I asked my good girlfriend to come over and be brutal in forcing me to part with those pieces that I would never wear again. I guess I am a bit of a hoarder when it comes to clothing -- I always hope that I will wear it in another season and hate to part with it. But my friend had no mercy and I ended up giving away fifteen large bags of clothing to friends and Good Will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt lighter, happier, and ready to start the painful divorce process from the safety and comfort of my "new" home.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>M. Gary Neuman: What Many Adults Confess About Their Parents Split</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/m-gary-neuman/the-long-way-home-for-adu_b_2911005.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2911005</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T16:07:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T16:07:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are millions of adults who experienced the trauma of their parents' divorce 20, 30 or 40 plus years ago. Some have found closure, but many more have not.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>M. Gary Neuman</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/m-gary-neuman/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;There are millions of adults who experienced the trauma of their parents' divorce 20, 30 or 40 plus years ago. Some have found closure, but many more have not. Regrettably, it is a time in a child's life that is never forgotten; it sticks with them. For anyone who's experienced it, you know it isn't only about divorce. It's about the years of tension in the home leading up to the divorce and those commonly miserable years after the divorce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifteen years ago, Miami-Dade became the first county in the United States that would not grant a divorce in a family until the children completed the &lt;a href="http://mgaryneuman.com/consultation/the-sandcastles-program/" target="_hplink"&gt;Sandcastles Program&lt;/a&gt; for children of divorce.  Since then, more than 300,000 children of divorce have completed the Sandcastles Program internationally and it continues to help children of divorce share their deepest emotions and gain a feeling of normalcy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'd like to think it all stops there -- in the past. Sadly, our childhoods remain a part of our adult fabric for better or for worse, and with divorce in the past, there is a load of negativity that never goes away. It seems that because divorce has become ubiquitous, people feel that it shouldn't be discussed -- as if they're whining. After all, &lt;em&gt;lots &lt;/em&gt;of people went through what you did as a kid. Who wants to hear about it? &lt;em&gt;Move on, get over it. How long can you keep rehashing the same old stuff? Give it up!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet the idea of swallowing and pretending it all away is what gives significant power to the problems in the past. Consider that in my recent study of 379 children of divorce, (the subject of my new book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Long-Way-Home-Powerful/dp/0470409223" target="_hplink"&gt;The Long Way Home&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;89 percent believe their parents' divorce clearly had a negative impact on their life, while 45 percent label the impact as severe.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;80 percent have experienced severe sadness or depression.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;72 percent feel their parents' divorce impacted their ability to sustain close relationships.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;The majority feel their parents' divorce has undermined their self-confidence and ability to trust.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is divorce's nasty little secret. It's why you are afraid of sounding weak when you talk about it -- to others as well as to yourself. It's understandable. After all, you don't want to feel that life is holding you back just because of what happened to you as a child, especially because it wasn't your fault. Unfortunately, pretending the feelings away won't get you to where you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an adult who was a child of divorce, give yourself permission to look back and be honest with yourself. Even as an adult, you can heal from your past and create a new future that is less reactive to it. Like so many others in my study who have been affected by divorce, it is possible to heal. The first step in helping yourself is to open up and allow yourself to recognize how your parents' divorce has affected you. Opening up is the beginning to finding a path of change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, identify how you feel today and notice that those feelings are reminiscent of your childhood. This process takes time and focused energy, and is the subject of my new book. In the book, I  outline how research participants followed a detailed program to help them learn about themselves and make significant changes. Perhaps for the first time, adult children of divorce can face their issues, grow from them and rid themselves from the ill effects of divorce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To learn more about Gary's just released book, The Long Way Home: The Powerful 4-Step Plan  for Adult Children of Divorce, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-0470409223,descCd-buy.html" target="_hplink"&gt;wiley.com/buy/0470409223&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
M Gary Neuman is a New York Times best-selling author, rabbi, and creator of Neuman Method Programs. He was on the Oprah show 11 times as well as having made multiple appearances on Today, Dateline, the View, NPR and others.  Oprah referred to Gary as "One of the best psychotherapists in the world." To receive discounts on Gary's Creating Your Best Marriage 11 DVD set program, go to &lt;a href="http://www.neumanmethod.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;NeumanMethod.com&lt;/a&gt; and use coupon code huffington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweet Gary questions at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mgaryneuman" target="_hplink"&gt;twitter.com/mgaryneuman&lt;/a&gt; and follow Gary at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/M.Gary.Neuman" target="_hplink"&gt;facebook.com/MGaryNeuman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052533/thumbs/s-ADULT-CHILDREN-OF-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
