<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Tammy Nelson, Ph.D.: What To Do When You Discover Your Spouse Is Cheating</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/can-i-get-over-an-affair-_b_2911106.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2911106</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T09:24:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T09:23:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The immediate response after discovering a spouse's affair is commonly disbelief, anger, sadness, loss or grief.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tammy Nelson, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted from &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy; Redefining Your Relationship After Infidelity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immediate response after discovering a spouse's affair is commonly disbelief, anger, sadness, loss or grief. It can take several years before the betrayed spouse is ready to even consider forgiveness, even if the partner who cheated begs for it. And through the cheating partner may immediately feel remorse and repeat "I'm sorry" over and over again, that apology may not get past the betray'ed partner's outer layer of hurt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is possible to move on and rebuild after infidelity. I have identified three distinct phases of recovery from an &lt;a href="http://janisaspring.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;affair&lt;/a&gt;: the crisis phase, the understanding (or insight) phase, and the vision phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crisis Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first phase of affair recovery, the crisis phase, happens when an affair is disclosed or discovered. The initial shock and deep betrayal can rock your confidence, and make you feel like everything you have ever known is collapsing.  It is important in this phase of the recovery after an affair to recognize that this is a phase -- you will get through this. This really difficult time will pass, and you will move into another stage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't make any decisions now about what to do with your relationship.  Take care of yourself and your family and hold onto those major decisions for a while. When the chaos has slowed down enough for you to breathe and look around, you may start to think more about whether or not you want to stay together and start a new monogamy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially after infidelity, it can be difficult for you to envision a new, shared future. The one person you turned to in the past for support when you were in pain is now the person causing you pain. It can seem as if there's no one to turn to. You may now think of your relationship as a liability instead of your strength. You may feel lonely and confused. You may long for the partner who always served as the support system in your life, and that time of innocence before you discovered the affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a time lapse in the grief process. The person who had the affair has known about the infidelity ever since it began. If you are just now discovering the affair, you are at a totally different point in the process than your partner is. You have only begun to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Role of Grief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A &lt;a href="http://www.stages-of-grief-recovery.com/kubler-ross-stages-of-grief.html" target="_hplink"&gt;grieving&lt;/a&gt; process is normal after an affair. As you move through the grieving process, many emotions will emerge, possibly including anger, fear, denial, and eventually acceptance. You can feel as if you are grieving a death, and in many ways, you are. You are grieving the old vision of your marriage or relationship. This is true whether you decide to stay together or move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both partners must grieve their losses if they are to build a new marriage. Grief is triggered by the loss of the future you thought you were headed toward together. Whatever ideas you had about how you would grow old as a couple, retire, have grandchildren, rock on the front porch together, or travel the world, the affair has now challenged that vision of a shared future. Grief is a process of letting go of that vision. And, interestingly, grief has a way of making room for a different future if you choose to create that possibility going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Understanding (or Insight) Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The second phase of affair recovery is the understanding (or insight) phase, and you will recognize when you are entering this phase when you start to look at how the affair happened. This second phase of affair recovery comes after the crisis has ebbed and you are moving past your intense anger and confusion. Although it can be a difficult time, this phase will help you to experience empathy for each other and can give you hope for the future if you decide you want to stay together. You may still not know whether you want to make things work for the long run, but you will be able to do some of the work on your past to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the affair and how it happened will help you to get clearer about what led you both to this point in your lives. This means you both need to explore the meaning of the affair. During this second phase of affair recovery, you may begin to wonder where your responsibility lies for what happened in your relationship. This is not about assigning blame, but a time to deconstruct the affair and the history of your marriage or relationship, to find out where the roots of the infidelity began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting to understand the affair can answer many of the questions that you may feel are still unanswered. Some of your frustration may be relieved at that point, and you may be ready to make some decisions about your relationship going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moving Past Blame&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If both partners are willing and ready to move into healing, you will notice a shift happening. Instead of feeling polarized into the good spouse and the bad spouse, the two of you will begin to realize that you each share responsibility for what happened in your relationship before the affair. There was most probably a dynamic in your marriage that contributed to the affair. When you start becoming aware of this shared dynamic, the recovery process becomes a shared experience between the two of you. The affair may even eventually move from being "his affair" or "her affair" to being "our affair."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start to feel this shift, it means you are moving into the next stage of your affair recovery. You are moving from the Insight phase into the Vision phase, where you are ready to look at a new future and a new monogamy, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vision Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When you reach the third phase of affair recovery, the vision phase, it is time to make some decisions about staying together, or letting go and moving on.  Here you can decide about whether or not it is possible to create a new future together. To do this, you should be clear about what your new monogamy will look like. In my new book, &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt;, there are distinct steps for developing that new relationship, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt; challenges the common view that an affair has to mean the end of a relationship. Monogamy as we know it is changing in our world and in our culture. Our ability to remain monogamous is becoming more difficult in an age when cheating is easier than ever. Marriage as we know it will be totally different by the end of this century. The couples that manage to stay together and make it work will be the ones who decide to create fluidity and flexibility in their partnerships, and find ways to make monogamy work for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information, &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed" target="_hplink"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.drtammynelson.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Dr. Tammy Nelson&lt;/a&gt; is a world renowned sex and relationship expert and the author of &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/getting-the-sex-you-want-book/" target="_hplink"&gt;Getting the Sex You Want&lt;/a&gt;.   She can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.drtammynelson.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;drtammynelson.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052524/thumbs/s-INFIDELITY-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>4 Major Red Flags You Should Never Ignore </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/red-flags_n_2934838.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934838</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:58:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T21:58:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>You know what they say: hindsight is 20/20. But it's not until you've been through divorce or a tough breakup that you begin to realize...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;You know what they say: hindsight is 20/20. But it's not until you've been through divorce or a tough breakup that you begin to realize how much truth that platitude actually holds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take it from the folks on Reddit. On Thursday night, the thread &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/1arkti/divorcees_of_reddit_what_things_did_your_ex_do/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Divorcees of Reddit, what things did your ex do before your marriage that, in hindsight, you should have known not to marry him/her?"&lt;/a&gt; blew up on the social network, with both men and women weighing in with the pre-marriage warning signs they ignored. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what were some of the most ominous red flags? For one man, it started with meeting the folks: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/intensenerd" target="_hplink"&gt;intensenerd&lt;/a&gt;: When I arrived, there were two men leaving their home wearing suits and driving a rental car.
When I asked who they were, her mom explained that it was 2 producers from the Jerry Springer show. They were there to interview her grandfather and her big brother.

&lt;p&gt;The episode they were invited to appear on was called "Grandpa stole my wallet and my girlfriend."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her brother couldn't go because his probation officer didn't want him leaving the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also found out right before we got married that she was cheating on her boyfriend with me... A man she then left me for again and is now divorced from.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yikes. Down-thread, one woman said a shady office relationship should have been warning enough: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/OfTheBegin_Ning" target="_hplink"&gt;OfTheBegin_Ning&lt;/a&gt;: He had an uncomfortably close “friendship” with a girl he worked with, and it was practically a weekly thing for me to ask if he was involved with her. He always denied it up and down. Yeah, they’re married now.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last straw for this Redditor? When her husband asked for an open marriage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For another woman, the pre-marriage warning sign was her boyfriend's utter lack of compassion when her grandfather died. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/Valeskatriona" target="_hplink"&gt;Valeskatriona:&lt;/a&gt; The day my grandfather died, I was crying on the front porch and he just stood there with his arms crossed and stared at me. I had to ask for a hug. He also did not come to the funeral and when I was with my family afterwords he sent me several text messages asking why I wasn't home already. When I got home he guilt tripped me, because I wasn't home earlier for him to comfort me. Yeah... I was an idiot. Needless the say, the marriage did not last.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But perhaps the most glaringly obvious red flag mentioned on the thread? &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/user/butthead_is_my_cat" target="_hplink"&gt;butthead_is_my_cat's&lt;/a&gt; partner's tendency to refer to their marriage as "starter marriage." Eek. Live and let live, we guess? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now we want to hear from you: What's the one thing your ex did before you married that should have tipped you off that the marriage wouldn't work out? Head to the comments to share your story or tweet us &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPost Divorce&lt;/a&gt;, then click through the slideshow for more relationship red flags. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--243162--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052058/thumbs/s-ASHAMED-MAN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Trey Anthony: Still Holding On to Anger About an Ex? Let it Go</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/trey-anthony/forgiving-an-ex_b_2929154.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2929154</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T21:04:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T21:33:03Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I am friends with all my exes! Many people find this very strange. Many years ago I had an extremely bad break up, and because there was so much hurt between us we decided to not speak. This was one of the most difficult and challenging times of my life. But as I get older I have little time for bitterness, anger, or hurt. If there is an ex in your life whom you feel anger towards or cannot speak to them, let them go.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Trey Anthony</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/trey-anthony/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I am friends with all my exes! Many people find this very strange. I also talk quite regularly to most of my exes and each one of them always calls me to wish me happy birthday! At my last birthday party, my ex came with her new partner, who I adore and we all had a grand old time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like receiving regular updates on my exes and I'm very close with most of them! Some of my exes have even flown or driven 15 hours to come to visit me in my new home and we have shared delightful conversations, giggling like school girls way into the night! I truly adore all of my ex partners and I think they are wonderful, amazing, brilliant people! I'm so glad that I have chosen wisely.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it's hard for me to comprehend loving someone so deeply and intimately and then pretending as if they never existed! Many years ago I had an extremely bad break up, and because there was so much hurt between us we decided to not speak. This was one of the most difficult and challenging times of my life. It kept me up at night. I went to therapy about it, and could not rid myself of the anger and hurt! I was filled with rage and took no responsibility for the role that I played in the demise of our relationship. I cried about it often. I told everyone I could the list of offences by my ex! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet even though I was angry, I just couldn't understand how someone I loved so deeply could act as if we never were... I was so sad that we were not able to come together to talk it out or even be in the same room without some sort of "drama" unfolding! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, time does heal all wounds and five years after our break up, I swallowed my pride and realized that I didn't need to be "right" I just wanted to be at peace. So I swallowed my pride and I sent a "peace" email and we agreed to meet. At that meeting we both shed tears of joy and hurt. We were able to talk and work things out. We both realized we needed to be in each other lives. There was so much more we needed to learn from each other, and much more growing that we needed to do as well. There was too much love there for us to just walk away -- too much herstory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get older and I become more committed to my spiritual path, I have little time for bitterness, anger, or hurt. I'm a person who loves passionately and loves deeply. I'm loyal. And if I tell you I love you, I will love you for life! You become my family. I pray often for all my exes, wishing them joy, love and laughter all the things I wish for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realize that everyone who comes into your life is a reflection of you. You chose them, they are mirrors of who you are, and you attracted them. So for me, every one of my partners have been beautiful learning lessons. I have loved them all differently. Learnt different things. And they have truly shaped the womyn I am, and slowly evolving to be. I loved them and I still love them all in my own special way. I want each one of them to be happy and live inspired lives! And I truly thank each and everyone of them for loving me fiercely.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my lesson to to everyone today is, I truly encourage you, to let go of anger, hurt and blame. If there is an ex in your life whom you feel anger towards or cannot speak to them, let them go...let them go with love.  Daily bless them and pray for them. Don't hold on to anger it's not good. Write them a letter, send it, or maybe don't send it. Maybe send them a peace email, reach out in a loving way or silently release them in your heart. But you must let go of the anger, remember that you use to love them.... and love is a gift -- always choose to unwrap it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Love is a gift of one's inner most soul to another so both can be whole."  -Buddhist quote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namaste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--259411--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052289/thumbs/s-BREAKUP-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Do I Adopt My Stepchild? </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/ask-the-attorney-steppare_n_2934362.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934362</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:54:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:54:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Q: For years, I have filled the role of a parent to my stepchild, and I would like that relationship to be legally recognized. How...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>canon-mcmillan.patch.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Q: For years, I have filled the role of a parent to my stepchild, and I would like that relationship to be legally recognized. How do I go about adopting my stepchild, as a stepparent?&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051924/thumbs/s-ADOPT-STEPCHILD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Common Is Infidelity?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/how-common-is-cheating--i_n_2934394.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934394</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:54:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:53:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Sometimes I worry that society is becoming immune to infidelity and cheating in a romantic relationship. We hear things like, “Half of all marriages end...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>psychcentral.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Sometimes I worry that society is becoming immune to infidelity and cheating in a romantic relationship. We hear things like, “Half of all marriages end in divorce” and “Half of people in a relationship admit to cheating.” We become desensitized and perhaps a bit pessimistic by hearing these disheartening statistics repeated over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051931/thumbs/s-CAUGHT-CHEATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: Well That's One Way To Show You're Single...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/funny-sticker_n_2934119.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934119</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:21:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T23:59:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Ever get tired of seeing those stick-figure family decals on the back of minivans? If the answer is yes, then this post might warm your...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Ever get tired of seeing those &lt;a href="http://minnesota.cbslocal.com/2013/02/20/good-question-how-did-family-stick-figures-become-so-popular/" target="_hplink"&gt;stick-figure family decals&lt;/a&gt; on the back of minivans? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer is yes, then this post might warm your cold, cold heart. On Friday, Reddit user HollahAtAllah &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/rva/comments/1asyo9/saw_this_little_nugget_in_church_hill_somebodys/" target="_hplink"&gt;posted a photo&lt;/a&gt; of one slightly embittered Hyundai Veloster owner's rear window. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/QSwUotI"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/QSwUotI.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that's one way to make your relationship status known. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you think of the window display, then click through the slideshow below for some of the funniest bumper sticker parodies we've ever seen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--287936--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051916/thumbs/s-STICK-FIGURE-FAMILY-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Inside Kevin Hart's Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce_n_2933725.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933725</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T19:17:17Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:17:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Actor and comedian Kevin Hart's bank account is thanking him right now. According to TMZ, although Hart is worth a reported $9 million, his ex-wife...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Actor and comedian Kevin Hart's bank account is thanking him right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;According to TMZ&lt;/a&gt;, although Hart is worth a &lt;a href="http://www.celebritynetworth.com/richest-celebrities/richest-comedians/kevin-hart-net-worth/" target="_hplink"&gt;reported $9 million&lt;/a&gt;, his ex-wife Torrei Hart received a relatively small sum in their divorce -- &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;a settlement of just $175,000.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2011/01/exclusive-documents-comedian-kevin-hart-files-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;filed for divorce &lt;/a&gt;from his wife of nearly eight years in February 2011. In the filing, he requested that the court not grant Torrei &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2011/01/exclusive-documents-comedian-kevin-hart-files-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;any spousal support.&lt;/a&gt; They &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;finalized their split&lt;/a&gt; in November 2011. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the divorce wasn't an entirely negative experience for the "Real Husbands of Hollywood" star, who recently opened up about how he's&lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/393704/kevin-hart-covers-ebony-talks-getting-serious-his-quot-lying-period-quot-and-why-he-never-makes-gay-jokes?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_hplink"&gt; changed for the better&lt;/a&gt; since the split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"When I was married, I definitely went through a lying period," he said in the &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/393704/kevin-hart-covers-ebony-talks-getting-serious-his-quot-lying-period-quot-and-why-he-never-makes-gay-jokes?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_hplink"&gt;April issue of Ebony magazine&lt;/a&gt;. "I just turned into a liar, but you learn from your mistakes. Being that guy once upon a time has helped me develop into the man I am now, and I approach relationships in a completely different manner."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Harts have &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2011/01/exclusive-documents-comedian-kevin-hart-files-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;two children together&lt;/a&gt; -- an 8-year-old daughter and a 5-year-old son. Kevin will reportedly pay his ex &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/22/kevin-hart-divorce-final/" target="_hplink"&gt;$19,785 a month in child support.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to test your knowledge of other celebrity divorce settlements:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--233083--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051765/thumbs/s-KEVIN-HART-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Natalie Gregg: The Biggest Myth About Child Custody</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-gregg/fathers-rights-in-divorce_b_2903819.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2903819</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T18:04:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T18:03:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary>During divorce proceedings, the level of past parental involvement is the most critical factor in determining both the level of access that each spouse will receive and the amount of child support that will be provided, if any.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Natalie Gregg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-gregg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;In my practice as a &lt;a href="http://nataliegregg.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce lawyer&lt;/a&gt;, the vast majority of the fathers whom I have represented want to remain actively involved as parents after their divorce has been settled. Very few want to sever ties with their children, even when they cannot stand the sight of their ex-wives.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
In fact, I am seeing an increasing number who are fighting to be named the primary conservator -- or the parent who determines where the children live and has majority of the access. This is especially true when both spouses are working full-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a working mom, and I benefit from a marriage in which parenting duties are truly split 50/50. However, having worked with over 600 divorcing clients, I can say that our relationship is an exception to the rule.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Even in dual income households, one spouse typically bears a disproportionate level of the parenting responsibilities. During divorce proceedings, the level of past parental involvement is the most critical factor in determining both the level of access that each spouse will receive and the amount of child support that will be provided, if any.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
From my perspective, the courts should not arbitrarily favor mothers over fathers. I believe firmly that the spouse who has served as the primary parental figure should remain in that role after the divorce has been finalized. And as such, they should receive a corresponding amount of the post-divorce estate. This is the case &lt;em&gt;regardless of the gender&lt;/em&gt; of the primary conservator.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As a marketing ploy, some family law firms tout themselves as "father's rights" firms. The truth is that, while some judges may arbitrarily favor the traditional model of a family with the mother as the primary caretaker and the father as the sole breadwinner, their decision of who will serve as primary managing conservator generally rests on the level of each spouse's involvement in the children's lives. If both spouses were working full-time and they shared parenting duties 50/50, then the father has just as solid an opportunity to be named the primary managing conservator as the mother.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
The key consideration is whether the father was equally (or more) involved in the children's lives and took a vested interest on a &lt;em&gt;daily basis&lt;/em&gt; in parenting. Examples include the following: taking the children to school, attending PTA meetings, making meals for the children, managing doctor appointments, choosing extracurricular activities and the like. Here, the court seeks to maintain what is closest to continuity for the children.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And as a divorcing parent, you should also seek to maintain as much strength in the foundation of your children's lives as possible. The worst behavior that I see in my practice is when divorcing spouses treat their children like property rather than people. Fighting over them is not the same as arguing over who gets the house or the car or the timeshare: when it comes to determining conservatorship, access and child support, your primary focus should be to build the most effective co-parenting relationship possible.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
As I often tell my clients, "You can love your kids or hate your ex-spouse; but you &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/natalie-gregg/how-to-tell-your-children_1_b_1792700.html" target="_hplink"&gt;cannot do both&lt;/a&gt; at the same time."&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And now, for my fellow mothers who are reading this article:&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I understand that we share a special bond with the children who grew within us for nine months before they met their fathers. However, when it comes to deciding their future, we truly need to focus on what is best for them (and which, at heart, is truly what is best for us). That could very well be having the father named as the primary conservator. You are no less of a mother to that child just because they now live with their father more than with you. In parenting, what matters most is the quality of the time that children receive from both of their parents.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This article neither constitutes nor is intended to be legal advice. Please be advised that if you need legal counsel, you should consult an attorney regarding your individual situation.  &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Georgianna Donadio, MSc, Ph.D., D.C.: Loving Again After Loss</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/georgianna-donadio-msc-phd/loving-again-after-loss_b_2883053.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2883053</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T17:33:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T17:33:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Losing love by breakup or death is one of the most profound and stressful things we as human beings can experience.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Georgianna Donadio, MSc, Ph.D., D.C.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/georgianna-donadio-msc-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Meaningful relationships, belonging and love are essential to our health, happiness and what we want, need and desire. It is one of psychologist Abraham Maslow's Hierarchy of Human Needs and the one of the most frequently conflicted areas of human interaction. The willingness to be vulnerable to love again after things go badly in an intimate relationship requires both courage and resilience to transverse the landscape of such profound emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing love by breakup or death is one of the most profound and stressful things we as human beings can experience. The loss of love can literally "break our hearts" and can even undermine our will to live. Sigmund Freud, MD, the well-known father of modern psychoanalysis, many decades ago stated that we "are never as hopelessly unhappy as when we lose love."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is what sustains our lives; so much so that research shows the impact of grief on the development and exacerbation of unresolved grief, and how it can result in the development of serious illness or fatal heart disease. The loss of love is something many of us fear and something many of us can't imagine happening when, on the surface, things in our relationship seem to be on an even keel. Yet, for most of us at one time or another, we experience the crushing pain of losing love and the almost obsessive reaction we have to try and regain that love, or find a way to end the pain and sense of emptiness that can often accompany such loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with a small press literary publication, The Sun, you may not have read this poignant essay, published in that magazine, written by Poe Ballantine. He provides insight to the necessity of trust within love. Trust is the element of love which provides the safe place necessary to share our lives and hearts with others. Trusting, and dealing with the loss of trust within love, requires great courage to be able to move beyond the loss and love again. It is interesting that we are inundated from many sources these days with information about wellness and how to prevent illness, when what many of us need is information about how to create more fulfilling and healthy relationships and prevent the heartbreak of losing love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ballantine's essay tells a story about his father:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"He kept a close ritual of coffee, then work, dinner, his television shows and his cigarettes. The newspaper stayed on the table open to the personals. He had opened them the first day she had left him, like the reflex of a man covering a wound after being shot. His face was gray from survival. He was a man who could not allow himself to break. The despair stretched out. The music from the stereo could not fill the emptiness. Our conversations were automatic, clock talk. His single guiding hope was that she would return."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"What had happened to my father - he never believed it would happen to him. He was fifty years old, settled, comfortable, secure. His children were raised. He had worked hard all his life and now he could relax. I understood why my mother had left him, but I still condemned her for leaving - for taking the easy way out. My father and I played cards and watched private-eye dramas on television. He looked in the personals, called once at something that looked right, but cancelled soon after; it just wasn't in him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"One Sunday afternoon I heard him crying in the bedroom. I didn't know what to do with a father who cried. He taught me all I knew, the important things: honesty, loyalty, firm handshake, the love beyond self-love, the duty of a man. Trust was his only religion and it was failing him and in turn it was the failure of the world."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The one thing a human being asks for on this earth is to be loved. Why should it be impossible?"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trusting, loving and the resilience to come back from the loss of love may be the next "health frontier." Nutrition, one of the more popular health topics, is not just about nourishing our tissues. Nourishing our hearts, which are hungry for love and acceptance, is another skill we need to learn. If we should be mindful of what we eat, how mindful should we become about how and who we love? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.cancer.gov/cancertopics/cancerlibrary/epeco/selfstudy/module-4-pdf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/3684749&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dad Who Posted Money Pics On Facebook Busted For Child Support: Cops</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/christopher-robinson-facebook-money_n_2934348.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2934348</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T17:25:19Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:10:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Christopher Robinson may have to pick that money off the floor and give it to his ex after cops used his Facebook photos of him...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Simon McCormack</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/simon-mccormack/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/03/facebook-money-pics-bust-dad-for-allegedly-dodging-child-support/" target="_hplink"&gt;Christopher Robinson may have to pick that money&lt;/a&gt; off the floor and give it to his ex after cops used his Facebook photos of him posing with cash to bust him for allegedly failing to pay child support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABC News reports that the Milwaukee man is charged with &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/03/facebook-money-pics-bust-dad-for-allegedly-dodging-child-support/" target="_hplink"&gt;three felony counts of failure to support his 3-year-old child,&lt;/a&gt; after he allegedly didn't make a single monthly child support payment for three years. He was supposed to pony up $150 a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What we do in these types of cases is we try to find out from other family members whether there is other information we may not be able to know about,” Milwaukee County Chief Deputy District Attorney Kent Lovern told ABCNews.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lovern told WDJT his office often uses Facebook to build cases against &lt;a href="http://www.cbs58.com/news/local-news/Father-Flaunts-Cash-on-Facebook-Busted-for-Child-Support-198868891.html" target="_hplink"&gt;suspected child support scofflaws.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's a great investigative tool for us because it gives us a glimpse into their real lives that our targets may be living," Lovern said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stir's Nicole Fabian-Weber tries to understand what would posses someone to post photos of themselves with money when they are &lt;a href="http://thestir.cafemom.com/technology/153004/child_support_avoiding_dad_busted" target="_hplink"&gt;delinquent on child support payments.&lt;/a&gt; She comes to the conclusion that it has something to do with the constant need for attention that Facebook engenders and feeds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It's awfully easy to get caught these days, thanks to Facebook. People want to be seen! They want to be heard! And clearly, that's predominantly what's on their minds. I mean, bailing out on three years of child support, then uploading a photo of cash. That's just dumb. And that, my Friends, is being drunk on Facebook.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/headlines/2013/03/facebook-money-pics-bust-dad-for-allegedly-dodging-child-support/" target="_hplink"&gt;ABC News reports&lt;/a&gt; that Robinson was served with an arrest warrant in February, but since he failed to appear, the warrant is still active. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051787/thumbs/s-CHRISTOPHER-ROBINSON-FACEBOOK-MONEY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>10 Relaxing Solo Vacations For Newly Single Divorcees</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/traveling-alone_n_2917230.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2917230</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T17:18:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T17:51:36Z</updated>
    
    <summary>After a divorce, self-care should be your number-one priority. And what better way to put yourself first that than by taking a relaxing solo vacation?...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Carolyn Gregoire</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carolyn-gregoire/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;After a divorce, self-care should be your number-one priority. And what better way to put yourself first that than by taking a relaxing solo vacation? Getting away from it all for a couple weeks or even just a long weekend can help you to regain perspective and rediscover the joys of purposeful solitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writer Veronica Chambers called solo travel "a journey back to the center of your self" &lt;a href="http://www.oprah.com/spirit/Solo-Vacations-Women-Traveling-Alone_1/3" target="_hplink"&gt;in an article on Oprah.com&lt;/a&gt;. "Travel has become more than a respite from the world I live in; it's a way to refill my emotional well," she writes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're planning to take a post-divorce trip, make sure to choose a relaxing (preferably coastal) location where you have the option to both relax and unwind, and also to enjoy adventure activities. Be sure to leave the kids with Grandma for the week while you indulge in some much-needed grown-up time. At these destinations, you can enjoy the &lt;a href="http://articles.latimes.com/1989-07-25/news/vw-261_1_nature-scene" target="_hplink"&gt;de-stressing benefits&lt;/a&gt; of spending time in nature while avoiding honeymooners and popular romantic vacation spots. Whether it's partying by the beach in Ibiza, or unwinding at a quaint bed and breakfast in Martha's Vineyard, click through the slideshow below for 10 peaceful, non-honeymooning vacations for divorcees traveling alone post-split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us: Did you go on a vacation after your divorce? What's your dream solo-travel destination? Share your thoughts in the comments or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostDivorce&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1047688/thumbs/s-TRAVELING-ALONE-mini.jpg?20" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Pros &amp; Cons Of Prenups</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/the-power-of-the-prenup-r_n_2933892.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933892</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T16:55:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T19:54:44Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A New York woman, Elizabeth Petrakis, recently announced that she’d had her prenuptial agreement voided, claiming she was coerced into signing it four days before...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.nytimes.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A New York woman, Elizabeth Petrakis, recently announced that she’d had her prenuptial agreement voided, claiming she was coerced into signing it four days before her wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051764/thumbs/s-PRENUP-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Blended Family Friday: Meet Valerie And Brandon's Family</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/22/blended-family-friday-mee_n_2927660.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2927660</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T16:35:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T17:17:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As part of our Blended Family Friday series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of our &lt;strong&gt;Blended Family Friday&lt;/strong&gt; series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together. Our hope is that by telling their stories, we'll bring you closer to blended family bliss in your own life!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we'd like you to meet Valerie and Brandon and their five kids. We knew we had to profile them after we took a gander at their weekly calendar -- you wouldn't &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; how many overlapping orthodontist appointments and extracurricular activities this couple manages to make happen every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi, Valerie! Please introduce us to your family. How long have you and your husband  been together? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My husband, Brandon, and I have been together for 3 1/2 years. I have four biological kids -- Kinsey, 15; Patrick, 14; Avery, 12; and Delaney, 7 -- and Brandon has one, his 14-year-old son, Corey. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the best thing about being part of a blended family?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For us, re-creating our family in a way that's happy and healthy for everyone is the best part. Rebuilding can be a good thing. We make traditions like a question game around the dinner table. We ask questions like, "If you could go anywhere on vacation, where would it be?" and everyone gets a turn to answer. Our kids love the stability, fun and companionship of having so many siblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moments when step-kids accept and appreciate you in your life is another great perk! The last few years have been an adjustment period. We feel like we are just hitting our stride in this family adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the biggest challenges of blended family life? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Finding time to love and pay attention to everyone as they need is the biggest challenge. Some days there isn't enough of me, but it's fun feeding, clothing and loving all these people. They make me crazy, but I like it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brandon says one of the biggest challenges is knowing where your boundaries are as a stepparent/disciplinarian. The step-parent role is precarious; you have to be more of a friend/supporting role for the biological parents. You also have to be able to switch back and forth really quickly between your roles, depending on which child in your home you are dealing with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice do you have for other blended families who feel like a peaceful family dynamic is out of reach?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My best advice would be to understand what your role is as a stepparent, partner and friend. Stay within the boundaries that work and be patient. A family is an ever-evolving creation that requires maintenance and care. Be respectful of the biological parents and build on the strengths of your family in support of one another. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nurture your marriage. We take trips or outings to reconnect, laugh and remember why we love each other without kids to interrupt. It helps keep the marriage bond strong. We have made mutual friends and try to have interests together -- we are friends and it makes us a better parenting team.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click through the slideshow the see photos of Valerie and Brandon's family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you'd like your own family to be featured on a Blended Family Friday, please email us at  &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt;. We're looking forward to hearing your story! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287746--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050407/thumbs/s-BLENDED-FAMILY-FRIDAY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Christina Pesoli: What’s Your Post-Split Personality?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christina-pesoli/postdivorce-personality-d_b_2884446.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2884446</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T16:21:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T16:21:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Divorce is the leading cause of temporary insanity. Trust me, I know.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Christina Pesoli</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christina-pesoli/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Divorce is the leading cause of temporary insanity. Trust me, I know. My work with divorcing women gives me a front row seat to the show. Whoever you are in your regular life -- whether you're Calm Carla, Together Tricia, or Fearless Frances -- you're not that same person while you are slogging through your divorce. And while there's nothing you can do to prevent the condition, there's a lot you can do to prepare for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five basic personality profiles that come standard with this temporary insanity. The tricky thing about these profiles is there's no telling who's likely to assume which personality.  It's not like there's a pattern to it -- like if you are normally Bad-Ass Barbara, you can expect to transform into Stalker Stacy, but if you're typically Calm Carla, you'll morph into Runner-up Rhonda. It ends up being luck of the draw. Like the "prize" in a box of Cracker Jack, you may not know exactly what you're going to get but you do know this much: the options are limited and all of them crappy. (Anyone want a pencil topper? I didn't think so.)&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
But here's how you can prepare: Familiarize yourself with the following five profiles, and have your friends and family familiarize themselves with them, too. Then, when one of you notices that you're starting to change, you can spring into action and start the appropriate treatment plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Train-wreck Trina&lt;/strong&gt;: Train-wreck Trina may be going through a grown-up life event like a divorce, but that doesn't mean she can't party like a sorority girl on academic probation. Train-wreck Trina thinks the best way to prove to everyone else -- but especially to her ex -- that her divorce hasn't caused her to miss a beat is to never pass up a happy hour or a one-night stand.  For her, divorce is a race against her ex to see who can re-couple up the fastest. And the finish line of moving on is moving in together.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Train-wreck Trina doesn't get is that replacing your partner without reviewing what went wrong with your last relationship sentences you to repeating your same mistakes. That's why rather than moving forward, Train-wreck Trina ends up spinning her wheels.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment plan for Train-wreck Trina is a ramped up social life that doesn't involve men.  Think girlfriend trips, book clubs, training for a triathlon -- anything to keep her busy, but out of bars and beds. That will help her to pass the time between relationships in a healthy way and give her the chance to sort out what went wrong before getting back into the ring.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitter Brittney&lt;/strong&gt;: Bitter Brittney never wanted this divorce and she's not going to let anyone forget it. Her daily forecast is angry with a chance of tirade. She systematically blow-torches every opportunity for a fresh start. Even when she meets new people, the first (and only) thing she wants to talk about is all the ways her no-good, A-hole of an ex did her wrong. Her vibe is so toxic that she drives even her closest friends away.  But because bitterness has become her baseline, Brittney has no way to gauge either how miserable she is or how miserable she is to be around.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment plan for Bitter Brittney is to establish a strict rule that forbids her from talking about her ex. She'll need to enlist her friends' and family's help in this effort. To start, she should designate an alternative topic -- like movies or current events -- and let everyone know what this substitute topic is. Then, when she finds herself wanting to talk about her ex, she or her friends can deliberately switch tracks to the "go to" topic instead. Over time, this practice will retrain Bitter Brittney's brain so that trash talking her ex is no longer her only topic of conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stalker Stacy&lt;/strong&gt;: Stalker Stacy has split up with her ex, but monitoring him is still her full-time job.  And when it comes to stalking, she definitely has skills.  We're not talking about a low-tech operation involving driving by her ex's house morning, noon, and night -- that's for beginners. She takes full advantage of today's technology, hacking into his credit card and email accounts so she can track all of his activities and interactions.  Oh, and you know that GPS feature on cell phones?  Well, her ex never thought to turn his off.  And since she still knows the password to his cell phone account, she can log in and clock his every move, too.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stalker Stacy is so consumed with secretly monitoring her ex that she has neither the interest nor the time to make plans with anyone else. For Stalker Stacy to get back to her regular self, she needs an intense new hobby -- something that will both occupy her time and get her adrenaline pumping.  A consuming new pastime like a class in ghost hunting or a physically demanding sport like mountain climbing or cycling will keep her mind engaged and break her habit of ex-husband hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner-up Rhonda&lt;/strong&gt;: Sure, her husband dumped her for his hot administrative assistant, but Runner-up Rhonda still has "first wife" status.  She knows deep down that her ex husband just can't live without her.  After all, he needs her to pick up his dry cleaning, print out the kids' weekly schedule and send a card to his mom on Mother's Day (she even signed his name and everything). She knows she's still a VIP in her ex-husband's life.  What she doesn't get is that the "P" stands for prisoner, not person -- and she's her own jailer.   With all the errand-running she does for her ex, she doesn't have the time or energy to establish her own post-divorce life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with Runner-up Rhonda isn't that she has a lot to give, it's to whom she's giving it.  In order to return to her normal personality, Runner-up Rhonda needs to find a new beneficiary for all of her nurturing energy. Volunteer gigs like spending time at a children's shelter or signing up for regular shifts for Meals on Wheels are good ways to indulge this tendency while moving forward with her own life rather than trying to keep her place in her ex's life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Victim Valerie&lt;/strong&gt;: Victim Valerie wants the world to know that she's still hurting over her divorce. So she uses Facebook as an outlet to share messages about healing, the precious nature of true friendship, the sacred value of women, and how it's not your fault when mean people hurt you, it's theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Victim Valerie needs to realize is that being a victim is supposed to be a temporary condition, not a permanent identity.  And while her friends were truly sorry for her at first, the "sell-by" date of their sympathy has long since expired.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victim Valerie needs to permanently pull the plug on her personal pity party. This requires putting herself in a position of power so she can begin to see herself in a different light. She doesn't have to run for governor (unless she's game, of course), but she should pick something in which she has interest and expertise and spearhead a project in that area. From coaching a youth basketball team to leading a Girl Scout troop to offering to serve as an officer in her neighborhood association, it's not the project that matters, it's the capacity in which she serves.   By volunteering to lead an effort, Victim Valerie will see herself as someone who has the power to make good things happen, not someone who sits by powerlessly while bad things happen to her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By catching these personality transformations early and instituting corrective measures as soon as possible, you can be assured of not just returning to your old self, but becoming You 2.0 -- a better version of who you were before your divorce. And there's a name for that girl, too -- it's Healthy Helen.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Healthy Helen doesn't seek out rocky roads, but when she finds herself on one she doesn't stall out, she navigates with both hands on the wheel. She stands up for herself yet she's honest about her own mistakes without beating herself up over them. She takes responsibility and learns what she can while always moving forward.  can't wait for you to get to know Healthy Helen. You're going to really dig her.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050504/thumbs/s-POST-SPLIT-PERSONALITY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marni Battista: What To Look For In Your Next Husband</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marni-battista/what-to-look-for-in-a-hus_b_2879685.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2879685</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-22T06:01:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-22T06:01:26Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When you're looking for a serious relationship after divorce, remember that like attracts like. Working on your own happiness is a great first step in moving to toward a healthy, loving relationship.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marni Battista</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marni-battista/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When you're finally ready to remarry post-divorce, you need to know what characteristics to look for in a husband. Although you've been married previously,  we're willing to guess that you didn't have a checklist before you took your vows! To help when you're looking for a long lasting, serious(ly) fun relationship that has the possibility of leading to marriage, here are five traits you should look for in a guy: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His actions match his words.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most important traits to look for in a long-term mate is that what they do is consistent with what they say they're going to do. If he calls when he says he's going to call, arrives when he says he's going to arrive, and is consistent over time, you can safely assume that this type of behavior will continue throughout the course of your relationship. When you decide to commit to each other, having someone who you can count on to do what he says he's going to do is &lt;em&gt;crucial&lt;/em&gt; and will contribute to a happy, healthy relationship (provided you do the same).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He has strong communication skills.&lt;/strong&gt;  Guys who are able to identify their feelings, express them appropriately andnmanage them will most likely have an easier time being in a relationship with a mature woman who has the same skills. Although it can be attractive at first when a guy is closed off and mysterious, as time goes on you're probably going to get frustrated. Having important conversations about commitment, kids and finances is going to be extremely difficult if your guy can't tell you his opinion. When you find a guy who can tell you clearly how he feels and is someone you can agree and disagree with in a healthy way, he might be the guy you want to put a ring on your finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He can take charge and make decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;  When you get married, having a spouse who can handle a difficult situation makes all the difference in the world. This doesn't mean you should look for someone who orders for you (or orders you around!), but if you find a guy who can masterfully solve a problem or protect you from a threat (even if it's just a pushy salesman), it's an amazing trait that you will want your long-term mate to have in his arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He has a great sense of humor.&lt;/strong&gt;  Any man who can see the lighter side of a somewhat serious situation is a great catch -- provided he does it in an appropriate way, of course. Finding a guy with a solid sense of humor moves him closer to the husband material category. If he makes you laugh when you're feeling down or helps lighten up your mood, you may have struck upon a diamond in the rough. Don't let this guy get away too fast; laughter can keep relationships fun and exciting, and a good belly laugh always makes any day better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;He shares a similar value set.&lt;/strong&gt; When you're looking for "the one" -- the person you're likely to be with forever (or at least for a long time) -- sharing the same values is  make-it-or-break-it. Perhaps it's common religious beliefs, if that means a lot to you, or even having the same views on family or raising kids if you decide to have them. Sharing values will not only bring you closer together, but it will also help to solidify your bond in the long term. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you're looking for a serious relationship after divorce, remember that like attracts like. Working on your own happiness is a great first step in moving to toward a healthy, loving relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1050500/thumbs/s-WHAT-TO-LOOK-FOR-IN-NEXT-HUSBAND-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
