<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Vicki Larson: Why You May Want To Consider An Open Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/vicki-larson/whats-so-wrong-with-an-op_b_3032948.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3032948</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-17T05:09:39Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T05:37:44Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Whether they work forever or not, open marriages seem to be a lot more honest than many marriages in which one or both of the spouses are cheating.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Vicki Larson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/vicki-larson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Will Smith and Jada Pinkett Smith have been in the headlines a lot in recent years, and not because of their movies. They're either on the&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/10/will-smith-jada-pinkett-s_n_1765341.html" target="_hplink"&gt; verge of divorce&lt;/a&gt; or they have an &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/03/jada-pinkett-will-smith-open-relationship-rumor_n_3007718.html" target="_hplink"&gt;open marriage&lt;/a&gt; -- and I'm not sure which horrifies people more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can understand why people might be concerned about them divorcing; they have two kids, Jaden, 14, and Willow, 12, and everyone worries about parents facing divorce (unlike &lt;a href="http://omgchronicles.vickilarson.com/2012/07/12/do-we-really-care-about-childfree-couples-who-divorce/" target="_hplink"&gt;childfree couples&lt;/a&gt;, for some reason). But I can't understand the big deal being made about their alleged open marriage, which everyone is assuming is true because of what &lt;a href="http://live.huffingtonpost.com/r/archive/segment/jada-pinkett-responds-to-open-relationship-rumor/515c5bb302a76037df0001ef" target="_hplink"&gt;Jada recently told HuffPost Live&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;"I've always told Will, 'You can do whatever you want as long as you can look at yourself in the mirror and be OK.' Because at the end of the day, Will is his own man. I'm here as his partner, but he is his own man. He has to decide who he wants to be and that's not for me to do for him. Or vice versa." &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just this week, &lt;a href="http://www.philly.com/philly/blogs/entertainment/celebrities_gossip/Jada-Pinkett-Smith-clarifies-statement-on-open-marriage.html" target="_hplink"&gt;she clarified her statement&lt;/a&gt; by saying they have a "grown" marriage, but obviously one with a lot of freedom:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Will and I BOTH can do WHATEVER we want, because we TRUST each other to do so. This does NOT mean we have an open relationship...this means we have a GROWN one."&lt;/blockquote&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of if you call it open or "grown," the reaction to their relationship is mixed. Are people upset, perhaps because they think it's morally wrong? Are they jealous? Are they curious in a "Gee, I've always wanted to do that but don't know how to bring that up with my partner" kind of way? Are those who are in an open marriage pleased that there are more of their kind? Are there former pro-open marriage types who've been burned by it now shaking their heads and thinking, "It will end soon, and ugly"?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't have the answers to those questions, but I have to imagine this -- whether they work forever or not, open marriages seem to be a lot more honest than many marriages in which one or both of the spouses are cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many people are cheating? It's hard to assess because the data is self-reported, so who really knows who's being honest and how he or she is defining cheating? If we're to believe &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/22/why-people-cheat_n_2483371.html" target="_hplink"&gt;recent research,&lt;/a&gt; 33 percent of men and 19 percent of women admit to getting some on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More might cheat if they &lt;a href="http://www.cosmopolitan.com/advice/tips/great-female-survey/cheating-statistics" target="_hplink"&gt;knew they wouldn't get busted&lt;/a&gt;. In another survey, two percent of women said they'd be "very likely" to cheat if there was no chance their partner would find out (just 5 percent of women admitted to having done so), while more than five percent of men would be "very likely" under those circumstances (and in this survey, fewer than three percent of men admitted to straying).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is the idea of an open relationship so threatening, especially when it's clear that many are having nonmonogamous relationships anyway while pretending they're monogamous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps because it's not the kind of conversation most people can easily bring up with a loved one. Being monogamous is an assumption we have once we get serious romantically --&lt;em&gt;Oh, we're a couple now so we won't sleep with anyone else. &lt;/em&gt; But since a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/vicki-larson/is-college-teaching-kids-_b_1688876.html" target="_hplink"&gt;lot of romances end because of cheating,&lt;/a&gt; I have to wonder why more couples don't talk openly about monogamy. Why aren't we asking each other whether it's been hard -- or not -- to be monogamous? Why aren't we making honest and ongoing discussions about sex, fidelity and monogamy an important part of our relationships? Susan Pease Gadoua and I address that in our forthcoming book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheNewIDo" target="_hplink"&gt;The New I Do: Reshaping Marriage for Cynics, Commitaphobes and Connubial DIYers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I &lt;a href="http://omgchronicles.vickilarson.com/2012/01/07/why-monogamy-is-failing-men/" target="_hplink"&gt;spoke with Eric Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, an American sociologist at England's University of Winchester and author of the provocative book, &lt;em&gt;The Monogamy Gap: Men, Love, and the Reality of Cheating&lt;/em&gt;, he said that people are afraid to be honest about things like monogamy and our sexual needs and desires. So instead, many cheat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;(M)onogamy is culturally compelled, so the decision has been made for us. For example, how much of a chance would a man stand to have a second date if on the first date he said that he was interested in an open relationship? But equally as important, at the point men enter into relationships they, too, think they want monogamy. It's only after being in a relationship for months or years that they badly want sex with others. But by this point, they don't want to break up with their partners because they have long-standing love. Instead of chancing that love by asking for extradyadic sex, they cheat. If they don't get caught (and most don't) it's a rational choice.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it better to turn a blind eye to possible infidelity in our relationships than to have an open marriage? I don't think so. So then why the shock and judgement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jada is very clear on what her 15-year marriage is based on: a deep friendship and a commitment to making it lifelong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;"I don't think it's easy to be married to anyone. I think that you have to go into a relationship knowing -- especially when you're dedicating yourself to someone for the rest of your life -- this is a life partnership. He's my best friend. He's been by my side through some of the most difficult parts of my life. And so that's something you can never take away."&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does being monogamous trump that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A version of this appeared on Vicki Larson's blog, &lt;a href="http://omgchronicles.vickilarson.com/2013/04/08/whats-so-bad-about-an-open-marriage/" target="_hplink"&gt;OMG Chronicles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090626/thumbs/s-OPEN-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mark Sanford's In Hot Water Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/mark-sanford-jenny-sanford_n_3096176.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3096176</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-17T00:09:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T09:10:09Z</updated>
    
    <summary>CHARLESTON, S.C. &amp;mdash; Former South Carolina Gov. Mark Sanford must appear in court two days after running for a vacant congressional seat to answer a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-gentilviso/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;CHARLESTON, S.C. &amp;mdash; Former South Carolina Gov. Mark Sanford must appear in court two days after running for a vacant congressional seat to answer a complaint that he trespassed at his ex-wife's home, according to court documents acquired by The Associated Press on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complaint says Jenny Sanford confronted Sanford leaving her Sullivans Island home on Feb. 3 by a rear door, using his cell phone for a flashlight. Her attorney filed the complaint the next day and Jenny Sanford confirmed Tuesday the documents are authentic.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The couple's 2010 divorce settlement says neither may enter the other's home without permission. Mark Sanford lives about a 20-minute drive away in downtown Charleston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Republican Mark Sanford is trying to revive his political career that was derailed by an extramarital affair that ended the couple's marriage. He faces Democrat Elizabeth Colbert Busch on May 7 as he tries to regain the 1st District congressional seat he held for three terms in the 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spokesman Joel Sawyer said the Sanford campaign had no immediate comment on the court documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complaint filed by Jenny Sanford's lawyer, Deena Smith McRackan, said that Mark Sanford has "entered into a pattern of entering onto plaintiff's property. Plaintiff has informed defendant on a number of occasions that this behavior is in violation of the court's order and has demanded that it not occur again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Febuary of 2011, McRackan sent a letter to Mark Sanford telling him not to trespass on Jenny Sanford's property. A copy of that letter was also sent to the local police, according to court filings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jenny Sanford said Tuesday that she has custody of the couple's four boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said the complaint has nothing to do with her former husband's efforts to rebuild his career in politics. She said it was filed with the court the day after the incident and when a family court judge last month set the case for the docket, it happened to be two days after the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I am doing my best not to get in the way of his race," Jenny Sanford told the AP. "I want him to sink or swim on his own. For the sake of my children I'm trying my best not to get in the way, but he makes things difficult for me when he does things like trespassing."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanford is trying to make a comeback after his political career was sidelined in 2009 after confessing an extramarital affair. As a sitting governor, he disappeared from the state for five days only to return and confess to an affair with an Argentine woman, Maria Chapur. He and Jenny Sanford soon divorced and he is now engaged to Chapur who lives in Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for Colbert Busch said that the campaign had no comment on the dispute between the Sanfords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December of 2011, there was another complaint against Mark Sanford brought by Jenny Sanford saying he had not made the $5,000 yearly contribution for one of their son's college education. Jenny Sanford said Tuesday that the matter has been resolved but would not comment further.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090516/thumbs/s-MARK-SANFORD-JENNY-SANFORD-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: The Note You Never Want To Read At The Breakfast Table</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/bad-breakup_n_3095439.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095439</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T23:46:24Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T23:45:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Think receiving a text is the worst way to be dumped? Think again. The image below, recently posted on Reddit, illustrates a sweet message, written...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Think receiving a text is the worst way to be dumped? Think again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image below, recently &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1c6cm7/a_breakup_in_your_breakfast/" target="_hplink"&gt;posted on Reddit,&lt;/a&gt; illustrates a sweet message, written in Alpha-Bits cereal no less, that quickly turns sour. The image was created by artist fleetingmind and originally posted to &lt;a href="http://www.hitrecord.org/records/1277887" target="_hplink"&gt;HitRecord, an artist collaboration site.&lt;/a&gt; Take a look below: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/pTHHLdy"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/pTHHLdy.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I like the idea of passive aggressive break up notes in every day life," fleetingmind &lt;a href="http://www.hitrecord.org/records/1277887" target="_hplink"&gt;wrote on HitRecord &lt;/a&gt;about the piece. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you think of this breakup below, then click through the slideshow below for 11 equally unique breakup letters found on the web. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--292416--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090449/thumbs/s-BREAKFAST-BREAKUP-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Check Out Phoebe &amp; Sun</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/new-poster-for-abcs-mistresses_n_3095802.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095802</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:53:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T22:53:19Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Get a first look at ABC's summer soap "Mistresses" marketing art below, featuring Alyssa Milano, Jes Macallan, Rochelle Aytes and Yunjin Kim. The drama series...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>EW</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jaimie-etkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Get a first look at ABC's summer soap "Mistresses" marketing art below, featuring Alyssa Milano, Jes Macallan, Rochelle Aytes and Yunjin Kim. The drama series is based on a UK show with the same title and follows the lives of four female friends with illicit and complex relationships. "Mistresses" debuts June 3. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090245/thumbs/s-MISTRESSES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Terry Gaspard, MSW, LICSW: The Forever Dad: Shattering the Myth of the Self-Centered Dad</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/terry-gaspard-msw-licsw/the-forever-dad-shatterin_b_3084692.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3084692</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:40:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T22:40:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What kids need is a loving, predictable father figure -- whether married to their mother or divorced. I don't think anyone can argue that point. However, I believe that divorced dads are often portrayed in the media in a negative light.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Terry Gaspard, MSW, LICSW</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/terry-gaspard-msw-licsw/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;What kids need is a loving, predictable father figure -- whether married to their mother or divorced. I don't think anyone can argue that point. However, I believe that divorced dads are often portrayed in the media in a negative light. For instance, Alison Patten's article The &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alison-patton/uncle-dad-syndrome_b_2986705.html" target="_hplink"&gt;'Uncle Dad Syndrome' &lt;/a&gt;posted on HuffPost Divorce recently depicts divorced dads as irresponsible blockheads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media often portrays a demoralized and demeaning image of divorced fathers. The typical divorced dad comes across as immature, self-centered, and irresponsible. When was the last time you read a story or saw a television show about a caring divorced father who was in touch with the needs of his children? Fathers and their kids suffer from assuming the worst about dads after a family dissolves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, it's important to counteract the negative press given to fathers post-divorce and to mention all of the "Forever Dads" who aren't immature, irresponsible or self-centered. What exactly is a "Forever Dad?" They are the ones who don't disappear. The dads you see at dance recitals and soccer games. They try hard to maintain a regular visitation schedule and call when they are running late. They thrive on watching their kids grow and support their healthy development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to better understand the obstacles faced by fathers after divorce, I interviewed several young adult women and their fathers who participated in &lt;a href="www.movingpastdivorce.com" target="_hplink"&gt;my research study&lt;/a&gt;. The following is a summary of the characteristics that the father-daughter pairs mentioned during our interviews. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A competent dad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Considers fatherhood an honor, a privilege, and a lifetime commitment.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Believes he plays an important role in the life of his kids.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Values input from his children's mother and speaks well of her.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Puts his kid's needs first and practices positive parenting.&lt;br /&gt;
•	Enjoys spending time with his kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most outspoken dads I met with, Brian, in his late forties, was eager to tell me about his close bond with his daughter Amanda. Brian personifies a father who is devoted to his daughter and wants the best for her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian never remarried after his four year marriage to Felicia dissolved -- making regular contacts with his daughter Amanda a priority. He describes his split from his ex-wife as contentious, saying "I made a point of recognizing that I'm going to do whatever is in Amanda's best interest. So even if I'm getting a line of baloney from my ex that she doesn't want to come (for a visit), I'm going to respect that. I'm not going to be a disruptive element in Amanda's life." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda, age 19, was an infant at the time of her parents' breakup and the custody arrangement was fairly traditional -- with her spending every other weekend and one weeknight with her dad. Brian has worked hard to reduce conflict with his ex-wife and reports swallowing many words and biting his tongue in an effort to keep the peace. With intensity in his voice, he says, "I always say to Amanda, you do what works for you. I'm not going to feel slighted or upset -- do whatever works for you." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges Brian and other dads face is the stereotypes that exist about divorced fathers. It's crucial to examine our beliefs and attitudes about the role of dads after divorce if we are going to break down barriers that create distance between fathers and their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, fostering alienation between a child and his or her dad is one of the cruelest and most selfish acts a parent can do to their own child. Society perpetuates a negative view of dads post-divorce. The exception is the movie &lt;em&gt;Spanglish&lt;/em&gt;, director James Brooks' poignant portrayal of a father who is a far better parent to his daughter than her mother.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the barriers that prevent dads and kids from maintaining a close bond after parental divorce? Many experts cite the importance of a divorced mom promoting her child's relationship with her father. Whenever possible, mothers need to encourage their children to sustain regular contact with their dads -- such as phone calls, holiday time, and special occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's also important for moms to eliminate negative comments about their ex-husband so her kids don't feel caught in the middle. Lastly, fathers who remain an integral part of their child's life after divorce can promote a loving relationship that endures through rough patches. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When parents divorce, children are forced to give up their sense of control. Let's face it, divorce is a decision made by parents -- not children. Divorce is a painful experience for everyone, but children raised in disrupted homes often feel the sting of divided loyalties. Loyalty conflicts are frequently at the root of a father/child wound because kids feel they have to choose between their parents.  Since children of divorce are particularly vulnerable to conflict between their parents, it's important for parents to be cordial and to avoid arguments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-custodial fathers, I believe, get a bad rap because divorce really disempowers them from being "half-time" parents. Instead, the emphasis is often placed on financial support. I would like to suggest that the emphasis should be equally placed on dads balancing time with their children and meeting their economic needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his landmark book, &lt;em&gt;Always Dad&lt;/em&gt;, Paul Mendelstein advises divorced fathers to find ways to play a crucial role in their children's lives. He suggests that they call a truce with their ex-spouse -- to put an end to active fighting and to collaborate. While this is may be a challenge at times, collaboration with an ex paves the way for greater cooperation in the future. Children flourish best when raised by both a father and a mother -- whether in a divorced or intact family. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow Terry Gaspard MSW, LICSW on &lt;a href="www.twitter.com/movepastdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/MovingPastDivorcecom/199571693452926?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://movingpastdivorce.com" target="_hplink"&gt;movingpastdivorce.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090440/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-DADS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Announcing Your Split On Social Media: Yay Or Nay?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/divorce-announcement_n_3094807.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3094807</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T22:12:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T22:11:36Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Is announcing your divorce via social media -- say, a carefully worded status update on Facebook or a cheeky Instagram photo showing off your ring-less...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Is announcing your divorce via social media -- say, a carefully worded status update on Facebook or a cheeky Instagram photo showing off your ring-less finger -- tasteless? Or is it a smart, relatively painless way to get the news across?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the question on our minds since we read a &lt;a href="http://www.indystar.com/article/20130415/LIFE/304150054?sf11680577=1" target="_hplink"&gt;recent Indianapolis Star story&lt;/a&gt; on the pros and cons of announcing the end of a marriage online, be it in the form of a blog post or a brief, to-the-point tweet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were curious to know what our divorced readers had to say on the subject, so we took the question to them on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter.&lt;/a&gt; Click through the slideshow below to see what they had to say, then head to the comments and let us know: Is announcing your split over social media smart or is it a little shameless? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--292370--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090133/thumbs/s-LIKE-DISLIKE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: How That Facebook Poke Could Cost You</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/facebook-cheating_n_3095264.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3095264</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:59:34Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:58:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It's no surprise that social media has made cheating easier than ever before -- after all, an old flame or flirty friend is only a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ashley Reich</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ashley-reich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It's no surprise that social media has made cheating easier than ever before -- after all, an old flame or flirty friend is only a few mouse clicks away. In fact, it's estimated that &lt;a href="http://www.aaml.org/sites/default/files/Divorce%20Lawyers%20Facebook%20Tops%20in%20Online%20Evidence.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;one in five U.S. adults use Facebook for flirting&lt;/a&gt;, according to a Pew Internet and American Life Project report from 2008.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But be warned: your online trysts may be used against you in divorce court. The American Academy of Matrimonial Lawyers found that &lt;a href="http://http://www.aaml.org/sites/default/files/Divorce%20Lawyers%20Facebook%20Tops%20in%20Online%20Evidence.pdf" target="_hplink"&gt;81 percent of their members&lt;/a&gt; have used evidence from Facebook, Twitter and other social networking sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious about how to protect yourself? Scroll through the infographic below from &lt;a href="http://www.totaldivorce.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Total Divorce&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src= "http://assets.totaldivorce.com/infographics/social-cheating-social-medias-influence-on-infidelity.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to test your knowledge of cheating statistics: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--263420--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090363/thumbs/s-FACEBOOK-CHEATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>OKCupid To Begin Accepting Bitcoin Payments For Premium Features</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/okcupid-bitcoin_n_3093427.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3093427</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T21:26:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:42:15Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Bitcoin's recent market high has piqued media interest in the coin and has apparently gotten the digital currency at least one new customer: online dating...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/betsy-isaacson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Bitcoin's &lt;a href="https://medium.com/money-banking/2b5ef79482cb" target="_hplink"&gt;recent market high&lt;/a&gt; has piqued media interest in the coin and has apparently gotten the digital currency at least one new customer: online dating site OKCupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://coinbase.tumblr.com/post/48102298494/okcupid-starts-accepting-bitcoin-using-coinbase" target="_hplink"&gt;OKCupid announced on Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; via Coinbase, a "bitcoin wallet" where people can buy and sell the digital currency, that it would begin taking payments &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/okcupid-accepting-bitcoins-2013-4" target="_hplink"&gt;in Bitcoin for its "A-List" features&lt;/a&gt;. The site is free to use, but the premium features get rid of ads, allow users to check profiles anonymously, and give users the option of sending messages to another person even if his or her inbox is full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site joins dozens of other sites, including &lt;a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/11/15/pay-another-way-bitcoin/" target="_hplink"&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://blog.reddit.com/2013/02/new-gold-payment-options-bitcoin-and.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;, in accepting the digital currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin prices on the dating site will reflect prices in U.S. dollars, &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2013/04/okcupid-says-it-will-accept-bitcoin-as-currency-falls-to-recent-low/" target="_hplink"&gt;Ars Technia reports&lt;/a&gt;. Sam Yagan, one of the company's founders, &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2013/04/okcupid-says-it-will-accept-bitcoin-as-currency-falls-to-recent-low/" target="_hplink"&gt;told the site&lt;/a&gt; that the company won't hoard the digital currency. Instead, it plans to accept the coin and exchange it for U.S. dollars via its partnership with &lt;a href="https://coinbase.com/about" target="_hplink"&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1089547/thumbs/s-OKCUPID-BITCOIN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Former Escort Reveals Why Men Cheat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/why-men-cheat_n_3093750.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3093750</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T19:36:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T19:34:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>While working as a high-class escort for nine years, Rebecca Dakin saw hundreds of married men turn to her to fulfill sexual needs not being...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;While working as a &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;high-class escort for nine years&lt;/a&gt;, Rebecca Dakin saw &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;hundreds of married men turn to her &lt;/a&gt;to fulfill sexual needs not being met by their wives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, she switched gears professionally and &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;became an infidelity counselor&lt;/a&gt;, using her experience as a call girl to teach women about how to satisfy their husbands. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I’ve spent years hearing men tell me why their relationships failed and why they slept with escorts or other women," the 37-year-old Brit&lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt; told The Sun.&lt;/a&gt; "I know better than anyone just what it is that women do that drives men away.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dakin says that the number one reason men look outside of their relationships for sex is because they're &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;not getting enough of it&lt;/a&gt; at home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dakin, other reasons for infidelity include a &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;need for thrill or excitement&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;feeling bored by the sex&lt;/a&gt; they receive from their partner or feeling &lt;a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/woman/real_life/4889529/hooker-turned-relationship-counsellor.html" target="_hplink"&gt;hesitant to share their intimate desires&lt;/a&gt; and fantasies with their spouse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it appears that research backs up Dakin's hypotheses.&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/22/why-people-cheat_n_2483371.html" target="_hplink"&gt; According to &lt;/a&gt; "The Normal Bar," an &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Normal-Bar-Surprising-Relationship/dp/0307951634?tag=vglnkc7225-20" target="_hplink"&gt;extensive survey of 100,000 people&lt;/a&gt; published this year, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/22/why-people-cheat_n_2483371.html" target="_hplink"&gt;71 percent &lt;/a&gt;of unfaithful men and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/22/why-people-cheat_n_2483371.html" target="_hplink"&gt;49 percent &lt;/a&gt;of unfaithful women said &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/22/why-people-cheat_n_2483371.html" target="_hplink"&gt;sexual boredom was the reason they cheated&lt;/a&gt; in their relationships. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below for 26 other reasons why men cheat, according to men. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--263653--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1089857/thumbs/s-WHY-MEN-CHEAT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>20 Things To Do Now That You're Single</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/the-single-girls-bucket-l_n_3093910.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3093910</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T19:15:28Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T19:14:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Breakups suck. OK, that's an understatement. Breakups make you feel like scum. No matter whose...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>thestir.cafemom.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Breakups suck. OK, that's an understatement. Breakups make you feel like scum. No matter whose &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1089743/thumbs/s-SINGLE-WOMAN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Guess What Cliché About Men And Women Turns Out To Be True?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/men-dont-understand-women_n_3093763.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3093763</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T17:59:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T21:51:26Z</updated>
    
    <summary>We're all sick of the idea that women and men cannot possibly relate to each other because "the language that men understand.. is ...food and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christina-huffington/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;We're all sick of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/04/men-women-differences-minimal-mars-venus-study_n_2618199.html" target="_hplink"&gt;the idea that women and men&lt;/a&gt; cannot possibly relate to each other because "&lt;a href="http://www.today.com/books/gabby-reece-marriage-men-communicate-through-food-sex-1C9307555" target="_hplink"&gt;the language that men understand.. is ...food and through sex&lt;/a&gt;” and because "&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/13/gabrielle-reece-laird-hamilton_n_3071594.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_hplink"&gt;to truly be feminine means being soft, receptive, and –- look out, here it comes –- submissive&lt;/a&gt;.” So, so sick of them. Unfortunately, one of the most pervasive clichés -- that men are incapable of understanding women -- now has some scientific evidence to back it up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A German study &lt;a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0060278#s1" target="_hplink"&gt;published online April 10th in the journal PLOS&lt;/a&gt; found that men do indeed have difficulty understanding how women feel -- at least from looking their eyes. The researchers, led by &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28661-men-cant-read-womens-eyes.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Boris Schiffer of the LWL-University Hospital&lt;/a&gt; in Bochum, Germany, put 22 men between the ages of 21 and 52 in a functional magnetic resonance imaging scanner (fMRI), which uses blood flow as a measure of brain activity. The men were shown images of 36 pairs of eyes -- half belonging to men and half belonging to women -- and asked to choose which of two given emotions the person was feeling. An interpretation of a person's emotions based only on a closeup of their eyes is called a "&lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/ideas-market/2013/04/15/its-official-men-dont-get-it/" target="_hplink"&gt;Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test&lt;/a&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers found that it was &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28661-men-cant-read-womens-eyes.html" target="_hplink"&gt;twice as difficult for the men to accurately guess what the women were feeling &lt;/a&gt;as it was for them to guess what the men were feeling. They also took longer attempting to interpret the women's eyes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what's the scientific explanation behind this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fMRI showed that the &lt;a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/articles/a/amygdala.htmhttp://www.sciencedaily.com/articles/a/amygdala.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;amygdala&lt;/a&gt; -- a part of the brain that helps process emotions -- was activated more intensely when the men looked at the eyes of other men than when they looked at the eyes of women. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cause of this discrepancy is unclear, though the researchers write in the paper that perhaps evolutionary imperatives made it more important for men to understand other men than to understand women. "As men were more involved in hunting and territory fights, it would have been important for them to be able to predict and foresee the intentions and actions of their male rivals." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research suggests that men don't have any trouble communicating their feelings with their eyes. Studies show us that a man's eyes are capable reflecting everything from his "&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/07/what-men-want-male-gaze_n_2258047.html" target="_hplink"&gt;underlying sexual motivation&lt;/a&gt;" to his &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Health/sexual-orientation-revealed-eye-dilation-study/story?id=16941556" target="_hplink"&gt;sexual orientation.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it seems that men really may have a hard time reading women. That doesn't mean that they shouldn't try, but it does mean that the next time your significant other/male boss/father doesn't realize you're upset, it may not be because he doesn't care. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1090342/thumbs/s-WOMEN-EYES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The 60 Greatest TV Themes Of All Time</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/tv-guide-magazines-60-greatest-tv-themes_n_3093512.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3093512</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T17:16:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T17:17:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary>For years TV Guide Magazine has told you what's worth watching, but what about what's worth hearing -- over and over again? In the best...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>TV Guide Magazine</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jaimie-etkin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;For years TV Guide Magazine has told you what's worth watching, but what about what's worth hearing -- over and over again? In the best TV theme songs, lyrics can summarize the backstory or comment on characters, while instrumentals can sell the mood or set the scene. Just try reading this list of shows without getting a few of their songs stuck in your head.  &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1089532/thumbs/s-TV-THEME-SONGS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Arianna Huffington: GPS for the Sole: Shoes, Stress, and a Child's Future</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arianna-huffington/gps-for-the-sole-shoes-st_b_3093207.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3093207</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T17:06:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T18:10:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As our minds are still grappling with the horror of the Boston bombings, and our hearts are still hurting for the victims and their loved ones, there is something we can do today to help the lives of children around the world. Today is the day that, since 2007, has been designated by the shoe company TOMS as "One Day Without Shoes." TOMS has donated 2 million pairs of shoes to children in more than 50 countries worldwide, and their tagline, "Leave Your Footprint," reflects how much we as individuals can be part of something bigger than ourselves. And that's not the only issue one can take action on today. At work, at home, and beyond, we are facing an epidemic of stress. National Stress Awareness Day is an opportunity to reflect on the things that cause you stress and the methods you can use to course-correct.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Arianna Huffington</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/arianna-huffington/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;As our minds are still grappling with the horror of the Boston bombings, and our hearts are still hurting for the victims and their loved ones, there is something we can do today to help the lives of children around the world. Today is the day that, since 2007, has been designated by the shoe company TOMS as "One Day Without Shoes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most powerful and growing movements in business is the emphasis on giving back, as more and more companies are realizing they can make a difference in people's lives and at the same time improve their bottom line. It's an ethos exemplified by companies like Warby Parker, which donates a pair of eyeglasses to someone in need for every pair sold, and TOMS, which does the same with shoes through its global giving program, "One For One." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That effort, which has donated 2 million pairs of shoes to children in more than 50 countries worldwide, began when TOMS founder Blake Mycoskie -- who also answers to the title Chief Shoe Giver -- traveled to Argentina in 2006. He saw just how many challenges children face when they grow up without shoes, from infections and injury to reduced education opportunities, since many schools require children to wear shoes. So no shoes, no education, no future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Amanda Schwartz puts it in her &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amanda-schwartz/one-day-without-shoes_b_3069438.html" target="_hplink"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about Partners in Health's partnership with TOMS in Malawi, where many people have to walk five miles just to get to a health clinic: "Walking five miles anywhere is hard for most everyone. Walking five miles when you're sick is unimaginable. Walking five miles when you're sick and when you are a kid is terrifying. Can you imagine what it would be like to do that and to be barefoot?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AOL and HuffPost have been observing and promoting "One Day Without Shoes" in our offices since 2011. (We also made a splash in the annual contest known as the &lt;a href="http://onedaywithoutshoes.com/challenge" target="_hplink"&gt;Barefoot Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, placing third with around 2,000 employees pledged to go without shoes.) The TOMS tagline, "Leave Your Footprint," reflects how much we as individuals can be part of something bigger than ourselves. And, to put the spotlight on the effort, we've been posting blogs by people who are already getting involved and making a difference. There's TOMS Chief Giving Officer &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sebastian-fries/how-shoes-can-do-more_b_3081725.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Sebastian Fries&lt;/a&gt; on the evolution of "One Day Without Shoes" to meet the changing needs of children around the world, Goods For Good founder &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/melissa-kushner/goods-for-good-malawi_b_3078144.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Melissa Kushner&lt;/a&gt; on investing in the children of Malawi, and Ohio State University student &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alexandra-constantinou/why-i-want-to-one-day_b_3076122.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Alexandra Constantinou&lt;/a&gt; on how going shoeless "inspires me to place myself in someone else's situation for one day."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's not the only issue one can take action on today. National Stress Awareness Day -- started by the nonprofit Health Resource Network, which has been celebrating April as &lt;a href="http://healthresourcenetwork.org/stress-awareness-month/" target="_hplink"&gt;Stress Awareness Month&lt;/a&gt; since 1992 -- is an opportunity to reflect on the things that cause you stress and the methods you can use to course-correct. At work, at home, and beyond, we are facing an epidemic of stress: In the last 30 years, self-reported stress &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-504763_162-57453502-10391704/american-women-young-people-are-more-stressed-than-their-counterparts-study-shows/" target="_hplink"&gt;has gone up 25 percent for men and 18 percent for women&lt;/a&gt;. We're surrounded by stressed-out leaders making terrible decisions. And the evidence is clear that as women scale new heights in the workplace, they pay a heavy price: Women in stressful jobs have a &lt;a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0040512" target="_hplink"&gt;nearly 40 percent increased risk of heart disease&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="http://forecast.diabetes.org/magazine/forecast/women-job-stress-and-diabetes-risk" target="_hplink"&gt;60 percent increased risk of diabetes&lt;/a&gt; compared to their less-stressed colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why we at HuffPost launched a free app, &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gps-for-the-soul/id586099254" target="_hplink"&gt;GPS for the Soul&lt;/a&gt;, to track your stress level through your heart rate variability and help you de-stress by launching a personalized guide of the photos of your loved ones, music, poetry, etc., that help you get back to the centered place in your life. So there's no better time to download the app and set yourself on a course of -- as our 18 HuffPost lifestyle sections dedicated to the cause put it -- Less Stress, More Living. Here's a video to get you started: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4C14ik8TLQA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lois Tarter: The Benefits Of Dating During Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lois-tarter/dating-during-divorce_b_3082409.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3082409</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T16:04:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T16:03:39Z</updated>
    
    <summary>People have mixed feelings about dating while going through the divorce process. While dating someone new can boost your confidence after a break-up, should you wait until the divorce is officially over before seeking out someone new?</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lois Tarter</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lois-tarter/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;People have mixed feelings about dating while going through the divorce process. While dating someone new can boost your confidence after a break-up, should you wait until the divorce is officially over before seeking out someone new?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the single life is a major adjustment. However, it also offers an exciting second chance at love. Some people have no issues dating before the divorce is final. Others would rather sign the divorce papers before moving ahead. And still others think they won't date until the divorce is finalized, but they change their mind when they meet someone new. You just never know when fate will intervene and a new special person will come along.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons that dating &lt;em&gt;during&lt;/em&gt; divorce may be the right choice for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Feel More Positive:&lt;/strong&gt; Dating will keep your mind off of the negative aspects of divorce.  It will get you in an upbeat frame of mind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Can Relax More:&lt;/strong&gt; You have probably been under a lot of pressure.  Dating someone new gives you the opportunity to relax more.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You're Able To Open Up:&lt;/strong&gt; When you're dating, you're much more open and social.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Make New Contacts:&lt;/strong&gt; The person you're dating is sure to have friends and it will create a whole new network of people for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Can Renew Your Sex Life:&lt;/strong&gt; In the final stages of your marriage, there was probably no sexual contact.  Now you're free to enjoy what you've been missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Broaden Your Horizons:&lt;/strong&gt; You will probably do things that you haven't done in a long time now that you're single. Be open to going on dates to art galleries, concerts and other cultural events. You can also go out with people that are in totally different worlds than the married world you were in.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the above benefits of dating during divorce, you simply may not be ready to do so. Here are some reasons dating during divorce may not be right for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Are Not Healed Yet:&lt;/strong&gt; You may think that you're ready to date, but you might not be healed yet emotionally. It is beneficial to work through any unsettled issues before taking on a new love interest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Are Worried About the Kids:&lt;/strong&gt; Dating before the divorce is final may not be best for your kids. Sure you can be discrete, but you don't want to be distracted from their needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Would Like to Be More Financially Secure:&lt;/strong&gt; Dating someone new can be expensive.  You may need some time to get your finances settled after the divorce before you go on some nights out on the town. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Want to Spend Some Time Alone: &lt;/strong&gt;You may want be alone for a bit and dating may not allow for that. You can do things you haven't done for a while or see friends you haven't seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You May Be Judged:&lt;/strong&gt; People who are against dating until the divorce is official may judge and gossip about you for moving forward now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You'd Rather Date Someone Who Is a Parent:&lt;/strong&gt; You may want to wait to meet someone else who is a single parent so you can relate to each other.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more dating advice during a divorce, pick up Lois Tarter's new book "The Divorce Ritual" by clicking &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Divorce-Ritual-Lois-Tarter/dp/098510130X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1365996180&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=lois+tarter" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1088394/thumbs/s-DATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Ozzy Osbourne Reveals Recent Drug Relapse</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/16/osbourne-split-rumors-ozzy-osbourne_n_3092311.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3092311</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-16T14:26:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T16:31:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Trouble in Oz? Nope. Black Sabbath singer Ozzy Osbourne took to his Facebook page Monday to address rumors that he and wife-of-31-years Sharon Osbourne were...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Youyoung Lee</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/youyoung-lee/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Trouble in Oz? Nope. Black Sabbath singer Ozzy Osbourne took to&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ozzyosbourne/posts/10151607133627318" target="_hplink"&gt; his Facebook page Monday&lt;/a&gt; to address rumors that he and wife-of-31-years Sharon Osbourne were &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/sharon-ozzy-osbourne-divorce-split_n_3084195.html?utm_hp_ref=celebrity" target="_hplink"&gt;living in separate households and headed for divorce&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the message, the 64-year-old rocker denied claims that he and Sharon were splitting, but did make a curveball revelation that had previously not been reported in the press -- that he had relapsed into "drinking and taking drugs" for over one year. He also called himself an "asshole" and copped to "insane behavior" but said he is now 44 days sober.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/ozzyosbourne/posts/10151607133627318" target="_hplink"&gt;full message&lt;/a&gt; is reposted below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;For the last year and a half I have been drinking and taking drugs. I was in a very dark place and was an asshole to the people I love most, my family. However, I am happy to say that I am now 44 days sober. 

&lt;p&gt;Just to set the record straight, Sharon and I are not divorcing. I’m just trying to be a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to apologize to Sharon, my family, my friends and my band mates for my insane behavior during this period………and my fans. &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ozzy had previously attributed his rehabilitation from substance abuse to Sharon, whom he married in 1982 after three years of dating. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1089107/thumbs/s-OSBOURNE-SPLIT-RUMORS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
