<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Confession: I'm Dying, And My Husband Is Having An Affair</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/cheating-husband-_n_3073116.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3073116</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T07:09:18Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T07:11:03Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Should you confront a cheating spouse? Even those with opposing answers to that question can agree that -- at the very least -- it's complicated....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ashley-reich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Should you confront a cheating spouse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even those with opposing answers to that question can agree that -- at the very least -- it's complicated. And the verdict becomes even more muddled when the realities of life are factored in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/dear_prudence/2013/04/dear_prudence_i_m_dying_and_my_husband_is_having_an_affair.html" target="_hplink"&gt;last Tuesday's "Dear Prudence"&lt;/a&gt; advice column on &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/authors.emily_yoffe.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Slate&lt;/a&gt;. A 32-year-old woman discovers that her husband has been having an affair and wonders whether to confront him. The catch? She's dying of a terminal illness -- she has six to eight months to live -- and her husband has been a tremendous source of support to her. &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/dear_prudence/2013/04/dear_prudence_i_m_dying_and_my_husband_is_having_an_affair.html" target="_hplink"&gt;She writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My husband has been amazingly supportive of me during this time...A few weeks ago while using his iPad to watch a movie, an email came in and I discovered he has been having an affair (emotional and sexual) with a co-worker for a few months now. For several days I cried, heartbroken at the betrayal, but now I feel like my husband deserves to have someone help him and support HIM through this emotional time...Do I confront my husband and tell him I understand? That although I am hurt, I forgive him and I don't want him to feel guilty? Or do I just keep quiet and let him continue? If our families find out after I'm gone, I'm worried they will think ill of him, and I don't want that either.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Yoffe -- or "Prudence" -- &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/dear_prudence/2013/04/dear_prudence_i_m_dying_and_my_husband_is_having_an_affair.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;advised the woman&lt;/a&gt; to consider hiring a therapist to help her work through the trauma. She also suggested that the woman confront her husband in a compassionate, loving way (&lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/life/dear_prudence/2013/04/dear_prudence_i_m_dying_and_my_husband_is_having_an_affair.html" target="_hplink"&gt;click over to Slate&lt;/a&gt; for the full exchange). She writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;This will be a hard, tearful discussion, but it will also probably be relief of a terrible, guilt-ridden burden for him. As for your family, you are very thoughtful to consider that if after your death it ever comes out there was someone else in his life, he will turn from angel to devil. You don't have to tell anyone else about this. But as you say your farewells to those closest to you, you can allude to it. Perhaps you can tell your family that you want them to know that life can be so difficult and complicated and that through all of it your husband has been everything you wanted. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all professionals agree. &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/laurie-israel/" target="_hplink"&gt;Attorney Laurie Israel&lt;/a&gt; suggested that the woman proceed without confronting her husband.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It would be a great gift to the husband, who is giving his wife his attention and loving care through her illness," Israel wrote in an e-mail to HuffPost Divorce. "Mutual marital processing of this affair under this unusual situation would lead to nothing positive, and it will be to the detriment of the quality of whatever time they have left. It would show great compassion and restraint for the wife to keep silent, and it would be a great gift to the husband who was faithful in the important ways during her illness. Without the pain brought about by disclosure, he would have a much greater chance to repartner with his lover after his wife’s death. That’s a wonderful gift she can give him, this faithful man who is her husband."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tammy Nelson, a relationship therapist and author of "&lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy; Redefining Your Relationship After Infidelity&lt;/a&gt;," acknowledged that the choice is a difficult one, but that the husband's affair may indeed be his way of coping with the illness. To get clarity about this decision, she suggests writing a letter to the husband as if he is reading it after the woman is gone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Tell him that you knew about the affair and that you were hurt but you understood. And that you forgive him," she said via e-mail. "Perhaps writing the letter will release the feelings that are weighing you down, and will put your fears to rest about his future and any possible repercussions. Or it may make it clear to you that you don't want to wait until you are gone to talk with him. Either way, no matter what you decide, your husband's love is not diminished by his affair. Don't let yourself rewrite the history of your marriage because of his indiscretion. People do things when they are grieving and frightened that they might not do under normal circumstances."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? We asked our &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter followers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook fans&lt;/a&gt; to weigh in -- click through the slideshow below to see what they had to say, then share your opinion in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--291752--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085106/thumbs/s-CHEATING-HUSBAND-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>10 Signs Your Marriage Is Doomed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/15/red-flags-relationships_n_3040560.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3040560</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T07:05:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T07:15:10Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By Susie and Otto Collins for YourTango.com Have you ever wondered whether or not something your partner just said or did is normal and okay?...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By&lt;a href="http://www.yourtango.com/experts/SusieandOttoCollins" target="_hplink"&gt; Susie and Otto Collins for YourTango.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered whether or not something your partner just said or did is normal and okay? Many of us second-guess ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You feel insulted, rejected or maybe even betrayed, but are conflicted about what to do and whether you're just making a big deal out of nothing. You worry that bringing up the offending words or behavior will heighten tension or start a fight, but the hurt and confusion remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way your partner is acting seems like a huge red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be tough to know when to speak up and ask your partner to make a change, and when to just let it go. We all have bad or "off" days once in awhile, and you may just blow off how annoyed or offended you feel. Our advice to you is to stop ignoring your partner's upsetting words and actions. Even if you look around at other people's relationships and see the very same behaviors, this doesn't mean you have to put up with it and suffer in silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, watch for these ten behaviors from your man:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. He tells you you're fat. &lt;/strong&gt;Even if it's disguised as a joke, if your partner criticizes your weight or certain parts of your body, you don't have to grit your teeth and listen. Even if you could stand to lose a few pounds, that is your decision to make -- not his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. He ignores you. &lt;/strong&gt;If he consistently tunes you out, refuses to talk or is constantly distracted by the game, his phone or anything else, this could mean your relationship is in the danger zone. No matter how busy your partner is, you shouldn't have to jump up and down trying to get his attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. He says one thing and does another.&lt;/strong&gt; When your partner nods and says "yes, dear" only to do the complete opposite of what he just agreed to, this is not okay. Watch for observable examples of whether or not his words match his actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. He yells at you when drunk. &lt;/strong&gt;We all lose our cool occasionally. If your man screams and yells at you when he's drunk and then blames it on the booze, this is no excuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. He forbids you from contact with friends or family. &lt;/strong&gt;Nobody has the right to tell you whom you can talk to or spend time with and this includes your partner. If he has a jealousy problem, stay calm and set boundaries. If he's truly concerned for your well-being, listen and consider his words but know that this is your choice to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. He sleeps around when drunk.&lt;/strong&gt; "I was wasted; it meant nothing," is not a valid excuse. Cheating is cheating and needs to be acknowledged and addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. He lies and breaks promises. &lt;/strong&gt;Even "white lies" or "little" broken promises are bad for trust. Make sure that you're creating an environment that promotes honesty and follow through, but do take lying seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. He puts you down. &lt;/strong&gt;There's a difference between a suggestion or helpful critique and a comment that is disrespectful and puts you down. Take a moment to really think about the words your partner said. Was he putting you down or were you hearing what he said through your own self-negative filter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. He is abusive.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it's physical, sexual, verbal or emotional, abuse is never okay. It's not healthy for you, and you don't have to subject yourself to it any longer. Make your safety and well-being your top priority. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. He refuses to commit. &lt;/strong&gt;This one is tricky, and it mainly applies to non-married couples. It's always your partner's choice whether or not he will commit to your relationship in the way you want him to. He's not wrong for it. But, if you are firm about wanting to be monogamous, to move in together, to get engaged, have children or to get married and he refuses to make that kind of commitment, this is a problem and a sign that you two might not be a match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you decide whether or not something your partner says or does is okay with you, remember a few things: It doesn't mean the situation is all his fault; it doesn't mean you should threaten to divorce him (unless you'll really do it); it doesn't mean he "owes" you; and it doesn't mean that you should punish him in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he does something that's not okay, it means that it's time for you to take a second look at how things are in your relationship. It's likely that whatever is going on is not beneficial for you, and it's probably not healthy for your marriage either. Decide what your next move will be. Will you create agreements with him to put changes in motion? Will you consider whether or not it's wise for you to stay in the relationship at all? Will you make some internal changes that could significantly affect his behavior?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice is yours to make. Remember, you deserve to be treated with respect, kindness and love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too many broken promises and nasty words? Here's help making one of the most important decisions you'll ever make: &lt;a href="http://www.stayorgo.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Should you stay or should you go?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Visit &lt;a href="http://www.stayorgo.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;stayorgo.com&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Stories On YourTango:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.yourtango.com/2013173136/30-things-guaranteed-start-silly-argument-your-spouse" target="_hplink"&gt;30 Things Guaranteed To Start An Argument With Your Spouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.yourtango.com/2012166459/opposites-attract-20-super-strange-celeb-couples" target="_hplink"&gt;Opposites Attract: 20 Super Strange Celeb Couples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.yourtango.com/2012168236/10-couples-who-stayed-together-despite-cheating-scandals" target="_hplink"&gt;10 Couples That Stayed Together Despite Cheating Scandals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.yourtango.com/breakups-and-divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Divorce: Survival Tips &amp; Advice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.yourtango.com/infidelity" target="_hplink"&gt;Infidelity: The Best Advice And Tips On YourTango&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086087/thumbs/s-MARRIAGE-DOOMED-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lindsey's Ex Jokes About Tiger's Masters Woes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/thomas-vonn-joke-tiger-woods-masters_n_3077965.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3077965</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-15T00:38:37Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-15T00:38:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>With Tiger Woods making headlines in the Masters and Lindsey Vonn watching from the sidelines at Augusta, the skier's ex-husband garnered a bit of attention...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Chris Greenberg</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-greenberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;With Tiger Woods &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/14/new-york-post-covers-tiger-woods-balls_n_3081421.html" target="_hplink"&gt;making headlines&lt;/a&gt; in the Masters and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/11/lindsey-vonn-the-masters-tiger-woods-photos_n_3061479.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Lindsey Vonn watching&lt;/a&gt; from the sidelines at Augusta, the skier's ex-husband garnered a bit of attention for himself with a joke on Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;No problem Masters tournament happy to call in and help. You always have to keep an eye on those cheaters ;)&lt;a href="http://t.co/u0pY3ftGzH" title="http://yhoo.it/Zh7TBu"&gt;yhoo.it/Zh7TBu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Thomas Vonn (@ThomasVonn) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ThomasVonn/status/323204060746498048"&gt;April 13, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Vonn tweeted on Saturday that he was the anonymous tipster who called Augusta National on Friday to report &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/13/tiger-woods-penalty-masters-drop_n_3075796.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Woods' illegal ball placement&lt;/a&gt; on the 15th hole. The &lt;a href="http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/augusta-national-statement-tiger-woods" target="_hplink"&gt;statement from Fred Ridley&lt;/a&gt;, chairman of the competition committees at Augusta National, revealed that the officials had been "prompted by a television viewer" in the process of assessing Woods a controversial two-stroke penalty. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas, a former U.S, skier and coach, and Lindsey &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/09/lindsey-vonn-and-thomas-v_n_2443308.html" target="_hplink"&gt;finalized their divorce&lt;/a&gt; in January. In March, Lindsey and Tiger &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/18/tiger-woods-lindsey-vonn-dating-announcement_n_2901686.html" target="_hplink"&gt;went public&lt;/a&gt; with their romance.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1086193/thumbs/s-LINDSEY-VONN-THOMAS-VONN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Was It Really Necessary For 10 Sheriffs To Escort Kim Kardashian Out Of Court?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/13/kim-kardashian-sherriffs_n_3076824.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3076824</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-13T18:36:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T21:43:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kim Kardashian proved she's the master of b*tch face, as she was escorted out of a Los Angeles courthouse by ten L.A. County sheriffs on...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Stephanie Marcus</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/stephanie-marcus/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Kim Kardashian proved she's the master of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/04/celebrities-giving-attitude-photos_n_1939694.html" target="_hplink"&gt;b*tch face&lt;/a&gt;, as she was escorted out of a Los Angeles courthouse by &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2308286/Kim-Kardashian-marches-court-flanked-TEN-sheriffs--furious-judge-blasts-estranged-husband-Kris-Humphries-show.html" target="_hplink"&gt;ten L.A. County sheriffs on Friday&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 32-year-old's estranged husband &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-court-divorce_n_3070464.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kris Humphries was a no show at the mandatory divorce settlement conference&lt;/a&gt;, and it's clear that Kardashian was &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-divorce_n_3072264.html" target="_hplink"&gt;none too pleased&lt;/a&gt;.  Superior Court Judge Hank Goldberg had to set another hearing for April 19, though it seems pointless since Humphries' lawyers said no settlement was reached and that a trial is still scheduled for May 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least the pregnant reality star can take some solace in the fact that Humphries might be fined for skipping out of their court date. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kardashian left the courthouse &lt;a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/04/13/kim-kardashian-court-leaving-guards-kris-humphries/" target="_hplink"&gt;flanked by what seems like an excessive amount of sheriffs&lt;/a&gt;, since we doubt anyone would dare mess with her at that moment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, if looks could kill...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="kim kardashian sheriffs" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085590/thumbs/o-KIM-KARDASHIAN-SHERIFFS-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="kim kardashian sheriffs" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085594/thumbs/o-KIM-KARDASHIAN-SHERIFFS-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085590/thumbs/s-KIM-KARDASHIAN-SHERIFFS-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kerri Zane: 5 Ways To Win A Single Mom's Heart</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kerri-zane/5-ways-to-win-the-heart-o_b_3052041.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.3052041</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-13T10:32:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T10:31:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Dating a single mom might not be the right choice for every single man. It takes a special kind of guy to want to be involved with a woman who is committed to devoting a significant amount of time and attention to her children.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kerri Zane</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kerri-zane/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Dating a single mom might not be the right choice for every single man. It takes a special kind of guy to want to be involved with a woman who is committed to devoting a significant amount of time and attention to her children. But it is also true that a vast majority of single moms -- who are nurturers by nature -- can be wonderful partners. They engender an amazing capacity to be flexible, compassionate and committed. So, for the single guy who has found himself drawn to a single mom, here are a few tips to win her heart.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.	&lt;strong&gt;Plan a family date night.&lt;/strong&gt; If you've met a single mom and your relationship has progressed to the point where it is time to meet her children, take the initiative and suggest a family date night.The first time you meet her kids should be short, sweet and very kid centric. The goal is to endear yourself to her children. For example, invite them all out for ice cream, to the park or to see a kid-friendly movie. The kids will be impressed with their mama's super cool new friend. Your lady will be incredibly impressed that you've come up with the idea. It will ease the kids into getting to know you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, as much as you would like to kiss her or hold her hand, refrain during this meeting. You've done a great job of making the kids feel special. Any kind of affection tendered toward their mom in front of them might make the kids feel threatened. You want to be a welcome addition to her family, not a threatening interloper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.	&lt;strong&gt;Find a babysitter.&lt;/strong&gt; Oftentimes the biggest obstacle in a single mom's dating life is finding adequate childcare. If it happens that she cannot arrange for her regular babysitter or a family member to stay with her children, offer to help her out. Perhaps you have a younger sibling who could step in to babysit. You might suggest a trusted member of your office staff or a neighbor you know and trust. Or search out one of the online babysitting services, like &lt;a href="http://care.com" target="_hplink"&gt;care.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://sittercity.com" target="_hplink"&gt;sittercity.com&lt;/a&gt;. Calm any stranger jitters by allowing your date to talk to or meet the babysitter prior to your evening out. This kind of single mom assistance will definitely give you "knight-in-shining-armor" brownie points. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.	&lt;strong&gt;Treat her to pamper time.&lt;/strong&gt; Single moms, especially working single moms, rarely take time out for themselves. Any kind of me-time activity is worth it's weight in gold. If you have the wherewithal to take her away for the weekend without her having to stress about child care worries, (see #2) do it! If it isn't possible to go away for an extended period of time, or money is tight, consider treating your special lady to an hour-long massage, facial or even a simple mani/pedi. It will do her a world of good and make you a superstar in her book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.	&lt;strong&gt;Support her parenting without stepping on her toes&lt;/strong&gt;. Although it may be challenging to not express your thoughts and opinions about how she raises her children, do your best to try and not interfere. This may be especially challenging if you are a single dad and have a particular standard for how you raise your children. Regardless, it is not your place to push your child-rearing methodology or to reprimand her kids. The only exception might be if and when your beloved asks for your help or input. In that case, you both may want to discuss your child-rearing thoughts privately. Then allow the single mom to incorporate your ideas into her child-rearing style. Kids will always be more likely to accept input from their biological parent. It's best to keep your relationship with her kids as even keel and non-confrontational as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5.	&lt;strong&gt;Know her kids come first.&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, the most important tip I can share with any man who is seeking the companionship of a single mom is to understand that her kids come first. This can frequently be a deal breaker for many relationships, but it doesn't have to be. As an independent and compassionate man, you understand that she's brought these children into the world and feels responsible for their welfare. Verbalize this to her and it will be gratefully received. The good news for you is that a woman's need to be a dedicated mother does not mean she can't be a loving companion. She can. Single moms have an amazing capacity for sharing all their love with everyone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my book &lt;a href="http://kerrizane.com" target="_hplink"&gt;"It Takes All 5,"&lt;/a&gt; I share with single moms that &lt;em&gt;"Dating is a journey, not a means to an end."&lt;/em&gt; Every relationship, whether it leads to a happily ever after or not, is a gift and a learning experience in this trip we call life. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085116/thumbs/s-SINGLE-MOM-DATE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Monique Honaman: The Key To Divorce-Proofing Your Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monique-honaman/great-sex-great-marriage_b_2989588.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2989588</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-13T10:30:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T10:29:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I believe that intimacy is critical to a great and lasting marriage. I have yet to meet a couple who was having marriage problems and thinking about divorce who told me that they still had phenomenal intimacy.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Monique Honaman</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monique-honaman/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;A reader recently commented on one my blog posts something to the effect of, "This author believes that having great sex makes for a great marriage." I think he intended for this to be a critical comment, but actually, I do believe that -- with some caveats, of course! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do believe that intimacy is critical to a great and lasting marriage. I have yet to meet a couple who was having marriage problems and thinking about divorce who told me that they still had phenomenal intimacy. Instead, what I often hear is this: "Somewhere along the line we drifted apart... we stopped talking, we stopped kissing, we stopped hugging, we stopped making love. We became roommates, not lovers."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by intimacy, I mean physical intimacy and also verbal intimacy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physical intimacy is sex, but it also includes hugging, holding hands, walking through the room and running your fingers through his or her hair, and kissing (really kissing!). Remember the scene from &lt;em&gt;Pretty Woman&lt;/em&gt; where Julia Roberts, as a prostitute, is asked by Richard Gere's character, "What do you do?" Her answer: "Everything. But I don't kiss on the mouth." That's exactly right -- sometimes it's not the sex that is intimate, it's the kissing on the mouth.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of the people I speak with tell me that all of this intimacy stopped. I often hear, "I get more physical touch from my friends than I do from my husband (or wife)." It's hard to regain that physical touch once it's gone; it's awkward to get it back, and frequently easier to initiate with a complete stranger than with the person you married. And yet, physical intimacy is critically important to a strong marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But verbal intimacy is also critical. Verbal intimacy is talking -- not about the kids or your schedules for the week -- but about your hopes and goals, your dreams and your fears. It's being comfortable going out to dinner, just the two of you, and not worrying about what you will talk about. I've seen couples whose social lives and vacation planning always had to include others because they didn't have enough to talk about with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have heard the saying that, "couples who pray together, stay together." That's verbal intimacy. I heard from a man recently who told me, "I'm not sure when we stopped talking. I wonder when our communication stopped. I gradually allowed my emotions and ego to become anesthetized... then she left." As with physical intimacy, it's hard to regain verbal intimacy once it's lost. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both physical and verbal intimacy require a dedicated focus. They require time. They require intention. We lead busy lives. As a nation, we're chronically tired. We have competing demands of work, children, extended family and volunteering. Because of these commitments, physical and verbal intimacy often fall by the wayside. No one wants to wake up one day and wonder, "I'm not sure when it all stopped. I feel like we are roommates." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line? Great intimacy is the key to a great marriage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have yet to see a husband and a wife who share great physical and verbal intimacy struggling in their marriage. I've never heard, "She is always touching me," or, "He always wants to open a bottle of wine and talk on the back porch," from anyone in marriage counseling. I haven't heard, "I love the way he kisses me when he comes home from work every day," and "She always asks me how I am doing and really listens," from anyone who is on the brink of divorce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm curious. Do you know anyone in a strong marriage who doesn't share great physical and verbal intimacy with his or her spouse? Is it possible?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1085115/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-PROOF-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTO: Kim Kardashian's Surprising Divorce Court Look</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-divorce_n_3072264.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3072264</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T23:00:15Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T23:11:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The most surprising thing to come out of Kim Kardashian's divorce settlement negotiations on Friday -- besides Kris Humphries not showing up? The reality star's...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;The most surprising thing to come out of Kim Kardashian's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-court-divorce_n_3070464.html" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce settlement negotiations on Friday&lt;/a&gt; -- besides &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-court-divorce_n_3070464.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kris Humphries not showing up&lt;/a&gt;? The reality star's decidedly conservative choice in outfit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With her hair slicked back into a tight pony-tail, the "Keeping Up With the Kardashians" star arrived at the Los Angeles courthouse in white slacks and a high-collared, gray patterned jacket -- &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more ladies-who-lunch than the va va voom looks we've come to expect from her: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHOTO: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="kim kardashian" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084913/original.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(Photo courtesy of AP)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you think of Kim K.'s conservative court attire in the comments, then click through the slideshow below for the best and worst divorce court looks from celebrities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEPOLLAJAX--15985--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084935/thumbs/s-KIM-KARDASHIAN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Calling It Quits</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/jane-seymour-james-keach-split_n_3072345.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3072345</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T21:39:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T21:52:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Jane Seymour has called it quits with her fourth husband, James Keach, to whom she's been married for the last 20 years. The couple has...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Liat Kornowski</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liat-kornowski/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Jane Seymour has called it quits with her fourth husband, James Keach, &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2308270/Jane-Seymour-confirms-split-fourth-husband-James-Keach-20-years.html" target="_hplink"&gt;to whom she's been married for the last 20 years&lt;/a&gt;. The couple has twin sons together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesperson for the 62-year-old actress confirmed the news and said Seymour and Keach, an award-winnng director and producer, "are separated and have been for several months. At this time they are negotiating the terms of their divorce."  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They will continue their relationship as devoted parents to their children, as business associates and partners, and in their joint dedication to preserving and furthering the charitable endeavors that they've worked on throughout their marriage," the spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to RadarOnline, &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/04/jane-seymour-marriage-over-kicks-husband-out-malibu-mansion/" target="_hplink"&gt;Seymour suspected Keach, 65, had been unfaithful&lt;/a&gt; and had kicked him out of their Malibu, Calif., home. "Jane heard that her husband was getting close to a woman that she knows –- that's when she lost it," a source allegedly told RadarOnline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be Seymour's fourth divorce. She's been previously married to Victor Geoffrey Planer, Michael Attenborough and David Flynn. She has two older children with Flynn.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084923/thumbs/s-JANE-SEYMOUR-JAMES-KEACH-SPLIT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>30 Things Readers Would Do Differently If They Remarried</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/second-marriages_n_3071742.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071742</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T21:33:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T22:23:58Z</updated>
    
    <summary>If you were to remarry, would what would you do differently? That's the question Emma Johnson tackled on Friday in a HuffPost Divorce blog listing...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;If you were to remarry, would what would you do differently?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the question Emma Johnson tackled on Friday in &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-johnson/25-ways-i-will-be-a-bette_b_3038693.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;a HuffPost Divorce blog&lt;/a&gt; listing the 25 things she would -- and wouldn't do -- if she were to remarry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"If I get a do-over and remarry, I hope I will be a different kind of wife. A better wife," &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-johnson/25-ways-i-will-be-a-bette_b_3038693.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Johnson wrote&lt;/a&gt; in the intro to her list, which included bullet points on everything from establishing separate bank accounts to making sex a priority. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought it was a useful exercise, so we asked our followers on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to share with us what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; would do differently if they were to marry again. Click through the slideshow below for some of the most interesting answers, then head to the comments to share your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--291713--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084771/thumbs/s-SECOND-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Divorce In A Day?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/quick-divorce_n_3071896.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071896</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T21:33:05Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T21:32:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Long, drawn-out divorce proceedings may soon be a thing of the past. According to local FOX affiliate FOX40, Sacramento Judge James Mize has designed a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Long, drawn-out divorce proceedings may soon be a thing of the past. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://fox40.com/2013/04/12/sacramento-judge-aims-to-expedite-divorce-process/" target="_hplink"&gt;local FOX affiliate FOX40&lt;/a&gt;, Sacramento Judge James Mize has designed a program that makes it quick and easy to untie the knot in &lt;a href="http://fox40.com/2013/04/12/sacramento-judge-aims-to-expedite-divorce-process/" target="_hplink"&gt;just one day&lt;/a&gt;. The program -- which &lt;a href="http://www.kcra.com/news/local-news/news-sacramento/One-Day-Divorce-Program-helps-divorcees-Sacramento-court/-/12969376/19515182/-/item/1/-/12jnny1z/-/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;officially starts Friday&lt;/a&gt; -- is aimed at people who &lt;a href="http://www.kcra.com/news/local-news/news-sacramento/One-Day-Divorce-Program-helps-divorcees-Sacramento-court/-/12969376/19515182/-/item/0/-/12jnny2z/-/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;can't afford to hire a divorce lawyer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are pulling folks who are at the bottom, who don’t have any help, who don’t have any representative assistance,” Mize &lt;a href="http://www.kcra.com/news/local-news/news-sacramento/One-Day-Divorce-Program-helps-divorcees-Sacramento-court/-/12969376/19515182/-/item/0/-/12jnny2z/-/index.html" target="_hplink"&gt;told NBC affiliate KCRA&lt;/a&gt; in March 2013. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fox40.com/2013/04/12/sacramento-judge-aims-to-expedite-divorce-process/" target="_hplink"&gt;Eighty attorneys, law students &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href="http://fox40.com/2013/04/12/sacramento-judge-aims-to-expedite-divorce-process/" target="_hplink"&gt;other staff&lt;/a&gt; will volunteer their services to help couples &lt;a href="http://www.saccourt.ca.gov/family/one-day-divorce.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;discuss the terms &lt;/a&gt;of their divorce agreements and &lt;a href="http://www.saccourt.ca.gov/family/one-day-divorce.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;prepare all of the necessary paperwork&lt;/a&gt; to obtain the final judgment. Once these steps are completed, the parties will &lt;a href="http://www.saccourt.ca.gov/family/one-day-divorce.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;go before the judge the same day&lt;/a&gt; and can leave the courthouse with a finalized judgment of dissolution of marriage in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above for more on Mize's new program. Then, click through the slideshow below for five hotels and resorts that offer packages that cater to divorcees. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084748/thumbs/s-QUICK-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'I Received Death Threats For Cheating'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/cheaters_n_3071898.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071898</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T20:37:37Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T20:36:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Should we have compassion for cheaters? Yes, according to HuffPost blogger Wendy Plump, the author of "Vow: A Memoir of Marriage (And Other Affairs)." In...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ashley Reich</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ashley-reich/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Should we have compassion for cheaters?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, according to HuffPost blogger Wendy Plump, the author of "&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Vow-Memoir-Marriage-Other-Affairs/dp/1608198235" target="_hplink"&gt;Vow: A Memoir of Marriage (And Other Affairs)&lt;/a&gt;." In an appearance on HuffPost Live this week, Plump -- who admits to having been both the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/wendy-plump/hold-the-wrath_b_2853699.html" target="_hplink"&gt;cheater &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the scorned spouse&lt;/a&gt; -- asked that we don't judge those who stray quite as harshly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"People who have had affairs are not necessarily devils, and perhaps deserve a little more compassion than we as a society, we as a culture give them," she said. "I understand that infidelity is extremely provocative and it's a difficult subject for many people, but since it happens so much it seems to me that a more measured approach, a more measured response to it might be a better way."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some readers don't agree. In response to her &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/wendy-plump/hold-the-wrath_b_2853699.html" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost blog on the same subject&lt;/a&gt; published last month, Plump received scores of negative comments, and even a death threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Somebody from Texas suggested that I come down to Texas and see what they do to women who cheat and was sort of a thinly veiled death threat," she said on HuffPost Live. "Not what I was expecting but that kind of thought is out there."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video above for more on Plump's take, then click through the slideshow below for what readers suggest you should say to a spouse after cheating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--266959--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084792/thumbs/s-CHEATING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Navy Officer Who Faked His Own Death To End Affair Faces Expulsion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/michael-ward-affair_n_3071602.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071602</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T19:44:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-14T00:10:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>GROTON, Conn. &amp;mdash; A former submarine commander who faked his death to end an extramarital affair should be honorably discharged from the Navy, a panel...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/gabrielle-dunkley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;GROTON, Conn. &amp;mdash; A former submarine commander who faked his death to end an extramarital affair should be honorably discharged from the Navy, a panel of officers recommended Friday after a daylong hearing in which the officer said he accepted "full and total accountability" for his behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cmdr. Michael P. Ward II, a married 43-year-old, sent his mistress in Virginia an email in July posing as a fictitious co-worker named Bob and saying Ward had died unexpectedly. Ward was relieved of his duties aboard the USS Pittsburgh in August a week after he'd taken command and has received a letter of reprimand for adultery and other military violations.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;After testimony from Ward's former superior officers, colleagues and shipmates, Ward, in his dress blues, acknowledged to the panel that he had had an affair and sent the bogus email to the woman in an effort to end it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The reason I did it was to sever the relationship," he said, "but the choice was ridiculous."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He apologized to the Navy and the sailors who served under him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three-officer board of inquiry recommended Ward retain his rank upon being discharged. Its decision goes to the secretary of the Navy for approval within 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the hearing, at Naval Submarine Base New London, the government countered that Ward discredited the Navy and that his removal put a strain on the fleet because officers had to be shuffled around to cover his removal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Commander Ward's actions show a complete lack of honesty, character and integrity," said Navy Lt. Griffin Farris, acting as prosecutor at the hearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward said he accepted responsibility for his actions and would regret them all his life, adding that he was grateful to his wife for standing by him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want to apologize directly to my wife for the hurt and harm and humiliation I have caused her," he said as she sat in the front row, her eyes red. "I accept full and total accountability for my actions."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, the Navy shouldn't throw away Ward's talent and training, said high-ranking officers with whom he has served. They said he made an awful mistake and was a fast-rising, hardworking officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before moving to Connecticut, Ward served on the Joint Chiefs of Staff, where he used his nuclear expertise to provide daily briefings to the chairman as the Fukushima disaster unfolded following the earthquake in Japan. Navy Capt. Lawrence Vincent, who worked with Ward in Washington, said he would serve with again and the handling of the affair struck him as out of character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"With Mike Ward, it was a true shock," Vincent said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ward was honest with his chain of command from the beginning, his lawyer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"This man probably would have been an admiral someday, and he's brought shame on himself, and he knows that," said Navy Cmdr. Daniel Cimmino, representing Ward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a senior enlisted sailor from the USS Pittsburgh told the panel that Ward at first denied the accusations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sailor, Master Chief Chris Beauprez, said he received a call on the submarine from a sister of Ward's girlfriend, who told him what Ward had done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beauprez said he told Ward about the call and Ward denied the woman's allegations, then said he'd address the situation himself. Beauprez testified that he had an implicit trust in what his commander said so he didn't take the matter any further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days later, he said, he heard Ward was being dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fellow Navy officer who had gone through training with Ward, Cmdr. Anthony Moore, testified that he heard about the affair, including the detail that Ward had used the name Tony Moore in an online dating profile that he used to meet the woman, when news of it first surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I was very surprised," Moore, who's based on a submarine squadron in Washington state, told the board by telephone. "And frankly, I was a little concerned for my reputation."&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084665/thumbs/s-MICHAEL-WARD-AFFAIR-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>WATCH: Why We Nag Our Spouses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/marriage-problems_n_3071261.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3071261</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T19:16:41Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T19:15:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In a HuffPost Divorce blog post earlier this month, author Monique Honaman wrote about how detrimental nagging can be in a marriage. "The cycle of...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monique-honaman/nag-nag-nag_b_2976104.html" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost Divorce blog post&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month, author Monique Honaman wrote about how detrimental nagging can be in a marriage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The cycle of bad communication (and nagging) can go from bad to worse," &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/monique-honaman/nag-nag-nag_b_2976104.html\" target="_hplink"&gt;Honaman wrote&lt;/a&gt;. "Though the spouses may not be communicating positively, at least they are communicating in some fashion. Is it when communication stops altogether that things take a turn for the worse, from salvageable to beyond repair, from marriage to divorce?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, Honamans sat down with HuffPost Live host Abby Huntsman and discussed what motivates people in relationships to nag one another. Watch the clip above to hear what she had to say, then click through the slideshow below for marriage lessons our readers learned after divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288757--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084529/thumbs/s-NAGGING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Blended Family Friday: Meet Susan And Peter's Family</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/blended-family-friday_n_3056616.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3056616</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T19:08:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T19:13:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As part of our Blended Family Friday series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of our &lt;strong&gt;Blended Family Friday&lt;/strong&gt; series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together. Our hope is that by telling their stories, we'll bring you closer to blended family bliss in your own life!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we'd like you to meet fiancés Susan and Peter and their four kids. After five years together -- and a lot of friendly prodding on their kids' part -- the pair will tie the knot this June. Congrats! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi, Susan! Please introduce us to your family. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My soon-to-be husband's name is Peter and between us, we have four kids: Maile, 20; Jake, 18; Jamie, 17; and Julia, 16. Maile and Jamie are from my first marriage, and Jake and Julia are from Peter's. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us a little about your engagement. Why did you decide to marry now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Peter and I were actually going to wait until they all graduated from college to get married. We wanted to focus on them and their needs for now. The kids are really the ones who wanted us to get married. I think they need to feel like this is forever. Recently, Jake, Peter's son, told me he wants my son Jamie to be his best man someday. I get teary thinking about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the best thing about being part of a blended family? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our kids get to relax! I think each set of kids felt responsible for their single, lonely parent. It's a lot of pressure on a kid. When my daughter was leaving for college she told me she was glad I had Peter because now she wouldn't have to worry. The kids just get to be kids now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the biggest challenge of blended family life? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our kids were older when we moved in together -- 16, 14, 13 and 12. Each household had its own set of rules and they weren't always the same. The "why can she do that when I can't?" stuff was tough. Little by little, we've found common ground, but it takes a lot of compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes you proudest of your family? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Oh, gosh, where do I begin? They are smart, funny, wonderful people, and they're mine! I love that the kids actually call and text each other just to say hi or to make fun of Peter or me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice do you have for other blended families who feel like a peaceful family dynamic is out of reach? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Don't take your opinion so seriously. People raise kids in many different ways. It's OK to compromise, your kids won't suffer; in fact, they'll be better off in the long run. The ability to have respect for all opinions in your household will go a long way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and also, love your partner. Peter and I help each other to be better parents, friends, and people. He's my rock! I can accomplish so much more with him by my side. I'm so glad our kids have this as a romantic model. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click through the slideshow the see photos of Valerie and Brandon's family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you'd like your own family to be featured on a Blended Family Friday, please email us at  &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt;. We're looking forward to hearing your story! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--291053--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084452/thumbs/s-BLENDED-FAMILY-FRIDAY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kim's Day In Court</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/12/kim-kardashian-court-divorce_n_3070464.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.3070464</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-12T17:09:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T23:08:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary>LOS ANGELES &amp;mdash; Kim Kardashian and Kris Humphries are getting another chance to settle their divorce case, and this time a judge wants the NBA...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liat-kornowski/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;LOS ANGELES &amp;mdash; Kim Kardashian and Kris Humphries are getting another chance to settle their divorce case, and this time a judge wants the NBA player to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humphries was a no-show for settlement talks Friday, and Superior Court Judge Hank Goldberg set another hearing for April 19. The judge also set a hearing for whether Humphries should be fined for not appearing at Friday's mandatory settlement hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Kardashian appeared in court, but none of Friday's discussions were conducted in open court. Humphries' lawyers said no settlement was reached and that a trial is still scheduled for May 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brooklyn Nets power forward wants his marriage to Kardashian annulled based on his allegations that it was fraudulent. Kardashian wants a traditional divorce, which would be her second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humphries has not yet laid out the specifics to support his fraud claim, but his former attorney has said Humphries wants an annulment because of his belief that Kardashian only married him because of her reality show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kardashian and her lawyer have denied the accusation. The "Keeping Up With the Kardashians" star was flanked by deputies as she left the courthouse shortly around noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She arrived under heavy security and was brought into the courtroom through a back entrance. Her hair was tied back in a ponytail, and she kept her hands crossed on her lap while she listened to Goldberg explain to reporters that the hearing would be closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I always wanted to be a juror," she joked to deputies before taking her seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kardashian is expecting a child with boyfriend Kanye West later this year. She appeared in court wearing white pants and a long ornate gray jacket. She was not accompanied by West or any members of her famous family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her mother, Kris Jenner, is expected to testify on her daughter's behalf at the trial. Humphries has not yet filed his witness list for the trial, which is expected to last a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthony McCartney can be reached at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mccartneyAP"&gt;http://twitter.com/mccartneyAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1084241/thumbs/s-KIM-KARDASHIAN-COURT-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
