<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Amira Young: 14 Life Lessons I Learned From Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amira-young/learning-curves-15-divorc_b_2935713.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935713</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T06:26:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T06:34:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I left my husband, nothing could prepare me for what I faced next: nasty rumors, money issues, a vengeful ex, romantic feelings for someone I did not expect and an overwhelming sense of grief.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Amira Young</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amira-young/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When I left my husband, nothing could prepare me for what I faced next: nasty rumors, money issues, a vengeful ex, romantic feelings for someone I did not expect and an overwhelming sense of grief. Divorce was new and frightening, and something I didn't know how to deal with emotionally. I was off on an adventure, but one on tumultuous seas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as with any great adventure, I picked up a lot of funny stories, tender moments, and -- of course -- lessons to move forward with. They are things I will take to heart as I establish myself again and, hopefully, move on to a better love. I have learned...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Not to care what people think.&lt;/strong&gt; People are going to talk, spread rumors and take sides. It's the nature of divorce. But if you're going to recover properly, you're going to have to tune it out. Do whatever is right for you, even if it's not the most popular thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. To put myself first. &lt;/strong&gt;I'm a self-admitted people pleaser, but you can't do that while trying to heal, otherwise you won't recover properly. Do what you need to do and focus on you. And for those with children, if you're happy, you'll have an easier time keeping your kids happy, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Mourning is key.&lt;/strong&gt; We may not think of divorce as a death, but it is the death of a relationship. Even if it was dead for a long time, you should do a certain amount of mourning. Grief is natural, and you shouldn't pretend your marriage didn't mean anything. It did. Process accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. To love myself. &lt;/strong&gt;In marriage, I forgot about me; after divorce, I had to learn who I was all over again. We need to be okay with who we are on our own. After all, as RuPaul says, "If you can't love yourself, how in the hell are you going to love anyone else? Can I get an Amen?" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. To have sex again. &lt;/strong&gt;It's scary to move on in the bedroom, but divorced sex is too much fun to pass up. I have learned plenty of new tricks and preferences to bring to a new relationship; they're things I would have never known if I stayed celibate post-split. Don't be afraid -- let loose and have fun! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. To take control of my finances.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most dangerous things I did in marriage was give financial control to my ex. The result was he hid money -- &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of money -- and overpowered me. I'm still recovering financially. You should always know where your money is and how your finances are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. The best support after divorce comes from fellow divorcees.&lt;/strong&gt; I am lucky to have several friends who are going through their divorces at the same time as me. We prove to each other that we're not crazy and keep each other in check. Sometimes it's the only thing that keeps us sane. If you don't have divorced friends, try to find a support group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Those that judge your actions during crisis aren't worth your time. &lt;/strong&gt;I did things over the course of my split that many of my friends didn't like. When thrown into an emotional crisis, we rebel and reshape ourselves in ways that may not always be positive. Good friends stand by you. They shouldn't cast judgment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Not to let anger dominate.&lt;/strong&gt; My ex's behavior towards me during our split, like making out with his new girlfriend very publicly six weeks after I left (also known as the way people found out about the divorce) and stealing money from me, was downright deplorable. I was so mad that I didn't realize he was reacting out of anger and weakness. Anger gets in the way of your heart and mind. Don't let it take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. To figure out where the marriage went wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are not owning part of the blame, look harder - it takes two to tango. I certainly made mistakes, such as trying to please everyone else so much that I didn't think about myself, picking the wrong partner and not being as open emotionally as I should have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. To laugh.&lt;/strong&gt; Whenever we start to laugh again is when we truly begin the healing process. Once you find your humor, there is nothing stopping you down the path of recovery. Find joy in everything, and things will get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. It's okay to cry. &lt;/strong&gt;Healing is not a linear process. Sometimes you'll take five steps forward, and then need to take three steps back and possibly have a mini-meltdown. It's all right to feel what you're feeling. You aren't superman (or woman) and don't need to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Know when you're ready for love again. &lt;/strong&gt;Two months after I left my ex, I realized that I had feelings for a close male friend who I suspected felt the same way. He was someone I would have seriously considered marrying, but I was too emotionally unstable and not ready yet to get involved with him. Although our friendship suffered as a result, it was the right decision at the time for me. We are the only ones who can say whether we're ready or not, so listen to your gut. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Love is still the most powerful thing in the universe.&lt;/strong&gt; My friends think I'm crazy to believe this after divorce, but love is a beautiful thing. I'm not talking real love, built on respect, communication and trust. The best part is that love takes many forms, like in friends and family. Cherish the love that's in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Shakespeare said (and my father, who quotes him regularly), "This, above all, to thine own self be true. And it must follow, as the night the day, thou canst not then be false to any man."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061641/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-LIFE-LESSONS-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Bill Swadley: Why You Should Avoid Family Court... At All Costs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-swadley/liars-court_b_2917619.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2917619</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T00:36:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:36:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In a perfect world, the mission of family court is to ensure that any agreement between the parents is in the best interest of the children.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Bill Swadley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-swadley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I've had the opportunity, albeit not by choice, to spend a few days at family court over the past six months. Family court, I was told by one lawyer who has spent the last 25 years in that area of his profession, is also known as "Liar's Court." The reason It's called this is very simple:  Almost everyone lies. They lie for various reasons. For personal gain, mostly, and sometimes out of a genuine concern for the welfare of the children involved. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, the mission of family court is to ensure that any agreement between the parents is in the best interest of the children. This, of course, would be a difficult task were everyone being forthright and honest, but when most everyone is playing fast and loose with the truth, it becomes a near impossibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I witnessed most commonly was the old "he said/she said" routine. In most cases, this was all there was. Neither party had any evidence to present, so they made false claims about each other, which left the judge to decide who was lying least (or maybe who was lying better?) This was usually how it went. There were instances where one party or the other did have evidence that had been filed with the court. In those rare instances, the judge still proceeded as if it were a case of "he said, she said" and largely ignored any evidence in favor of hearing arguments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many problems in the family court system and they vary in degree and severity, sometimes particular to the state or county in question, but from what I've witnessed, read, and been told, the level of dishonesty displayed by the parties and their lawyers in family court is consistent and pervasive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons Liar's Court exists, even in that most important area of family law, is the backlog most courts experience on an ongoing basis, especially those in large metropolitan areas. The backlog is so extreme that no judge could possibly familiarize him or herself thoroughly with each file given the daily barrage of cases they're inundated with. This leave the judge with little recourse but to ask the parties to tell their stories and hope that he can find the truth in the statements made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that, regardless of the evidence filed in the case, once the parties arrive in court they only need to be able to tell a convincing story and their evidence may or may not receive a proper review. Many, many tactics are used to try to sway the judge towards one side or the other under these circumstances, and it's a virtual free-for-all of dishonesty, but the big trick happens before the couple arrives in court with their respective lawyers. That is, getting the case to court in the first place. (This is especially important if you happen to have no case to begin with.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engage the other party's lawyer in conversation about the case in an effort to demonstrate attempted negotiations, but don't actually negotiate. Keep making the same offer even if the other party is willing to compromise. Remember, the goal isn't to settle, but to get the case in front of a judge. These sham negotiations are necessary in the event that the judge asks if any settlement negotiations were attempted. A really clever lawyer will find a way to accuse the other lawyer of being unwilling to negotiate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;File as much paperwork with the court as possible. Don't worry about redundancy or lack of veracity in the filing. No one will read any of it. The goal here is to make the file so thick and unwieldy that the judge will not have time to review it (or at least not think he has time) and he will believe  that the case is extremely complicated. This will also serve to dissuade him or her from asking whether negotiations were held.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep the couple from talking to each other. God forbid they should come to an agreement before going to court. Whatever it takes, make sure they fear and distrust each other. This will keep two people from talking surer than anything else.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prepare arguments in anticipation of the judge's questions on the matter, knowing full well that the documents you've filed haven't been read by him/her or anyone else. Then spin, spin, spin, spin until the web of the story is so complicated and personally heartfelt that your client looks like Gandhi and theirs is the picture of Satan himself. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Collect handsome reward. Win or lose, getting a case before a judge that should have been settled out of court is a big payday regardless of the outcome. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
All ironic bitterness aside, my advice to any divorcing couple, especially those with children, is simply this: &lt;strong&gt;Stay out of court.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your lawyer tells you, it's likely not in your best interest or that of your children. If you find a lawyer who advises  you that you'll do better with a judge than settling the matter with your former spouse, get a second opinion. Then get a third. When you find a lawyer who advises you to work out a settlement outside the court system, hire that person  That's your Jerry Maguire. (For those of you who don't remember or haven't seen the film, Jerry Maguire was a sports agent who set out to end corruption and dishonesty in his profession single-handedly. Laughter ensues.) He/she may be a cockeyed optimist, but is also one you can likely trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know what you think in the comments section below. My experience with &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-swadley/the-reality-of-child-supp_b_823550.html" target="_hplink"&gt;writing about this subject matter in the past &lt;/a&gt;tells me that many lawyers will have lots to say about what I've written here, much of it surprisingly uncomplimentary. My answer to their most frequently asked question is: "No, I don't think you're the whole problem, but I do believe you are integral to the problem and have it in your power to affect it in a positive way."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>16 Ways To Be A Better Stepparent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/stepparent-advice_n_2974474.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2974474</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T23:41:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T23:41:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When you marry someone with kids, it's understandable to want to win over your new stepkids quickly. But the road to a stable relationship with...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;When you marry someone with kids, it's understandable to want to win over your new stepkids quickly. But the road to a stable relationship with your spouse's children isn't always easy, especially when everyone involved seems to have an opinion on what you should -- and shouldn't -- be doing as a stepparent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the situation a little less stressful for our readers, earlier this week, we asked &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/stepparent-advice-how-to_n_2951878.html" target="_hplink"&gt;five HuffPost Divorce experts&lt;/a&gt; for their best advice on creating a healthy bond with stepkids. Take a look at their &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/stepparent-advice-how-to_n_2951878.html" target="_hplink"&gt;great tips here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, our stepparent readers drew on personal experience and offered their tried-and-true tips on everything from what your stepkids should call you, to the importance of building a relationship with kids before disciplining. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to read their best advice, then &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostDivorce&lt;/a&gt; the three things &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think stepparents need to know to cultivate a better relationship with their stepkids. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289074--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061389/thumbs/s-STEPFAMILY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Diane L. Danois, J.D.: What The Passover Story Can Teach Us About Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/diane-l-danois-jd/the-passover-story-and-ch_b_2973115.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2973115</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T21:33:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T21:32:35Z</updated>
    
    <summary>While thinking about the Passover holiday, it occurred to me that there are lessons to be learned from this particular spiritual event</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Diane L. Danois, J.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/diane-l-danois-jd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;My parents recently celebrated their 55th wedding anniversary. While marveling at their marital longevity and thinking about the Passover holiday, it occurred to me that there are lessons to be learned from this particular spiritual event. Passover is a holiday marked with many customs and rituals. Among them is the telling of the story of the liberation of the Israelites from slavery in ancient Egypt during the holiday meal, which took place on Monday and Tuesday of this week. It is customary for the leader at the dinner table to engage conversation with everyone in a question and answer fashion, encouraging children to participate, while telling many stories throughout the night. At one point during the evening, the leader tells the story of The Four Sons, who were all very different and who each had questions about this special night. One by one, each son asked the leader about the customs they were learning, stories they were hearing, and rituals they were performing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wise Son&lt;/em&gt; asked a very detailed question, demonstrating his interest and desire for a satisfying answer;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Wicked Son&lt;/em&gt; asked his question defensively, challenging the traditions and rituals, and why he should even care about them;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Simple Son&lt;/em&gt; asked about all of the symbolism he witnessed during the meal, wanting to learn and understand more about their meanings; and&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Son Who Is Too Young to Know What to Ask&lt;/em&gt; was gently encouraged by his parents to simply be interested in what was happening around him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leader explains that while each of the Four Sons were experiencing the &lt;em&gt;same &lt;/em&gt;rituals and customs at dinner, each would interpret what was going on around him differently. Therefore, it would be important to respond to each of the inquiries from each son differently, with patience and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, too, is the way in which our children experience and interpret their parents' divorce.  Multiple children from the &lt;em&gt;same &lt;/em&gt;household, witnessing the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; disputes, and experiencing the &lt;em&gt;same &lt;/em&gt;events, will often internalize and react dramatically differently. While we may not be able to categorize the personalities of our children into the simplistic "wise, wicked, simple and too young" traits, we can appreciate the differences in our children, and can adjust how we interact with them accordingly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this: Parents have been divorced for two years and have 50/50 time-sharing, alternating one-week on/off at each home. During this time, the son and daughter have seemingly happily packed their suitcases every Sunday afternoon, and switched houses. One day, however, while packing his suitcase, the son unexpectedly burst into tears. "I'm tired of going back and forth. No one ever asked me what I wanted. I don't like living out of a suitcase.  I never asked for this divorce, and I don't want to have to choose between living with my mom or dad."  &lt;em&gt;No one ever asked me what I wanted. &lt;/em&gt; Sometimes as adults, we're so focused on our own lives, that we forget the impact our divorce has on our childrens' lives, and we forget to give them an opportunity to ask their own questions. There are many questions children want answered about their parents' divorce. Some of the more common questions (and how to respond) are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where will I live?  Will I have to change schools?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For the young child, your response should try to satisfy fears that you won't be together anymore. Set expectations that you will attend as many special events as possible, that you are interested in what he/she is doing, and that the divorce will not affect how you feel about him/her. For the older child, listen to his/her concerns about the living arrangements, and provide some flexibility whenever reasonable and possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who wanted the divorce?  Is it &lt;em&gt;my &lt;/em&gt;fault?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Assure all children, regardless of age, that the divorce has nothing to do with anything they said or did. Reassure their feelings of guilt that their behavior caused the divorce. Explain that it takes two people to marry and two people to divorce, and that who initiated the divorce is unimportant. For the older children, who may be searching for more specific answers, give them a forum to ask questions, providing appropriate responses without maligning the other parent.  When necessary, engage a family therapist or counselor to participate in sessions where there exists a safe platform and environment to address his/her concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When will I be able to see Mom/Dad?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;There is nothing more important for a child than keeping the lines of communication wide open between parents.  No matter how much you detest your spouse, your children must never feel like they have limited or no access to the other parent. Encourage daily phone calls, allow for mid-timesharing visits, and force yourself to be as flexible as reasonably possible.  Your child's well-being depends upon it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will you still come to see me at sports/school play/recitals?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Just say, "YES!"  Make every effort to maintain the norm for your child, recognizing that you can't be everywhere all the time. Set expectations for your child to minimize disappointment.  If you can't be there, explain the reasons (not blaming the other parent, of course). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the divorce is about you and your spouse, for the egocentric child, the concerns are completely focused inward... what will happen to ME?  Just like the leader of the Seder, it is our responsibility as parents to tell each child, separately and in a way he/she will understand, &lt;em&gt;what the divorce means to him/her&lt;/em&gt;.  It is our responsibility to tell them the "story," of the divorce in a way that they will understand.  It is our responsibility to encourage them to ask questions about what they see, hear and do, and provide responses as openly and as honestly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>9 Things You Need To Survive Your Split</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/divorce-care-package_n_2973446.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973446</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T21:16:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:56:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>If there's ever a time you need a little distraction in your life, it's during the divorce process. That's why we launched our Divorce Care...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If there's ever a time you need a little distraction in your life, it's during the divorce process. That's why we launched our &lt;strong&gt;Divorce Care Package&lt;/strong&gt; series. With each post, we'll show you what things -- books, movies, recipes -- helped others relieve stress in the midst of divorce, in the hopes that a few of their picks will serve you well, too. Want to share what got you through your divorce? Email us at &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt; or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPost Divorce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can a woman depend on to get her through a divorce? According to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-ball/" target="_hplink"&gt;HuffPost blogger Jennifer Ball,&lt;/a&gt; it's simple: a good dog, the love of your kids, Nora Ephron's highly relatable work -- &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;this guy: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="jon hamm" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061090/thumbs/h-JON-HAMM-320x320.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh. Yeah, we get that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, Ball, who blogs regularly about post-split life at &lt;a href="http://happyhausfrau.blogspot.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Happy Hausfrau&lt;/a&gt;, shares how each item helped her get through her divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288756--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061247/thumbs/s-KIDART-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Danica Patrick Opens Up About Boyfriend</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/danica-patrick-divorce-_n_2973413.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973413</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T20:05:13Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T20:04:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>On Saturday, NASCAR driver Danica Patrick sat down with Marc Malkin of E! News to dish on her post-split romance with fellow driver Ricky Stenhouse,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;On Saturday, NASCAR driver Danica Patrick sat down with Marc Malkin of E! News to &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/402086/nascar-danica-patrick-and-boyfriend-ricky-stenhouse-jr-spill-on-their-romance?cmpid=rss-000000-rssfeed-365-topstories&amp;utm_source=eonline&amp;utm_medium=rssfeeds&amp;utm_campaign=rss_topstories" target="_hplink"&gt;dish on her post-split romance&lt;/a&gt; with fellow driver Ricky Stenhouse, Jr. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'll say, 'Babe, am I less hot when I'm not good on [the] track? Does that make me less attractive?'" she said. "And he's like, 'Hon, I'm not with you because you're a race car driver.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stenhouse is Patrick's first boyfriend since she filed for divorce from physical therapist Paul Hospenthal in January 2013. She first announced their &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DanicaPatrick/posts/470280563014806" target="_hplink"&gt;plans to divorce&lt;/a&gt; in November 2012 on her &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DanicaPatrick/posts/470280563014806" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook page.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the split, Patrick has seen some major professional success. In February, she hit a career high when she became the first woman to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/19/danica-patrick-nascar-_n_2718695.html" target="_hplink"&gt;win the pole position&lt;/a&gt; for the Daytona 500 and achieved &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/nascar/2013/02/24/daytona-500-2013-danica-patrick/1943125/" target="_hplink"&gt;a top-10 finish.&lt;/a&gt; But she has also seen her fair share of disappointments. In March, she blew a tire and &lt;a href="http://cdn.speedwaydigest.com/index.php/news/sprint-cup-series-news/item/9498-tire-problem-ends-patrick-s-day-early-at-phoenix" target="_hplink"&gt;finished 39th at the Subway Fresh Fit 500&lt;/a&gt; in Phoenix. The following week, she landed in&lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/nascar/2013/03/10/danica-patrick-las-vegas-sprint-cup/1977055/" target="_hplink"&gt; 33rd place at the Kobalt Tools 400&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick isn't the first NASCAR superstar to call it quits with her spouse. Click through the slides below for five others who did the same.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--227111--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061087/thumbs/s-DANICA-PATRICK-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Celebrities Who Called Off Their Engagements</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/celebrities-who-called-off-engagements_n_2973506.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2973506</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T19:05:35Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T20:15:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>They're on, they're off. Whether or not Miley Cyrus and Liam Hemsworth make it as a couple, one thing's clear: Those who called out 19...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Youyoung Lee</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/youyoung-lee/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;They're on, they're off. Whether or not &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/24/liam-hemsworth-engaged-actor-miley-cyrus_n_2944799.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Miley Cyrus and Liam Hemsworth make it as a couple&lt;/a&gt;, one thing's clear: Those who called out &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/06/19/miley-cyrus-engaged-too-young-to-marry-liam-hemsworth_n_1609980.html" target="_hplink"&gt;19 years old as simply too young&lt;/a&gt; to be betrothed are now nodding their heads in vindication. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like the "Last Song" co-stars are simply following in the long tradition of famous stars who have called off their engagement before hitting the altar. From Courteney Cox and Michael Keaton to Britney Spears and Jason Trawick, Hollywood sees more romantic mixups than an episode of "Gossip Girl." Launch our gallery below to see the most notable broken engagements in recent memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289004--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061028/thumbs/s-CELEBRITIES-WHO-CALLED-OFF-THEIR-ENGAGEMENTS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kimberly Seltzer: How To Avoid Dating A Narcissist</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kimberly-seltzer/4-narcissist-busters-from_b_2935538.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935538</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T15:49:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T15:49:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Amazing, talented  caregivers attract narcissists. What is going on?</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kimberly Seltzer</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kimberly-seltzer/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;You were married for 15 years. You did everything possible for your spouse. You knew how they took their coffee in the morning and what their favorite dish was. You even knew about the various events that took place in their day and expressed interest. When they were unhappy, you tried doing things for them so that they would be loving again. But no matter what you did or said it was never enough. They cheated, lied or turned to drugs and alcohol to fill them up.  You finally divorce. Now after the fog has lifted and you've come out the other side, you think to yourself, "They never knew me and what I liked... it was all about them." Moreover, you realize that you keep attracting these same types of people into your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a common repetitive phenomenon that I see in my practice at &lt;a href="http://theartofcharm.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Art of Charm.&lt;/a&gt; Amazing, talented  caregivers attract narcissists. What is going on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Narcissists prey on caregivers because they make them feel better. They are insecure and empty, so they rely on external things (like money, sex, expensive cars, etc.) to fill them up and gain attention. When I coach people, I teach them how to detect signs of a narcissist. You can't change them, but you can change &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; perception so that you can spot a narcissist the minute you say hello. Here are four narcissist busters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Set boundaries:&lt;/strong&gt; Treat yourself as well as you treat others. Set boundaries and declare your wants and needs. If you are a caretaker, be careful that you are not putting others before you. Let your date know what you like and dislike. Do they respect your desires or only do what they want?&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. Look for reciprocity:&lt;/strong&gt; Narcissists are really good at being charming and telling stories and sharing what is great about them. When meeting your dates, observe if they are just as interested in you and your stories. Is there reciprocity in the conversation or is it just one-sided? What are you doing to reinforce that dynamic? Be careful to not just sit and listen to it all. Instead, try talking about your interests, express your feelings and see if they listen.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3. Don't give it all away:&lt;/strong&gt; Don't give away your personal value by doing too much, too soon, too fast. Narcissists will eat you up. Pay attention to how you are relating to your dates or potential partners.  Are you always playing therapist by listening intently, offering advice and doing things for them? You can offer these things as a loving partner but pace it out and see if they are able to offer you the same in return.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4. Test if words get put into action:&lt;/strong&gt; Does the person you are attracted to mean what they say and say what they mean? Narcissists love to talk but rarely follow through.  Remember, actions always speak louder than words.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Finally, use this time in your life as an opportunity to change the pattern of attracting narcissists. Instead, focus on what you can do during the first phase of dating in order to attract a person who likes you for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; rather than what you can provide for them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kimberly Seltzer LCSW is a Therapist, Matchmaker, Personal Image Expert and Dating Coach at &lt;a href="http://theartofcharm.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;The Art of Charm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059493/thumbs/s-DATE-NARCISSIST-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>What Happens To Babies When Their Parents Argue</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/sounds-of-arguing-affect-_n_2971911.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2971911</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T15:19:24Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T16:31:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By: Tanya Lewis, LiveScience Staff Writer Published: 03/27/2013 09:30 AM EDT on LiveScience Hearing the sounds of arguments affects how a baby's brain processes emotional...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;By: Tanya Lewis, LiveScience Staff Writer &lt;br /&gt;
Published: 03/27/2013 09:30 AM EDT on LiveScience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Hearing the sounds of arguments affects how a baby's brain processes emotional tones of a voice, a new study finds. The little ones' brains lit up in response to angry tones, even while they were asleep.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Babies' minds are extremely malleable. The environments and events they experience shape their brains for good or for ill. Stress due to maltreatment or being raised in an institution can take a toll on a baby's development. But this study, to be published in a forthcoming issue of the journal Psychological Science, shows that even moderate &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/20820-stress-alters-brain-kids.html"&gt;stresses can affect brain function&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;We were interested in whether a common source of early stress in children's lives — conflict between parents — is associated with how infants' brains function,&amp;quot; lead study author Alice Graham of the University of Oregon said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Graham and her colleagues scanned the &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/1892-sleeping-babies-brains-buzz.html"&gt;brains of 20 sleeping infants&lt;/a&gt;, ages 6 months to 12 months, using functional magnetic resonance imaging (a technique that measures blood flow as a proxy for brain activity). Inside the scanner, the babies heard nonsense sentences spoken by a male adult in very angry, mildly angry, happy or neutral tones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The sleeping infants' brains showed distinct patterns of activity corresponding to each different emotional tone, the study revealed. Compared with babies raised in healthy homes, infants in high-conflict homes (as reported by their mothers) had a greater response to the very angry voice in brain regions involved in stress and emotion regulation — the rostral anterior cingulated cortex, the caudate, the thalamus and the hypothalamus. Previous &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/4380-humans-baboons-stress.html"&gt;studies in animals&lt;/a&gt; indicated that these regions show effects of early life stress on development, and this study suggests human babies may experience a similar phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The findings suggest babies are aware of parental conflicts and that these conflicts may affect how the infants' brains handle stress and emotion, Graham said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow &lt;em&gt;Tanya Lewis &lt;/em&gt;on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tanyalewis314"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/117033537877488293678/posts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Follow us &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LiveScience"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@livescience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/#!/livescience"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101164570444913213957/posts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Original article on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28165-sounds-of-arguing-affect-sleeping-babies-brains.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;LiveScience.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/17894-10-scientific-parenting-tips.html'&gt;10 Scientific Tips For Raising Happy Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/12932-11-facts-parent-baby-brain.html'&gt;11 Facts Every Parent Should Know About Their Baby's Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.myhealthnewsdaily.com/3369-baby-myths-debunked.html'&gt;7 Baby Myths Debunked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; Copyright 2013 LiveScience, a TechMediaNetwork company. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. ]]&gt; &lt;/content&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1060389/thumbs/s-SLEEPING-BABY-mini.jpg?5" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Bon Appetit: Cadbury Creme Eggs: Everything You Ever Wanted to Know</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bon-appetit/cadbury-creme-eggs_b_2958223.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2958223</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T13:49:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T15:15:15Z</updated>
    
    <summary>How they're made, and the most popular methods to eat them.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Bon Appetit</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bon-appetit/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Louise McCready, &lt;a href="http://www.bonappetit.com?mbid=synd_huffpotaste" target="_hplink"&gt;Bon Appétit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-26-cadburycreameggsinwrappers.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-26-cadburycreameggsinwrappers.jpg" width="484" height="332" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Little History&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;In 1824, John Cadbury opened a shop in Birmingham where he sold tea, coffee, hops, mustard, cocoa, and drinking chocolate, which he made himself using a mortar and pestle. A century later, in 1923, the company that grew out of his shop released its first cream-filled eggs. But the Cadbury Creme Easter Eggs we all know and love weren't invented until 1971. Four years later, the first TV ad appeared for Cadbury Creme Eggs and these chocolate confections became an international Easter classic. Many Americans will remember the "clucking bunny" campaign, begun in 1982.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more: &lt;a href="http://www.bonappetit.com/recipes/2013/01/salty-chocolate-chunk-cookies?mbid=synd_huffpotaste" target="_hplink"&gt;Your New Favorite Chocolate Chip Cookie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are they made?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The Cadbury Creme Egg is manufactured by pouring liquid chocolate into a half-egg shaped mold, which is then filled with white fondant and a dab of yellow fondant. Because the fondant has a greater density than chocolate, the two don't mix together and the fondant pushes the chocolate outwards. The two mold halves are quickly closed and cooled to allow the chocolate to set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you eat yours?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;In 1985 Cadbury launched the memorable ad campaign, "How do your eat yours?" The official Cadbury website offers two methods: "egg and soliders" and "bite and lick." If you prefer egg and soldiers, you eat the chocolate egg like a soft-boiled egg by placing it in an egg cup and eating the fondant filling with a spoon or scooping it out with Cadbury Fingers. "Bite and lick" -- pretty self-explanatory -- describes the method of biting the top and sucking out the cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read More: &lt;a href="http://www.bonappetit.com/blogsandforums/blogs/badaily/2013/01/9-ways-to-upgrade-instant-rame.html?mbid=synd_huffpotaste" target="_hplink"&gt;Easy Ways to Upgrade Instant Ramen Noodles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to a Cadbury survey: &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;53 percent of people bite off the top, lick out the cream, then eat the chocolate&lt;br /&gt;
20 percent just bite straight through &lt;br /&gt;
6 percent use their finger to scoop out the cream &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extra tip Cadbury offers is to mash the remaining chocolate shell (left after biting the top off and eating the fondant) and mix it with a dash of Grand Marnier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;More from Bon Appétit:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.bonappetit.com/tipstools/slideshows/2011/08/10-unhealthy-foods?mbid=synd_huffpostaste#slide=1" target="_hplink"&gt;Healthy Snacks? Maybe Not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.bonappetit.com/recipes/slideshows/2008/04/spring_vegetables_slideshow?mbid=synd_huffpotaste#slide=1" target="_hplink"&gt;Spring Vegetables: 26 Ways to Eat 'Em&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.bonappetit.com/blogsandforums/blogs/badaily/2013/01/essential-kitchen-gadgets.html?mbid=synd_huffpotaste" target="_hplink"&gt;8 Essential Kitchen Gadgets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=" http://www.bonappetit.com/recipes/slideshows/2008/05/burgers_and_sliders_slideshow?mbid=synd_huffpotaste" target="_hplink"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Top 20 Best-Tasting Burger Recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059527/thumbs/s-CADBURY-EGGS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>The Worst Diet Mistakes For Hair And Nails</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/bad-hair-nails-diet-foods_n_2964618.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2964618</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T12:33:42Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T12:33:43Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Just like your skin, your hair and nails are affected by the foods you choose to eat. And we're not talking about the sheen of...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Sarah Klein</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sarah-klein/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Just like your skin, your hair and nails are affected by the foods you choose to eat. And we're not talking about the sheen of those lustrous waves or a hangnail. Both hair and nails can become brittle and dry, and hair can thin or fall out without the right range of nutritious picks in your diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Both are a barometer of how well (or how poorly) you're feeding the body," says dermatologist Jessica Wu, M.D., author of "Feed Your Face" and &lt;a href="http://www.everydayhealth.com/skin-beauty/skin-doctor-jessica-wu.aspx" target="_hplink"&gt;skin and beauty expert for Daily Glow&lt;/a&gt;, "as well as your overall health."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both hair and nails are made from the same protein, called keratin, so it makes sense that similar diet choices would affect them both, she explains. Of course, a number of other lifestyle choices also play a role, including smoking, she says, since it reduces circulation and may cut down on the amount of biotin in the blood. &lt;a href="http://www.umm.edu/altmed/articles/vitamin-h-000342.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;Biotin&lt;/a&gt;, often added to hair and nail products, seems to strengthen both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less research exists to document the &lt;a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/nails/WO00020/NSECTIONGROUP=2" target="_hplink"&gt;impact of various foods on hair and nail health&lt;/a&gt; than to illustrate the role of diet in healthy skin. But there are still a few foods to consider avoiding if you're concerned about brittle nails or thinning hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288720--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058711/thumbs/s-BAD-HAIR-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTOS: Is Kirsten Dunst Going Gray?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/kirsten-dunst-gray-hair-gang-signs_n_2970394.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2970394</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T12:11:26Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T19:46:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Kirsten Dunst's style is as fashion-forward as it comes. Her roles in "The Virgin Suicides" and "Marie Antoinette" launched trend after trend, and Dunst's personal...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lauren-leibowitz/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/kirsten-dunst-style" target="_hplink"&gt;Kirsten Dunst&lt;/a&gt;'s style is as fashion-forward as it comes. Her roles in "The Virgin Suicides" and "Marie Antoinette" launched trend after trend, and Dunst's personal outfits make her an off-duty superstar. Surely any look on a magazine she covers should be one to copy, right? Get ready for the latest trend modeled by &lt;a href="http://bullettmedia.com/article/kirsten-dunst-in-defiance-of-gravity/" target="_hplink"&gt;Kirsten Dunst: gray hair&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billed in Bullett Magazine as "America's edgiest sweetheart," the glossy's cover story dip-dyes Dunst in a wash of silvery tones. Bullett's interview includes an outlandish declaration of &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/kirsten-dunst-brad-pitt_n_2970106.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Dunst's "disgust" with kissing Brad Pitt&lt;/a&gt; for one of her earliest film role. Her &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2300247/Kirsten-Dunst-sports-silver-streaks-hair-new-avant-garde-photo-shoot.html" target="_hplink"&gt;gray hair is paired with other avant-garde accessories&lt;/a&gt;, like &lt;a href="http://www.fabsugar.com/Ear-Cuff-Earrings-Trend-28577937" target="_hplink"&gt;ear cuffs&lt;/a&gt;, bronze eyeshadow and... gang signs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Bullett's interview, &lt;a href="http://bullettmedia.com/article/kirsten-dunst-in-defiance-of-gravity/" target="_hplink"&gt;the gang symbol was Dunst's idea&lt;/a&gt;. “Come on, guys,” she said. “Let’s make this controversial. Let’s sell magazines!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think Dunst makes gray look great? Take a look below! Read the interview and see the shots featuring Dunst as a natural blonde over at Bullett's website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHOTOS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="kirsten dunst gray hair" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059894/thumbs/o-KIRSTEN-DUNST-GRAY-HAIR-570.jpg?15" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="kirsten dunst gray hair" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059904/thumbs/o-KIRSTEN-DUNST-GRAY-HAIR-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="kirsten dunst gray hair" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059909/thumbs/o-KIRSTEN-DUNST-GRAY-HAIR-570.jpg?5" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other celebs who've made drastic hair changes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--284915--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want more? Be sure to check out HuffPost Style on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/huffpoststyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/HuffPostStyle" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffpoststyle.tumblr.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffpoststyle/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and Instagram at @HuffPostStyle.&lt;br /&gt;
--&lt;br /&gt;
Do you have a style story idea or tip? Email us at stylesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059894/thumbs/s-KIRSTEN-DUNST-GRAY-HAIR-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>PHOTOS: The World's Best Islands</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/28/the-10-best-islands-in-the-world_n_2951255.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2951255</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T11:58:25Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T17:20:08Z</updated>
    
    <summary>If these magnificent spots aren't on your radar, they should be.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kate Auletta</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kate-auletta/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;TripAdvisor is all about its annual lists: The &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/20/worlds-best-beaches-accor_n_2718799.html?utm_hp_ref=why-we-vacation" target="_hplink"&gt;best beaches&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/05/worlds-most-romantic-hotels_n_2617821.html?utm_hp_ref=why-we-vacation" target="_hplink"&gt;most romantic hotels&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/16/worlds-best-hotels-tripadvisor_n_2455645.html?utm_hp_ref=why-we-vacation" target="_hplink"&gt;best hotels,&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/05/best-family-hotels-in-the-world_n_2807695.html?utm_hp_ref=why-we-vacation" target="_hplink"&gt;best hotels for families&lt;/a&gt; being among them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its newest list examines the islands of the world, and the U.S. in particular. While Florida has five of the 10 best islands in the United States, TripAdvisor users ranked three islands in Asia and the Pacific as the all-around best. Either way you slice it, these islands are on many travelers' bucket lists. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the top 10 islands below and leave your judgements in comments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All photos courtesy of TripAdvisor&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055353/thumbs/s-BEST-ISLANDS-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lauren Parker: Why I Called It Off</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lauren-parker/i-called-off-my-wedding-dont-regret-it_b_2957950.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2957950</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T11:56:59Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T15:05:43Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What my ex said to me one afternoon that made me realize the relationship was over.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lauren Parker</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lauren-parker/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days is the amount of time that I spent lying face down in a completely dark guest bedroom in my childhood home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to be clear, I would have spent the two days laying face down on the (surprisingly still really comfortable) extra-long twin bed in the room where I grew up. The thing is, I couldn't. My wedding dress was hanging from my wrought-iron canopy bedframe and train of the dress spilled over onto my entire bed. Lush, snowflake-white silk faille cascaded from ceiling-to-floor -- and the massive train, outstretched, seemed to pour on and on for miles. I couldn't bring myself to move the thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, literally. I couldn't move it. It weighed, like, 20 pounds and the garment bag towered over me*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*That accompanied by the fact that the mere idea of looking at it made me physically ill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had just called my wedding off. I needed a nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six is the number of times that I tried to call off my wedding. Six times from the moment I got engaged on a warm, still summer evening to the day that I handed back my beautiful engagement ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to pinpoint exactly why or precisely when I knew that I had to call my wedding off. I had a sneaking suspicion that things were doomed when my partner and I would get into heated arguments about little things, like the way the refrigerator was organized. I just do not think tomatoes belong in the fridge. They get mealy. I also do not think this is cause for a meltdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the wedding date crept closer, my mother-in-law to-be became increasingly involved in our engagement. You should know that I come from a big, boisterous family, so I am used to the comforting closeness of tight-knit relationships -- but this situation took "tight-knit" to the next level. Every move we made was evaluated, judged, commented on. The mere suggestion of eliminating a few people from our wedding guest list to make the event more personal and intimate became cause for hurtful words and finger pointing. As the wedding date drew ever closer, my mother-in-law to-be slowly revealed herself: she was less June Cleaver, more &lt;em&gt;Sex and the City&lt;/em&gt;'s Bunny MacDougal. (Truthfully, both scare me a little, but I bet June Cleaver makes really great chocolate chip cookies.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things seem silly and, sure, some of them are (what is a broken engagement story without some comic relief, after all?). I did not find it silly, though, when my fiancée turned to me one afternoon and said: "I think you should quit your job. I know we talked about graduate school, but you don't need to do that either." That was the breaking point, where all of our little issues culminated into a major moment where I realized I had lost myself. I had access to new information that I had not yet uncovered when I got engaged quickly, even hastily, after just a handful of months. I had to make a choice: was I going to quit my job, forget graduate school, and find another path for myself? Or would I do the smart thing -- the courageous thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-hundred-and-six.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-hundred-and-six people is, in my case, the number of people to whom you have to break the news. Usually this is done by some swift combination of you, your family, your wedding party, and your wedding planner, if you have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, if you have already mailed invitations, this is best done at scale by small, discreet, elegant printed cards on the "thickest cardstock" in "dove grey" or "black" simple typeface, said my stationer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know, like a funeral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The wedding of Miss _____________
to Mr. _____________
will no longer take place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes, you think this is a complete waste of time, money, and energy and you would rather just do it over Twitter or something equally as inappropriate. Maybe LinkedIn. Feels more professional.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Just about three weeks after I called the wedding off -- minus one glittering engagement ring and 11.5 pounds (what I like to call the "post-breakup party favor") -- a girlfriend pulled me aside at an impossibly chic book party we were attending uptown. She told me quietly, almost conspiratorially: "When I called my wedding off, my mother was so mortified that she made me sit at the dining room table with her and hand-address apology notes to each and every guest. We did 450 of them."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, with an almost-shocking matter-of-factness, she plucked a smoked salmon puff off of a silver tray, popped it in her mouth, and nonchalantly chirped: "But that was my second broken engagement. For the first one, we did those, um, the card things. Really thick cardstock."&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eleven months is the amount of time that it took me to sit down and put my experience into words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am finally doing this because when I called my wedding off I found exactly zero thoughtful, candid, honest, heart wrenching, emotional, relatable, or otherwise simply practical pieces, books, or personal accounts of other women who had done the same. I am not sure if this is because most people just move on and try to forget it ever happened, or if they are scarred by the experience, or if they just don't really feel like rehashing it. I know I would have appreciated something, though. Somebody -- anybody -- who had gone through this who wanted to share her story to help another struggling girl who wasn't sure if things would work themselves out in the end.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
This is not a "How to Figure Out if you are Engaged to the Wrong Person and When to Call It Off" guide -- and to be clear, that is not what I was looking for when I scoured the Internet for anything remotely applicable to my situation. Life is complicated. Relationships are tricky, personal, and distinctly individual. I am in absolutely no place to advise anybody else on whether or not his or her upcoming marriage is doomed for failure. I am just a normal girl, who fell in love, and everything was perfect -- and then, suddenly, it wasn't.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
All I wanted to know after calling off my wedding was that somebody else went through my same experience. To know that somebody else endured all of the horrified "I'm SO sorry" texts, emails, phone calls, instant messages, and in-person run-ins -- when, really, the broken engagement was something to be celebrated. It was an event that was all-at-once smart, responsible, and mature.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
I am not here to tell you whether or not you should call off your wedding. I don't have a checklist to help you quantify or second-guess. Not my place, not my message. This is a big decision -- and one that you have to make based on your own individual situation. My message is less about your relationship and more about you and what you should know.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
If you are reading this and you are thinking about calling off your wedding, I hope that you are able to make the right decision for yourself -- and for nobody else. Not your partner. Not his or her family. Not for your parents -- but for you.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And if you are reading this and have already called off your wedding, you need to know that everything will be okay. It probably does not feel like it today, and it may not even feel like it tomorrow, or a week from now, or six months from now. You will hurt. You will feel painfully lonely. You might feel humiliated. You may even experience momentary regret or remorse for the decision.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
And then -- one day -- you won't. Everybody will get over it. People will forget. You will forget.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Because, like John Lennon said, "everything will be okay in the end. If it's not okay, then it's not the end."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, it is just the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057012/thumbs/s-BROKEN-ENGAGEMENT-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Ann Margaret Carrozza: 4 Legal Issues To Consider Before Marrying Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-margaret-carrozza/second-marriage-estate-planning-in-a-second_b_2956022.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2956022</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T10:09:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T10:26:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Love may be lovelier -- but it is also a whole lot more complicated the second time around. Record numbers of us will, one day, be in a second marriage. The pool of eligible second marriage candidates is vast as a result of both the high divorce rate and increased longevity. But before saying 'I do' (again), there are a few legal issues that merit consideration.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ann Margaret Carrozza</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-margaret-carrozza/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Love may be lovelier -- but it is also a whole lot more complicated the second time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record numbers of us will, one day, be in a second marriage. The pool of eligible second marriage candidates is vast as a result of both the high divorce rate and increased longevity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before saying "I do" (again), there are a few legal issues that merit consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How should the new spouse be provided for in the estate plan? The competing interests here are typically one's adult children and the new spouse. There is an expectation that assets accumulated in the first marriage will, in some measure, inure to the benefit of the children of that marriage. On the other hand, the new spouse may not have sufficient assets to provide for retirement needs in the event that he or she is widowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the compromise solution was to provide that the estate be held 'in trust' for the lifetime benefit of the surviving spouse. During widowhood, the surviving spouse received income from trust assets. Some trusts also provided for distributions of principal, in the discretion of the trustee. Then, upon the survivor's subsequent death, the trust terminated and all remaining assets reverted to the adult children of the first to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right of Election&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The laws of every state seek to prevent a spouse from being totally disinherited. Absent an explicit waiver, a surviving spouse is entitled to the greater of $50,000 or one-third (1/3) of the entire estate.  The only asset not counted for purposes of calculating the elective share is life insurance. Every other asset, whether passing through the will or directly to a named beneficiary, will be counted. For example, if an estate worth $900,000 consists of a 401K of $400,000 and CDs of $500,000 and adult children are the named beneficiaries, the surviving spouse can lay claim to  $300,000 of the assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 1992, the so-called elective share portion must pass outright to the spouse as opposed to being held in a trust. Anyone considering using such a trust to provide for the surviving spouse must now get their written consent ahead of time in the form of a valid pre or post nuptial agreement. This consent is also required if the estate plan contemplates totally disinheriting a spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Roof Over One's Head&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In a second marriage situation, the primary residence is commonly titled in one party's name. Thought must be given to the survivor's living arrangements upon death of the owner. The most common (but imperfect) remedy is to grant the non-owner survivor a life estate in the home. Then upon the subsequent death of the survivor, the home will revert to the adult children or other beneficiaries of the first to die. This approach makes intuitive sense but can sometimes have unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A life estate for the survivor quite literally means that he or she is the de facto owner until death. The family would, therefore, be unable to sell the home or otherwise use it regardless of whether the survivor gets remarried, moves away or winds up in a nursing home for years. To add insult to injury, the nursing home would be entitled to require that the property be rented out and the income used toward the survivor's care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better solution would be to grant the surviving spouse a 'Right of Occupancy' in the house. With this, we can specify events in addition to death which will have the legal effect of terminating the survivor's right to reside in the property. For example, the right of occupancy might terminate upon the earlier of the survivor's death, remarriage, voluntary vacatur, or absence from the property for a continuous period in excess of four months. This specificity will prevent the adult children from being stuck with an asset that they can't sell or otherwise use. It is also critically important that the Will or Trust creating the right of occupancy clearly spell out who is responsible for what expenses.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prenuptial Agreements&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is estimated that the divorce rate for second marriages exceeds 60 percent. Hammering out the legal and financial issues ahead of time can prevent much costly legal wrangling later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond establishing who gets what in the event of death or divorce, prenuptial agreements are increasingly being used to address financial issues within the marriage. These so-called 'lifestyle clauses' can be used to establish spending priorities and parameters. For example, the parties may wish to place limits on financial assistance given to their respective family members. Record numbers of baby boomers are caught in the squeeze between helping their adult kids who are unemployed or under employed and helping aging parents cover the cost of long term care. While generosity is admirable, if one party goes into debt to pay for a daughter's lavish wedding, this will certainly have an impact on both spouses.  It is better to address this issue on the front end . The same goes for a party who signs a personal guarantee at his mother's nursing home. This action has the potential to compromise both parties' retirement security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postnuptial Agreements&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For generations, married couples having problems had only two choices: Grin and bear it, or leave. This is because legal contracts between married people were not recognized under common law. Today, married couples in 46 states now have the right to contract with each other in order to resolve or prevent a whole host of problems. Increased legal acceptance has resulted in matrimonial attorneys everywhere drafting more of these agreements than ever before.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postnuptial agreements can be used to settle a wide variety of marital disputes. Financial disagreements, housekeeping issues and vacation selections are common components of these contracts. Some couples even ask to include a 'sex schedule' within the document. Though it is doubtful that this schedule would be legally enforceable in a court of law, (thank goodness) it may serve to clarify expectations between the parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postnuptial agreements are also useful in times of marital crisis. When the cheating spouse is groveling for a second chance, the aggrieved party can now ask for more than just his or her word that it won't happen again. Monetary penalties for future indiscretions are commonly incorporated into the document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 'post-nup' is also gaining ground amongst happily married couples in first marriages. In the context of estate planning, everyone should give some thought to the (depressing prospect) of the surviving spouse remarrying. Where should the couple's assets go upon the subsequent demise of the remarried spouse? The inevitable response is "to our children". Without an agreement in place, however, the new spouse will have elective share rights (discussed above) to the estate. Moreover, even if the widow or widower doesn't remarry, he or she may develop a cognitive impairment and be prey to con-artists as well as an assortment of financial liabilities. The post-nup can require the surviving spouse to adhere to the estate plan originally agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1056853/thumbs/s-SECOND-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
