<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lisa Arends: The Most Valuable Lesson The End Of My Marriage Taught Me</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-arends/10-lessons-i-learned-from_b_2926625.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2926625</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T05:47:03Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T05:46:38Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I found myself suddenly single at the age of 32 after being betrayed by my best friend and</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa Arends</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-arends/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Often, the lessons we need most are the ones we are most resistant to. I never wanted to be divorced. In fact, losing my husband, through any means, was my greatest fear in life. So, when I found myself suddenly single at the age of 32 after being betrayed by my best friend and partner of 16 years, I was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best lessons can often be found when we are facing unanticipated change and loss. It is a window where we are lost and searching, broken and vulnerable, wanting and open. It is a time when the ego has been forcefully stripped away and we are able to face those challenging lessons that we may usually avoid. In those moments, we learn who we really are and what we are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are some of the lessons I learned on the heels of my divorce:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
1) When gratitude is your wrapping paper, everything is a gift.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You cannot always change your circumstances, but you can always change your attitude. I wasted time after the divorce being angry and playing victim. Slowly, ever so slowly, I began to soften and to look at the bigger picture. The divorce and its associated trauma happened; I could not alter that reality. I could, however, choose to change my reaction. I have begun to practice radical gratitude -- being thankful for the man who deceived and abandoned me. I began by writing a list of ten reasons I am thankful for him and I continue to write a note of gratitude every time I make a payment on the debt he left behind. The situation hasn't changed, but I now can view my divorce as a springboard for better things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Happiness is my choice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I used to tell my husband, "You make me happy." I meant those words as a compliment, an endearment. I wanted him to know how much he meant to me. When he left, I realized that if he truly made me happy, then he also took my potential well-being out the door with him. I also began to see the unfair burden I placed on him by making him the keeper of my happiness. That was not fair to him or to me. I have learned to take responsibility for my own happiness. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
3) The past doesn't stay buried.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My ex husband came from an alcoholic family. He denounced their dynamics and always said that his biggest fear was turning into his father. I took his word for it; I thought he was safe from their destructive patterns since he was aware of them and wanted to make different choices. I underestimated the power of the past. If there is one thing that alcoholic families excel at, it's keeping secrets. Apparently those lessons of silence and secrets were too embedded for him to overcome. The skill set was just waiting in the wings until the right moment came along. When he began to struggle during our marriage (with money, alcohol, depression, employment... who knows?), his reflexes kicked in and he covered it up. The past is like a vampire -- if you try to defeat it solely by burying it, it will come back to bite you.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4) "Knew" is not the same as "know."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I met my husband when I was just 16. I knew his family. I knew everything from the name of his elementary school to his biggest fears and wishes in life. I thought I knew him. I could describe every little nuance of my husband with the utmost confidence. It was misplaced confidence. I didn't realize that the man I knew was no longer the man in front of me. We are all fluid, changing with age and environment. Getting to know someone never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Work avoidance goes both ways.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have always had a tendency to work. A lot. I always saw that as a positive trait, an asset. It was only more recently that I realized that my drive to work was often out of a fear of what I would see if I slowed down. The divorce acted like a highlighter in my life, illuminating areas that I used to avoid through work. I learned to slow down and to trust in my ability to face the present. I now breathe through discomfort rather than try to hide from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) The body often knows more than the mind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For the last couple years of my marriage, I seemed to catch every cold that came through the school where I worked. I had trouble sleeping, often waking in the middle of the night. I sensed a tension coursing through my body -- a low-level, yet ever-present anxiety. Since there were no outward signs of discord in my marriage, I assumed the tension was due to a difficult time at work. I was shocked to realize, after I recovered from the initial trauma of the abandonment, that my body was more relaxed than it had been in years. I now listen to my body's messages even when they seem unfounded. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
7) Wellness is not measured in hours at the gym.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I used to think I was well. I ate a healthy diet, exercised daily and even managed to do a little yoga once in a while. I used to think I was well, but I wasn't. After the divorce, I had to rebuild my health and this time, I had a much more holistic and balanced approach. I became a math teacher after struggling with the material myself as a child. I was drawn to wellness coaching for a similar reason. It allows me to utilize my teaching skills along with what I have learned about wellness from a balanced standpoint after my own journey. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
8) There is a difference between trust and complacency.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My ex husband gained my trust over many years. He held his word and voiced his thoughts. I trusted him completely. I trusted him so much that I became complacent. I assumed the trust would remain and that he would continue to be honest and faithful. I assumed wrong. I have learned to trust again (through the help of my dog!) but I will never again become complacent. My eyes now remain wide open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) Life is not a waiting room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I used to be an expert at delaying life. I would prioritize work and promise myself a break in some imagined future. I would squirrel away money, imaging it being saved for some mythical future. When the divorce washed away my life in one destructive wave, I realized that I was waiting rather than living. I still work hard and I'm still frugal by nature, but I no longer put life off for the future. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
10) Holding is out of love;clinging is out of fear.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I never would have described myself as clingy with my ex -- I was independent (often too much so), not jealous and was frequently apart from him for long periods while he traveled. It was only afterwards that I saw how clingy I truly was. With clinging, you are desperately attached to an outcome, grasping out of fear. I was clinging in a way and it was holding me still, static, unable to move. I now have healthy desires and passions which encourage investment in the now and the goal, but not in the outcomes that are out of my control. I realize that this describes my current relationship. I am so much more relaxed about the "outcome." Facing my fears has had a way of diminishing them. I am no less committed to the current relationship, no less in love. But it feels different. I'm not grasping. I'm holding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some of these lessons, I am now doing master's level work. With others, I am repeating the introductory course. Either way, it is okay. The point is not to get an "A," rather the intention is to be open to new lessons and to persevere through even the most difficult tutorials. I just hope I don't have to endure such a harsh teacher again!&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063124/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-LESSONS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Emma Johnson: What To Say To A Divorcing Friend</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-johnson/should-you-always-say-im-_b_2935944.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935944</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T05:38:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T05:39:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Over the past few years, I've had interesting discussions around the question, "Should you say 'I'm sorry,' when someone reveals they're getting divorced?"</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emma Johnson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-johnson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;My son Lucas is going through a phase when he misses his dad a lot. When he stubs his toe, or is trying to unwind at bedtime, he calls out, "I want Daaadddy." There is an uncomplicated and raw sorrow there that is different than the other many times he cries in a given day. I imagine during these moments he thinks to the comfort of his dad, who lives a mile away, and who he sees twice each week. Maybe when you're barely three, the sadness of not getting a sprinkle cookie bleeds into the sadness of missing a parent. I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know that it is sad, no matter what. Divorce comes with sadness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I've had interesting discussions around the question, "Should you say 'I'm sorry,' when someone reveals they're getting divorced?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some argue that is not an appropriate response because you never know how the announcer feels about the split. If they're thrilled at their new freedom, or blissful at banishing a bad spouse, why would a condolence be in order?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear that argument loud and clear. After all, I've written numerous times that I was surprised to find that I was am &lt;a href="http://www.wealthysinglemommy.com/what-if-your-failed-marriage-was-really-a-success/" target="_hplink"&gt;much happier outside of my own marriage&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the wrenching heartache, destroyed dreams and turning my life topsy-turvy, the net result of my divorce has been positive, I've felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I fall in favor of offering up a polite, "I'm sorry," as a pat response when someone reveals their relationship is over. After all, "I'm sorry" is always appropriate upon learning of the end of a life. It is the prerogative of the mourner to say, "It was a blessing -- they were suffering," or "It was quick, and we are grateful we can all move on now." There is nearly always at least a note of sadness when someone dies. Custom and sensitivity call for condolences, no matter the feelings or assumptions of the person hearing the news. The same holds true for the end of a relationship. Even if the final result was positive, pain and grief are always part of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking through this issue last night as the kids were getting ready for bedtime. "Look," I said to Lucas we stood in the kitchen, arguing over whether he had to eat the last bite of his banana. "Look at all the snow outside!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked him up so he could see the large clumps of flakes fall down to coat the street below. We pointed at the birds in the tree outside that window, and wondered whether they were cold, or if their fluffed-up feathers kept them warm. Something in this sleepy moment, maybe feeling vulnerable in the weather or sensing a call for a cozy embrace, Lucas cried out as he does. Cried out for his Daddy. His dad moved out before Lucas was born, but who hasn't felt that dull ache of missing someone you love?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I held Lucas to me and he quickly nuzzled his head into my neck. Tristian Prettyman's &lt;br /&gt;
"All I Want is You" came on the radio, and as I swayed to the sweet melody and silly lyrics, I could see Lucas and my reflection in the window. Behind us was the gold glow of our warm apartment. I had one of the moments I sometimes have -- moments when I well up with the feeling of being a proud and confident mother lion, presiding over the safe den I've created for my babies. But in that image of that strong mom was also my hurt child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm sorry," I said. Lucas let his body hang heavy in my arms as I swayed and swayed. "I'm sorry."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063121/thumbs/s-IM-SORRY-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>My Proudest Moment As A Stepparent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/stepparents_n_2981073.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981073</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T22:32:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T23:20:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Every stepparent remembers the moment they finally earned their stepkids' seal of approval. It's a meaningful moment -- as any stepparent can tell you, a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Every stepparent remembers the moment they finally earned their stepkids' seal of approval. It's a meaningful moment -- as any stepparent can tell you, a stepchild's trust can be hard won, sometimes taking years and years to gain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1b8qa9/as_a_stepdad_of_3_this_was_my_proudest_moment_to/" target="_hplink"&gt;Redditor Jedi_Hog shared his shiningest moment&lt;/a&gt; as a stepparent -- in meme form. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-29-ScreenShot20130329at3.02.26PM.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-29-ScreenShot20130329at3.02.26PM.png" width="398" height="402" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.quickmeme.com/meme/3tkwcq/" target="_hplink"&gt;quickmeme.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stepdad's success story won over Reddit, with fellow stepparents and stepkids weighing in with their personal stories in the comments. We were especially touched by Redditor MorganaLeFaye's &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1b8qa9/as_a_stepdad_of_3_this_was_my_proudest_moment_to/" target="_hplink"&gt;sweet tribute to her stepdad: &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My dad is the man who raised me. I met him when I was four.

&lt;p&gt;He's the one that put the band-aids on skinned knees and went to my school plays even though he really didn't want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's the one who got very awkward whenever I would cry because he really didn't know what to do to fix me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's the man who went to McDonalds or Taco Bell when my mom was working late and he was put in charge of "making us a healthy, well balanced dinner."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the man who hooked the stereo speakers up to the TV when I was very young and turned our living room into a movie theater so we could watch Jurassic Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the man who walked me down the aisle and cried on my wedding day as he told me how beautiful I looked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He may not be genetically related to me, but he is in every sense my father.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to extend the love by asking our readers to share their proudest moments as stepparents. Click through the slideshow below for some of our favorite responses, then head to the comments and tell us about your best stepparent stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289220--HH&gt;`&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063084/thumbs/s-STEPPARENTING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>5 Ways Divorce Will Impact Your Finances</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/five-ways-divorce-will-im_n_2980949.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980949</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:35:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:35:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Divorce can hurt the pocketbook in ways that some people don’t expect. Lost income, child support, spousal support all hurt. But there are other ways...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.latimes.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Divorce can hurt the pocketbook in ways that some people don’t expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost income, child support, spousal support all hurt. But there are other ways that divorce affects finances, said Samantha Fraelich, vice president of Bernard R. Wolfe &amp; Associates, a Chevy Chase, Md., wealth management firm. Here are five of them:&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062759/thumbs/s-FINANCES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: One Realtor's Creative Alternative To Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/funny-billboard-_n_2980138.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980138</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:52:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T19:19:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Why divorce when you can just get a bigger house? That's the logic Toronto real estate agent Chris Clarke put to use on a billboard...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Why divorce when you can just get a bigger house? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the logic Toronto real estate agent Chris Clarke put to use on a billboard &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/1b4z8a/realtor_logic/" target="_hplink"&gt;posted on Reddit by ShiftyBizniss&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/CgsMVJa"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CgsMVJa.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem solved, unhappily married couples! (And just in case the realtor's logic is lost on you, here's &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/1b4z8a/realtor_logic/c93yyk2" target="_hplink"&gt;Redditor TryptamineTea's&lt;/a&gt; helpful explainer: "Buy a bigger house, and you won't have to deal with each other.") &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062634/thumbs/s-CGSMVJA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>5 Bad Boyz Who May Or May Not Be Using Charity To Repair Their Image</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/5-bad-boy-celebrities-turned-good_n_2975507.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2975507</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:07:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:20:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It seems like more often than not lately, celebrity bad boys make headlines for the decisions that could land them in the slammer or at...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/eleanor-goldberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It seems like more often than not lately, celebrity bad boys make headlines for the decisions that could land them in the slammer or at the very least, make their moms hang their heads in shame. But even some of the worst offenders know better than to only leave behind a trail of sins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five famous guys below have tarnished images, but are working to get their reputations out of the gutter by putting their money and names behind noteworthy causes, and, of course, pairing the effort with a pic that makes you go "Awww."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRINCE HARRY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="prince harry" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062216/thumbs/o-PRINCE-HARRY-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prince Harry can be a royal pain in the butt. Literally. Last summer, this regal bad boy bore his privates to the world when &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/21/prince-harry-nude-pics-photos_n_1820333.html" target="_blank"&gt;nude photos of him playing strip billiards&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas were leaked. But Will’s little bro has since cleaned up his traveling act. Harry spent time with &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/27/prince-harry-lesotho-charity-photos_n_2772676.html" target="_blank"&gt;disadvantaged African children&lt;/a&gt; in February and is&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/prince-harry-vets-us-trip_n_2947663.html?utm_hp_ref=impact" target="_blank"&gt; planning a trip to the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; to visit vets and Hurricane Sandy victims, all activities that require being fully clothed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHRIS BROWN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="chris brown" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062227/thumbs/o-CHRIS-BROWN-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, Chris Brown apologized, and Rihanna forgave him. But even though he may never get back into public's good graces, the defamed rapper is apparently set on proving he's a changed man. His recently-launched charity, the &lt;a href="https://api.viglink.com/api/click?format=go&amp;key=5b0c3ed66765f886c6984ee1c41b292d&amp;loc=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Ftmp%2F2975507_93.html%3Fpreview%3Dyes&amp;v=1&amp;libid=1364578997291&amp;out=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.huffingtonpost.com%2F2012%2F11%2F05%2Fchris-brown-launches-charity-symphonic-love_n_2078689.html&amp;ref=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Fentry%2F%3Fentry_id%3D2975507&amp;title=Chris%20Brown%2C%20Prince%20Harry%2C%20Other%20Bad%20Boys%20Who%20May%20Or%20May%20Not%20Be%20Using%20Charity%20To%20Repair%20Their%20Image&amp;txt=the%20Symphonic%20Love%20Foundation&amp;jsonp=vglnk_jsonp_13645798136212" target="_hplink"&gt;Symphonic Love Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, and artist Romero Britto joined forces to paint a &lt;a href="https://api.viglink.com/api/click?format=go&amp;key=5b0c3ed66765f886c6984ee1c41b292d&amp;loc=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Ftmp%2F2975507_93.html%3Fpreview%3Dyes&amp;v=1&amp;libid=1364578997291&amp;out=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.huffingtonpost.com%2F2013%2F03%2F28%2Fchris-brown-symphonic-love-foundation-graffiti-best-buddies_n_2970935.html&amp;ref=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Fentry%2F%3Fentry_id%3D2975507&amp;title=Chris%20Brown%2C%20Prince%20Harry%2C%20Other%20Bad%20Boys%20Who%20May%20Or%20May%20Not%20Be%20Using%20Charity%20To%20Repair%20Their%20Image&amp;txt=paint%20a%20graffiti%20mural%20&amp;jsonp=vglnk_jsonp_13645798264373" target="_hplink"&gt;graffiti mural&lt;/a&gt; to raise funds for Best Buddies International, an organization that supports people with developmental disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHARLIE SHEEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="charlie sheen" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062243/thumbs/o-CHARLIE-SHEEN-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/01/19/charlie-sheen-spends-26k-on-prostitutes-in-cocaine-filled-weekend_n_810821.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Charlie Sheen&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps best known for dropping thousands on prostitutes and cocaine, but the troubled star has also been throwing money at worthy causes as of late. The former “Two and a Half Men” star gave &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/11/charlie-sheen-jasmine-faulk_n_2277886.html" target="_hplink"&gt;$75,000 to a young girl with cancer &lt;/a&gt;in December, pledged $50,000 last summer to the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/06/charlie-sheen-cincinnati-reds-fund_n_1746600.html " target="_hplink"&gt;Cincinnati Reds Fund,&lt;/a&gt; which helps improve the lives of youth in the community, and in February, he &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/15/charlie-sheen-therapy-dog_n_2694278.html" target="_hplink"&gt;bought a therapy dog for a girl who was injured&lt;/a&gt; in a freak amusement park accident. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KOBE BRYANT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="kobe bryant" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062301/thumbs/o-KOBE-BRYANT-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 2003 sexual assault charge marred his reputation, but &lt;a href="http://videos.huffingtonpost.com/entertainment/kobe-bryant-says-that-the-rape-charge-made-him-a-better-person-517420405" target="_hplink"&gt;Kobe Bryant &lt;/a&gt;says that the experience has made him a “better person.” Part of his image makeover included opening the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/06/07/kobe-bryant-announces-new_n_872761.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kobe and Vanessa Bryant Family Foundation,&lt;/a&gt; a nonprofit that’s working to end youth homelessness in Los Angeles. The Lakers star also turned an injury into a positive moment when he &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/09/kobe-bryants-mask-charity_n_1502593.html" target="_hplink"&gt;auctioned off the facemask&lt;/a&gt; he wore after breaking his nose to raise funds for his charity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAY LEWIS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="ray lewis" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062312/thumbs/o-RAY-LEWIS-570.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What murder charge? &lt;a href="http://baltimore.cbslocal.com/2013/01/24/5-common-misconceptions-about-ray-lewis-murder-trial/" target="_hplink"&gt;Ray Lewis &lt;/a&gt;was charged, and eventually acquitted, in the 2000 deaths of two Atlanta men, but the public seems to have long forgiven the Super Bowl champion. He helped gain the favor of fans by getting involved with people in need in Baltimore. He launched the&lt;a href="http://rlff.org/mainhome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Ray Lewis Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, a nonprofit that helps disadvantaged youth and families and the famed linebacker &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/nfl/playoffs/2012/story/_/id/8803657/ray-lewis-unquestioned-hall-fame-credentials-legacy-complicated" target="_hplink"&gt;distributes school supplies &lt;/a&gt;to needy kids and provides toys for kids at Christmas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do you think? Do these bad boyz have their hearts in the right place now or are these simply charity stunts? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062481/thumbs/s-CHRIS-BROWN-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Blended Family Friday: Meet Mimi and Stu's Family</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/blended-family-friday_n_2975161.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2975161</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:04:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T18:04:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As part of our Blended Family Friday series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of our &lt;strong&gt;Blended Family Friday&lt;/strong&gt; series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together. Our hope is that by telling their stories, we'll bring you closer to blended family bliss in your own life!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we'd like you to meet Mimi and Stu and their four kids. The unique thing about this blended family? Their incredible (and enviable!) relationship with their former spouses. Read on for their inspiring story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi, Mimi! Please introduce us to your family. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My husband Stu and I have been married almost eight years. Between us we have four children. Our oldest is Austin. He's 18 and nearly ready to leave the nest.  He will be swimming for the University of Tennessee in the fall. Next is Camille. She will be 17 in April. The "little girls" are 12. Phoebe and Ansley are twins through marriage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the biggest challenges of blended family life? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Blending a family is never easy and the beginning was rough. The biggest challenge was for the children to suddenly have to share "their parent" with the other kids. Stu and I worked very hard to show love and affection to all four of them. We ate dinner together every night. We played a lot of wiffle ball games together, had family movie nights and went to all of the kids' events as a family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the best thing about being part of a blended family? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When Stu and I came together, we did not just put our kids under one roof, we reached out to our ex spouses. We included Blaire (Stu's ex-wife) and Steve (my ex-husband) in our family. The former spouses are a huge part of our lives! We invite them to everything: Christmas, Thanksgiving, birthdays, plays, sporting events, anything they could make. Stu and I have the children most of the time, but Stu's ex-wife lives near us and is often with us, too. She even spends the night on Christmas Eve so that she can see the kids get their Santa gifts. I think the best thing about our blended family is that we have four adults working together to support each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes you proudest of your family?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our kids refer to Stu, Steve, Blaire and me as "the parents" and ask any of us for advice in times of need. I am so proud of all of us. We have put the children first and have created a real family. In fact, Stu and I have to travel for work soon and Steve will be staying at our house taking care of all four kids! We all work together and our children are thriving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice do you have for other blended families who feel like a peaceful dynamic is out of reach?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My advice to anyone working on blending a family is to always put the child first. Never, ever, say a negative word about your ex in front of your child. Be flexible and patient. It takes time. Always remember when the kids are acting out it's because they are hurting. Take a deep breath and think of a way to lift them up. Be kind to your former spouse.  Try to include them in your child's life. Your children deserve loving adults in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click through the slideshow the see photos of Mimi and Stu's family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you'd like your own family to be featured on a Blended Family Friday, please email us at  &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt;. We're looking forward to hearing your story! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289095--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061525/thumbs/s-BLENDED-FAMILY-FRIDAY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jennifer Gardella: Why Divorce Is Like The Shawshank Tunnel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-gardella/post_4550_b_2935681.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935681</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:01:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T18:01:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Gold seal, signed papers, judge's gavel -- no matter how your divorced is finalized, the official ends marks the start of your post divorce life.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jennifer Gardella</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-gardella/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Gold seal, signed papers, judge's gavel -- no matter how your divorced is finalized, the official ends marks the start of your post divorce life. For many, this time resembles the crawl through the infamous Shawshank Tunnel. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
You may know the scene from the movie: Andy Dufresne escapes from prison through a sewage pipe and crawls through 500 yards "smelling foulness I can't even imagine." This is very similar to the post-divorce proverbial tunnel. For you, it may feel dark, it may actually smell foul, you may wonder what will happen next, and often ask "when will it ever end?"&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Everyone who enters the post-divorce tunnel has a very different set of tasks to complete.  You may need to find a place to live, a new job and secure health insurance. All sorts of accounts will need to be separated and possessions divided. Your ex could be parading around a new significant other and that requires adjustment. You may be changing your name, opening new financial accounts and learning to cook for one. There may be substantial emotional healing to process and strength to build. There is a lot to be dealt with in the tunnel. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a divorced mom of three daughters, I am often called upon by &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-gardella/your-divorce-welcome-wago_b_2451272.html" target="_hplink"&gt;friends and strangers for my best advice on how to get through their divorce&lt;/a&gt;.  And while I have helped them to see that all will be ok, I actually haven't been able give them advice on how to get through the tunnel, because until recently, I never experienced it. When I came out of my marriage, I jumped into two back-to-back relationships, each shielding me from the tunnel experience. I was not required to find full-time employment because I was working on my doctorate, and then worked for my most recent ex. I didn't have to find a place to live because &lt;a href="http://njdivorcedmoms.blogspot.com/2013/02/why-my-children-nest.html" target="_hplink"&gt;when I wasn't with my kids,&lt;/a&gt; I stayed with my boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in January, my relationship ended and I found myself about to enter the Shawshank tunnel for the first time. I was devastated. It wasn't the end of the relationship that caused me pain, the end was a relief. Rather, it was a feeling of "how did I get to a point where at 43 years old, I am homeless for half of each month, unemployed (since I had worked for my ex), still have an incomplete dissertation, too much weight on my hips, and a high BMI?" Just as Andy was desperate to get into that tunnel and start crawling to a better life, well, so was I. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started to craw,l I was shocked to realize a newfound abundance of emotional energy.  Previously, every last bit of that energy had been dumped into a relationship that hadn't been working. With that emotional space free, I found great peace, and saw nothing but opportunities. In fact, I was happier than ever, even though I was crawling through proverbial sewage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, there is a beautiful simplicity to the tunnel. Your choices are limited to standing still, going forward or moving backward.  I had absolutely no desire to stay stuck or go backward, so forward I moved. Some steps have been big, some have been messy, and others I have taken on blind faith. I just keep moving, focused and determined.  Self doubt lives in the sewage of the tunnel and I suffocate it when it surfaces. My inner core strength and close circle of friends act as continual reminders that I am strong enough, talented enough, and resourceful enough to make it out to the other side. Armed with my newfound feeling of inner peace, my resolve is stronger than ever. I have fully embraced the process of tunnel crawling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tunnel allows great focus because you just can't stand up and look around, after all, you are in a tiny tunnel; if you stand up you'll hit your head. Also, there aren't many distractions in the tunnel, so I remain focused. Well that's not entirely true, I have allowed one distraction in -- hey, a girl can have a little fun, can't she?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have I accomplished so far while crawling in the tunnel?  I have found a very peaceful space to stay with two amazing friends when I am not with my children. These fabulous women have welcomed me into their families and homes and just as important as the roof over my head is the friendship they provide. I have also finished my dissertation which I will defend in early April and I am contracted to teach during the summer. When I first jumped into the tunnel, I made a commitment to eating healthier and exercising more. I've lost 15 pounds, fit into my skinny jeans (filled out better than ever due to endless squats) and my BMI is normal. Oh, and did I mention I'm launching a business? Not too bad for eight weeks.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
But while many pieces have come together, I'm still in the tunnel.  Next up is getting my professional life in order. My business launches in late April and the job search continues. My amazing business coach &lt;a href="http://www.marcuspadulchick.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Marcus Padulchick&lt;/a&gt; has helped me realize that I should go in search of the right job, not just any job.  I have built a diverse skill set and impressive credentials over the last 20 years and the right job will come along. I thank Marcus in my heart every day for his sage advice. I'm committed to the process of the tunnel and want the process to work itself out in the right time.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This crawling that I have done has brought fullness to my life I never anticipated. Opportunities, ideas, and most importantly, people have found their way to my path and are extraordinary additions. This stage of putting together the foundation of my post-divorce life is exciting.  While I am enjoying my time in the tunnel, I am looking forward to crawling out -- but I'm just not there yet.  A little more time in the tunnel will do me some good.  And at the end of the tunnel is when the building work begins. Building on all of this excitement, finding the right person to share it with, and then the beginning of my journey to my Zihuatanejo.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Pregnant Man's' Divorce Rejected</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/pregnant-man-judge-reject_n_2979968.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2979968</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T17:33:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T19:13:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>PHOENIX &amp;mdash; An Arizona judge on Friday refused to grant a divorce for a transgender Arizona man who gave birth to three children after beginning...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;PHOENIX &amp;mdash; An Arizona judge on Friday refused to grant a divorce for a transgender Arizona man who gave birth to three children after beginning to change his sex from female.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maricopa County Family Court Judge Douglas Gerlach ruled that Arizona's ban on same-sex marriages prevents Thomas Beatie's 9-year union from being recognized as valid.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Thomas Beatie was born a woman and later underwent a double-mastectomy, and began testosterone hormone therapy and psychological treatment to become a man, but he retained female reproductive organs and gave birth to three children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerlach said he had no jurisdiction to approve a divorce because there's insufficient evidence that Beatie was a man when he married Nancy Beatie in Hawaii. He said the Beaties never provided records to fully explain what Thomas Beatie actually had done and not done to become a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The decision here is not based on the conclusion that this case involves a same-sex marriage merely because one of the parties is a transsexual male, but instead, the decision is compelled by the fact that the parties failed to prove that (Thomas Beatie) was a transsexual male when they were issued their marriage license," he wrote in Friday's ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for Beatie, Ryan Gordon, said the judge's comments came as a shock and that Beatie plans to appeal the ruling. He said Beatie legally was married as a man and never was required to disclose that he retained female reproductive organs when applying for and being granted a new birth certificate in Hawaii as a man. He said Beatie halted testosterone treatments so that he could give birth to his children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's unfortunate that the judge out here doesn't recognize marriage in another state," Gordon said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beatie is eager to end his marriage, but the couple's divorce plans stalled last summer when Gerlach said he was unable to find legal authority defining a man as someone who can give birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerlach's ruling didn't address whether Arizona law allows a person who was born female to marry another female after undergoing a sex change operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A separate ruling issued Friday by Gerlach sets guidelines on how the Beaties will co-parent their three children and grants them joint authority in making legal decisions. Thomas Beatie is required to pay nearly $240 a month to Nancy Beatie for child support, but she won't get alimony because the marriage was declared invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nancy Beatie's attorney, David Higgins, praised Gerlach for the thoroughness of the decision on the marriage, although it wasn't the one she had hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He still sees a same-sex marriage, but he gave us all the rulings that we're asking for as far as the children," Higgins said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Center for Lesbian Rights, which isn't involved in the Beatie divorce case, has said courts have declared marriages involving a transgender person invalid in a handful of cases across the country, but that those cases had different factual and legal issues than those in the Beatie case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Beatie, known as "The Pregnant Man," was born Tracy Lehuanani Lagondino in Oahu, Hawaii. He began testosterone treatments in 1997 and underwent double mastectomy and chest reconstruction surgery in 2002. He changed his Hawaii driver's license to say he was a man and had a Hawaiian court approve his name change to Thomas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerlach's ruling noted that Thomas Beatie halted the testosterone treatments and that he didn't provide documentation for any additional non-surgical efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Beatie married his partner Nancy in early 2003 in Honolulu and became pregnant because Nancy was unable to have children. Thomas Beatie conceived with donated sperm and gave birth to children who are now 4, 3 and 2 years old. The couple eventually moved to Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beatie has garnered a range of media attention, making the rounds on talk shows such as Larry King and Oprah Winfrey and winning a spot on Barbara Walters' list of "10 Most Fascinating People" in 2008, alongside President Barack Obama, conservative commentator Rush Limbaugh and swimmer Michael Phelps. He also published a book, "Labor Of Love: The Story of One Man's Extraordinary Pregnancy," the cover displaying an image of a shirtless Thomas sporting facial hair and holding a hand over his bare pregnant belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fonseca reported from Flagstaff, Ariz. Associated Press Writer Jacques Billeaud in Phoenix contributed to this report.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062436/thumbs/s-PREGNANT-MAN-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Allison Pescosolido, M.A: How To Keep Bad Communication From Ruining Your Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/allison-pescosolido-ma/the-dogs-and-cats-of-rela_b_2967168.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2967168</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T16:12:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T16:34:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Fighting like cats and dogs can be one sign that a couple may be heading towards divorce.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Allison Pescosolido, M.A</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/allison-pescosolido-ma/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Fighting like cats and dogs can be one sign that a couple may be heading towards divorce.  Often, couples get caught in the trap of over analyzing, misinterpreting and building resentments because of simple errors in communication. These errors lead to conflict, resentments and oftentimes contentious divorce. Men and women often think differently, whether the cause is the brain or behavior. It is no wonder that within our conflicting patterns of communication the wires get crossed. When communication begins to break down, there is a simple solution: stop searching for hidden meaning.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Relationships are fraught with language, and frequent breakdowns in communication can cause major challenges. There are words we use to directly communicate, the non-verbal cues of facial expressions and body language and even the short-hand of shared experience that couples use when in private. Language, however, has its issues. In any mode of communication, there is a disparity between the intent of the message and perceived meaning of the message. This can cause problems, as we try to find meaning in words or actions that may essentially be meaningless. Within a relationship, this search for meaning can be dangerous. Misunderstanding and manufacturing intent for a perceived message lays the foundation for eventual divorce. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Think of a dog and a cat. Their language, in fact their brains, read meanings in completely different ways. When &lt;a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/canine-corner/201112/what-dog-s-tail-wags-really-mean-some-new-scientific-data" target="_hplink"&gt;a dog wags its tail&lt;/a&gt; it is saying, "I'm happy; let's play." When &lt;a href="http://www.tailsinc.com/2012/09/understanding-cat-tail-language/" target="_hplink"&gt;a cat's tail flicks its tail&lt;/a&gt; it is saying, "I'm hunting; I'm about to pounce." You can see the language barrier clearly when observing pets interacting. When a dog approaches a cat, tail waving excitedly, the cat will shy away. The cat perceives the dog's actions as a threat. The same problem occurs in reverse. A dog will approach a cat with a waving tail thinking that the cat wants to play -- until it gets a swat in the face.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
We're the same way when interpreting the meaning of language, whether it's words, expressions or tones. Like the dog and cat, we need to keep from over-analyzing meaning behind the actions and words of others. When your significant other comes home from work with an attitude, it probably isn't you they are angry with. Or when your partner forgets that dinner with the Jones's is tonight, that doesn't mean they weren't listening. They probably have other things on their mind and trust you to keep them on track.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
If your spouse doesn't directly tell you something is wrong, don't assume that his or her actions are about you. One of the hardest things for people to do in relationships is to stop the cycle of interpreting meaning where there is no meaning. Here are three questions you can ask yourself before getting upset.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;•   Is this a one time occurrence or part of a pattern?&lt;/strong&gt; If its one time, drop it. Don't waste your energy on a fluke. If its a pattern that upsets you, address it with kindness and provide possible solutions. Keep in mind that the solution may involve changing your behavior. For example, if your spouse is always upset coming home from work, give them a little space. Leaving them alone for an hour will give them time to adjust from a rough day or long commute.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;•   Am I over-reading?&lt;/strong&gt; Like the dog and cat, we put meaning to actions and words. If your spouse says, "I'm tired; can I skip the party tonight?" they are probably just tired. They are not avoiding you or skipping your friends or family. Let them rest and feel comfortable going out on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•&lt;strong&gt;   Am I communicating clearly?&lt;/strong&gt; Are you wagging your tail and not getting the response you want? This could be a sign that your partner doesn't understand the language you are using. Instead of attempting subtlety, be clear with your intentions and actions. Facial expressions and body language might not be read correctly. If you don't directly state your feelings, he won't know them.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
A healthy relationship involves communication. But that communication needs to be clear and understandable. We also need to stop over analyzing our relationships. Don't interpret all of your spouses actions as a message to you. They aren't. Your spouse feels and sees the world through their own filters. If they want you to get a message, they will explicitly tell you. Relax into your relationship. That's one key to happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061587/thumbs/s-COMMUNICATION-PROBLEM-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Mom &amp; Dad's Fights Can Negatively Affect Kids' Brains</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/fighting-in-front-of-kids_n_2979031.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2979031</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T15:31:52Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T15:32:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>By: Stephanie Pappas, LiveScience Senior Writer Published: 03/29/2013 07:14 AM EDT on LiveScience Arguments between Mom and Dad can alter the stress responses of children,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Samakow</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-samakow/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;By: Stephanie Pappas, LiveScience Senior Writer &lt;br /&gt;
Published: 03/29/2013 07:14 AM EDT on LiveScience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Arguments between Mom and Dad can alter the stress responses of children, new research finds, possibly resulting in kids who lag behind their peers in problem solving.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The study, released today (March 28) in the journal Child Development, followed second- and third-graders for three years, asking them about their &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/15624-conflict-levels-remain-marriage.html"&gt;parents' fights&lt;/a&gt; and measuring changes in the kids' ability to deal with stress over time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;We're trying to understand how environmental stress can shape the development of &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/20820-stress-alters-brain-kids.html"&gt;children's stress response systems&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; study researcher J. Benjamin Hinnant of the Catholic University of America, told LiveScience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;In turn,&amp;quot; Hinnant added, &amp;quot;we want to understand how development of these stress-response systems is related to children's cognitive performance.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Measuring stress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; To do so, Hinnant and his colleagues turned to a measurement called respiratory sinus arrhythmia (RSA). RSA is the pattern that keeps the breath and the heart rate in sync with one another; it's controlled by the parasympathetic &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/22665-nervous-system.html"&gt;nervous system&lt;/a&gt;, the part of the nervous system that's in the driver's seat while people are at rest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; At rest, RSA should be high, indicating that the parasympathetic nervous system is in charge. A high RSA is linked to a lower resting heart rate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; During a moment of stress, however, the calming parasympathetic nervous system becomes less dominant, and the sympathetic nervous system kicks in, triggering the &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/18983-gene-male-stress-response.html"&gt;fight-or-flight response&lt;/a&gt;. Pupils dilate, the sweat glands kick into action, the blood vessels constrict and the heart speeds up. These responses can be useful in the short term — active blood flow and primed sweat glands are beneficial for, say, running from a lion — but over time, repeated activation of this system and suppression of the parasympathetic system can be rough on the body. [&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/20355-5-ways-cells-deal-stress.html"&gt;5 Ways Your Cells Deal With Stress&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;When parasympathetic nervous system activity declines for whatever reason, it can seem to result in a lot of negative health and behavioral and psychological outcomes for people,&amp;quot; Hinnant said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Angry parents, stressed kids&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Hinnant and his colleagues, funded by a National Institutes of Health grant awarded to Mona El-Sheikh of Auburn University, recruited 251 healthy second- and third-graders living in two-parent homes (88 percent of parents were married, and the rest cohabiting). At ages 8, 9 and 10, the kids came into the psychology lab to complete a test of cognitive abilities, including a task in which they had to trace a star using a mirror. During this star-tracing task, researchers used electrocardiograph (ECG) electrodes to measure the children's heart rates, and a strap around their chests to measure how quickly they inhaled and exhaled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The kids also reported how much their &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/6648-divorce-bad-kids.html"&gt;parents fought&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The heart rate and breathing measurements enabled the researchers to calculate RSA, and thus peek into the action of the parasympathetic nervous system. They found that kids who lived in high-conflict homes at age 8 had reduced RSA reactivity to the stressful star-tracing task at age 9 — but only if their RSA was low to begin with.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; What these findings mean, Hinnant said, is that the kids with naturally low RSA seem vulnerable to stress-system burnout when exposed to a chronic stressor like fighting parents. A healthy kid would show a big change in RSA in response to the stressful task, indicating that their stress systems were gearing up for a challenge. These low-RSA, biologically vulnerable children, on the other hand, seemed burned out by the stress in their daily lives and didn't respond appropriately when a moment of acute stress came along. [&lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/17894-10-scientific-parenting-tips.html"&gt;10 Scientific Tips For Raising Happy Kids&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; Hinnant compared the kids' stress systems with overworked muscles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Working out some is good for our body,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;quot;It strengthens your muscles. But if you were made to run on a treadmill for 24 hours, eventually your muscles would tear apart.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Stress and problem solving&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The apparent stress burnout seemed to have real-world consequences. The burnt-out kids developed most slowly in an area called fluid cognitive ability, essentially a measure of their aptitude at solving new problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Eventually they started lagging behind all the other children in terms of their fluid problem-solving skills,&amp;quot; Hinnant said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; The findings help explain how biology and the environment interact to create kids with easily observable problems, he said. Hinnant's colleagues at Auburn University are now working on studies of kids in adolescence, an important time when many troubled teens fall into &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/17938-teens-prone-addiction-mental-illness.html"&gt;substance abuse and delinquency&lt;/a&gt;, he said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Stress can get under your skin and have influences on how your body functions, which then translates to, potentially, problems in other areas of your life as well,&amp;quot; Hinnant said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Follow Stephanie Pappas on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sipappas"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101831066787121148004/posts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Follow us &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LiveScience"&gt;&lt;em&gt;@livescience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/#!/livescience"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/101164570444913213957/posts"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google+&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Original article on &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/28284-marital-conflict-child-development.html"&gt;LiveScience.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/13850-10-facts-parent-teen-brain.html'&gt;10 Facts Every Parent Should Know about Their Teen's Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/14144-parenting-tips-compassion-esteem.html'&gt;5 Ways to Foster Self-Compassion in Your Child&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.livescience.com/14104-happy-marriage-tips.html'&gt;6 Scientific Tips for a Successful Marriage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; Copyright 2013 LiveScience, a TechMediaNetwork company. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. ]]&gt; &lt;/content&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062176/thumbs/s-FIGHTING-IN-FRONT-OF-KIDS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>10 Houseplants For A Restful Home</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/best-houseplants-destress_n_2964013.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2964013</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T12:21:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T23:16:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Did you know bringing the outdoors in can help relieve tension?</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Carolyn Gregoire</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/carolyn-gregoire/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;House plants are the ultimate in functional decorating. Some well-placed greenery can not only brighten a space but also purify the air -- and they're also helpful in creating a more relaxing, restful ambiance in any room. We know that spending time in nature is linked to &lt;a href="http://www.aarp.org/politics-society/advocacy/info-07-2012/health-benefits-of-nature.html" target="_hplink"&gt;reduced stress levels&lt;/a&gt; and relieve tension. In fact, in a &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18329704" target="_hplink"&gt;2008 study&lt;/a&gt;, Dutch researchers found that hospital patients with indoor plants in their rooms reported lower stress levels than patients without them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's why we've rounded up 10 beautiful houseplants that are easy to take care of and effective at increasing oxygen and clearing out toxins for cleaner breathing air. (Some were listed in the top 10 best air-purifiers in a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2009/02/10/nasas-guide-to-the-best-p_n_165588.html" target="_hplink"&gt;study of houseplants by NASA scientists&lt;/a&gt;!). So try adding one to your bedroom or office space for a little dose of zen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your favorite decorative plants? Tell us in the comments or tweet &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;@HuffPostHome&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have something to say? Check out HuffPost Home on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/HuffPostHome" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=" https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostHome?ref=hl" target="_hplink"&gt; Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://pinterest.com/huffposthome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://huffposthome.tumblr.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=" http://web.stagram.com/n/huffposthome" target="_hplink"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you have a home story idea or tip? Email us at homesubmissions@huffingtonpost.com. (PR pitches sent to this address will be ignored.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061817/thumbs/s-HOUSEPLANTS-DESTRESS-HOME-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>How Grandparents Can Help Grandkids Survive Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/divorce-children_n_2972336.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2972336</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T11:20:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T11:41:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>SPECIAL FROM Grandparents.com In the weeks after his parents filed for divorce, one 3-year-old boy bombarded his paternal grandparents with invitations to visit his house....</summary>
    <author>
        <name/>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rebecca-klein/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPECIAL FROM&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.Grandparents.com" target="_hplink"&gt;Grandparents.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the weeks after his parents filed for divorce, one 3-year-old boy bombarded his paternal grandparents with invitations to visit his house. It was a tricky situation. They wondered if their son would view an appearance at his ex-wife's house as disloyal. They questioned if their daughter-in-law would even feel comfortable seeing them so soon after the breakup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, their grandson was reaching out to them. Would he feel abandoned and unloved if they didn't make a point to honor his request? The couple hemmed and hawed before ultimately deciding to go to their grandson. Rather than enter into his home, though, they picked him up and took him to a nearby playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your adult child is getting divorced, grandparenting is about to get a lot more complicated. Suddenly it's no longer just about building sandcastles with your grandchild, scarfing down ice cream, and letting him stay up past bedtime to catch the tail-end of his favorite Disney movie. Now, there are the feelings of four different groups to consider: the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; grandparents, your child, your child's ex-spouse, and your grandchild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Place, Your Grandchild's Safe Haven&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After your child's divorce is announced, your home and the time you spend with your grandchildren should remain as similar to pre-divorce visits as you can manage, says Lillian Carson, Ph.D., a psychotherapist and grandmother of 10 who wrote "&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Essential-Grandparents-Guide-Divorce-Difference/dp/1558746897" target="_hplink"&gt;The Essential Grandparents' Guide to Divorce: Making a Difference in the Family&lt;/a&gt;" (Health Communications). "Time with grandparents can be a relief for grandchildren who may be caught in the middle of two parents. Your home should be a neutral zone." Keep the focus on your growing relationship with your grandchildren, not their parents' disintegrating one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When They Confide in You&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't be surprised if the stability of your home encourages your grandchildren to share feelings they are unable to express to their parents for fear that they will be taking sides. Sure, when your adult child is going through a divorce, it's the main topic of conversation. You talk about it with your spouse. You talk about it with your best friend. You talk about it with your child. But, be careful not to spend all of the time you have with your grandchildren delving into their feelings about the divorce. “Don't try to be your grandchild's therapist,” advises Carson. “That's not your job.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only when your grandchildren mention the divorce, should you address it with them, she says. If they mention it, be an attentive listener and offer your love and empathy. Chances are you may be feeling emotions similar to theirs: anger, guilt, sadness, anxiety. Both your grandchildren and you are involved in a difficult situation that was not your choice to enter into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your grandchild opens up to you, frame your response positively and reassure him or her that the divorce is not his or her fault, suggests Marsha Temlock, M.A., a grandmother and author of "&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Your-Childs-Divorce-Expect-What-Rebuilding/dp/1886230668" target="_hplink"&gt;Your Child's Divorce: What to Expect... What You Can Do&lt;/a&gt;" (Impact Publishers). If you feel your grandchild is bringing up an issue that should be addressed by the parents, don't involve your grandchild when you approach them or broach the topic by saying something along the lines of "When Katie was visiting, she told me... "&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, when you are alone with your adult child, guide the subject with a non-accusatory musing such as, "I noticed that sometimes Katie has trouble falling asleep. I think she misses having both parents around at bedtime. Maybe you could call her at bedtime?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared for an angry reaction such as, "Well if someone hadn't asked for a divorce, she'd have both parents at bedtime!" Try to be sympathetic, but point out that everyone's main goal is to help the child adapt to the new situation, without blaming ex-spouses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They're All Ears&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Try not to stir things up," says Carson. "A good rule of thumb is to ask yourself, 'What would be the value of passing on this information? Would it be helpful to my grandchild?'" No matter what your personal opinions are, always remember that your grandchild loves both of his or her parents, despite any occasional display of anger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One grandmother believes that the casual, positive comments she makes show her grandchildren that even though their parents are divorced, she still thinks their mom is a good person. "If we're making spaghetti," she says, "I'll say something like, 'Your mom always makes the best meatballs. What a great cook she is.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no matter how tempting it may be, don't play spy by trying to get information that could be used in divorce proceedings. If, when your grandchild talks to you, what they say becomes fodder for the parents' arguments, your grandchild will realize this and feel unable to trust you. Then, who will he or she have to turn to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ex-Spouse: Friend, Enemy, None of the Above?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a divorce, many fathers are only able to see their children every other weekend when they try to squeeze in as much one-on-one time as possible. So, it's no surprise that research by Jeanne Hilton, Ph.D. shows that when a father becomes a non-custodial parent, the child's relationship with his or her paternal grandparents suffers. That's why Temlock encourages grandparents to maintain a relationship with their child's ex-spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karen Bastille, whose 3-year-old granddaughter, Maya's parents divorced, says her ex-son-in-law has retained a role in the family. "Maya's dad will often visit her in my home on 'Daddy Day'. He'll order pizza and we'll all have lunch together. It's a treat my granddaughter has come to regard as a ritual,” says Bastille. “Sometimes, he will even stay for dinner."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carson admits that sometimes an adult child may see this as a betrayal. “But, it's not being disloyal. Communicate to your child that even though it may seem that you are helping his or her ex-spouse, you are just trying to maintain a relationship with your grandchild,” she says. You should be able to support your child during the divorce and have a healthy relationship with your grandchild, without having to choose one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birthday Parties Times Two?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many celebrations and holidays are child-centered. You may be wondering if, after the divorce, there will be two birthday parties, two Easter egg hunts... two Thanksgivings? Since her daughter and son-in-law divorced, Bastille says that some holidays have been one-family events while others have included both families. When they are all together, she says, everyone manages to remember the most important thing -- Maya's happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It can be awkward for the adults, but family members have been able to control any lingering emotional turmoil and make it a good day for Maya,” she says. Of course, every family is different, and some divorces are more acrimonious than others. If a grandchild's parents' marriage ended bitterly, and emotions are still raw, joint celebrations don't have to be insisted upon. Ask yourself if it would be more difficult for the child not to see both parents together at the celebration, or to see them there together, arguing the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although grandparenting through a divorce can be a challenge, the role you play in your grandchild's life may also become more crucial. As Bastille has learned, grandparents can offer not only their love, but “an oasis of sameness when everything else in your grandchild's family life is changing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more on Grandparents&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.grandparents.com/family-and-relationships/divorce/relationships-after-divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Staying Connected to Your Ex-Daughter-in-Law After Divorce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.grandparents.com/family-and-relationships/divorce/happy-stepmother-rachelle-katz" target="_hplink"&gt;How to Be a Happier Stepgrandmother&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.grandparents.com/family-and-relationships/divorce/divorce-advice" target="_hplink"&gt;Divorce After 50: Tips to Make Moving On Easier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061187/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-CHILDREN-mini.jpg?13" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Amira Young: 14 Life Lessons I Learned From Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amira-young/learning-curves-15-divorc_b_2935713.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935713</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T06:26:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T06:34:48Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I left my husband, nothing could prepare me for what I faced next: nasty rumors, money issues, a vengeful ex, romantic feelings for someone I did not expect and an overwhelming sense of grief.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Amira Young</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amira-young/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When I left my husband, nothing could prepare me for what I faced next: nasty rumors, money issues, a vengeful ex, romantic feelings for someone I did not expect and an overwhelming sense of grief. Divorce was new and frightening, and something I didn't know how to deal with emotionally. I was off on an adventure, but one on tumultuous seas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as with any great adventure, I picked up a lot of funny stories, tender moments, and -- of course -- lessons to move forward with. They are things I will take to heart as I establish myself again and, hopefully, move on to a better love. I have learned...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Not to care what people think.&lt;/strong&gt; People are going to talk, spread rumors and take sides. It's the nature of divorce. But if you're going to recover properly, you're going to have to tune it out. Do whatever is right for you, even if it's not the most popular thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. To put myself first. &lt;/strong&gt;I'm a self-admitted people pleaser, but you can't do that while trying to heal, otherwise you won't recover properly. Do what you need to do and focus on you. And for those with children, if you're happy, you'll have an easier time keeping your kids happy, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Mourning is key.&lt;/strong&gt; We may not think of divorce as a death, but it is the death of a relationship. Even if it was dead for a long time, you should do a certain amount of mourning. Grief is natural, and you shouldn't pretend your marriage didn't mean anything. It did. Process accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. To love myself. &lt;/strong&gt;In marriage, I forgot about me; after divorce, I had to learn who I was all over again. We need to be okay with who we are on our own. After all, as RuPaul says, "If you can't love yourself, how in the hell are you going to love anyone else? Can I get an Amen?" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. To have sex again. &lt;/strong&gt;It's scary to move on in the bedroom, but divorced sex is too much fun to pass up. I have learned plenty of new tricks and preferences to bring to a new relationship; they're things I would have never known if I stayed celibate post-split. Don't be afraid -- let loose and have fun! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. To take control of my finances.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most dangerous things I did in marriage was give financial control to my ex. The result was he hid money -- &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of money -- and overpowered me. I'm still recovering financially. You should always know where your money is and how your finances are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. The best support after divorce comes from fellow divorcees.&lt;/strong&gt; I am lucky to have several friends who are going through their divorces at the same time as me. We prove to each other that we're not crazy and keep each other in check. Sometimes it's the only thing that keeps us sane. If you don't have divorced friends, try to find a support group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Those that judge your actions during crisis aren't worth your time. &lt;/strong&gt;I did things over the course of my split that many of my friends didn't like. When thrown into an emotional crisis, we rebel and reshape ourselves in ways that may not always be positive. Good friends stand by you. They shouldn't cast judgment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Not to let anger dominate.&lt;/strong&gt; My ex's behavior towards me during our split, like making out with his new girlfriend very publicly six weeks after I left (also known as the way people found out about the divorce) and stealing money from me, was downright deplorable. I was so mad that I didn't realize he was reacting out of anger and weakness. Anger gets in the way of your heart and mind. Don't let it take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. To figure out where the marriage went wrong.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are not owning part of the blame, look harder - it takes two to tango. I certainly made mistakes, such as trying to please everyone else so much that I didn't think about myself, picking the wrong partner and not being as open emotionally as I should have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. To laugh.&lt;/strong&gt; Whenever we start to laugh again is when we truly begin the healing process. Once you find your humor, there is nothing stopping you down the path of recovery. Find joy in everything, and things will get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. It's okay to cry. &lt;/strong&gt;Healing is not a linear process. Sometimes you'll take five steps forward, and then need to take three steps back and possibly have a mini-meltdown. It's all right to feel what you're feeling. You aren't superman (or woman) and don't need to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Know when you're ready for love again. &lt;/strong&gt;Two months after I left my ex, I realized that I had feelings for a close male friend who I suspected felt the same way. He was someone I would have seriously considered marrying, but I was too emotionally unstable and not ready yet to get involved with him. Although our friendship suffered as a result, it was the right decision at the time for me. We are the only ones who can say whether we're ready or not, so listen to your gut. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Love is still the most powerful thing in the universe.&lt;/strong&gt; My friends think I'm crazy to believe this after divorce, but love is a beautiful thing. I'm not talking real love, built on respect, communication and trust. The best part is that love takes many forms, like in friends and family. Cherish the love that's in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Shakespeare said (and my father, who quotes him regularly), "This, above all, to thine own self be true. And it must follow, as the night the day, thou canst not then be false to any man."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061641/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-LIFE-LESSONS-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Bill Swadley: Why You Should Avoid Family Court... At All Costs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-swadley/liars-court_b_2917619.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2917619</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T00:36:38Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:36:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In a perfect world, the mission of family court is to ensure that any agreement between the parents is in the best interest of the children.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Bill Swadley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-swadley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I've had the opportunity, albeit not by choice, to spend a few days at family court over the past six months. Family court, I was told by one lawyer who has spent the last 25 years in that area of his profession, is also known as "Liar's Court." The reason It's called this is very simple:  Almost everyone lies. They lie for various reasons. For personal gain, mostly, and sometimes out of a genuine concern for the welfare of the children involved. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, the mission of family court is to ensure that any agreement between the parents is in the best interest of the children. This, of course, would be a difficult task were everyone being forthright and honest, but when most everyone is playing fast and loose with the truth, it becomes a near impossibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I witnessed most commonly was the old "he said/she said" routine. In most cases, this was all there was. Neither party had any evidence to present, so they made false claims about each other, which left the judge to decide who was lying least (or maybe who was lying better?) This was usually how it went. There were instances where one party or the other did have evidence that had been filed with the court. In those rare instances, the judge still proceeded as if it were a case of "he said, she said" and largely ignored any evidence in favor of hearing arguments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many problems in the family court system and they vary in degree and severity, sometimes particular to the state or county in question, but from what I've witnessed, read, and been told, the level of dishonesty displayed by the parties and their lawyers in family court is consistent and pervasive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons Liar's Court exists, even in that most important area of family law, is the backlog most courts experience on an ongoing basis, especially those in large metropolitan areas. The backlog is so extreme that no judge could possibly familiarize him or herself thoroughly with each file given the daily barrage of cases they're inundated with. This leave the judge with little recourse but to ask the parties to tell their stories and hope that he can find the truth in the statements made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that, regardless of the evidence filed in the case, once the parties arrive in court they only need to be able to tell a convincing story and their evidence may or may not receive a proper review. Many, many tactics are used to try to sway the judge towards one side or the other under these circumstances, and it's a virtual free-for-all of dishonesty, but the big trick happens before the couple arrives in court with their respective lawyers. That is, getting the case to court in the first place. (This is especially important if you happen to have no case to begin with.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engage the other party's lawyer in conversation about the case in an effort to demonstrate attempted negotiations, but don't actually negotiate. Keep making the same offer even if the other party is willing to compromise. Remember, the goal isn't to settle, but to get the case in front of a judge. These sham negotiations are necessary in the event that the judge asks if any settlement negotiations were attempted. A really clever lawyer will find a way to accuse the other lawyer of being unwilling to negotiate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;File as much paperwork with the court as possible. Don't worry about redundancy or lack of veracity in the filing. No one will read any of it. The goal here is to make the file so thick and unwieldy that the judge will not have time to review it (or at least not think he has time) and he will believe  that the case is extremely complicated. This will also serve to dissuade him or her from asking whether negotiations were held.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep the couple from talking to each other. God forbid they should come to an agreement before going to court. Whatever it takes, make sure they fear and distrust each other. This will keep two people from talking surer than anything else.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prepare arguments in anticipation of the judge's questions on the matter, knowing full well that the documents you've filed haven't been read by him/her or anyone else. Then spin, spin, spin, spin until the web of the story is so complicated and personally heartfelt that your client looks like Gandhi and theirs is the picture of Satan himself. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Collect handsome reward. Win or lose, getting a case before a judge that should have been settled out of court is a big payday regardless of the outcome. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
All ironic bitterness aside, my advice to any divorcing couple, especially those with children, is simply this: &lt;strong&gt;Stay out of court.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your lawyer tells you, it's likely not in your best interest or that of your children. If you find a lawyer who advises  you that you'll do better with a judge than settling the matter with your former spouse, get a second opinion. Then get a third. When you find a lawyer who advises you to work out a settlement outside the court system, hire that person  That's your Jerry Maguire. (For those of you who don't remember or haven't seen the film, Jerry Maguire was a sports agent who set out to end corruption and dishonesty in his profession single-handedly. Laughter ensues.) He/she may be a cockeyed optimist, but is also one you can likely trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let me know what you think in the comments section below. My experience with &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/bill-swadley/the-reality-of-child-supp_b_823550.html" target="_hplink"&gt;writing about this subject matter in the past &lt;/a&gt;tells me that many lawyers will have lots to say about what I've written here, much of it surprisingly uncomplimentary. My answer to their most frequently asked question is: "No, I don't think you're the whole problem, but I do believe you are integral to the problem and have it in your power to affect it in a positive way."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
