<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jackie Morgan MacDougall: Do Good Moms Make Bad Wives?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jackie-morgan-macdougall/7-tips-to-save-your-marri_b_2909724.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2909724</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-26T07:10:33Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-26T07:10:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>After years letting your marriage run on auto pilot, I wouldn't be so sure your spouse will be waiting with open arms.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jackie Morgan MacDougall</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jackie-morgan-macdougall/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Every classroom has one. Maybe she's even you. She's the mom who lives and breathes all things motherhood, using every ounce of energy to provide the precious little ones with the ultimate childhood experience. She bakes from scratch, has dinner on the table every night at 5:00 p.m. sharp and can whip together homemade costumes for the entire 5th grade cast of Wizard of Oz faster than you can say "And your little dog, too."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't even get me started on her crafting skills. While I try to avoid eye contact when I see that my son's teacher needs tiny fall trees cut out, that lady knows her way around a glue gun like nobody's business. She's like a cross between Martha Stewart and MacGyver, using pipe cleaner and a rock to create memorable holiday gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, most of us struggle with the simple task of juggling homework and soccer practice -- there's no shame in that, right? Nope, not her. She not only gets it all done but heads up the carnival committee and organizes the next class party at the same time. I want to scream at her "My God, woman, don't you sleep?" But I'm starting to think that if you showed up at her house in the middle of the night, you'd see her put away on a shelf with the rest of the wind-up robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for every other mom who thinks that she's perfect, setting the bar the rest of us can't even come close to, there's a certain someone who's anything but impressed... her husband. Because while she's spending sleepless nights frosting cupcakes and sewing costumes, he's feeling neglected and going to bed alone. Which brings me to my question...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do good moms make bad wives?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jessica is no stranger to the good mom, bad wife question. In a recent conversation, she revealed to me that she believes her dedication to the kids was a major contributing factor in the recent demise of her marriage, creating resentment, competition and feelings of neglect in her husband. "He hated that [I always volunteered] because it set into the time that should've been fed into him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But was he partially responsible for leading her to a life of extreme motherhood in the first place? Jessica admits that throughout her marriage, she's often felt unappreciated and not supported emotionally, leaving her with unmet needs. Using her time with the kids to fill those needs was good for the kids and her. "Because I needed validation and emotional gratification that he wasn't providing, the kid stuff was easy to take on. I always get a 'thank you.' Volunteering is very validating for me; it's rewarding and fulfilling."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think almost anyone who's walked into their young child's classroom can relate. The feeling you get when your kid notices your arrival can be pretty intoxicating, and knowing you're making an impact is exhilarating. But what happens in a few years when your kid begs you not to come and refuses to be seen with you? After years letting your marriage run on auto pilot, I wouldn't be so sure your spouse will be waiting with open arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.healthymarriageinfo.org/couples/lists-for-couples/index.aspx#6" target="_hplink"&gt;National Healthy Marriage Resource Center&lt;/a&gt; cites spending time together, showing respect and exploring common interests as a few of their 10 tips to having a healthy marriage. I'm no therapist, but I've got my own tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call each other names. &lt;/strong&gt;There's nothing worse than hearing a couple call each other "mommy" and "daddy" when there are no kids in a 100-yard radius. Referring to each other by name is a tiny, yet effective, way to recall the person you loved pre-kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just say no.&lt;/strong&gt; Say it with me... "I can't volunteer to run the bake sale this time." Say it, own it, live it. I promise you, if you utter those words, you will not die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just say yes.&lt;/strong&gt; Rumor has it, men often lose interest in alone time after hitting a certain age. Turn him down time after time and I guarantee he'll lose it with you much earlier. Just sayin'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize. &lt;/strong&gt;Listen, I'm not saying you shouldn't be involved with the kids. Volunteering and running the activities show is a positive thing and helps connect you with the kids. But do you really think Groundhog Day requires individually-wrapped holiday gift bags filled with pencils and Punxsutawney Phil-shaped erasers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forsake all others.&lt;/strong&gt; That's right, it's in the vows. Somewhere between sickness and health and richer/poorer, you agreed to forsake all others. While we think about staying faithful to our partner in the biblical sense, vows were about putting each other first. I'm not saying to neglect the kids, but they won't exactly suffer by seeing their parents put each other at the top of the list, instead serving as relationship role models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop making excuses.&lt;/strong&gt; I know I can be the first to suggest skipping date night in order to save a little cash. But the price of dinner and a sitter is nothing compared to the cost of divorce. So put on some lipstick and get your butt out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skip the crayons.&lt;/strong&gt; Here's a date night rule to live by: If there's a play area in the restaurant, find somewhere else to eat. Chain restaurants are packed with screaming kids and stressed-out parents, not the atmosphere to encourage kid-free conversation and romance. I know you love your never-ending breadsticks, but save Olive Garden for family night, OK?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you a better mom or wife? Share your tips to a healthy marriage and how you balance both!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055560/thumbs/s-GOOD-MOM-BAD-WIFE-mini.jpg?15" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: The Messy Way One Woman Got Back At Her Cheating Husband </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/cheating-husband_n_2951322.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2951322</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T22:52:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:51:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One woman's response to having her heart broken by her cheating husband? Breaking his stuff. On Monday, Reddit user jennny55 shared a photo of her...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;One woman's response to having her heart broken by her cheating husband? Breaking his stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/1azhlr/my_neighbor_caught_her_husband_cheating/" target="_hplink"&gt;Reddit user jennny55 shared a photo&lt;/a&gt; of her neighbor's belongings thrown out on the lawn after his wife discovered he had cheated. Take a look at the scene here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/LzLxr8E"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LzLxr8E.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who needs moving boxes, anyway? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head to the comments to share your thoughts on the wife's response, then click through the slideshow for five more stories of exes who got revenge post-split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--257277--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055503/thumbs/s-REVENGE-INFIDELITY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Dennis Quaid And Wife Back Together... Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/dennis-quaid-divorce_n_2950257.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950257</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T22:40:16Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:39:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Dennis Quaid and estranged wife Kimberly Buffington-Quaid are reportedly getting back together... again. Despite filing for divorce in November 2012, TMZ reports that the couple...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Dennis Quaid and estranged wife Kimberly Buffington-Quaid are reportedly getting back together... again.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/367701/dennis-quaid-files-for-divorce-asks-for-joint-custody-of-twins" target="_hplink"&gt;filing for divorce &lt;/a&gt; in November 2012, &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/23/dennis-quaid-wife-kimberly-back-together-divorce-filing/" target="_hplink"&gt;TMZ reports&lt;/a&gt; that the couple has reconciled. But there is one big issue: the pair already signed the divorce documents, &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/23/dennis-quaid-wife-kimberly-back-together-divorce-filing" target="_hplink"&gt;which means the split is set to become final soon.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://www.raoulfelder.com/clients.html" target="_hplink"&gt;celebrity divorce lawyer Raoul Felder&lt;/a&gt;, the couple's next move depends on whether or not a judge has already signed the divorce papers.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"If the judge did not sign the divorce order, then they can simply say they withdraw it, sign a stipulation to withdraw it and that's the end of it," Felder told HuffPost Divorce. "But if the judge did sign the order, they would have to go to court to get a new order to vacate the prior judgment of divorce."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn't the first time that the pair has split up and reconciled. In March 2012, Buffington-Quaid &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2012/03/09/dennis-quaid-divorce-kimberly-buffington/#.T1pTgXLLyRk" target="_hplink"&gt;filed for divorce&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000598/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Vegas" actor&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/313991/dennis-quaid-s-wife-stops-divorce-explosive-couple-trying-to-make-it-work-source-says" target="_hplink"&gt;withdrew the petition&lt;/a&gt; just two months later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The couple -- who are parents to &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/367701/dennis-quaid-files-for-divorce-asks-for-joint-custody-of-twins" target="_hplink"&gt;5-year-old twins&lt;/a&gt;  -- &lt;a href="http://www.ew.com/ew/article/0,,661042,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;tied the knot &lt;/a&gt; in July 2004. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quaid has been &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/dennis-quaids-wife-kimberly-buffington-quaid-files-for-separation-20121910" target="_hplink"&gt;married twice before&lt;/a&gt; -- first to actress PJ Soles and later to actress Meg Ryan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to test your knowledge of eight other celebrities who reconciled with an ex post-split. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--209534--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055017/thumbs/s-DENNIS-QUAID-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>14 Ways To De-Stress When Your Ex Has the Kids</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/divorce-stress_n_2950800.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950800</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T21:14:43Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T21:17:46Z</updated>
    
    <summary>One surprising silver-lining to divorce? Having time to yourself when your ex has the kids. You miss them, of course, but once you've adjusted to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;One surprising silver-lining to divorce? Having time to yourself when your ex has the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You miss them, of course, but once you've adjusted to the quiet -- and the complete lack of Nick Jr. on your TV -- that uninterrupted "me time" can be exactly what you need after a long week of soccer practices, doctor's appointments and carpooling to school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just ask HuffPost Divorce readers. From morning yoga classes, to well-earned naps, click through the slideshow below to see how our readers de-stress when the ex has the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--287666--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1055206/thumbs/s-NAP-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Elisabeth Moss Opens Up About Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/elisabeth-moss_n_2950149.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2950149</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T20:44:02Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:47:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Mad Men" actress Elisabeth Moss doesn't mince words when it comes to discussing her 8-month marriage to "Saturday Night Live" funnyman Fred Armisen. A year...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"Mad Men" actress Elisabeth Moss doesn't mince words when it comes to discussing her 8-month marriage to "Saturday Night Live" funnyman Fred Armisen. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year after saying that the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/03/08/elizabeth-moss-fred-armisen_n_1332911.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"greatest impersonation [Armisen] does is that of a normal person,"&lt;/a&gt; the 30-year-old actress gave more insight into what she learned from her marriage to the comedian in an interview with &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/magazine/elisabeth-moss-on-what-peggy-wont-do-this-season-on-mad-men.html?src=dayp&amp;_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Oh, God. I learned so much," &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/17/magazine/elisabeth-moss-on-what-peggy-wont-do-this-season-on-mad-men.html?src=dayp&amp;_r=0" target="_hplink"&gt;Moss told the Times in early March&lt;/a&gt;. "Not to be at all Oprah on you, but it is one of those things where you are kind of glad to have learned those lessons at an early age -- to get them out of the way." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moss and Armisen married &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20315431,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;in October 2009&lt;/a&gt; and  &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/08/13/elisabeth-moss-fred-armis_n_681825.html" target="_hplink"&gt;split in May 2010&lt;/a&gt;. Less than a week after their split, Armisen was reportedly &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/08/18/fred-armisen-abby-elliott_n_687102.html " target="_hplink"&gt;dating SNL co-star Abby Elliott&lt;/a&gt;. His relationship with Elliott &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20532202,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;ended in September 2011&lt;/a&gt;. Moss has recently been linked to &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20605313,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Australian cinematographer Adam Arkapaw. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2013, Armisen admitted to Howard Stern that he was a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/08/fred-armisen-elisabeth-moss-marriage_n_2433188.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"terrible husband"&lt;/a&gt; to Moss. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I want it all ... fast," &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/08/fred-armisen-elisabeth-moss-marriage_n_2433188.html" target="_hplink"&gt;he told Stern&lt;/a&gt;. "I want to be married, I want to live together ... and then somewhere around a year or two years, I get freaked out. I freak out emotionally and then I actually feel like 'Oh my God, who's this stranger in my house?'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they aren't the first celebrity exes to dish about their relationship after a split. Click through the slideshow below to read more shocking statements celebs have made post-divorce:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--238408--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054899/thumbs/s-ELISABETH-MOSS-FRED-ARMISEN-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Austin Blood: The Truth About Infidelity Today</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/austin-blood/social-media-booty-call_b_2908531.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2908531</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T17:06:55Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T23:16:52Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Whereas twenty years ago a married man might have to go to a bar or romance a co-worker for an extramarital booty call, today he can save himself all that hassle with just a few mouse clicks.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Austin Blood</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/austin-blood/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Unless you've been living on the moon for the past couple of years, you've noticed the massive surge in the number of websites dedicated to online dating. Along with old standbys like eHarmony and Match.com, hundreds of new sites now cater to every kink, taste and fetish imaginable. If that's your thing, smile your best Cheshire grin. It's a brand new day on the world wide web and you're only a few mouse clicks away from finding your first love or "dating" an incarcerated felon. Anything you want is there for the taking if you're so inclined; all you need is an internet connection and a little time on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New dating websites are blasting their way into every home in America with the cultural equivalent of an atomic bomb. The shockwaves they're leaving behind are resonating through the landscape with permanent and irreversible effects. Many online dating sites now offer an unprecedented opportunity to find that perfect match... even if you already have a significant other. As proof, one need look no further than AshleyMadison.com. Last year, this notoriously naughty website for married people seeking affairs signed up its ten-millionth member. That's the number "1" with &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; zeros, my friend! Traditional values have long been under siege, but never like this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this scenario....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late one evening while you're asleep, your husband clicks over to AshleyMadison out of curiosity. The kids are in bed and he's had a lousy day. He's stressed out about work and finances and the two of you aren't connecting like you used to. He heard about this website from a co-worker but just can't believe it until he sees it. He tells himself, "There's no harm in just checking it out...I would never have an affair."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click. Click. Click. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later he's chatting with a woman across town. (Yes, it really is that easy) She's cute. &lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; cute. And lonely. Soon messages are flying back and forth like a flurry of ping pong balls. He likes her. She likes him. It's exciting, so he'll likely return tomorrow night for some more "innocent" chat. After you've gone to sleep, of course. Over time they agree to meet for the "harmless" lunch. And before you know it...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BOOM!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Monogamy takes one in the nuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of extramarital booty calls, can you guess the number one site for online hookups? The site that puts even Mistress Madison to shame? If you said Facebook, you're correct. The same scene is repeated thousands of times across America every evening. Suburban housewife. Mother of two. Happily married... or so she tells herself. Late one night she's uploading family photos on Facebook when a message icon pops up in the corner of her screen. It's Dave, an old fling from high school. "Hey Cutie," he says. Completely harmless... right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrong! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the next several months, she unknowingly and unintentionally heads down the most slippery of slopes. It all starts innocently enough. At first, it's just surface talk. Family, career, kids and life in general. As the weeks pass, she begins to look forward to their evenings together online. With her glass of wine in hand and her husband and kids asleep, her time with Dave becomes her happy place and the escape she so badly needs. Dave is easy on the eyes and a fantastic listener. And unlike her husband, he really seems to understand her.  Over time, she begins to feel alive again. Not since her early 20's has she felt this vibrant. What began as simple online chat session eventually explodes into a blaze of passion she thought long extinguished. Before you know it, they begin to share details intimate enough to make a porn star blush. And it's all downhill from there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another blow to Mr. Monogamy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer number of people on Facebook now make it the easiest place to start down the path to an extramarital sheet shuffle. In fact, the American Academy of Matrimonial Lawyers says &lt;a href="http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/tech/news/2010-06-29-facebook-divorce_N.htm" target="_hplink"&gt;sixty-six percent of their lawyers&lt;/a&gt; now cite Facebook as the primary source of evidence in their divorce proceedings. With stats like these, it's clear that everyday folks from all walks of life are going online in droves and meeting up with old and new flames alike. For the lonely wife or horny husband, the web is now a category five tempest of temptation swirling with opportunities that didn't exist even a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now before we go any further, let me be very clear on one point: the websites themselves aren't the real issue here. Their popularity is purely symptomatic of deeper sociological matters beyond the scope of this article. The websites don't make people cheat any more than cars force people to drive drunk. What the technology does is make it substantially &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; by creating or facilitating the opportunity. Whereas twenty years ago a married man might have to go to a bar or romance a co-worker for an extramarital booty call, today he can save himself all that hassle with just a few mouse clicks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for society at large?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contend the infidelity rate will continue to increase exponentially, for married and unmarried couples alike. It's simply too damn easy to have an affair in the new millennium. This in turn will have an immense social impact on our culture as the concept of traditional marriage as a viable union takes a blow to the balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't believe me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For countless couples, marriage after the ten-year mark is already synonymous with boredom, loneliness and sometimes plain ol' misery. By almost any metric, traditional marriage is on the skids if modern statistics are to be believed. For starters, the divorce rate is higher than the Empire State Building and more couples than ever are opting instead for cohabitation and open lifestyle choices. And that was before this new wave of technology made it easier than ever to sneak around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those times I feel compelled to share the cold, hard truth of reality. Particularly given that my sworn mission is to be an advocate for all women and a critical part of this charge is creating awareness of issues with life-altering potential in a woman's world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues for better or for worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-19-signature.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-19-signature.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-19-signature-thumb.png" width="80" height="27" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a href="www.AustinBlood.com" target="_hplink"&gt;www.AustinBlood.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fan Page: &lt;a href="www.Facebook.com/TheAustinBlood" target="_hplink"&gt;www.Facebook.com/TheAustinBlood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marcy Miller: A Simple Way To Begin Moving On Post-Split </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marcy-miller/the-joy-of-nesting_b_2935535.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935535</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T16:54:47Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T16:54:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary>After discovering that my husband was cheating and kicking him out of our home, I was left with a broken heart, anxiety and angst, and a house full of reminders of him</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marcy Miller</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marcy-miller/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;After discovering that my husband was cheating and kicking him out of our home, I was left with a broken heart, anxiety and angst, and a house full of reminders of him. It was very painful to see his clothes in the closet, toiletries in the bathroom, tools in the garage and smiling pictures of us from happier days staring at me in every room. The memories were overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something needed to be done quickly to give me peace in my own home. I needed to reclaim my space and inject a bit of estrogen to comfort me. First, I loaded boxes of shoes, books, knick-knacks, memories, sweaters,  jeans and other non-hanging clothes and moved them carefully to my clean and dry garage. I then bought garment bags and a coat rack and hung his shirts, suits, sport coats and slacks in these, which I moved to the garage as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I had the pictures to deal with. I stored our wedding album and pictures from the reception in a box in the garage, and I tore up the pictures in the frames and spent quality time culling through pictures of friends and family to replace them. It felt like a breath of fresh air to walk into the room and see familiar, loving, smiling faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I still felt my soon-to-be-ex's presence, and I needed a clean start. So I decided to re-paint the bedroom. I had originally chosen a very neutral light pastel green on the walls, but it was time to shake up the place. I chose a deep purple/gray to change the atmosphere completely.  And what a difference a few coats of paint can make!  It lifted my spirits and helped me to forget the years of sleeping in the same bed with him. I also bought new sheets and pillows, and started to sleep in the middle of the bed instead of on "my side."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it was time to reorganize and shed all the clothes that I had been keeping in my closet but had not had the time or energy to cull. I asked my good girlfriend to come over and be brutal in forcing me to part with those pieces that I would never wear again. I guess I am a bit of a hoarder when it comes to clothing -- I always hope that I will wear it in another season and hate to part with it. But my friend had no mercy and I ended up giving away fifteen large bags of clothing to friends and Good Will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt lighter, happier, and ready to start the painful divorce process from the safety and comfort of my "new" home.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>M. Gary Neuman: What Many Adults Confess About Their Parents’ Split</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/m-gary-neuman/the-long-way-home-for-adu_b_2911005.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2911005</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T16:07:44Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T16:07:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>There are millions of adults who experienced the trauma of their parents' divorce 20, 30 or 40 plus years ago. Some have found closure, but many more have not.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>M. Gary Neuman</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/m-gary-neuman/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;There are millions of adults who experienced the trauma of their parents' divorce 20, 30 or 40 plus years ago. Some have found closure, but many more have not. Regrettably, it is a time in a child's life that is never forgotten; it sticks with them. For anyone who's experienced it, you know it isn't only about divorce. It's about the years of tension in the home leading up to the divorce and those commonly miserable years after the divorce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifteen years ago, Miami-Dade became the first county in the United States that would not grant a divorce in a family until the children completed the &lt;a href="http://mgaryneuman.com/consultation/the-sandcastles-program/" target="_hplink"&gt;Sandcastles Program&lt;/a&gt; for children of divorce.  Since then, more than 300,000 children of divorce have completed the Sandcastles Program internationally and it continues to help children of divorce share their deepest emotions and gain a feeling of normalcy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'd like to think it all stops there -- in the past. Sadly, our childhoods remain a part of our adult fabric for better or for worse, and with divorce in the past, there is a load of negativity that never goes away. It seems that because divorce has become ubiquitous, people feel that it shouldn't be discussed -- as if they're whining. After all, &lt;em&gt;lots &lt;/em&gt;of people went through what you did as a kid. Who wants to hear about it? &lt;em&gt;Move on, get over it. How long can you keep rehashing the same old stuff? Give it up!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet the idea of swallowing and pretending it all away is what gives significant power to the problems in the past. Consider that in my recent study of 379 children of divorce, (the subject of my new book, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Long-Way-Home-Powerful/dp/0470409223" target="_hplink"&gt;The Long Way Home&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;89 percent believe their parents' divorce clearly had a negative impact on their life, while 45 percent label the impact as severe.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;80 percent have experienced severe sadness or depression.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;72 percent feel their parents' divorce impacted their ability to sustain close relationships.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;The majority feel their parents' divorce has undermined their self-confidence and ability to trust.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is divorce's nasty little secret. It's why you are afraid of sounding weak when you talk about it -- to others as well as to yourself. It's understandable. After all, you don't want to feel that life is holding you back just because of what happened to you as a child, especially because it wasn't your fault. Unfortunately, pretending the feelings away won't get you to where you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an adult who was a child of divorce, give yourself permission to look back and be honest with yourself. Even as an adult, you can heal from your past and create a new future that is less reactive to it. Like so many others in my study who have been affected by divorce, it is possible to heal. The first step in helping yourself is to open up and allow yourself to recognize how your parents' divorce has affected you. Opening up is the beginning to finding a path of change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, identify how you feel today and notice that those feelings are reminiscent of your childhood. This process takes time and focused energy, and is the subject of my new book. In the book, I  outline how research participants followed a detailed program to help them learn about themselves and make significant changes. Perhaps for the first time, adult children of divorce can face their issues, grow from them and rid themselves from the ill effects of divorce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To learn more about Gary's just released book, The Long Way Home: The Powerful 4-Step Plan  for Adult Children of Divorce, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-0470409223,descCd-buy.html" target="_hplink"&gt;wiley.com/buy/0470409223&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
M Gary Neuman is a New York Times best-selling author, rabbi, and creator of Neuman Method Programs. He was on the Oprah show 11 times as well as having made multiple appearances on Today, Dateline, the View, NPR and others.  Oprah referred to Gary as "One of the best psychotherapists in the world." To receive discounts on Gary's Creating Your Best Marriage 11 DVD set program, go to &lt;a href="http://www.neumanmethod.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;NeumanMethod.com&lt;/a&gt; and use coupon code huffington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweet Gary questions at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mgaryneuman" target="_hplink"&gt;twitter.com/mgaryneuman&lt;/a&gt; and follow Gary at &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/M.Gary.Neuman" target="_hplink"&gt;facebook.com/MGaryNeuman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052533/thumbs/s-ADULT-CHILDREN-OF-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kris Humphries And Lamar Odom Battle On The Court</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/kris-humphries-lamar-odom-photo_n_2948711.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2948711</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T15:02:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T15:02:47Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Talk about awkward. Kris Humphries literally bumped into his former brother-in-law Lamar Odom on the basketball court Saturday (March 23) as the Brooklyn Nets took...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Talk about &lt;em&gt;awkward&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kris Humphries literally bumped into his former brother-in-law Lamar Odom &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/03/kardashian-men-lamar-odom-and-kris-humphries-go-head-to-head-on-basketball-court/" target="_hplink"&gt;on the basketball court Saturday&lt;/a&gt; (March 23) as the Brooklyn Nets took on the Los Angeles Clippers at the Staples Center in L.A. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, the two are still family, considering Humphries' divorce from ex-wife Kim Kardashian &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/25/kim-kardashian-kris-humphries_n_2552879.html" target="_hplink"&gt;hasn't been finalized&lt;/a&gt;. Odom is married to Khloe Kardashian, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KhloeKardashian" target="_hplink"&gt;who tweeted during the game&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is insane!!!!&lt;/p&gt;— KhloéKardashianOdom (@KhloeKardashian) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KhloeKardashian/status/315685838707097601"&gt;March 24, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We're not sure if she was referring to the drama on or off the court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly Humphries' team lost to Odom's with a final score of 95-101. Looks like the Kardashians win ... again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See Kris and Lamar battle it out below:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="kris humphries lamar odom" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054328/thumbs/o-KRIS-HUMPHRIES-LAMAR-ODOM-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054328/thumbs/s-KRIS-HUMPHRIES-LAMAR-ODOM-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Sandra Bullock's Philandering Ex Remarries </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/jesse-james-alexis-dejoria-married_n_2947769.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2947769</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:49:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:01:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Here's to hoping she knows what she's doing ... Jesse James, Sandra Bullock's ex and notorious philanderer, tied the knot this weekend for the fourth...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Liat Kornowski</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/liat-kornowski/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Here's to hoping she knows what she's doing ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesse James, Sandra Bullock's ex and notorious philanderer, &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2298651/Sandra-Bullocks-ex-Jesse-James-ties-knot-drag-racer-Alexis-Dijoria-dating-just-seven-months.html" target="_hplink"&gt;tied the knot this weekend for the fourth time&lt;/a&gt;. The lucky lady, 35-year-old Alexis DeJoria, is a drag racer and the daughter of billionaire John Paul DeJoria, co-founder of Paul Mitchell hair products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James, 43, and his lady love &lt;a href="http://www.people.com/people/article/0,,20685016,00.html" target="_hplink"&gt;walked down the aisle at John Paul's Malibu home&lt;/a&gt;. James' youngest daughter, Sunny, 9, and DeJoria's daughter Bella, 10, acted as flower girls, reports People.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two have been dating for all of seven months and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/21/jesse-james-alexis-dejoria-engaged-heiress-paul-mitchell-drag-racer_n_2170298.html" target="_hplink"&gt;got engaged after only one month&lt;/a&gt;, after bonding over their mutual love of motor-racing and body art. According to Star magazine, &lt;a href="http://radaronline.com/exclusives/2013/03/jesse-james-dating-alexis-dejoria-wedding/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Jesse's always had a man crush on John Paul,"&lt;/a&gt; so an appreciation for DeJoria's father is also something they have in common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though there were rumors prior to the wedding that James plans to invite his Hollywood ex, Bullock, to the ceremony, there's no evidence she was in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James was married to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/21/jesse-james-alexis-dejoria-engaged-heiress-paul-mitchell-drag-racer_n_2170298.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Bullock for five years until she filed for a divorce in 2010&lt;/a&gt;, when she learned he had cheated on her with multiple women. He was also engaged to Kat Von D, who broke off their engagement in 2011 after learning he had cheated on her with at least 19 women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James was also previously &lt;a href="http://www.accesshollywood.com/jesse-james-engaged-to-drag-racer-alexis-dejoria-report_article_72787" target="_hplink"&gt;married to Karla James and adult film star Janine Lindemulder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053966/thumbs/s-JESSE-JAMES-ALEXIS-DEJORIA-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: 66 Inspirational Quotes About Marriage Equality</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/gay-marriage-quotes_n_2947825.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2947825</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:37:54Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:41:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Two cases will go before the Supreme Court regarding the legality of same-sex marriage in the United States, one on March 26 and the other...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Noah Michelson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/noah-michelson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Two cases will go before the Supreme Court regarding the legality of same-sex marriage in the United States, one on March 26 and the other the following day, March 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, the Justices will hear arguments involving Proposition 8, the legislation which made gay marriage illegal in California in 2008. And on Wednesday, the Court will consider the constitutionality of the Defense of Marriage Act, which was signed into law in 1996 and federally defines marriage as the legal union of one man and one woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've seen an incredible amount of progress on the marriage equality front in the last 10 years -- including a huge push that came in just the last few months when same-sex marriage was made legal in Washington, Maryland and Maine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we nervously watch and wait to see how the Supreme Court rules on these two historic cases, we thought now was a good time to showcase some inspiring quotes about the fight for marriage equality. We've chosen 66 great quotes from queer people and their allies and featured them in the slideshow below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a favorite quote that isn't featured? Tell us in the comments section, along with your thoughts on what you think is going to happen regarding the Prop 8 and DOMA cases.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054004/thumbs/s-GAY-MARRIAGE-QUOTES-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Intimacy Intervention: 'Help! I Can't Stop Sleeping With My No-Good Ex'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/abiola-abrams-intimacy-intervention-cant-stop-sleeping-with-ex_n_2933883.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2933883</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T12:22:32Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:15:30Z</updated>
    
    <summary> Passionate Living Coach Abiola Abrams gives love, dating and self-esteem advice on the CW's Bill Cunningham Show and all over the web through her...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jessica Cumberbatch Anderson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jessica-anderson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="essence logo1" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1051757/thumbs/r-ESSENCE-LOGO1-medium260.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passionate Living Coach Abiola Abrams gives love, dating and self-esteem advice on the CW's Bill Cunningham Show and all over the web through her hit web series AbiolaTV. Now she wants to help you keep things spicy and fresh between the sheets. Are you in need of an intimacy intervention? Just ask Abiola!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear Abiola,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep sleeping with my ex. He was my first and I’m ready to move on but I just can’t. We have been best friends since childhood, so I never thought he would treat me this way. He’s driving me crazy! I thought we were soul mates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our six years together, there was so much infidelity. He got married to someone else behind my back even though it was not legal because his divorce was not final. He was living with me for 11 months when he left the house one morning to get married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time photos of him with other women pop up on my Facebook timeline I go crazy. I have gained weight, I’m depressed and in a rut. Now I just started having sex with him again and I don’t know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help me get out of this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signed,&lt;br /&gt;
Ex-hausted in Ex-cruciating Pain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Ex-uberantly About to Move Forward,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goddess sister, it is time for an ex-orcism. First of all, you have my deepest sympathy. I say that because the only way to get past this is to grieve the death of the relationship, as off base as it was, heal your self-worth and move forward like the queen you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is not driving you crazy, sis. You are willingly showing up in your party pants and paying for the bus ticket to get there. You’re not alone. A recent YourTango Breakup Survey shows that more than half of single people say that thinking about their exes keeps them from finding new love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sleeping with” with this man is only ex-acerbating the situation. We are creatures of habit but to put it bluntly, having sex with this ex is like eating your vomit. The meal might have tasted great at one time but now it can just make you ill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to abruptly ex-purge. Cut off contact. Unfriend him on all social media. You don’t need to see “Loser is now in a relationship with Rachet” pop up on her timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why you are having trouble walking away: when we are sexually intimate our brains blast us with feel-good chemicals like oxytocin, dopamine and endorphins. Your adrenaline also starts going. As women, we can find ourselves deluded about the prospects of a defunct relationship because we have recharged our attachment bonds. Every time you are intimate with him and your body hits you with more oxytocin, you reinforce this. If you are trying to move forward, romping with him keeps you stuck in the same place. It’s a matter of physics and inertia. You can’t evolve while still actively engaged with someone who continues to treat you like less than a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ex is an unscrupulous human being. I’m sure both of his wives would agree. You cannot be soul mates when one partner is lacking a soul. A relationship works between two whole healthy people. This “man" is neither whole nor healthy. You are trying to make right with your body what you could not make work with your clothes on. You need to rebuild trust in yourself by making better choices because not only has this man betrayed you, but you have betrayed yourself. Take full responsibility for your actions. I say this not to beat up on you, but if you make only him responsible, then only he can fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main issue is what I like to call “deservability.” You deserve much better than to have a man who would leave your house to marry someone else. That is emotional abuse. It’s time to woman up and become your own best friend. Breakup pain is awful but there’s no getting around that. On the other side there is wholeness, healing and freedom, promise. The only way to reclaim your joy and power is to go through the fire, love and forgive yourself, learn the lessons and then move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day you’ll look back and wonder, what was I thinking? It’s okay, princess. We all do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abiola Abrams is the founder of The Bombshell Academy blog, online school and web series over at AbiolaTV. Follow her on Twitter to continue the discussion about this week's hot topic, and then email her your burning questions now. Anything you send will be posted anonymously, promise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052200/thumbs/s-ABIOLA-ABRAMS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>3 Ways Sex Changes For Men After 50</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/sex-over-50-men_n_2925739.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2925739</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T11:29:12Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T12:02:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When it comes to how sex over 50 for men, all interested parties seem to focus on erections -- or, more specifically, the increased difficulty...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Anthonia Akitunde</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/anthonia-akitunde/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;When it comes to how &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/12/sex-over-50-not-having-sex_n_1561339.html" target="_hplink"&gt;sex over 50&lt;/a&gt; for men, all interested parties seem to focus on erections -- or, more specifically, the increased difficulty to get and/or maintain an erection that goes with age. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sex for men over 50 changes in other ways besides a higher likelihood of dealing with&lt;a href="http://www.webmd.com/erectile-dysfunction/default.htm" target="_hplink"&gt; erectile dysfunction&lt;/a&gt;, according to certified sex and relationship expert Joe Kort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Men have their own midlife crisis," Kort said. "They're bodies, their hair, their erections... their masculinity is starting to change. It's really about their virility as a man. Some of it is that they want to feel more like a man. They have to wrestle with their own masculinity."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kort spoke with Huff/Post50 about three ways sex changes for men over 50. Have you experienced these differences? Tell us your thoughts in the comments section or via Twitter @HuffPost50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;1. Men feel closer to their sexual partners.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common stereotype of men being distant after having sex is based on biology, Korte said. While men and women have the same levels of &lt;a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/basics/oxytocin" target="_hplink"&gt;oxytocin&lt;/a&gt;, the so-called "love hormone" that is responsible for&lt;a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=be-mine-forever-oxytocin" target="_hplink"&gt; bonding to partners&lt;/a&gt; and children, men have more testosterone, which is a hormonal distancer, Korte explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Men's testosterone starts dropping in the 40s and really starts lowering in their 50s," he said. But because their oxytocin levels remain the same, men over 50 find themselves attaching more to their partners after sex, a complete 180 from how men typically feel after intercourse, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They're shocked themselves at how much they can attach," Korte said. This attachment bore out in a 2012 study where &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/11/study-oxytocin-the-love-hormone-makes-men-in-relationships-want-to-stay-away-from-other-women/265314/" target="_hplink"&gt;monogamous men who received a nasal spray of oxytocin&lt;/a&gt; were more likely to keep their distance from an attractive female and avoid sending romantic interest signals compared to single men. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;2. Men become more open to expressing their sexuality in different ways.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women tend to be more open about their sexual fantasies, going beyond the mechanics of sex to explore different scenarios and ways to express intimacy, Kort said. But that changes for men over 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They have a fluidity with what they want sexually, because their erections can't work," meaning they have to find new ways to be sexual, he said. "They're doing things, wanting things because they aren't so rigid." (No pun intended.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men over 50 become more vocal about their sexual fantasies, and begin to broaden their ideas of what turns them on, considering "even fantasies they wouldn't have imagined before," Kort told Huff/Post50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The defenses aren't as strong anymore," he said. "Maybe they're more bored with their fantasies, [maybe] it doesn't get them to the edge like it used to. [But] they're more open-minded to different things because they're older."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;big&gt;3. Men become driven by fear.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call it little red Corvette syndrome -- but when men hit 50, that desire for a new, younger model becomes overwhelming, Kort said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"There is research that supports you're looking for someone who can bear your children," he said. "So there is some biology behind it. Women have it too, but it's not as prominent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"They really start wanting the ideal that they always wanted," Kort explained. "It's not an issue of right or wrong, they're just panicked. Internally, they get scared and they act on it because their time is running out. [They think], 'I'm never going to attract a woman like this again, and I want it'."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1053782/thumbs/s-SEX-OVER-50-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Sandy Weiner: 4 Things Men Should Never Do On A First Date</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sandy-weiner/advice-for-guys-4-tips-fo_b_2916383.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2916383</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-25T05:39:51Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-25T06:11:40Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The bottom line is that first impressions matter in dating. If you want a great relationship with someone special, you need to put your best self forward.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Sandy Weiner</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/sandy-weiner/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;This is for all you newly single men out there. Are you fed up with first dates that don't lead to a second date? Do you sometimes scratch your head and ask yourself, "Why didn't she want to go out with me again? I thought things were going well." I want to help you understand women better. I want you to have more success in getting that second date. So, I'm going to reveal some dating tips based on my personal experiences, plus those shared by my divorced friends and the clients I coach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are, if you felt that a date went well but she never wants to date you again, you might have said or done something that turned her off. You probably didn't even realize it. The following tips could mean the difference between a lonely Saturday night in front of the TV with a beer or another great date with that lovely woman. Here are the four things men should &lt;em&gt;never &lt;/em&gt;do on a first date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't talk about sex.&lt;/strong&gt; Not on the first phone call or the first date. Confident, self-respecting women don't want to be objectified. It's not that women are not interested in sex. Quite the contrary -- most of us love sex! But don't talk about your sexual conquests with us on a first date. Please take time to get to know us. Like us for our intelligence, warmth, kindness, creativity and wit. Do &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; us that you're physically attracted to us, but don't make it the primary focus of why you're into us. When you ease into the physical relationship, most of us respond better.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't be negative.&lt;/strong&gt; Please don't talk about what sucks in your life. We're sorry that you lost your job. We understand that your kids are driving you crazy. We feel bad that you don't have much of an appetite since your wife left you. You've lost weight. You've gained weight. You're in debt. You have kidney stones or irritable bowel syndrome. Listen up: we all have "stuff" that frustrates or overwhelms us. There is a time and place to share the big stuff of our lives; the first date is not it. We don't know you well enough yet. It feels overwhelming and inappropriate to us. If we end up in a relationship with you, by all means, share it all with us. We'll care about you and want to support you then. But this is only the first date, so please stay positive.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't discuss your ex.&lt;/strong&gt; Your relationship with your ex was terrible. She threw you out of the house. You were blindsided. She took all your money. She has full custody of your kids. We get it, divorce is hard, and sometimes the ex has done very hurtful things. But we don't want to hear about it -- not on a first date or a first phone call. Maybe later. We want to talk about what's going on for you now. What are your dreams? Your passions? Stay in the present, and we'll both enjoy the date much more. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don't be rude.&lt;/strong&gt; If you're unkind to the waiter, doorman, toll collector, or any other person you come in contact with on that first date, we will judge you as unkind. We want to be in a relationship with someone who is considerate, compassionate and warm. Go out of your way to be nice, and chances are, you'll get that second date.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that first impressions matter in dating. If you want a great relationship with someone special, you need to put your best self forward. You're judging us as much as we're judging you. I'm sure we're doing or saying things that are turning you off, too. We want to understand you guys better. We want to improve our dating success, too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's start communicating here about what we can do to bring about more healthy, loving relationships. Please share your thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And you're invited to sign up &lt;a href=" http://eepurl.com/w3bHv" target="_hplink"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for my brand new FREE report, &lt;strong&gt;"The Top 3 Mistakes Midlife Daters Make &amp; How to Turn Them Around to Find Love Now!"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052531/thumbs/s-MALE-DATING-TIPS-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Rosalind Sedacca: How To Talk To Your Children After Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rosalind-sedacca/talk-to-not-at-your-child_b_2903747.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2903747</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-23T17:28:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-23T17:27:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Too often, busy parents find themselves talking "at" their children, but not "to" them. And most especially, not "with" them.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Rosalind Sedacca</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rosalind-sedacca/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Therapists are always reminding parents to talk to their children. Unfortunately, many parents need just such a reminder -- especially in today's mega-paced culture in which just sitting down to a family dinner together seems to be a major accomplishment. Too often, busy parents find themselves talking "at" their children, but not "to" them. And most especially, not "with" them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, of course, is problematic in any family trying to raise socially, emotionally and spiritually healthy children. However, it is especially dangerous if that family is facing the challenges of divorce or separation.  If your parent-child communication skills and rapport is not optimal before discussions about divorce or family lifestyle changes come up, the likeliness of a peaceful, successful outcome is dramatically jeopardized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that reason, more than ever before, parents need to create a bond of trust and support with their children when the family is facing any level of upheaval.  If that respectful bond and trust is broken or tenuous, children are much more likely to feel abandoned, neglected and fearful about their safety and security in the face of separation of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is never too late to bridge that gap and start authentic communication with your children. Honesty is always important in any parent-child relationship, but it becomes extremely significant at this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all communication must be age-appropriate. And these talks are never a license for a dumping session about your soon-to-be ex or former spouse. Whining, complaining, sarcasm, disrespect and related behaviors are not healthy forms of communication, especially with sensitive children. They don't want you to air your dirty laundry with them. They want to feel safe, loved, secure and supported as they move into a transition in life that they did not desire or create. Insulting or criticizing their other parent affects them to their core. Your children are innocent and many parents need to remind themselves of this fact again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has never been a better time than now to boost your level of communication with your children, regardless of your marital status. Share some of your own feelings and experiences with life's challenges before you start asking them questions about their life. Knowing that you personally deal with fears, anxieties, doubts and related emotions gives your children permission to talk about those they are experiencing. It makes them feel more okay about their own insecurities. And it encourages them to talk more frankly with you about challenges they face in all facets of their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't wait for a special occasion to start honestly and candidly talking to your children. Determine to make sincere communication with your children a regular part of your family life. You will never regret it and you will come to reap surprising rewards in the months and years ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*   *   *   *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rosalind Sedacca, CCT is author of How Do I Tell the Kids about the Divorce? A Create-a-Storybook Guide to Preparing Your Children - with Love! For more information about this innovative new approach to that tough conversation, visit &lt;a href="http://www.childcentereddivorce.com/kids/" target="_hplink"&gt;howdoitellthekids.com&lt;/a&gt;. For Rosalind's free ebook on Post-Divorce Parenting: Success Strategies for Getting It Right, other articles and valuable resources for parents, visit &lt;a href="http://www.childcentereddivorce.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;childcentereddivorce.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1052525/thumbs/s-KIDS-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
