<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Ann Margaret Carrozza: 4 Legal Issues To Consider Before Marrying Again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-margaret-carrozza/second-marriage-estate-planning-in-a-second_b_2956022.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2956022</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T10:09:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T10:26:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Love may be lovelier -- but it is also a whole lot more complicated the second time around. Record numbers of us will, one day, be in a second marriage. The pool of eligible second marriage candidates is vast as a result of both the high divorce rate and increased longevity. But before saying 'I do' (again), there are a few legal issues that merit consideration.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ann Margaret Carrozza</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-margaret-carrozza/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Love may be lovelier -- but it is also a whole lot more complicated the second time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record numbers of us will, one day, be in a second marriage. The pool of eligible second marriage candidates is vast as a result of both the high divorce rate and increased longevity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before saying "I do" (again), there are a few legal issues that merit consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How should the new spouse be provided for in the estate plan? The competing interests here are typically one's adult children and the new spouse. There is an expectation that assets accumulated in the first marriage will, in some measure, inure to the benefit of the children of that marriage. On the other hand, the new spouse may not have sufficient assets to provide for retirement needs in the event that he or she is widowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the compromise solution was to provide that the estate be held 'in trust' for the lifetime benefit of the surviving spouse. During widowhood, the surviving spouse received income from trust assets. Some trusts also provided for distributions of principal, in the discretion of the trustee. Then, upon the survivor's subsequent death, the trust terminated and all remaining assets reverted to the adult children of the first to die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right of Election&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The laws of every state seek to prevent a spouse from being totally disinherited. Absent an explicit waiver, a surviving spouse is entitled to the greater of $50,000 or one-third (1/3) of the entire estate.  The only asset not counted for purposes of calculating the elective share is life insurance. Every other asset, whether passing through the will or directly to a named beneficiary, will be counted. For example, if an estate worth $900,000 consists of a 401K of $400,000 and CDs of $500,000 and adult children are the named beneficiaries, the surviving spouse can lay claim to  $300,000 of the assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 1992, the so-called elective share portion must pass outright to the spouse as opposed to being held in a trust. Anyone considering using such a trust to provide for the surviving spouse must now get their written consent ahead of time in the form of a valid pre or post nuptial agreement. This consent is also required if the estate plan contemplates totally disinheriting a spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Roof Over One's Head&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In a second marriage situation, the primary residence is commonly titled in one party's name. Thought must be given to the survivor's living arrangements upon death of the owner. The most common (but imperfect) remedy is to grant the non-owner survivor a life estate in the home. Then upon the subsequent death of the survivor, the home will revert to the adult children or other beneficiaries of the first to die. This approach makes intuitive sense but can sometimes have unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A life estate for the survivor quite literally means that he or she is the de facto owner until death. The family would, therefore, be unable to sell the home or otherwise use it regardless of whether the survivor gets remarried, moves away or winds up in a nursing home for years. To add insult to injury, the nursing home would be entitled to require that the property be rented out and the income used toward the survivor's care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better solution would be to grant the surviving spouse a 'Right of Occupancy' in the house. With this, we can specify events in addition to death which will have the legal effect of terminating the survivor's right to reside in the property. For example, the right of occupancy might terminate upon the earlier of the survivor's death, remarriage, voluntary vacatur, or absence from the property for a continuous period in excess of four months. This specificity will prevent the adult children from being stuck with an asset that they can't sell or otherwise use. It is also critically important that the Will or Trust creating the right of occupancy clearly spell out who is responsible for what expenses.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prenuptial Agreements&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is estimated that the divorce rate for second marriages exceeds 60 percent. Hammering out the legal and financial issues ahead of time can prevent much costly legal wrangling later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond establishing who gets what in the event of death or divorce, prenuptial agreements are increasingly being used to address financial issues within the marriage. These so-called 'lifestyle clauses' can be used to establish spending priorities and parameters. For example, the parties may wish to place limits on financial assistance given to their respective family members. Record numbers of baby boomers are caught in the squeeze between helping their adult kids who are unemployed or under employed and helping aging parents cover the cost of long term care. While generosity is admirable, if one party goes into debt to pay for a daughter's lavish wedding, this will certainly have an impact on both spouses.  It is better to address this issue on the front end . The same goes for a party who signs a personal guarantee at his mother's nursing home. This action has the potential to compromise both parties' retirement security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postnuptial Agreements&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For generations, married couples having problems had only two choices: Grin and bear it, or leave. This is because legal contracts between married people were not recognized under common law. Today, married couples in 46 states now have the right to contract with each other in order to resolve or prevent a whole host of problems. Increased legal acceptance has resulted in matrimonial attorneys everywhere drafting more of these agreements than ever before.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postnuptial agreements can be used to settle a wide variety of marital disputes. Financial disagreements, housekeeping issues and vacation selections are common components of these contracts. Some couples even ask to include a 'sex schedule' within the document. Though it is doubtful that this schedule would be legally enforceable in a court of law, (thank goodness) it may serve to clarify expectations between the parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postnuptial agreements are also useful in times of marital crisis. When the cheating spouse is groveling for a second chance, the aggrieved party can now ask for more than just his or her word that it won't happen again. Monetary penalties for future indiscretions are commonly incorporated into the document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 'post-nup' is also gaining ground amongst happily married couples in first marriages. In the context of estate planning, everyone should give some thought to the (depressing prospect) of the surviving spouse remarrying. Where should the couple's assets go upon the subsequent demise of the remarried spouse? The inevitable response is "to our children". Without an agreement in place, however, the new spouse will have elective share rights (discussed above) to the estate. Moreover, even if the widow or widower doesn't remarry, he or she may develop a cognitive impairment and be prey to con-artists as well as an assortment of financial liabilities. The post-nup can require the surviving spouse to adhere to the estate plan originally agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1056853/thumbs/s-SECOND-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Ann Brenoff: Do We Ever Outgrow Our Lust For Bad Boys?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-brenoff/bad-boys-on-the-fly-do-we-ever-outgrow-lust_b_2908748.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2908748</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T10:05:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T10:21:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I was in my 20s and 30s, I specialized in dating bad boys. Call it the lure of the forbidden fruit or the ultimate revenge on my parents; I don't actually have a good explanation of why I spent more than a decade with men who had a less-than-sterling track record in the relationship arena.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Ann Brenoff</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-brenoff/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When I was in my 20s and 30s, I specialized in dating bad boys. Call it the lure of the forbidden fruit or the ultimate revenge on my parents; I don't actually have a good explanation of why I spent more than a decade with men who had a less-than-sterling track record in the relationship arena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I abandoned my pattern of rejecting men simply because they were smart, kind and nice to me. But what puzzles me nowadays is how so many women my age are still drawn to bad boys -- men who don't call when they say they will; men who can't remain faithful; men who sponge off you -- doing things like stiffing you with the check in the restaurant because they always forget their wallet; men who lie to you and make you doubt your sanity when you confront them; men who disappear without explanation and then pop back into your life expecting to take up where they left off. And, of course, men who don't want what you want and yet you somehow believe that, in time, they will. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last may be the crux of it; is there a more powerful aphrodisiac than the notion you can change someone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At younger ages, so says popular science, it's our hormones that do us in. Bad boys look more attractive to us when we wear our ovulation goggles, &lt;a href="http://www.livescience.com/20294-women-choose-bad-boys.html?utm_content=LiveScience&amp;utm_campaign=seo%2Bblitz&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_medium=social%2Bmedia" target="_hplink"&gt;found a University of Texas study last year.&lt;/a&gt; Our baby-seeking hormones make Mr. Wrong look like Mr. Right. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we can write off 28-year-old World Cup alpine skier &lt;a href="http://www.newser.com/story/164649/tiger-woods-im-dating-lindsey-vonn.html#.UUeZPMiY090.facebook" target="_hplink"&gt;Lindsay Vonn taking up with Tiger Woods&lt;/a&gt; -- a show of hands please of anyone who thinks those two will go the distance -- but why are older women, whose hormones now mostly amuse themselves by turning up the body temperature at inappropriate moments, making the same foolish choices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men? They of course have their own foibles when it comes to making inappropriate choices in mates, but today I'm talking to the ladies: Why are you still drawn to men who behave badly even though by this point in your life, you've likely heard a million friends say that you are settling for less than you deserve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ann-brenoff/lean-back_b_2811552.html" target="_hplink"&gt; it took a jolt to my system for me to move past this phase&lt;/a&gt; and not reject a man simply because he treated me well. Remember Groucho Marx' line about not wanting to join a club that would have him as a member? I think we don't stop accepting second-class treatment until we stop believing that's what we deserve. At least that was my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My nice-guy husband and I were friends -- co-workers actually -- for years before we began dating. He was a guy friend who I would use as a sounding board and whine to regularly about whoever I was dating at the moment. I remember that during one of our regular Monday night football and pizza "dates" at my house, he moved to kiss me. I was so startled, I pushed him away. I told him I didn't have feelings for him "that way" and that at the root of it, we were very different people with different interests. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He replied that yes, we had different interests but we had one big thing in common: We both believed that I deserved to be treated well. And then he added, "I least I think you do, Ann, I'm not always sure how you feel about that." It was my wakeup slap; we were married about a year later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's my story, but I think with older women, there may also be something else at play. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad boys add the spice to lives that might otherwise feel bland, said &lt;a href="http://www.relationshipguru.us/" target="_hplink"&gt;Victoria Howard, author of five books including "Why Women Love Bad Boys."&lt;/a&gt;  She has been counseling women in South Florida for more than eight years and is, herself, twice divorced. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's the James Dean attraction," she says. "How else do you explain Mick Jagger? He's not that handsome -- far from it -- but women go ape over him."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some women, she said, just can't break the pattern. They sit by the phone waiting for the bad boy to call. They cry to their women friends when he forgets their birthday. And then they forgive him -- or more likely don't even bring up his transgressions because they don't feel they have a "right" to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It can be awful," Howard said. Howard was married to an older man. When she came home from not winning the Mrs. America beauty pagaent, he told her he wanted a divorce because she lost. "He told me that I wasn't pretty enough. I was a real-life Stepford wife. It took years of therapy to get over it," Howard said. Howard has been engaged three times in the past 15 years and considers it a victory that she didn't marry any of the three. "All bad boys," she reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We figure she wants the spice, but without the heartburn.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;q&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1056782/thumbs/s-BAD-BOYS-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Kevin A. Hansen: Cheaters Reveal Their Secret Regrets</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kevin-a-hansen/9-secret-regrets-of-cheat_b_2917341.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2917341</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-28T05:26:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-28T05:26:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Nothing rocks a marriage likes infidelity, and quite often the result is divorce. But once the truth comes out, do the cheating spouses regret the affair -- or just regret getting caught?</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kevin A. Hansen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kevin-a-hansen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Nothing rocks a marriage likes infidelity, and quite often the result is divorce. But once the truth comes out, do the cheating spouses regret the affair -- or just regret getting caught? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people whose secret regrets are featured in my bestselling &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kevin-Hansen/e/B004G7EJUK/ref=ntt_athr_dp_pel_1" target="_hplink"&gt;Secret Regrets book series&lt;/a&gt; are truly sorry for betraying their spouses, and are ready to accept responsibility and learn from their mistakes. Others try to justify their actions and don't regre the affair -- they regret the way they handled the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are nine secret regrets of cheating exes from my &lt;a href="http://www.SecretRegrets.com" target="_hplink"&gt;www.SecretRegrets.com&lt;/a&gt; online confessional &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kevin-Hansen/e/B004G7EJUK/ref=ntt_athr_dp_pel_1" target="_hplink"&gt;and book series&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288827--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059490/thumbs/s-CHEATER-REGRETS-mini.jpg?17" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>John Edwards' Daughter On Dad's Affair: 'I Was Devastated'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/cate-edwards-john-edwards-affair_n_2966760.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2966760</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T23:04:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T23:29:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary>John Edwards' eldest daughter is speaking out for the first time since her father's trial over alleged campaign finance violations. In an interview set to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/chris-gentilviso/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;John Edwards' eldest daughter is speaking out for the first time since her &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/31/john-edwards-trial_n_1561041.html" target="_hplink"&gt;father's trial&lt;/a&gt; over alleged campaign finance violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interview set to air Friday on NBC's "Today" and "Rock Center with Brian Williams," &lt;a href="http://todaynews.today.com/_news/2013/03/27/17488488-john-edwards-eldest-daughter-i-was-mad-devastated-about-affair?lite" target="_hplink"&gt;Cate Edwards opens up&lt;/a&gt; about her feelings when she found out about her dad's affair with Rielle Hunter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I guess he and my mom decided that that was, you know, how it needed to be done," she told NBC. "So yeah, I was devastated. And I was disappointed. I mean, these are my parents."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last May, John Edwards' campaign finance case was &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/31/john-edwards-trial-mistrial_n_1560562.html" target="_hplink"&gt;declared a mistrial&lt;/a&gt; when jurors were unable to pinpoint if he used donors' money to mask his pregnant mistress. The trial did lift Edwards' affair with Hunter into the public eye -- relations that took place while his wife, &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/12/07/elizabeth-edwards-dead_n_793416.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Elizabeth Edwards&lt;/a&gt;, was ill with cancer. She died in December 2010 at age 61.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't think God's through with me," Edwards said after the mistrial. "I really believe he thinks there's still some good things I can do."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunter published a tell-all book that was released in June, entitled &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/06/17/rielle-hunter-memoir_n_1604239.html" target="_hplink"&gt;"What Really Happened: John Edwards, Our Daughter and Me."&lt;/a&gt; Among the topics addressed were Hunter's views on Edwards' parenting of their daughter, Quinn, as well as his thoughts during his trial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Associated Press:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Days before his indictment Hunter asked: "So if you went to jail, what kind of jail would it be? One of those country clubs?"

&lt;p&gt;"He said, 'Yeah.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"'Where?'" she asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"'Probably Virginia.'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So Quinn and I will move to Virginia. Virginia is a great state."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only low-security federal prison in Virginia is in Petersburg, where former Washington, D.C., mayor Marion Barry once served time.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059465/thumbs/s-CATE-EDWARDS-JOHN-EDWARDS-AFFAIR-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>31 Pieces Of Marriage Advice From Divorcés</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/marriage-advice-_n_2965656.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2965656</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T21:12:10Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T21:11:43Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Want to divorce-proof your marriage? Take some advice from a divorcé. Seriously. Consider, for instance, the advice life coach Meg Buck offered Wednesday in a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Want to divorce-proof your marriage? Take some advice from a divorcé.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Consider, for instance, the advice &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/meg-buck/what-i-know-about-marriag_b_2951150.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;life coach Meg Buck offered Wednesday in a blog&lt;/a&gt; featuring the 10 biggest lessons she learned from divorcing in her twenties. One takeaway? Just "being in love is not going to cut it. You need more," like the ability to communicate and "depend on each other during the rocky times."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buck's post-split relationship real talk had us wondering what our divorced readers learned from their past marriages, so we posed the question to them on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click through the slideshow below to see what they had to say, then head to the comments to share what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; learned about marriage from divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--288757--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1059004/thumbs/s-MARRIAGE-ADVICE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>"Housewives" React To Porsha Stewart's Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/porsha-stewarts-real-hous_n_2965074.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2965074</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T20:13:14Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T20:39:44Z</updated>
    
    <summary>On Tuesday, reports surfaced that former NFL player Kordell Stewart had filed for divorce from his wife of less than two years, "Real Housewives of...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Kelsey Borresen</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kelsey-borresen/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, reports surfaced that former NFL player Kordell Stewart had&lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/26/kordell-stewart-divorce-real-housewives-atlanta-porsha-williams/" target="_hplink"&gt; filed for divorce&lt;/a&gt; from his wife of less than two years, "Real Housewives of Atlanta" star Porsha Stewart. Soon after, kinds words of love and support began flooding in from her reality show castmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NeNe Leakes took to her &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NeNeLeakes" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt; Tuesday morning to show she was there for her fellow "Atlanta Housewife."   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--TWEET--316586135113568256--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Leakes wasn't the only cast member to publicly wish her well. Former Miss USA Kenya Moore -- who is often seen &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/17/rhoa-kenya-porsha-strange-words-video_n_2313629.html" target="_hplink"&gt;feuding with Porsha &lt;/a&gt;on the reality show -- &lt;a href="http://www.eonline.com/news/401554/real-housewives-of-atlanta-star-kenya-moore-reacts-to-porsha-williams-and-kordell-stewart-divorce" target="_hplink"&gt;released a statement to E! News &lt;/a&gt;speaking out in support of the reality star.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's no secret that Porsha and I have had our differences," she said. "However, I would never want to see anyone go through pain or suffering such as in a divorce. I'm a hopeless romantic and believe in love and hope they can get past their differences. I do wish Porsha well and know she will do what is best for her."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News of the split came as a surprise to Porsha, who reportedly &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/kordell-stewart-divorcing-porsha-stewart-shes-completely-blindsided-2013263" target="_hplink"&gt;found out about the divorce through the media&lt;/a&gt;. An unnamed source &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/kordell-stewart-divorcing-porsha-stewart-shes-completely-blindsided-2013263" target="_hplink"&gt;told Us Weekly&lt;/a&gt; that the reality star was &lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/kordell-stewart-divorcing-porsha-stewart-shes-completely-blindsided-2013263" target="_hplink"&gt;"completely blindsided"&lt;/a&gt; by her husband's filing.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The estranged pair has &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/kordell-stewart-divorce-porsha_n_2955815.html" target="_hplink"&gt;no children together&lt;/a&gt;, but Kordell &lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/26/kordell-stewart-divorce-real-housewives-atlanta-porsha-williams/" target="_hplink"&gt;has one son &lt;/a&gt;from a previous relationship. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stewarts' split is the latest in a long string of Bravo "Housewives" divorces. Click through the slideshow below for more on the split and 37 other "Real Housewives" who called it quits with their husbands.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--196732--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce"target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058826/thumbs/s-PORSHA-STEWART-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Why You Should Consider Filing For Divorce First</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/what-are-the-financial-an_n_2957011.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2957011</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T18:15:20Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T18:14:51Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Over the years, I’ve had several clients who felt blindsided when their husbands announced intentions to divorce. Some thought all was well enough in their...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.forbes.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Over the years, I’ve had several clients who felt blindsided when their husbands announced intentions to divorce. Some thought all was well enough in their marriage; others knew there were problems, but didn’t think the issues were insurmountable. Whatever the circumstances, divorce can sometimes come as a complete shock.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1056748/thumbs/s-UNHAPPY-COUPLE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Cameron Frye: You Should Tell a Girl You're Married... Before You Sleep With Her</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/cameron-frye/you-should-tell-a-girl-youre-married_b_2964005.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2964005</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T18:13:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T18:21:28Z</updated>
    
    <summary>I slept with a married guy. I wish I could say this was a one-time thing, but it's not the first time I've been the other woman.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Cameron Frye</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/cameron-frye/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I slept with a married guy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say this was a one-time thing, but it's not the first time I've been the other woman. I'm not proud of it and I don't know why I'm always the lucky girl this happens too. It's not like I didn't come from a good home, my parents love each other and never had any major martial problems. I'm sure if Hank (my Dad) did step out on Nora (my Mom), she would stab him in his sleep -- plus, they would never be able to afford two divorce lawyers. No, after 40-something years of marriage, they're still painfully in love and they still kiss before my Dad leaves for work in the morning. It's adorable.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate them and their happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've lost 300 pounds (21 stone) and I'd like to think I don't have to make the same mistakes I made when I was the size of a manatee. I want to find that one person who accepts me -- for the good and the bad and sticks by my neurotic ass no matter what -- whether it's God awful and going down like the Hindenburg or when everything is perfect and we're tip-toeing thru the tulips. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I had the weird urge to listen to &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skU-jBFzXl0" target="_hplink"&gt;Tiny Tim&lt;/a&gt; and you need to suffer along with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only I could be that cold, heartless beast who feels nothing. Life would be so much easier. Not really, but you know what I mean. As much as I don't see myself as the marrying kind(lies), the idea of dying alone and unloved is scary and the funny thing is -- these thoughts never popped in my head or bothered me when I was a cow like creature roaming around beautiful downtown Boston. For whatever reason, since losing the weight, I want more out of life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't want to be the hose bag side dish, who settles. I want it all. *bangs head* It's embarrassing. I wish I wasn't like this. I wish I could lock up these feelings and throw away the key. But I can't. I have to own it and deal with it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you reprogram an evil (yet adorable) woman overnight, so she forgets all the horseshit stuff from the past and sticks to what she's good at? Being cold, funny and not caring about being alone? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No? Thanks for nothing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, before you start judging me on my selection of men, I didn't know he was married. The man in question didn't wear a ring and he sold me a false bill of goods. Found out that "his place" was actually his friend's place. He's just watching it while his friend is working in China. He redid everything to make the apartment look like his! He went so far as swapping out his friend's pictures for his! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so that is probably something a crazy person does -- but he did it and surprisingly enough, I thought he was normal. Needless to say, I'm a horrible judge of character. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a weird, sick way, I'm flattered he did all that to get me. But that's also something a crazy person says. Once again, horrible judge of character -- I'm sure &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mary_Jo_Kopechne" target="_hplink"&gt;Mary Jo Kopechne&lt;/a&gt;'s mom was a lot like me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You want to go to a party and the Kennedy boy will drive you home? That sounds lovely, tell Teddy I said 'H!'"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I guess I should share with you how I found out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had gone out on a few dates and started sleeping with each other as soon as humanly possible. I move quickly -- I know, I know. I shouldn't. Thanks for the lecture, Mom! Listen, I liked him and I knew the feeling was mutual -- so why not rush into something and potentially ruin it with sex? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's healthy, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were at "his place" and we had just finished up. It was late, and he had just popped into the bath for a shame shower when his phone started to ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Can you get that?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that's when it went downhill. See, he got cocky and thought he was in the clear. It's a rookie mistake and let's face it -- we've all made them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn't gotten the sentence "He's in the shower, can I take a message?" out of my mouth, before the women on the other end of the phone started freaking out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Who the fuck is this? I knew that motherfucker was up to something! Tell that asshole that his WIFE wants him home right now, because he needs to get up early tomorrow and start looking for a good lawyer! "&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me -- "Yes, ma'am."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Fuck you, whore!" *dial tone*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that was uncalled for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fought back the urge to call her back, scream at her and explain my side of the story. But since I didn't want to be hunted down by a more than likely unstable woman and die a painful death, I decided against it. I mean, she did have a right to be mad. I would be too. But it's not my fault he's a fool with amazing taste in side pieces. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat for a minute or two in shock and then he walked out of the bathroom, completely clueless to what just occurred. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Was that my office?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"No," I said and smiled. I got up, gave him a kiss and punched him in the stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JZEIMQ42-oU" target="_hplink"&gt;DOWN GOES FRAZIER!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often wonder what causes a person that starts speaking in tongues, but that's the best way to describe the verbal bashing I gave him. I cursed him out. I cursed out his parents for raising him poorly. I cursed his wife out for giving him a reason to cheat and for cursing me out. I followed that up with another punch to the gut and throwing a lamp at him on my way out. Probably overkill, but I didn't want to leave any stone (or lamp) unturned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's called a couple times since the proverbial shit hit the fan. I've been ignoring his calls, mainly because if I answer the phone I'll more than likely have the urge to throw it against a wall and I'm not eligible for an upgrade until the summer.  IPhones &amp; Lumias are expensive.&lt;br /&gt;
I thought everything was supposed to be easier when you got skinny? Lies, all lies! Listen, I know life  wasn't going to be magical and wonderful when I got to my goal size - but seriously? I have to deal with this nonsense now? I just want my day in the sun and not have to deal with this bullshit constantly. Evidently my weight loss turned me into one of those insufferable Taylor Swift creatures who are awful human beings and impossible to deal with. I missed the whole thing about losing weight turns you into a moron. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is, if my life was rainbows and sugar-free lollipops, I'd complain about how bored I was.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dumbass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind you I'm typing this piece out while wearing Cynthia Rowley, playing with my &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NsGWq6ULfCs&amp;feature=youtu.be" target="_hplink"&gt;talking Chewbacca doll&lt;/a&gt; and listening to &lt;a href="http://www.grahamcoxon.co.uk/" target="_hplink"&gt;Graham Coxon&lt;/a&gt;'s most recent record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a complicated woman. Maybe that's my problem? Hardly, I'm an asshole who's asking for too much.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/930609/thumbs/s-CHEATING-BETTER-MARRIAGE-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Mary T. Kelly, M.A.: The Worst Thing To Say To Stepmoms</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mary-t-kelly-ma/you-knew-it-was-a-package_b_2925350.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2925350</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T17:07:24Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T17:06:55Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In over ten years of working with stepmothers, I've rarely met one who would fall under the definition of an "evil stepmother".</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Mary T. Kelly, M.A.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mary-t-kelly-ma/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;"You knew it was a package deal."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If every stepmother got five bucks for every time she heard this, she could easily afford a vacation to a fabulous spa for a much needed and well-deserved rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most anyone who has had the courage, love and determination to partner with someone who has children, whether they have children themselves or not, intended to be a loving influence, ally and perhaps even a parental figure to their stepchildren. In over ten years of working with stepmothers, I've rarely met one who would fall under the definition of an "evil stepmother".  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common laments I hear from the stepmothers I work with is, "I had no idea it would be this hard." Many of them had excellent relationships with the children of their partners before marriage or living together. These children were respectful, kind and expressed love and affection for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for many stepmothers, whether it happened right after they said, "I do" or when their darling stepchild turned into a resentful teenager, something shifted and they found that they were the object of blame, hostility and rude behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When these stepmothers began to express how painful this was to their partners and/or friends, they were often told, "You knew it was a package deal" or "You chose someone who had children. You knew what you were getting yourself into."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But did they? Are there really thousands of women who blindly went into a marriage with a man who had children, not really accepting that he had children? Of course not. Yet the culture seems to want to blame stepmothers for struggling when they find they are living in a home where they are suddenly and inexplicably disliked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many adult stepkids have confessed to me that while they liked their father's girlfriend before they got married, the day they became husband and wife, these new stepchildren were surprised to find that they had sudden and strong feelings of dislike for their new stepparent.  The remarriage was a symbol of the permanency that their parents would never be reunited.  The loss of their family may not have been fully grieved until the remarriage smacked them in the face and reminded them that the family they once knew and loved was now gone forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many stepmothers who marry men with young children, they enjoyed years of peaceful and loving relationships with their stepchildren. They prided themselves on the fact that they had a truly "blended" family and had genuine feelings of care and love for their stepchildren.  But wait.  The stepchild became a teenager and the stepmother found that she was the first dog that got kicked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These women were stunned and rightfully hurt.  What had they done?  Why had this happened?  And, should they dare to complain to someone who didn't understand the ever-changing nature of stepfamily dynamics, they were often shamed and talked down to with clichés such as the title of this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not helpful. Do people really believe these women's IQ's suddenly dropped into the double digits and that the thought never occurred to them that they were marrying someone who had children? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepmoms don't need platitudes, they need validation, compassion and understanding. They need to be reminded that it isn't personal, that most children, no matter their age, are always going to have natural loyalty binds towards their biological parents, even if that parent is deceased or has abandoned them. That like any family, there are bound to be increased times of stress, strain and tension and that they are not responsible for not having foreseen or anticipated this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepmoms need their partners to cover their backs when their stepchildren treat them with disrespect, blame and disdain. People might be surprised to know how many fathers don't do this because they feel torn between their children and their new spouse. The stepmom is left hung to dry and wondering how to live in a home that no longer feels safe. Telling her, "You chose this!" often provokes unearned guilt and self-doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older I get, the more the wise adages passed on to me by my Mother ring true. "Don't judge someone until you've walked a mile in their shoes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's not a platitude, it's just plain common sense.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Tina Swithin: Why Our Family Courts Are Failing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tina-swithin/why-our-family-courts-are_b_2908574.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2908574</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T16:44:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T16:43:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The family court system in the United States is failing our children.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tina Swithin</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tina-swithin/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;The family court system in the United States is failing our children. Our appointed judges and commissioners are supposed to act in the best interest of the child, but unfortunately, they are not. My friend, Amie, was able to eloquently express what she deems as the primary issue in our family court system: the courts have a threshold of what they deem as acceptable but as mothers, as fathers, as parents and as a society, our thresholds should be much higher. The pendulum has been swung too far in different directions when it comes to mothers' rights and fathers' rights. I am not sold on the notion that an individual should have rights just because they have the ability to procreate.  A child's right to be safe and loved should supersede parental rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My case is classified as a "high-conflict divorce," however, the sad reality is that I am &lt;a href="http://onemomsbattle.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;divorcing a narcissist&lt;/a&gt; and the family court system is uneducated when it comes to this disorder. I usually have a sick feeling in the pit of my stomach as I wait for my court case to be called. Compared to drug abuse, physical abuse, sexual abuse and abandonment issues that are often addressed before us, my ex-husband, Seth, is a welcomed relief to the court. Seth seems educated, articulate and he is fighting for his children.  Step back into reality for a moment and the truth is that Seth isn't fighting for custody of our children, he is fighting to win and to gain control over me. Winning and control are the primary driving forces of individuals with personality disorders.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently spoke to Bill Eddy, an attorney, therapist and mediator and the President of the &lt;a href="http://www.highconflictinstitute.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;High Conflict Institute&lt;/a&gt;.  I have followed Mr. Eddy's work for the past two years and his book, "&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Splitting-Protecting-Borderline-Narcissistic-Personality/dp/1608820254/ref=as_li_tf_cw?&amp;linkCode=waf&amp;tag=onmosba-20" target="_hplink"&gt;Splitting: Protecting Yourself While Divorcing Someone with Borderline or Narcissistic Personality Disorder&lt;/a&gt;" has become my legal bible. Mr. Eddy is on the frontlines of the crisis in the family courts and founded the "&lt;a href="http://www.highconflictinstitute.com/new-ways-for-families" target="_hplink"&gt;New Ways for Families&lt;/a&gt;" method of managing high-conflict family court cases. In addition, Mr. Eddy co-developed the "&lt;a href="http://www.highconflictinstitute.com/books-a-products/hci-patternviewer" target="_hplink"&gt;HCI PatternViewer&lt;/a&gt;" program for analyzing high conflict behavior in family court cases. Mr. Eddy was kind enough to share the insight he has gained from being entrenched in the family court system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;"Tina Swithin is correct that the Family Court system is generally not educated about personality disorders, which creates several serious problems. Personality disorders are not obvious on the surface, which is why many people marry those with these disorders and why many courts are easily misled by them -- for months or years. To really understand what is going on takes looking under the surface and knowing what patterns of behavior to look for. This takes time and special knowledge, which family courts don't have, so decisions often favor those with the desperate emotions or the calculating control of those with personality disorders. 

&lt;p&gt;The adversarial process of the court brings out the worst behavior for those with personality disorders. They become extremely defensive and often much more dangerous, as they resort to extreme efforts for power and control over the other party, the children, the professionals and the judge. This can include lying, spreading rumors, hiding money, hiding children, false allegations and even violence. Many cases that I have read of family court related shootings happen within 2-3 weeks of a court hearing.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Family courts need more training, more time and more money for services for parents stuck in high-conflict cases. None of these are likely to occur any time soon -- in fact, the opposite is occurring. Yet society reaps what it sows and this is the future for many of the next generation. This is a mental health problem and a public health problem, and needs to be recognized as such."     &lt;/blockquote&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite simply, the judges and commissioners of the family court system are not taking the proper time to evaluate high-conflict custody cases. The judges are too focused on moving cases through the courtroom like cattle. Two healthy parents should be able to come to an agreement based on what is in the best interest of the child. Unfortunately, in many cases such as mine, there is only one healthy parent.  Our court system needs to receive ongoing education about high-conflict divorces and personality disorders.  Thankfully, there are people like Bill Eddy from the &lt;a href="http://www.highconflictinstitute.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;High Conflict Institute&lt;/a&gt; who is working tirelessly to provide education, but this is just the beginning of what is needed to make changes in our system.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like a doctor becomes accustomed to the cycle of life, our courts have become accustomed to abuse, neglect and abandonment. This issue begins in the courtroom and trickles down to everyone who has a hand in the family court system. This includes the very people who are supposed to protect our children such as parenting evaluators, counselors and therapists, Guardian ad Litems and Child Welfare Services. As a society, we should demand a higher threshold when it comes to our children. Sadly, these issues come back to parental rights and the fact that the family court system places a higher priority on parental rights than what is truly in the best interest of our children.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Marie Hartwell-Walker, Ed.D.: How To Introduce Your Kids To A New Love</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marie-hartwellwalker-edd/introducing-your-children_b_2911299.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2911299</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T16:03:11Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T16:02:44Z</updated>
    
    <summary>You can and should take the time to really get to know someone before involving the children.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Marie Hartwell-Walker, Ed.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/marie-hartwellwalker-edd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;You've been through a hard divorce and recovery. You've met someone and want to start dating. You want desperately to have a social life again that isn't centered on parents and children. And yes, you wouldn't mind a little love and intimacy after what seems like forever. But then there's the effect on the kids. You feel torn between your own wants and needs and your concerns about how the kids will react to a new person in your life. What's the best way to bring them all together?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no hard and fast rules, of course, but some approaches do work better than others. Parents who manage the transition well often follow these basic guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) First, remember that children don't recover from change with the same timing that you do.&lt;/strong&gt; Unless things were so bad that there was regular discussion of divorce, the kids have had less time than you did to adjust to the idea. You and your ex probably spent months making a decision before you told the children. Even if they thought something might be up, the announcement was new to them the day you made it. In addition, their relationship with their other parent or parent-figure is different from yours. There are many people who are lousy partners but still decent parents. You can't expect your kids to be ready for someone new just because you are.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Slow down. &lt;/strong&gt;You can and should take the time to really get to know someone before involving the children. It's simply not fair to ask them to fold someone into their lives, only to have him or her disappear a few months later when you discover it's not going to work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Shared custody can make things easier.&lt;/strong&gt; While you get to know your new love, schedule your dates when your kids are with the other parent. This gives you the privacy you need to develop a relationship and to become more intimate without getting the kids involved. If your ex has dropped out of the picture, schedule your dates when the kids are at an after school program or a Saturday event. Another option is to trade off "play dates" with another parent to give yourself social time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Once you've decided that the person you are dating is "the one", by all means do the introductions.&lt;/strong&gt; But do take it slow. Don't make the first encounter happen over breakfast after a sleep-over. Take the time to include kids and your new love on outings the kids will enjoy. A few trips to the playground, a hike or two, visits to the children's museum, a library or a local kid attraction will give both parties a low-key way to get to know each other. Make sure you give your children the attention they are accustomed to getting from you even while you are all together and that your date puts the kids' needs first. This isn't the adults' "date". It's the kids' time to warm up to this new person in your life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Only bring someone home overnight if you are pretty certain this relationship is going to stick.&lt;/strong&gt; Evidence of your sexual involvement can be confusing to young kids and embarrassing to older ones. The need to respect your closed door is a new level of intimacy for everyone, not just the adults. Once that line is crossed, it will be much harder for the children to understand and adjust if you call the relationship off. Further, it's very important to be clear about your values about sex outside marriage. Children do learn what they live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's difficult to be so measured and thoughtful about children's needs if you are excited about a new person, especially if you've been lonely for adult company for some time. But taking the time is worth it. When the children have had the opportunity to develop their own relationship with your new love, there will be far less conflict later on.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057497/thumbs/s-INTRODUCE-KID-TO-NEW-LOVE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Can You Be Too Close To Your Significant Other?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/healthy-relationships-are-closeness-intimacy-_n_2924319.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2924319</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T15:09:53Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T18:59:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>A close romantic relationship is generally believed to be better than a distant one. According to a new study, "Closeness Discrepancies in Romantic Relationships," however,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Christina Huffington</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/christina-huffington/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;A close romantic relationship is &lt;a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/communication-success/201209/how-enhance-closeness-in-your-relationship" target="_hplink"&gt;generally believed&lt;/a&gt; to be better than a distant one. According to a new study, &lt;a href="http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/14/closeness-in-a-relationship-is-it-overrated/" target="_hplink"&gt;"Closeness Discrepancies in Romantic Relationships,"&lt;/a&gt; however, the degree of closeness in a relationship does not necessarily translate into how happy a person is, both in the relationship and generally. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study -- &lt;a href="http://psp.sagepub.com/content/39/4/456" target="_hplink"&gt;published online in the &lt;em&gt;Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin&lt;/em&gt; in February 2013&lt;/a&gt; -- found that satisfaction with a relationship is not determined by how close a person is to their partner but rather by how much that level of closeness corresponds to their desired level of closeness. In other words, someone can be very satisfied with a relatively disconnected relationship as long as they aren't seeking a greater connection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study's authors, &lt;a href="http://www.mailman.columbia.edu/our-faculty/profile?uni=dmf2119" target="_hplink"&gt;David M. Frost&lt;/a&gt;, an assistant professor at Columbia's Mailman School of Public Health &lt;a href="http://www.indeed.com/r/Cat-Forrester/c3c00132ae36a33a" target="_hplink"&gt;Cat Forrester&lt;/a&gt;, graduate student who studied under Dr. Frost at San Francisco State University, had &lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2013-02/cums-wed021213.php" target="_hplink"&gt;732 men and women complete annual online surveys&lt;/a&gt; over a three-year period. The surveys included questions on relationship closeness, relationship satisfaction, commitment, break-up thoughts, and depression. Ideal closeness and closeness in reality were evaluated using the psychological method &lt;a href="http://www.haverford.edu/psych/ble/continuous_ios/originalios.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Inclusion of Other in Self&lt;/a&gt; (IOS), which consists of six sets overlapping circles depicting things like values, viewpoints and personality traits. The more overlapping the circles, the closer the couple is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifty-seven percent of those surveyed wished they were closer to their partner; 37 percent were happy with the level of closeness in their relationship; and five percent said they felt too close to their partner. Satisfaction in the relationship, however, was not determined by level of closeness but rather by &lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2013-02/cums-wed021213.php" target="_hplink"&gt;degree of difference in the "closeness discrepancy."&lt;/a&gt; The larger the closeness discrepancy, the unhappier the person was in their relationship -- regardless of whether they felt too close or not close enough to their partner. A high degree of difference in the "closeness discrepancy" is &lt;a href="http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/14/closeness-in-a-relationship-is-it-overrated/" target="_hplink"&gt;linked to a greater likelihood of breaking up&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the study demonstrates that relationship satisfaction is derived from an alignment in real and desired closeness, there is no denying that we are &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books/about/Close_Romantic_Relationships.html?id=u6havmfPWrsC" target="_hplink"&gt;inundated with information&lt;/a&gt; emphasizing the importance of an intimate romantic relationship. A 2008 study examined the link &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18447076" target="_hplink"&gt;between American culture and romantic closeness&lt;/a&gt;, finding that the cultural importance placed on romantic relationships can actually lead to a greater degree of loneliness when one is not engaged in a relationship as compared to South Korea, which doesn't place the same premium on romance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's best not to make too many assumptions about what constitutes a healthy relationship," &lt;a href="http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2013-02/cums-wed021213.php" target="_hplink"&gt;Frost said in a press release&lt;/a&gt;. "Rather, we need to hear from people about how close they are in their relationships and how that compares to how close they'd ideally like to be."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/690658/thumbs/s-TOUCHING-mini.jpg?4" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Porsha Williams Completely 'Blindsided' By Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/27/stewart-divorce-porsha-williams-kordell-stewart_n_2962489.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2962489</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T14:40:48Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T14:41:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>"Real Housewives of Atalanta" star Porsha Stewart was shocked when she learned that her husband of less than two years, former NFL star Kordell Stewart,...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Cavan Sieczkowski</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/cavan-sieczkowski/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;"Real Housewives of Atalanta" star Porsha Stewart was shocked when she learned that her husband of less than two years, former NFL star Kordell Stewart, had filed for divorce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tmz.com/2013/03/26/porsha-williams-kordell-stewart-divorce-statement/?adid=hero3" target="_hplink"&gt;Porsha was reportedly blindsided by Kordell's divorce&lt;/a&gt; request, according to TMZ. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Us Weekly reports the 31-year-old reality star found out about her husband's decision in the press. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"&lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/kordell-stewart-divorcing-porsha-stewart-shes-completely-blindsided-2013263" target="_hplink"&gt;Mrs. Stewart had held off on filing for a divorce&lt;/a&gt; herself and remained committed to the marriage because Mr. Stewart promised to work on the marriage with her," a rep for Porsha said in a statement to the magazine. "Instead, he misled her and she found out about the filing in the media."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/26/kordell-stewart-divorce-porsha_n_2955815.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kordell filed the petition for divorce from Porsha&lt;/a&gt; on March 22 in Fulton County Court. He requested the split on the grounds that "the &lt;a href="http://www.accessatlanta.com/weblogs/southern-squall/2013/mar/26/real-housewives-atlantas-porshas-husband-files-div/" target="_hplink"&gt;marriage is irretrievably broken&lt;/a&gt;," the Atlanta Journal-Constitution first reported. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stewarts' relationship was a central feature in Season 5 of Bravo's "Real Housewives of Atalanta." His domineering ways and their struggle to get pregnant appeared to be points of tension in the marriage. Castmate &lt;a href="http://www.bravotv.com/the-real-housewives-of-atlanta/season-5/blogs/nene-leakes/is-kordell-controlling?page=0,2" target="_hplink"&gt;NeNe Leakes criticized Kordell for being controlling&lt;/a&gt;, but Porsha defended him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't have a problem with a man having an opinion," &lt;a href="http://hollywoodlife.com/2013/03/26/porsha-stewart-divorce-kordell-stewart-marriage-interview-video/" target="_hplink"&gt;Porsha told Hollywood Life before news of the split was made public.&lt;/a&gt; "If you're my man, I need you to know where you're leading our family. I love that about him. Along the way, some things I agree with and some things I don't. As long as he can respect my opinion." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, she did admit they had some things to improve. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I definitely want to continue our family," she said. "Him and I have to make sure that the foundation before that child gets here is solid. And that's what we're working on." &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porsha is reportedly devastated and not answering calls or texts from friends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although she did not specifically mention the divorce, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PorshaDStewart/status/316667994036117505" target="_hplink"&gt;Porsha tweeted&lt;/a&gt; a thank you to her followers for their prayers on Tuesday night. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Porsha is the granddaughter of Civil Rights leader and philanthropist Rev. Hosea Williams. Kordell previously played for the Pittsburgh Steelers. The two met in 2009 and married on May 21, 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058250/thumbs/s-STEWART-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Molly Alexander Darden: How I Survived -- And Thrived -- On Less Money After My Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/molly-alexander-darden/off-the-grid-peace-comes-dropping-slowly_b_2935130.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935130</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T11:30:31Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T11:53:42Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I saw divorce looming in my near future last year, I evaluated my life choices, realizing that my income would be reduced by 58 percent. Friends and family members assumed I would get a job to supplement my meager Social Security income, and they urged me to do so. But, as usual, I took the path of independence, carefully thinking over my needs and options.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Molly Alexander Darden</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/molly-alexander-darden/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;When I saw divorce looming in my near future last year, I evaluated my life choices, realizing that my income would be reduced by 58 percent. Friends and family members assumed I would get a job to supplement my meager Social Security income, and they urged me to do so. But, as usual, I took the path of independence, carefully thinking over my needs and options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an unexpected inheritance, and knowing my ex would not be interested in sharing taxes and home maintenance with me, I invested in paying off the mortgage when my home was under water. It is now appreciating nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also bought a new Prius-C (for city driving), and set up two container gardens, each 4-feet-by-4-feet. With a new Mac computer, Kindle and a cell phone, I have my basic needs. Perhaps the biggest decision I made was to live out my remaining years debt free. If I can't afford something, I just don't get it and so far I'm enjoying tremendous peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how I manage, drawing on the wisdom of various sages who say, "reduce your wants for peace of mind," and the experience of nine years' living in rural Ireland where my water supply was jerry-rigged, and heating and cooking were by solid fuel (turf).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over there, living in a community of some seven farming families, most of whom had little discretionary income, I learned from them and we depended on each other. Those wonderful years were among the emotionally richest of my life because I felt I was living, to a degree, as my ancestors had done in the same area of Ireland. The idea that I had to impress no one by living beyond my means became ingrained. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, though, I do have the luxuries of running water and central heat and air conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my gardens here in suburban Atlanta, I planted a variety of vegetables and herbs last summer, enjoying wonderful meals of fresh, organic foods. Of course, I do purchase dairy products, meats and my three luxuries -- Weight Watchers ice cream bars, popcorn and Dove dark chocolate, which I carefully ration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden continues and grows despite some freezing winter temperatures, because I cover it whenever temps go too low, and open it to the sun as the days warm up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the guideline of a serving portion equalling the palm of a hand, my portions are generally no bigger than approximately 2-3/4 by 3-1/4 inches, and that certainly satisfies me. One of my favorite dinners is a handful of turnip greens, cherry tomatoes and sage or basil (from the garden) sauteed with garlic and walnuts in olive oil, and crowned with an egg. No wastage, no spoilage. Just right. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to reduce my electricity bills by $400 last year simply by hanging my laundry outside to dry, or draping it across a drying rack. And I love the feeling of going in the fresh air (even in the winter, though I love it less then), and the wonderful fresh fragrance of the clothing. And, of course, I turn out lights when I leave the room. With my most recent assessment from the Power Company, they say I've reduced my use of electricity this year by 31 percent over last year, already! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For telephone service, I use my cell phone and, when that's down (rarely), I use Google Phone; I video-chat with my daughter-in-law in Dubai free of charge via Google+ hangout or (audio only) Google phone. I get free books from Kindle, read magazines at the library and enjoy one movie per month on XFinity. "Argo" will probably be my next one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although my savings are quite reduced after all the big initial expenditures, they are again climbing slowly and steadily. But I believe my greatest benefit from this independent lifestyle is that, despite being well hooked into modern technology, I am grounded in simple pleasures and values. I feel a spiritual and emotional connection to the Almighty and to my ancestors so that, for me, Yeats' words ring true: "Peace comes dropping slowly."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1054802/thumbs/s-OFF-THE-GRID-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Meg Buck: 10 Lessons I Learned About Marriage From Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/meg-buck/what-i-know-about-marriag_b_2951150.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2951150</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-27T06:29:04Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T16:03:13Z</updated>
    
    <summary>What I didn't know when I tied the knot at 22.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Meg Buck</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/meg-buck/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;I married my first love when I was 22. We'd been together for four years and I was having his baby, so it seemed like the right thing to do. It turns out that I was wrong -- we ended up getting divorced after less than a year of marriage. Here's what I learned from the experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don't get married because it seems like a good idea.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
We were very much in love, but we hadn't faced any extreme ups or downs in our dating relationship and saw no reason married life would be any different. We didn't consider the additional stress of a newborn, let alone how much life changes as one continues to grow, get older, and take on greater responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Being in love is not going to cut it. You need more.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
My marriage to husband #1 fell apart within a year. We held expectations of one another that we never communicated, and this led to some pretty deep-seated resentments. We didn't turn to each other or depend on one another during the rocky times. The wedge between us grew until we didn't relate to each other at all. It got to the point that I didn't even want him coming home at night, never mind any idea of having sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We co-existed for a short while until I knew things had to change. I told him I wanted to get counseling, but he told me there was nothing wrong. &lt;em&gt;What? &lt;/em&gt;Nothing wrong? We don't talk! We're unhappy! At least I was unhappy. I felt hurt that that wasn't reason enough to seek help to rebuild our relationship. I didn't think I could face fighting for my marriage by myself. I felt like a total failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your marriage is not you. Marriage is not a measure of your worth or value to others.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Our divorce was awful. We were angry and hurt, and lashed out at each other.&lt;br /&gt;
I was consumed by my anger. I had put my trust in husband #1 and he failed me. At least, that's what I told myself. I felt like he had done something to me by not being the husband I wanted him to be. It took years of hard work for us to make our way out of this morass of upset and resentment. But we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then came husband #2. I was determined to make this relationship work. Between divorcing #1 and meeting #2, I'd met and dated a dozen men. I resolved to make this relationship different than the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The state of your relationship has something to do with you, not just the other person.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
When #2 and I met, we lived nearly 500 miles from one another. Our relationship began with a conversation that looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Should we do this?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't know. I don't know how to have a long distance relationship that works."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I don't know how to do it either. But I think we can do it together."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"You're right. Let's do it. Let's do whatever it takes."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Do whatever it takes. Make that your commitment, not just to your partner but to your relationship.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 It wasn't long before I was pregnant. Number-two and I spent three days discussing our options. Both aborting and going through with the pregnancy would change our lives forever. An abortion meant feelings we couldn't imagine for we didn't know how long. Having the baby meant his moving 500 miles to create a family with me and I wasn't willing to ask him to do that. If he was going to move, it was because he wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Share your feelings, fears, concerns, commitments and goals with your partner. Listen to your partner's feelings, fears, concerns, commitments and goals. Let their feelings be as important as yours.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We realized that the only reason we were considering aborting was because we were afraid of what life would look like if we decided to keep the baby, and we didn't want to live lives of, or make decisions from, fear. So we decided to have the baby, and in the process turn upside down everything we knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Go with the flow. It's so much easier to accept and roll with the punches than to wish earnestly for something else to happen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since we met, #2 and I have seen a lot of transition and change: we have moved three times and I chose to give up custody of my older son instead of fighting a custody battle with #1. Not to mention our son was born. Some days our saving grace was simply being able to talk to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Tell your partner what you need. Be as honest as you possibly can, every day &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Number-two did not propose right away. We had agreed that we would not get married until we were certain it was what we both wanted. I'd jumped that gun before and was not about to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Trust your partner implicitly. They have pledged their life to you too. They're in this too. They want it to work too.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Early in our engagement, my older son asked me when we were going to get divorced. I realized that all he knew was divorce. I told him that his soon-to-be stepfather and I were not going to get divorced. He asked how I knew. I told him that divorce isn't an option for us. We are committed to doing whatever it takes to stay together. Marriage may not always be easy, look pretty, or feel nice. And that is okay. Life isn't always easy, doesn't always look pretty or feel nice. And that is okay, too. His father and I hadn't known these things. And that was okay too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Focus on the good, in your partner and in your relationship. Focus on the good in life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For a pre-wedding gift, my mother-in-law gave us a small, heart-shaped plaque. I hung it in our bathroom so we both can see it every day. It says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marriage is like a Garden &lt;br /&gt;
it takes a lot of love &lt;br /&gt;
&amp; a little work &lt;br /&gt;
each day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn't have said it better myself.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1057486/thumbs/s-MARRIAGE-LESSONS-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
