<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US">
  <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://huffingtonpost.superfeedr.com" />
<title>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/feeds/verticals/divorce/index.xml" type="text/html"/>
  <author>
    <name>webmaster@huffingtonpost.com</name>
  </author>
  <rights>Copyright 2007, HuffingtonPost.com, Inc.</rights>
  <subtitle>Divorce on HuffingtonPost.com</subtitle>
  <generator>Good old fashioned elbow grease.</generator>
  <entry>
	    <title>Tammy Nelson, Ph.D.: The Real Reason Affairs Happen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/why-did-the-affair-happen_b_2981223.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2981223</id>
    
    <published>2013-04-01T06:00:49Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T05:57:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Often, when we discover that a partner has been cheating, the first question is an anguished "Why?"</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Tammy Nelson, Ph.D.</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excerpted from&lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt; The New Monogamy; Redefining Your relationship After Infidelity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, when we discover that a partner has been cheating, the first question is an anguished "Why?" This often-unanswerable question is what drives us to ruminate on what happened, and we may force our partners to talk about the details over and over again, hoping to find the answers we are searching for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things you will need to do to heal from an affair is to explore this question of why it happened and to be open to hearing the real, honest truth. Most people want to blame the cheating partner. And the cheating partner does have to take responsibility for pursuing the outside relationship. But no affair happens in a vacuum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collusion in the Affair&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collusion means "secret cooperation." The &lt;a href="http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/collusion" target="_hplink"&gt;dictionary&lt;/a&gt; says that collusion is "secret cooperation between two people in order to do something underhanded or undesirable." Many couples, if they are honest with themselves, may find that the partner who was cheated on colluded with the infidelity even if he or she didn't participate directly in the affair. That means that on some level, there was some type of cooperation, even if unconscious, to make the affair happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This secret cooperation may mean the betrayed partner is doing something in the relationship to collude with his or her partner's behavior, even if he or she doesn't realize it. To be unconsciously aware means that on some level, the betrayed partner had an idea that their spouse was cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00926239508404389?tab=permissions#tabModule" target="_hplink"&gt;1995 study&lt;/a&gt;, two groups of practicing therapists described extramarital affairs they treated or were themselves involved in. They reported that &lt;a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00926239508404389?tab=permissions&amp;#tabModule" target="_hplink"&gt;89%&lt;/a&gt; of betrayed spouses in the study were consciously aware of the infidelity or, even if they did not acknowledge it, really did know about the affair. The majority of the betrayed spouses behaved as if they were in collusion with their cheating partners, even when they said they were opposed to the affairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maria and Frank had been stuck in conflict over Maria's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tammy-nelson-phd/can-i-get-over-an-affair-_b_2911106.html" target="_hplink"&gt;affair&lt;/a&gt; for over a year. Maria had cheated on Frank with a neighbor, Joe, someone they saw weekly for card games and occasional barbeques. When Frank found out that Maria had cheated with Joe, he became incensed and almost left her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time progressed and Maria and Frank discussed the affair, Maria shared her confusion with her husband: "I always felt that you approved of my relationship with Joe. You saw how he flirted with me, and you even encouraged me to go over there when his wife was out of town. You used to say that Joe was probably lonely and that maybe I should go over and have a drink with him. Now you are so mad at me! There's some kind of mixed message here."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank was furious with Maria for insinuating that he pushed her into the affair: "I never told you to cheat with him. Did I ever say, 'Go sleep with Joe; he and his wife aren't having any?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Frank's feelings calmed down, he tried to see things from Maria's point of view, to find some empathy for her experience: "I guess it makes sense that she would move toward Joe. Maybe I was hoping that they would cheat so I would have an excuse to leave."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maria said, "This is not your fault. I definitely made the move to step over the line."  Frank realized he had unconsciously colluded with her about the affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affairs as Exits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An exit can be any behavior that a partner uses to avoid being truly present in the relationship, whether emotionally, psychologically, sexually, or even physically. Harville Hendrix, author of the best-selling self-help book &lt;a href="http://www.theimagoshop.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Getting the Love You Want: A Guide for Couples&lt;/a&gt;, says smaller exits can include anything that helps you to avoid dealing with conflict or intimacy, including being on the computer, checking e-mails, texting, or staying late at work. Any behavior that is used to avoid ways to engage with your partner is considered an exit. Bigger exits include things like gambling, drinking, and taking drugs. An affair is considered one of the biggest exits and is what Hendrix called &lt;a href="http://harvillehendrix.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;"an invisible divorce."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.drtammynelson.com/events/" target="_hplink"&gt;Affairs&lt;/a&gt; are only one way to exit from the relationship, but they can be a powerful and damaging way to avoid the intimacy of a monogamous partnership. However, whenever the person who is exiting traces his or her behavior back to the moment he or she exited, it often becomes clear that at that time, his or her partner was exiting as well. If the cheating partner can trace his or her behavior back to the point where the indiscretion began, it may become clear that the affair was an attempt to deal with the feelings of a partner who "exited" the relationship first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike and Sheila came to therapy after Mike had an affair with a woman he met on the Internet. Every time he tried to talk to Sheila about his loneliness and feelings of disconnection, she would get defensive and accuse Mike of trying to shut down her needs professionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike said, "I never wanted her to stop working. I wanted her to be home with me. Eventually I started a relationship with this woman who advertised on adult websites. She never let me down, and whenever I was lonely, she was there for me."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, one or both partners may see an affair as a way to avoid conflict or intimacy, and eventually may see it as an exit from the relationship. In exploring why your partner pursued an affair, you may discover that he perceived that you exited the relationship first. This can be a difficult thing to accept, especially amid the fresh pain of a newly discovered affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the "why" of an affair is not as important as what happens after, if you can create a &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/books/" target="_hplink"&gt;new monogamy&lt;/a&gt;, together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information on creating your new monogamy and a new relationship together, &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Tammy Nelson is a world renowned sex and relationship expert and the author of &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/newmonogamyautographed/" target="_hplink"&gt;The New Monogamy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.drtammynelson.com/products-page/book/getting-the-sex-you-want-book/" target="_hplink"&gt;Getting the Sex You Want&lt;/a&gt;.   She can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.drtammynelson.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;www.drtammynelson.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063125/thumbs/s-INFIDELITY-mini.jpg?14" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Reality TV Star Files Counterclaim For Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/31/porsha-williams-divorce-reality-tv-star-files-counterclaim-for-divorce_n_2988350.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2988350</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T13:33:07Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T13:44:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>ATLANTA -- A lawyer for reality television star Porsha Williams says his client has filed a counterclaim for divorce against her former NFL player husband...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brennan-williams/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;ATLANTA -- A lawyer for reality television star Porsha Williams says his client has filed a counterclaim for divorce against her former NFL player husband Kordell Stewart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lawyer Randy Kessler said Friday that Williams responded with the counterclaim after former Pittsburgh Steelers quarterback Kordell Stewart filed for divorce in Fulton County Superior Court in Atlanta last week. Stewart's filing says his marriage to Williams is "irretrievably broken."&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The pair appears on Bravo's "The Real Housewives of Atlanta." Kessler said earlier this week that Williams learned of the divorce from the media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewart's filing says the two married on May 21, 2011, and have no children together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewart asks the court to find there are no marital assets to divide. He asks that neither side be ordered to pay alimony.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1058250/thumbs/s-STEWART-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Susan Patton: Why I Told Female Princeton Students To Find A Husband</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/susan-patton/why-i-told-female-princeton-students-to-find-a-husband_b_2988154.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2988154</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T13:13:50Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T13:14:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>The extreme reaction to my letter is astonishing. Honestly, it was intended as little more than honest advice from a Jewish mother.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Susan Patton</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/susan-patton/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Since publishing a &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-bahadur/susan-patton-daily-princetonian-find-a-husband-princeton_b_2979789.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_hplink"&gt;letter to the editor in the &lt;em&gt;Daily Princetonian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Friday, some people have asked me to clarify whether I intended it to be read as satire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My letter was serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sincerely feel that too much focus has been placed on encouraging young women only to achieve professionally. I understand that this can be seen as retrogressive, but for those women who aspire to what used to be thought of as a traditional life with home and family, there is almost no ink addressing personal fulfillment outside of the workplace. Specifically, finding lifelong friends and the right partner with whom to share a life and raise a family.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I understand that all women don't want marriage (to men or other women) and or children, but for those that do, identifying the right partner is critical. One of the criteria by which I am defining the right partner is someone with shared educational and intellectual appreciation. Yes, that can be found after college and outside of Princeton, but the concentration of outstanding men (and women) will never be greater than it is as a student. I wanted to encourage the wonderful young women on Princeton's campus to take advantage of this while they can. From a sheer numbers perspective, the odds will never be as good again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popularity of Nikki Mueller's video (&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YDhf9qwiA34" target="_hplink"&gt;I Went to Princeton, Bitch&lt;/a&gt;) comically attests to the difficulty Princeton women face from men who are threatened by their academic credentials. It doesn't address how unsatisfying it is for exceptionally well educated women to be with men who are not their intellectual equal. I am divorced. I did not marry a Princeton man. I wish I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://nymag.com/thecut/2013/03/princeton-mom-to-all-students-find-a-husband.html" target="_hplink"&gt;extreme reaction to my letter&lt;/a&gt; is astonishing. Honestly, it was intended as little more than honest advice from a Jewish mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, yes, this is exactly the advice I would give my daughters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RELATED ON &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/women/" target="_hplink"&gt;HUFFPOST WOMEN&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/nina-bahadur/susan-patton-daily-princetonian-find-a-husband-princeton_b_2979789.html?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women?utm_hp_ref=women&amp;ir=Women" target="_hplink"&gt;7 Questions For The Alumna Telling Princeton Women To 'Find A Husband'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063759/thumbs/s-PRINCETON-FIND-A-HUSBAND-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>John Blumenthal: What Every Post 50 Gentleman Needs to Know</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/john-blumenthal/dating-over-50-etiquette_b_2945728.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2945728</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-31T12:38:01Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-31T12:38:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>All women expect you to act like a gentleman but the definition of that word has become decidedly cloudy in today's complicated world.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>John Blumenthal</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/john-blumenthal/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;It is 1963 and you are 10 years old. One night, your family decides to go out to dinner. When you arrive at the restaurant, your father opens the car door for your mother. At the entrance, he opens that door too, then politely ushers her inside. In the foyer, he helps her remove her coat. When you arrive at your table, your mother stands by her chair and your father pulls it out for her. As her buttocks descend towards the seat, he pushes it forward with impeccable timing. When the waitress comes over, your father orders the food. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 1963 standards, your father was a perfect gentleman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how you were taught to treat women and this is how you treated your high school sweetheart when you were 16, although there was always the risk that the chair-pulling exercise could have tragic results if your timing was a little off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then things changed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is 1971 and you are a college freshman. Books have been written about a new concept called "women's lib," but you have not read them. You have always respected the rights of women, but you are clueless about the new etiquette. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ask a girl out and take her to a pizza joint. When you rush to open the car door for her, she is already in the process of opening it herself, thus accidentally slamming you in the knees; when you hurry to open the restaurant door, she tells you she is more than capable of opening a door by herself; when you try to help her remove her coat, she thinks you are assaulting her from behind and defensively elbows you in the stomach; when you try to pull out her chair, she gives you a look that says, "Are you kidding me?" Things go downhill from there; you do not get a second date. She thinks you are weird. Your ego is bruised, as are your kneecaps. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flash forward. Now you are 60 and recently divorced. You start dating again but you have no idea what is expected of you in the etiquette department. Your ex-wife had demanded very little of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having come of age in the 1960s, you may have decided that the gentlemanly arts as practiced by your father are obsolete and that it is sufficient simply to come across as a kind, considerate, caring fellow. But your date will not know that right away. Your mastery of the gentlemanly arts might play a significant role in making a good first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The women you date will probably be about your age, which means they have experienced the same changes in etiquette. But nowadays, many women prefer the old style and find it charming and perhaps mandatory to have car doors opened for them by older men like you; others would rather do things for themselves. What to do? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best advice is to play it by ear. If she remains in the car for more than five seconds after you have parked, this can mean one of two things -- either she has somehow become glued to the car seat or she expects you to open the door for her; if she glowers when you attempt to open the front door, let her do it for herself or suffer a collision as the door hits you in the face as you both struggle to open it; helping her remove her coat will always be an area of confusion and you do not want her elbow and your solar plexus to meet; if you try to pull her chair out for her, chances are she and everybody else in the place will think you're an idiot because nobody does that anymore except maybe at nursing homes in Britain. Should you order for her? Who the hell knows? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All women expect you to act like a gentleman but the definition of that word has become decidedly cloudy in today's complicated world. Times change. Two-hundred years ago, men covered puddles with their bodies so their dates would not get their feet wet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chivalry however, is not entirely dead. You are free to slay any dragons that may lurk in the restaurant parking lot should they breathe fire at your date (unless she has a black belt in &lt;em&gt;tae kwon do&lt;/em&gt;, in which case you will feel profoundly humiliated). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063757/thumbs/s-DATING-OVER-50-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Meryl Streep's Daughter Ends Her Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/30/mamie-gummer-benjamin-walker-split_n_2985199.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2985199</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T18:20:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T18:20:02Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Meryl Streep's daughter is calling it quits with her husband of almost two years. Mamie Gummer and Benjamin Walker have split, her rep tells Us...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Leigh Blickley</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/leigh-blickley/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Meryl Streep's daughter is calling it quits with her husband of almost two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/news/mamie-gummer-husband-benjamin-walker-split-meryl-streeps-daughter-ending-marriage-2013303" target="_hplink"&gt;Mamie Gummer and Benjamin Walker have split&lt;/a&gt;, her rep tells Us Weekly, adding, "It's very amicable."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/15/emily-owens-md-premiere-mamie-gummer_n_1966650.html" target="_hplink"&gt;The "Emily Owens, M.D." star&lt;/a&gt;, 29, met &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/vanity-fair/ben-walker-on-emcat-on-a_b_2689932.html" target="_hplink"&gt;fellow actor Walker&lt;/a&gt;, 30, in 2008 while performing in the Broadway production of "Les Liaisons Dangereuses" together. They &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2010/10/14/meryl-streeps-daughter-ma_n_762442.html" target="_hplink"&gt;announced their engagement in Oct. 2009&lt;/a&gt; and officially tied the knot at the Gummer's Connecticut estate in July 2011, in front of fellow stars like Claire Danes and Laura Linney. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A source close to Gummer, who is the daughter of Streep and her longtime husband, sculptor Don Gummer, says &lt;a href="http://www.justjared.com/2013/03/30/benjamin-walker-mamie-gummer-split/" target="_hplink"&gt;the break up is "very new."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063501/thumbs/s-MAMIE-GUMMER-BENJAMIN-WALKER-SPLIT-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Lisa Arends: The Most Valuable Lesson The End Of My Marriage Taught Me</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-arends/10-lessons-i-learned-from_b_2926625.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2926625</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T05:47:03Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T17:03:35Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When I found myself suddenly single at the age of 32 after being betrayed by my best friend and</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Lisa Arends</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/lisa-arends/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Often, the lessons we need most are the ones we are most resistant to. I never wanted to be divorced. In fact, losing my husband, through any means, was my greatest fear in life. So, when I found myself suddenly single at the age of 32 after being betrayed by my best friend and partner of 16 years, I was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best lessons can often be found when we are facing unanticipated change and loss. It is a window where we are lost and searching, broken and vulnerable, wanting and open. It is a time when the ego has been forcefully stripped away and we are able to face those challenging lessons that we may usually avoid. In those moments, we learn who we really are and what we are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are some of the lessons I learned on the heels of my divorce:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
1) When gratitude is your wrapping paper, everything is a gift.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You cannot always change your circumstances, but you can always change your attitude. I wasted time after the divorce being angry and playing victim. Slowly, ever so slowly, I began to soften and to look at the bigger picture. The divorce and its associated trauma happened; I could not alter that reality. I could, however, choose to change my reaction. I have begun to practice radical gratitude -- being thankful for the man who deceived and abandoned me. I began by writing a list of ten reasons I am thankful for him and I continue to write a note of gratitude every time I make a payment on the debt he left behind. The situation hasn't changed, but I now can view my divorce as a springboard for better things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Happiness is my choice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I used to tell my husband, "You make me happy." I meant those words as a compliment, an endearment. I wanted him to know how much he meant to me. When he left, I realized that if he truly made me happy, then he also took my potential well-being out the door with him. I also began to see the unfair burden I placed on him by making him the keeper of my happiness. That was not fair to him or to me. I have learned to take responsibility for my own happiness. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
3) The past doesn't stay buried.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My ex husband came from an alcoholic family. He denounced their dynamics and always said that his biggest fear was turning into his father. I took his word for it; I thought he was safe from their destructive patterns since he was aware of them and wanted to make different choices. I underestimated the power of the past. If there is one thing that alcoholic families excel at, it's keeping secrets. Apparently those lessons of silence and secrets were too embedded for him to overcome. The skill set was just waiting in the wings until the right moment came along. When he began to struggle during our marriage (with money, alcohol, depression, employment... who knows?), his reflexes kicked in and he covered it up. The past is like a vampire -- if you try to defeat it solely by burying it, it will come back to bite you.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4) "Knew" is not the same as "know."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I met my husband when I was just 16. I knew his family. I knew everything from the name of his elementary school to his biggest fears and wishes in life. I thought I knew him. I could describe every little nuance of my husband with the utmost confidence. It was misplaced confidence. I didn't realize that the man I knew was no longer the man in front of me. We are all fluid, changing with age and environment. Getting to know someone never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Work avoidance goes both ways.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have always had a tendency to work. A lot. I always saw that as a positive trait, an asset. It was only more recently that I realized that my drive to work was often out of a fear of what I would see if I slowed down. The divorce acted like a highlighter in my life, illuminating areas that I used to avoid through work. I learned to slow down and to trust in my ability to face the present. I now breathe through discomfort rather than try to hide from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) The body often knows more than the mind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For the last couple years of my marriage, I seemed to catch every cold that came through the school where I worked. I had trouble sleeping, often waking in the middle of the night. I sensed a tension coursing through my body -- a low-level, yet ever-present anxiety. Since there were no outward signs of discord in my marriage, I assumed the tension was due to a difficult time at work. I was shocked to realize, after I recovered from the initial trauma of the abandonment, that my body was more relaxed than it had been in years. I now listen to my body's messages even when they seem unfounded. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
7) Wellness is not measured in hours at the gym.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I used to think I was well. I ate a healthy diet, exercised daily and even managed to do a little yoga once in a while. I used to think I was well, but I wasn't. After the divorce, I had to rebuild my health and this time, I had a much more holistic and balanced approach. I became a math teacher after struggling with the material myself as a child. I was drawn to wellness coaching for a similar reason. It allows me to utilize my teaching skills along with what I have learned about wellness from a balanced standpoint after my own journey. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
8) There is a difference between trust and complacency.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My ex husband gained my trust over many years. He held his word and voiced his thoughts. I trusted him completely. I trusted him so much that I became complacent. I assumed the trust would remain and that he would continue to be honest and faithful. I assumed wrong. I have learned to trust again (through the help of my dog!) but I will never again become complacent. My eyes now remain wide open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) Life is not a waiting room.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I used to be an expert at delaying life. I would prioritize work and promise myself a break in some imagined future. I would squirrel away money, imaging it being saved for some mythical future. When the divorce washed away my life in one destructive wave, I realized that I was waiting rather than living. I still work hard and I'm still frugal by nature, but I no longer put life off for the future. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
10) Holding is out of love; clinging is out of fear.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I never would have described myself as clingy with my ex -- I was independent (often too much so), not jealous and was frequently apart from him for long periods while he traveled. It was only afterwards that I saw how clingy I truly was. With clinging, you are desperately attached to an outcome, grasping out of fear. I was clinging in a way and it was holding me still, static, unable to move. I now have healthy desires and passions which encourage investment in the now and the goal, but not in the outcomes that are out of my control. I realize that this describes my current relationship. I am so much more relaxed about the "outcome." Facing my fears has had a way of diminishing them. I am no less committed to the current relationship, no less in love. But it feels different. I'm not grasping. I'm holding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some of these lessons, I am now doing master's level work. With others, I am repeating the introductory course. Either way, it is okay. The point is not to get an "A," rather the intention is to be open to new lessons and to persevere through even the most difficult tutorials. I just hope I don't have to endure such a harsh teacher again!&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063124/thumbs/s-DIVORCE-LESSONS-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Emma Johnson: What To Say To A Divorcing Friend</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-johnson/should-you-always-say-im-_b_2935944.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935944</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-30T05:38:06Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-30T05:39:01Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Over the past few years, I've had interesting discussions around the question, "Should you say 'I'm sorry,' when someone reveals they're getting divorced?"</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Emma Johnson</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/emma-johnson/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;My son Lucas is going through a phase when he misses his dad a lot. When he stubs his toe, or is trying to unwind at bedtime, he calls out, "I want Daaadddy." There is an uncomplicated and raw sorrow there that is different than the other many times he cries in a given day. I imagine during these moments he thinks to the comfort of his dad, who lives a mile away, and who he sees twice each week. Maybe when you're barely three, the sadness of not getting a sprinkle cookie bleeds into the sadness of missing a parent. I don't know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know that it is sad, no matter what. Divorce comes with sadness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I've had interesting discussions around the question, "Should you say 'I'm sorry,' when someone reveals they're getting divorced?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some argue that is not an appropriate response because you never know how the announcer feels about the split. If they're thrilled at their new freedom, or blissful at banishing a bad spouse, why would a condolence be in order?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear that argument loud and clear. After all, I've written numerous times that I was surprised to find that I was am &lt;a href="http://www.wealthysinglemommy.com/what-if-your-failed-marriage-was-really-a-success/" target="_hplink"&gt;much happier outside of my own marriage&lt;/a&gt;. Despite the wrenching heartache, destroyed dreams and turning my life topsy-turvy, the net result of my divorce has been positive, I've felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I fall in favor of offering up a polite, "I'm sorry," as a pat response when someone reveals their relationship is over. After all, "I'm sorry" is always appropriate upon learning of the end of a life. It is the prerogative of the mourner to say, "It was a blessing -- they were suffering," or "It was quick, and we are grateful we can all move on now." There is nearly always at least a note of sadness when someone dies. Custom and sensitivity call for condolences, no matter the feelings or assumptions of the person hearing the news. The same holds true for the end of a relationship. Even if the final result was positive, pain and grief are always part of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking through this issue last night as the kids were getting ready for bedtime. "Look," I said to Lucas we stood in the kitchen, arguing over whether he had to eat the last bite of his banana. "Look at all the snow outside!"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked him up so he could see the large clumps of flakes fall down to coat the street below. We pointed at the birds in the tree outside that window, and wondered whether they were cold, or if their fluffed-up feathers kept them warm. Something in this sleepy moment, maybe feeling vulnerable in the weather or sensing a call for a cozy embrace, Lucas cried out as he does. Cried out for his Daddy. His dad moved out before Lucas was born, but who hasn't felt that dull ache of missing someone you love?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I held Lucas to me and he quickly nuzzled his head into my neck. Tristian Prettyman's &lt;br /&gt;
"All I Want is You" came on the radio, and as I swayed to the sweet melody and silly lyrics, I could see Lucas and my reflection in the window. Behind us was the gold glow of our warm apartment. I had one of the moments I sometimes have -- moments when I well up with the feeling of being a proud and confident mother lion, presiding over the safe den I've created for my babies. But in that image of that strong mom was also my hurt child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"I'm sorry," I said. Lucas let his body hang heavy in my arms as I swayed and swayed. "I'm sorry."&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063121/thumbs/s-IM-SORRY-DIVORCE-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>My Proudest Moment As A Stepparent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/stepparents_n_2981073.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2981073</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T22:32:09Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T23:20:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Every stepparent remembers the moment they finally earned their stepkids' seal of approval. It's a meaningful moment -- as any stepparent can tell you, a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Every stepparent remembers the moment they finally earned their stepkids' seal of approval. It's a meaningful moment -- as any stepparent can tell you, a stepchild's trust can be hard won, sometimes taking years and years to gain. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1b8qa9/as_a_stepdad_of_3_this_was_my_proudest_moment_to/" target="_hplink"&gt;Redditor Jedi_Hog shared his shiningest moment&lt;/a&gt; as a stepparent -- in meme form. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="2013-03-29-ScreenShot20130329at3.02.26PM.png" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2013-03-29-ScreenShot20130329at3.02.26PM.png" width="398" height="402" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.quickmeme.com/meme/3tkwcq/" target="_hplink"&gt;quickmeme.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stepdad's success story won over Reddit, with fellow stepparents and stepkids weighing in with their personal stories in the comments. We were especially touched by Redditor MorganaLeFaye's &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1b8qa9/as_a_stepdad_of_3_this_was_my_proudest_moment_to/" target="_hplink"&gt;sweet tribute to her stepdad: &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My dad is the man who raised me. I met him when I was four.

&lt;p&gt;He's the one that put the band-aids on skinned knees and went to my school plays even though he really didn't want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's the one who got very awkward whenever I would cry because he really didn't know what to do to fix me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He's the man who went to McDonalds or Taco Bell when my mom was working late and he was put in charge of "making us a healthy, well balanced dinner."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the man who hooked the stereo speakers up to the TV when I was very young and turned our living room into a movie theater so we could watch Jurassic Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the man who walked me down the aisle and cried on my wedding day as he told me how beautiful I looked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He may not be genetically related to me, but he is in every sense my father.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to extend the love by asking our readers to share their proudest moments as stepparents. Click through the slideshow below for some of our favorite responses, then head to the comments and tell us about your best stepparent stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289220--HH&gt;`&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1063084/thumbs/s-STEPPARENTING-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>5 Ways Divorce Will Impact Your Finances</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/five-ways-divorce-will-im_n_2980949.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980949</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T20:35:45Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:35:12Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Divorce can hurt the pocketbook in ways that some people don’t expect. Lost income, child support, spousal support all hurt. But there are other ways...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>www.latimes.com</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Divorce can hurt the pocketbook in ways that some people don’t expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lost income, child support, spousal support all hurt. But there are other ways that divorce affects finances, said Samantha Fraelich, vice president of Bernard R. Wolfe &amp; Associates, a Chevy Chase, Md., wealth management firm. Here are five of them:&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062759/thumbs/s-FINANCES-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>LOOK: One Realtor's Creative Alternative To Divorce</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/funny-billboard-_n_2980138.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2980138</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:52:08Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T19:19:29Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Why divorce when you can just get a bigger house? That's the logic Toronto real estate agent Chris Clarke put to use on a billboard...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;Why divorce when you can just get a bigger house? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's the logic Toronto real estate agent Chris Clarke put to use on a billboard &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/1b4z8a/realtor_logic/" target="_hplink"&gt;posted on Reddit by ShiftyBizniss&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday. Take a look here: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/CgsMVJa"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CgsMVJa.jpg" alt="" title="Hosted by imgur.com" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem solved, unhappily married couples! (And just in case the realtor's logic is lost on you, here's &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/1b4z8a/realtor_logic/c93yyk2" target="_hplink"&gt;Redditor TryptamineTea's&lt;/a&gt; helpful explainer: "Buy a bigger house, and you won't have to deal with each other.") &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062634/thumbs/s-CGSMVJA-mini.jpg?12" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>5 Bad Boyz Who May Or May Not Be Using Charity To Repair Their Image</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/5-bad-boy-celebrities-turned-good_n_2975507.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce&amp;ir=Divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2975507</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:07:46Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T20:20:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It seems like more often than not lately, celebrity bad boys make headlines for the decisions that could land them in the slammer or at...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>The Huffington Post</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/eleanor-goldberg/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;It seems like more often than not lately, celebrity bad boys make headlines for the decisions that could land them in the slammer or at the very least, make their moms hang their heads in shame. But even some of the worst offenders know better than to only leave behind a trail of sins. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five famous guys below have tarnished images, but are working to get their reputations out of the gutter by putting their money and names behind noteworthy causes, and, of course, pairing the effort with a pic that makes you go "Awww."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRINCE HARRY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="prince harry" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062216/thumbs/o-PRINCE-HARRY-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prince Harry can be a royal pain in the butt. Literally. Last summer, this regal bad boy bore his privates to the world when &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/21/prince-harry-nude-pics-photos_n_1820333.html" target="_blank"&gt;nude photos of him playing strip billiards&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas were leaked. But Will’s little bro has since cleaned up his traveling act. Harry spent time with &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/27/prince-harry-lesotho-charity-photos_n_2772676.html" target="_blank"&gt;disadvantaged African children&lt;/a&gt; in February and is&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/25/prince-harry-vets-us-trip_n_2947663.html?utm_hp_ref=impact" target="_blank"&gt; planning a trip to the U.S.&lt;/a&gt; to visit vets and Hurricane Sandy victims, all activities that require being fully clothed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHRIS BROWN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="chris brown" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062227/thumbs/o-CHRIS-BROWN-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, Chris Brown apologized, and Rihanna forgave him. But even though he may never get back into public's good graces, the defamed rapper is apparently set on proving he's a changed man. His recently-launched charity, the &lt;a href="https://api.viglink.com/api/click?format=go&amp;key=5b0c3ed66765f886c6984ee1c41b292d&amp;loc=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Ftmp%2F2975507_93.html%3Fpreview%3Dyes&amp;v=1&amp;libid=1364578997291&amp;out=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.huffingtonpost.com%2F2012%2F11%2F05%2Fchris-brown-launches-charity-symphonic-love_n_2078689.html&amp;ref=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Fentry%2F%3Fentry_id%3D2975507&amp;title=Chris%20Brown%2C%20Prince%20Harry%2C%20Other%20Bad%20Boys%20Who%20May%20Or%20May%20Not%20Be%20Using%20Charity%20To%20Repair%20Their%20Image&amp;txt=the%20Symphonic%20Love%20Foundation&amp;jsonp=vglnk_jsonp_13645798136212" target="_hplink"&gt;Symphonic Love Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, and artist Romero Britto joined forces to paint a &lt;a href="https://api.viglink.com/api/click?format=go&amp;key=5b0c3ed66765f886c6984ee1c41b292d&amp;loc=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Ftmp%2F2975507_93.html%3Fpreview%3Dyes&amp;v=1&amp;libid=1364578997291&amp;out=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.huffingtonpost.com%2F2013%2F03%2F28%2Fchris-brown-symphonic-love-foundation-graffiti-best-buddies_n_2970935.html&amp;ref=https%3A%2F%2Feditorial.huffingtonpost.com%2Fentry%2F%3Fentry_id%3D2975507&amp;title=Chris%20Brown%2C%20Prince%20Harry%2C%20Other%20Bad%20Boys%20Who%20May%20Or%20May%20Not%20Be%20Using%20Charity%20To%20Repair%20Their%20Image&amp;txt=paint%20a%20graffiti%20mural%20&amp;jsonp=vglnk_jsonp_13645798264373" target="_hplink"&gt;graffiti mural&lt;/a&gt; to raise funds for Best Buddies International, an organization that supports people with developmental disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHARLIE SHEEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="charlie sheen" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062243/thumbs/o-CHARLIE-SHEEN-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/01/19/charlie-sheen-spends-26k-on-prostitutes-in-cocaine-filled-weekend_n_810821.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Charlie Sheen&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps best known for dropping thousands on prostitutes and cocaine, but the troubled star has also been throwing money at worthy causes as of late. The former “Two and a Half Men” star gave &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/12/11/charlie-sheen-jasmine-faulk_n_2277886.html" target="_hplink"&gt;$75,000 to a young girl with cancer &lt;/a&gt;in December, pledged $50,000 last summer to the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/06/charlie-sheen-cincinnati-reds-fund_n_1746600.html " target="_hplink"&gt;Cincinnati Reds Fund,&lt;/a&gt; which helps improve the lives of youth in the community, and in February, he &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/15/charlie-sheen-therapy-dog_n_2694278.html" target="_hplink"&gt;bought a therapy dog for a girl who was injured&lt;/a&gt; in a freak amusement park accident. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KOBE BRYANT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="kobe bryant" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062301/thumbs/o-KOBE-BRYANT-570.jpg?7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 2003 sexual assault charge marred his reputation, but &lt;a href="http://videos.huffingtonpost.com/entertainment/kobe-bryant-says-that-the-rape-charge-made-him-a-better-person-517420405" target="_hplink"&gt;Kobe Bryant &lt;/a&gt;says that the experience has made him a “better person.” Part of his image makeover included opening the &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/06/07/kobe-bryant-announces-new_n_872761.html" target="_hplink"&gt;Kobe and Vanessa Bryant Family Foundation,&lt;/a&gt; a nonprofit that’s working to end youth homelessness in Los Angeles. The Lakers star also turned an injury into a positive moment when he &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/05/09/kobe-bryants-mask-charity_n_1502593.html" target="_hplink"&gt;auctioned off the facemask&lt;/a&gt; he wore after breaking his nose to raise funds for his charity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAY LEWIS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="ray lewis" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062312/thumbs/o-RAY-LEWIS-570.jpg?6" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What murder charge? &lt;a href="http://baltimore.cbslocal.com/2013/01/24/5-common-misconceptions-about-ray-lewis-murder-trial/" target="_hplink"&gt;Ray Lewis &lt;/a&gt;was charged, and eventually acquitted, in the 2000 deaths of two Atlanta men, but the public seems to have long forgiven the Super Bowl champion. He helped gain the favor of fans by getting involved with people in need in Baltimore. He launched the&lt;a href="http://rlff.org/mainhome/" target="_hplink"&gt;Ray Lewis Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, a nonprofit that helps disadvantaged youth and families and the famed linebacker &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/nfl/playoffs/2012/story/_/id/8803657/ray-lewis-unquestioned-hall-fame-credentials-legacy-complicated" target="_hplink"&gt;distributes school supplies &lt;/a&gt;to needy kids and provides toys for kids at Christmas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do you think? Do these bad boyz have their hearts in the right place now or are these simply charity stunts? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062481/thumbs/s-CHRIS-BROWN-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Blended Family Friday: Meet Mimi and Stu's Family</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/blended-family-friday_n_2975161.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2975161</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:04:58Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T18:04:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>As part of our Blended Family Friday series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Brittany Wong</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of our &lt;strong&gt;Blended Family Friday&lt;/strong&gt; series, each week we're spotlighting a different stepfamily to learn how they successfully blended their two families together. Our hope is that by telling their stories, we'll bring you closer to blended family bliss in your own life!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we'd like you to meet Mimi and Stu and their four kids. The unique thing about this blended family? Their incredible (and enviable!) relationship with their former spouses. Read on for their inspiring story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi, Mimi! Please introduce us to your family. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My husband Stu and I have been married almost eight years. Between us we have four children. Our oldest is Austin. He's 18 and nearly ready to leave the nest.  He will be swimming for the University of Tennessee in the fall. Next is Camille. She will be 17 in April. The "little girls" are 12. Phoebe and Ansley are twins through marriage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the biggest challenges of blended family life? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Blending a family is never easy and the beginning was rough. The biggest challenge was for the children to suddenly have to share "their parent" with the other kids. Stu and I worked very hard to show love and affection to all four of them. We ate dinner together every night. We played a lot of wiffle ball games together, had family movie nights and went to all of the kids' events as a family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What's the best thing about being part of a blended family? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When Stu and I came together, we did not just put our kids under one roof, we reached out to our ex spouses. We included Blaire (Stu's ex-wife) and Steve (my ex-husband) in our family. The former spouses are a huge part of our lives! We invite them to everything: Christmas, Thanksgiving, birthdays, plays, sporting events, anything they could make. Stu and I have the children most of the time, but Stu's ex-wife lives near us and is often with us, too. She even spends the night on Christmas Eve so that she can see the kids get their Santa gifts. I think the best thing about our blended family is that we have four adults working together to support each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What makes you proudest of your family?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our kids refer to Stu, Steve, Blaire and me as "the parents" and ask any of us for advice in times of need. I am so proud of all of us. We have put the children first and have created a real family. In fact, Stu and I have to travel for work soon and Steve will be staying at our house taking care of all four kids! We all work together and our children are thriving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What advice do you have for other blended families who feel like a peaceful dynamic is out of reach?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My advice to anyone working on blending a family is to always put the child first. Never, ever, say a negative word about your ex in front of your child. Be flexible and patient. It takes time. Always remember when the kids are acting out it's because they are hurting. Take a deep breath and think of a way to lift them up. Be kind to your former spouse.  Try to include them in your child's life. Your children deserve loving adults in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click through the slideshow the see photos of Mimi and Stu's family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you'd like your own family to be featured on a Blended Family Friday, please email us at  &lt;a href="mailto:divorce@huffingtonpost.com" target="_hplink"&gt;divorce@huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt;. We're looking forward to hearing your story! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;HH--236SLIDEEXPAND--289095--HH&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep in touch! Check out HuffPost Divorce on &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/HuffPostDivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/huffpostdivorce" target="_hplink"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061525/thumbs/s-BLENDED-FAMILY-FRIDAY-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Jennifer Gardella: Why Divorce Is Like The Shawshank Tunnel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-gardella/post_4550_b_2935681.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2935681</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T18:01:36Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T18:01:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Gold seal, signed papers, judge's gavel -- no matter how your divorced is finalized, the official ends marks the start of your post divorce life.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jennifer Gardella</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-gardella/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Gold seal, signed papers, judge's gavel -- no matter how your divorced is finalized, the official ends marks the start of your post divorce life. For many, this time resembles the crawl through the infamous Shawshank Tunnel. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
You may know the scene from the movie: Andy Dufresne escapes from prison through a sewage pipe and crawls through 500 yards "smelling foulness I can't even imagine." This is very similar to the post-divorce proverbial tunnel. For you, it may feel dark, it may actually smell foul, you may wonder what will happen next, and often ask "when will it ever end?"&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Everyone who enters the post-divorce tunnel has a very different set of tasks to complete.  You may need to find a place to live, a new job and secure health insurance. All sorts of accounts will need to be separated and possessions divided. Your ex could be parading around a new significant other and that requires adjustment. You may be changing your name, opening new financial accounts and learning to cook for one. There may be substantial emotional healing to process and strength to build. There is a lot to be dealt with in the tunnel. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a divorced mom of three daughters, I am often called upon by &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jennifer-gardella/your-divorce-welcome-wago_b_2451272.html" target="_hplink"&gt;friends and strangers for my best advice on how to get through their divorce&lt;/a&gt;.  And while I have helped them to see that all will be ok, I actually haven't been able give them advice on how to get through the tunnel, because until recently, I never experienced it. When I came out of my marriage, I jumped into two back-to-back relationships, each shielding me from the tunnel experience. I was not required to find full-time employment because I was working on my doctorate, and then worked for my most recent ex. I didn't have to find a place to live because &lt;a href="http://njdivorcedmoms.blogspot.com/2013/02/why-my-children-nest.html" target="_hplink"&gt;when I wasn't with my kids,&lt;/a&gt; I stayed with my boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in January, my relationship ended and I found myself about to enter the Shawshank tunnel for the first time. I was devastated. It wasn't the end of the relationship that caused me pain, the end was a relief. Rather, it was a feeling of "how did I get to a point where at 43 years old, I am homeless for half of each month, unemployed (since I had worked for my ex), still have an incomplete dissertation, too much weight on my hips, and a high BMI?" Just as Andy was desperate to get into that tunnel and start crawling to a better life, well, so was I. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I started to craw,l I was shocked to realize a newfound abundance of emotional energy.  Previously, every last bit of that energy had been dumped into a relationship that hadn't been working. With that emotional space free, I found great peace, and saw nothing but opportunities. In fact, I was happier than ever, even though I was crawling through proverbial sewage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, there is a beautiful simplicity to the tunnel. Your choices are limited to standing still, going forward or moving backward.  I had absolutely no desire to stay stuck or go backward, so forward I moved. Some steps have been big, some have been messy, and others I have taken on blind faith. I just keep moving, focused and determined.  Self doubt lives in the sewage of the tunnel and I suffocate it when it surfaces. My inner core strength and close circle of friends act as continual reminders that I am strong enough, talented enough, and resourceful enough to make it out to the other side. Armed with my newfound feeling of inner peace, my resolve is stronger than ever. I have fully embraced the process of tunnel crawling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tunnel allows great focus because you just can't stand up and look around, after all, you are in a tiny tunnel; if you stand up you'll hit your head. Also, there aren't many distractions in the tunnel, so I remain focused. Well that's not entirely true, I have allowed one distraction in -- hey, a girl can have a little fun, can't she?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have I accomplished so far while crawling in the tunnel?  I have found a very peaceful space to stay with two amazing friends when I am not with my children. These fabulous women have welcomed me into their families and homes and just as important as the roof over my head is the friendship they provide. I have also finished my dissertation which I will defend in early April and I am contracted to teach during the summer. When I first jumped into the tunnel, I made a commitment to eating healthier and exercising more. I've lost 15 pounds, fit into my skinny jeans (filled out better than ever due to endless squats) and my BMI is normal. Oh, and did I mention I'm launching a business? Not too bad for eight weeks.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
But while many pieces have come together, I'm still in the tunnel.  Next up is getting my professional life in order. My business launches in late April and the job search continues. My amazing business coach &lt;a href="http://www.marcuspadulchick.com/" target="_hplink"&gt;Marcus Padulchick&lt;/a&gt; has helped me realize that I should go in search of the right job, not just any job.  I have built a diverse skill set and impressive credentials over the last 20 years and the right job will come along. I thank Marcus in my heart every day for his sage advice. I'm committed to the process of the tunnel and want the process to work itself out in the right time.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This crawling that I have done has brought fullness to my life I never anticipated. Opportunities, ideas, and most importantly, people have found their way to my path and are extraordinary additions. This stage of putting together the foundation of my post-divorce life is exciting.  While I am enjoying my time in the tunnel, I am looking forward to crawling out -- but I'm just not there yet.  A little more time in the tunnel will do me some good.  And at the end of the tunnel is when the building work begins. Building on all of this excitement, finding the right person to share it with, and then the beginning of my journey to my Zihuatanejo.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>'Pregnant Man's' Divorce Rejected</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/29/pregnant-man-judge-reject_n_2979968.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/thenewswire//2.2979968</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T17:33:23Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T19:13:06Z</updated>
    
    <summary>PHOENIX &amp;mdash; An Arizona judge on Friday refused to grant a divorce for a transgender Arizona man who gave birth to three children after beginning...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>AP</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/brittany-wong/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/thenewswire/">
        &lt;p&gt;PHOENIX &amp;mdash; An Arizona judge on Friday refused to grant a divorce for a transgender Arizona man who gave birth to three children after beginning to change his sex from female.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maricopa County Family Court Judge Douglas Gerlach ruled that Arizona's ban on same-sex marriages prevents Thomas Beatie's 9-year union from being recognized as valid.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Thomas Beatie was born a woman and later underwent a double-mastectomy, and began testosterone hormone therapy and psychological treatment to become a man, but he retained female reproductive organs and gave birth to three children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerlach said he had no jurisdiction to approve a divorce because there's insufficient evidence that Beatie was a man when he married Nancy Beatie in Hawaii. He said the Beaties never provided records to fully explain what Thomas Beatie actually had done and not done to become a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The decision here is not based on the conclusion that this case involves a same-sex marriage merely because one of the parties is a transsexual male, but instead, the decision is compelled by the fact that the parties failed to prove that (Thomas Beatie) was a transsexual male when they were issued their marriage license," he wrote in Friday's ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spokesman for Beatie, Ryan Gordon, said the judge's comments came as a shock and that Beatie plans to appeal the ruling. He said Beatie legally was married as a man and never was required to disclose that he retained female reproductive organs when applying for and being granted a new birth certificate in Hawaii as a man. He said Beatie halted testosterone treatments so that he could give birth to his children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"It's unfortunate that the judge out here doesn't recognize marriage in another state," Gordon said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beatie is eager to end his marriage, but the couple's divorce plans stalled last summer when Gerlach said he was unable to find legal authority defining a man as someone who can give birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerlach's ruling didn't address whether Arizona law allows a person who was born female to marry another female after undergoing a sex change operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A separate ruling issued Friday by Gerlach sets guidelines on how the Beaties will co-parent their three children and grants them joint authority in making legal decisions. Thomas Beatie is required to pay nearly $240 a month to Nancy Beatie for child support, but she won't get alimony because the marriage was declared invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nancy Beatie's attorney, David Higgins, praised Gerlach for the thoroughness of the decision on the marriage, although it wasn't the one she had hoped for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"He still sees a same-sex marriage, but he gave us all the rulings that we're asking for as far as the children," Higgins said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Center for Lesbian Rights, which isn't involved in the Beatie divorce case, has said courts have declared marriages involving a transgender person invalid in a handful of cases across the country, but that those cases had different factual and legal issues than those in the Beatie case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Beatie, known as "The Pregnant Man," was born Tracy Lehuanani Lagondino in Oahu, Hawaii. He began testosterone treatments in 1997 and underwent double mastectomy and chest reconstruction surgery in 2002. He changed his Hawaii driver's license to say he was a man and had a Hawaiian court approve his name change to Thomas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gerlach's ruling noted that Thomas Beatie halted the testosterone treatments and that he didn't provide documentation for any additional non-surgical efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Beatie married his partner Nancy in early 2003 in Honolulu and became pregnant because Nancy was unable to have children. Thomas Beatie conceived with donated sperm and gave birth to children who are now 4, 3 and 2 years old. The couple eventually moved to Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beatie has garnered a range of media attention, making the rounds on talk shows such as Larry King and Oprah Winfrey and winning a spot on Barbara Walters' list of "10 Most Fascinating People" in 2008, alongside President Barack Obama, conservative commentator Rush Limbaugh and swimmer Michael Phelps. He also published a book, "Labor Of Love: The Story of One Man's Extraordinary Pregnancy," the cover displaying an image of a shirtless Thomas sporting facial hair and holding a hand over his bare pregnant belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;___&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fonseca reported from Flagstaff, Ariz. Associated Press Writer Jacques Billeaud in Phoenix contributed to this report.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1062436/thumbs/s-PREGNANT-MAN-mini.jpg?7" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
  <entry>
	    <title>Allison Pescosolido, M.A: How To Keep Bad Communication From Ruining Your Marriage</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/allison-pescosolido-ma/the-dogs-and-cats-of-rela_b_2967168.html?utm_hp_ref=divorce"/>
    <id>tag:www.huffingtonpost.com,2013:/theblog//3.2967168</id>
    
    <published>2013-03-29T16:12:22Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-29T16:34:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Fighting like cats and dogs can be one sign that a couple may be heading towards divorce.</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Allison Pescosolido, M.A</name>
        <uri>http://www.huffingtonpost.com/allison-pescosolido-ma/</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/">
        &lt;p&gt;Fighting like cats and dogs can be one sign that a couple may be heading towards divorce.  Often, couples get caught in the trap of over analyzing, misinterpreting and building resentments because of simple errors in communication. These errors lead to conflict, resentments and oftentimes contentious divorce. Men and women often think differently, whether the cause is the brain or behavior. It is no wonder that within our conflicting patterns of communication the wires get crossed. When communication begins to break down, there is a simple solution: stop searching for hidden meaning.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Relationships are fraught with language, and frequent breakdowns in communication can cause major challenges. There are words we use to directly communicate, the non-verbal cues of facial expressions and body language and even the short-hand of shared experience that couples use when in private. Language, however, has its issues. In any mode of communication, there is a disparity between the intent of the message and perceived meaning of the message. This can cause problems, as we try to find meaning in words or actions that may essentially be meaningless. Within a relationship, this search for meaning can be dangerous. Misunderstanding and manufacturing intent for a perceived message lays the foundation for eventual divorce. &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Think of a dog and a cat. Their language, in fact their brains, read meanings in completely different ways. When &lt;a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/canine-corner/201112/what-dog-s-tail-wags-really-mean-some-new-scientific-data" target="_hplink"&gt;a dog wags its tail&lt;/a&gt; it is saying, "I'm happy; let's play." When &lt;a href="http://www.tailsinc.com/2012/09/understanding-cat-tail-language/" target="_hplink"&gt;a cat's tail flicks its tail&lt;/a&gt; it is saying, "I'm hunting; I'm about to pounce." You can see the language barrier clearly when observing pets interacting. When a dog approaches a cat, tail waving excitedly, the cat will shy away. The cat perceives the dog's actions as a threat. The same problem occurs in reverse. A dog will approach a cat with a waving tail thinking that the cat wants to play -- until it gets a swat in the face.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
We're the same way when interpreting the meaning of language, whether it's words, expressions or tones. Like the dog and cat, we need to keep from over-analyzing meaning behind the actions and words of others. When your significant other comes home from work with an attitude, it probably isn't you they are angry with. Or when your partner forgets that dinner with the Jones's is tonight, that doesn't mean they weren't listening. They probably have other things on their mind and trust you to keep them on track.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
If your spouse doesn't directly tell you something is wrong, don't assume that his or her actions are about you. One of the hardest things for people to do in relationships is to stop the cycle of interpreting meaning where there is no meaning. Here are three questions you can ask yourself before getting upset.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;•   Is this a one time occurrence or part of a pattern?&lt;/strong&gt; If its one time, drop it. Don't waste your energy on a fluke. If its a pattern that upsets you, address it with kindness and provide possible solutions. Keep in mind that the solution may involve changing your behavior. For example, if your spouse is always upset coming home from work, give them a little space. Leaving them alone for an hour will give them time to adjust from a rough day or long commute.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;•   Am I over-reading?&lt;/strong&gt; Like the dog and cat, we put meaning to actions and words. If your spouse says, "I'm tired; can I skip the party tonight?" they are probably just tired. They are not avoiding you or skipping your friends or family. Let them rest and feel comfortable going out on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•&lt;strong&gt;   Am I communicating clearly?&lt;/strong&gt; Are you wagging your tail and not getting the response you want? This could be a sign that your partner doesn't understand the language you are using. Instead of attempting subtlety, be clear with your intentions and actions. Facial expressions and body language might not be read correctly. If you don't directly state your feelings, he won't know them.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
A healthy relationship involves communication. But that communication needs to be clear and understandable. We also need to stop over analyzing our relationships. Don't interpret all of your spouses actions as a message to you. They aren't. Your spouse feels and sees the world through their own filters. If they want you to get a message, they will explicitly tell you. Relax into your relationship. That's one key to happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
        
    </content>
		<link src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/1061587/thumbs/s-COMMUNICATION-PROBLEM-mini.jpg?6" type="image/jpeg" rel="enclosure"/>
	
	
	
</entry>
</feed>
