<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Oh Clementine</title>
	<atom:link href="http://ohclementine.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://ohclementine.com</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:39:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Nice things</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/nice-things/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/nice-things/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3782</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello. Did you know I am very stressed right now? No? Why not? Is it because we never talk? I guess that could be why. Or maybe you do know that I am very stressed right now, and that I'm at a point where every overwhelming emotion turns into tears, and most emotions become overwhelming, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello. Did you know I am very stressed right now? No? Why not? Is it because we never talk? I guess that could be why. Or maybe you do know that I am very stressed right now, and that I'm at a point where every overwhelming emotion turns into tears, and most emotions become overwhelming, and really it sounds a lot worse than it really is. I have, like, three weeks of classes left, you know?</p>
<p>Okay, but, I'm very stressed, and I'm sleeping horribly a lot of the time, not always because I'm an asshole and stay up until 4am reading fanfiction, sometimes just because I'm too stressed to sleep and have early conferences in which everyone makes jokes about absolutist regimes while I write a letter to my aunt about the weather. So, there you go. However, I have been trying to do small but nice things to take care of myself, because I tend to neglect myself in favour of everything else, and as L'Oreal says, I AM WORTH IT. <em>OKAY</em>? I AM. So, here are some of the things I have been doing to keep myself from curling into the fetal position and shutting down completely.</p>
<h3>Working out</h3>
<p>God, RIGHT? This is ME we're talking about. One day I had this history midterm, and the thing is that when I have things to do for school I will do almost literally anything before the thing I actually need to do, and I was just like, "I should work out," and so I did, and now I mainly do it to procrastinate, but sometimes I do it JUST BECAUSE I WANT TO. Like, I actively get a hankering to make myself sweat and cramp up. God, who <em>am</em> I?</p>
<p>But, really, even though in the moment sometimes I'm like, "I would rather nail my eyeballs to a wall than hold this plank for one second longer," when it's done I feel really good. And I am noticing an improvement, which is cool, because being able to feel tangible progress is one of the best ways to keep me motivated. So. I am this person now, and even though I know exercise is a good thing, I kind of hate myself for it because I spent so long not being this person, and now I work out BEFORE class sometimes. Whereas in the rest of the history of my life, anything BEFORE school was time to sleep or endlessly browse Tumblr, and everything AFTER school was when I did things. I think I've really started to achieve adulthood here.</p>
<h3>Drinking tea</h3>
<p>This one might seem kind of stupid and frivolous, but my morning cup of tea really helps me wake up in a good mood, and my evening (read: midnight) cup of tea helps me relax and get in the right frame of mind for bedtime. And then there are the supplementary cups of tea throughout the day, of course. I've always been a big tea drinker, but I used to keep it all confined to the evening. Now I just drink tea all day, and, honestly, it's really nice. I think part of it is just having a routine, but it's also good to have something enjoyable to associate morning with. Because, yeah, I may be a person who works out before class sometimes, but I don't know if I'll ever be a morning person. Ugh.</p>
<h3>Spending time on my makeup</h3>
<p>I used to be very strongly against the idea of my makeup routine taking more than about 10 minutes out of my morning, mostly because I liked sleeping a lot. (Okay, I still do. Obviously.) Also, I saw makeup more as something I <em>had</em> to do, so I did the bare minimum things that I thought were necessary in order to put my face out into the world. These days, it takes me about 20-30 minutes every morning to do my makeup. Past me would be appalled. So many people I know would be appalled. 20-30 minutes isn't even that long, compared to a lot of other people, but it's long enough that I know a fair amount of people are reading this being like, "Ugh, why?" I just really enjoy not rushing it, and having fun with it, and being a bit indulgent for awhile. Taking half an hour just for myself, to do something completely frivolous but that makes me happy, is a nice way to start my day. And these days I do it less because I feel like I have to, and more because there are so many possibilities. It's <em>fun</em> to pick colours and textures and line thickness, and I know some of you are like, "Yeah fucking right," but what can I say? I actually really like my morning routine lately.</p>
<p>A corollary to this is wearing bright lipstick regularly. I started doing this on days I had exams, just to pump myself up, and it made me feel so good about myself that I started doing it for no reason at all. Because, really, who even needs a reason to wear bright lipstick? I'M WORTH IT, remember? And bright lipstick is fucking awesome.</p>
<p>Also, I always have excellent nails, thank you for noticing.</p>
<h3>Decorating</h3>
<p>I didn't finish decorating my room until January, when I decided to just cover every surface with stuff. My room is very "university dorm room", with lots of cards, posters, and pictures of my favourite musicians (and X Factor bands, OF COURSE), and it's nothing special, but it actually went a long way in cheering me up this winter. (Which, honestly, is quite a feat, because <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/winter/" title="related post">winter kind of sucks my soul out</a>.) I've actually been adding new stuff to my walls pretty frequently, and even though it's not exactly impressive artwork or anything, having postcards from the cool places I've been, pictures of my friends, and my British teen idols staring at me is much preferable to being surrounded by four stark white walls!</p>
<p>What are some small things you do to take care of yourself?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/nice-things/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The term &quot;identity crisis&quot; is more dramatic than this really is</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 22:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[i like]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3775</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I want to know how people existed pre-internet, how people went through a "holy shit I'm turning 19 soon1 and will only have a year left of being a teenager" identity crisis if not publicly, for anyone to read, recorded in excruciating detail. Seriously, what did people do? How did people live before oversharing became [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to know how people existed pre-internet, how people went through a "holy shit I'm turning 19 soon<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/#footnote_0_3775" id="identifier_0_3775" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="like, in 3 months and one day">1</a></sup> and will only have a year left of being a teenager" identity crisis if not publicly, for anyone to read, recorded in excruciating detail. Seriously, what did people do? How did people live before oversharing became easier than just, you know, not doing that?</p>
<p>Here's a cool fun thing: I'm obsessed with my hair lately. Well, I mean, I always kind of am, I'm very vain about my hair because even though it has a tendency to frizz it's generally good hair. I was itching for a change, though, and I definitely thought I got that change out of my system in December <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/i-have-no-hair-and-im-not-at-all-overdramatic/" title="related post">when I chopped off ten inches</a>, because, let's be real, that was a fairly big deal, even though by this point it's already grown out quite a bit.</p>
<p>But, no, since January 11 I have been in a deep state of flux, and inner turmoil, not in like an unnecessarily dramatic way, just in the way that I'm actually regressing, and it's fucking awful. I'm kidding, it's not awful at all. I love living the tween years I never had. But let's not talk about that anymore. Let's talk about my hair.</p>
<p>I decided, like maybe a week or so ago, that I wanted purple hair. It just started as a sort of hypothetical, mostly because I was looking at pictures of Perrie Edwards, which of course is a part of my regression. But, look, okay?</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dYr8h3i.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>Of course, other people have done the lavender hair thing with varying degrees of success, like Kelly Osbourne and Katy Perry, and I thought it was nice, but I wouldn't say I was especially impressed with it or anything. But now Perrie is my teen idol, even though she's less than eleven months older than me, and I was just like, "I wonder if I could rock lavender hair," just really hypothetically, but now I can't expel that idea from my brain.</p>
<p>I don't even know if I could, but the thing is that I'm obsessed with the idea. I'm not doing anything about it right now, because I want to do it right (read: professionally) and I don't have the money, and also because I don't want it to affect my employment opportunities over the summer, and also because I don't want to rush into something like bleaching my entire head of hair and semi-permanently applying an unnatural colour on top of that, you know? I may be a nearly nineteen-year-old who acts like a pre-adolescent idiot, but I have that much common sense.</p>
<p>But I think I'm probably going to do it when the time is right, because, really, I should get this out of my system while I'm still a teenager with no real responsibilities, and also YOLO.</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3775" class="footnote">like, in 3 months and one day</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#039;s talk about that song</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 21:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arguably funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foolishness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I've touched on this before but never written a full post on it, and there's no time like the present! The present is 2:05am on a school night, but it's cool, sleep is so whatever, who even needs to do that, not me, and probably not Harry Styles either. If it's good enough for him [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've touched on this before but never written a full post on it, and there's no time like the present! The present is 2:05am on a school night, but it's cool, sleep is so whatever, who even needs to do that, not me, and probably not Harry Styles either. If it's good enough for him it's good enough for me.</p>
<p>Okay. That song. I hesitate to name it and prefer to just keep it at arm's length with a euphemism, like Voldemort. I'm afraid that if I name it a Death Eater will apparate and Avada Kedavra me, or whatever the Muggle equivalent is. </p>
<p>That awful song that you totally think about when you think of my name. <em>That</em> song.</p>
<p>Now, let me tell you something. This is nothing personal against you, and I'm sure you have many redeeming qualities like maybe you're really funny or you volunteer with puppies or you know how to graph a parabola, but if you meet me, hear my name, start singing that fucking song, and then wait for me to shower you with praise for your unprecedented wit, my entire body will be consumed with a potent rage and I will probably hate you. Because, one, that's not original, I get that all the time, do you really think that isn't something I put up with constantly, and two, HAVE YOU EVER PAID ATTENTION TO THE LYRICS OF THAT SONG? HAVE YOU? Because I have, and they're awful, and one time at my cottage we were having a campfire and my grandpa started singing it and I got so mad I burst into tears and ran away and it caused a lot of drama, and it all could have been avoided if only that song didn't exist. This is why we need time travel! So many people say if they had a time machine they'd kill Hitler, and I'm not saying that's not on my list, I'm just saying that my top priority would be preventing Percy Montrose from putting such a shitty song into the world.</p>
<p>The thing is that people don't realize what the song is. They only know the first line, you know, the one that uses a term of endearment. Like, why wouldn't I like to be called your darling? (Actually, fyi, it's kind of creepy. Only Harry Styles and Kat Dennings are allowed to call me their darling.) But the thing is that you need to listen to the lyrics that come next and realize that they are deeply unsettling on various levels.</p>
<p><em>Drove she ducklings to the water<br />
Ev'ry morning just at nine,<br />
Hit her foot against a splinter,<br />
Fell into the foaming brine.</em></p>
<p>Hmm, that's nice, it's a little girl named Clementine who likes to feed the ducks, nothing to see here, oh wait, shit, her dumbass fucking miner father<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/#footnote_0_3768" id="identifier_0_3768" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="who, by the way, I always picture as my own father, making it SO MUCH WORSE">1</a></sup> wasn't paying attention to her, and now she's drowning. That's lovely! Very nice! A heartwarming tune! But wait, there's more! (I should be an infomercial voiceover, totally my bag, why do I need a liberal arts degree again?)</p>
<p><em>Ruby lips above the water,<br />
Blowing bubbles, soft and fine,<br />
But, alas, I was no swimmer,<br />
So I lost my Clementine.</em></p>
<p>Oh, wow, lovely evocative imagery of a small child drowning, really super. A fucking plus, Percy Montrose, you piece of shit. OH, WAIT. Her idiot father doesn't know how to swim, so he just lets her drown. And then writes beautiful poetry about how her mouth looked as it gasped its dying breaths. So nice. I can see why this song has endured in the folk canon. Oh, come on, what the hell do you mean there's more, Jesus Christ.</p>
<p><em>How I missed her! How I missed her,<br />
How I missed my Clementine,<br />
But I kissed her little sister,<br />
I forgot my Clementine</em></p>
<p>This is repeated three times, just in case the vivid imagery of a drowning child wasn't holding your interest and you started nodding off, because it's very important to reinforce the fact that Clementine's father watched her drown and then forgot about her because he had another child, one who wasn't a shitty idiot who fell into the water while feeding the ducks. Outstanding!</p>
<p>Then there are like a million verses describing her grave, and then her dad dies of old age, which really is so unfair, karma should have made him drown, and then at the end they're like, "Hey, Boy Scouts, learn CPR so children don't have to die!"</p>
<p>Okay, so, the end, when you sing this song at me you are evoking a convoluted narrative in which a little girl bearing my name drowns because her father is too stupid to be alive, then is overshadowed by her younger sister instead of being properly mourned, and then you find out the whole upsetting story was just to teach a bunch of boys the importance of artificial resuscitation, and can you see why it's not endearing when you sing it at me? Bye.</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3768" class="footnote">who, by the way, I always picture as my own father, making it SO MUCH WORSE</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Search terms, part 3: One Direction and the Pope</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/search-terms-part-3-one-direction-and-the-pope/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/search-terms-part-3-one-direction-and-the-pope/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 20:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3761</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello! It is time for the third installment in the "This is the dumb shit I Google" series. Once again, these are all things I have Googled, not things that people have Googled to find my site. Actually, those search terms are almost never funny. But this stuff is gold! very happy celebrities fat birds [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello! It is time for the third installment in the "This is the dumb shit I Google" series. Once again, these are all things I have Googled, not things that people have Googled to find my site. Actually, those search terms are almost never funny. But this stuff is gold!</p>
<p>very happy celebrities<br />
fat birds<br />
cat nose health<br />
what's the point of whiskers<br />
poetic names<br />
dog with piercing eyes, dog that paul ryan looks like<br />
dogs that look stupid<br />
cat anxiety, cat mental illness, cat mental illness signs, cat insanity test (<em>I worry about my cat a lot</em>)<br />
baby tomato, little tomato, what are little tomatoes called<br />
how many times were hogwarts exams cancelled<br />
mitt romney as a turkey<br />
nick jonas ass (<em>twice, ugh, I'm awful, I don't deserve the gift of life</em>)<br />
bird with lampshade head, bird with built in hat<br />
what if there were no stars, effects of not having stars<br />
homosexuality and teen wolf<br />
abe linc's son<br />
shovel teeth (<em>It's a legitimate thing, it's called sinodonty</em>)<br />
book with dragon and human performing mating ritual<br />
show where people sing with pigeons, show where people sing with scary things<br />
morrissey jokes<br />
mitt romney in a spiral of despair<br />
fun things to do on the inretnet when you adre durnk<br />
what's goin on with livejournal<br />
Siri how do you feel about Bill Gates<br />
metal horns clipart<br />
can you tattoo a cat<br />
joe biden smiling<br />
how many teens are pregnant in america (<em>I'm always concerned about real world problems, you know</em>)<br />
DANIEL DAY LEWIS LOOKS LIKE MORRISSEY (<em>he totally does, he does, he does, I will fight you on this</em>)<br />
ron jeremy but not disgusting<br />
bald eagles mating<br />
pope arrest<br />
is this a dagger which i see before me (<em>like 8 fucking times</em>)<br />
who was the youngest pope<br />
longest serving popes<br />
does benedict get to keep his name<br />
what do unbaptized peopel do at communion<br />
which mcgill residence did win butler live in<br />
how many days have i been alive<br />
what's wrong with justin bieber<br />
pope news<br />
incest in hamlet<br />
WHAT'S HAPPENING WITH THE POPE</p>
<p>And then, all of these, all within the last two months:<br />
does zayn malik swear<br />
when does 1d3d come out<br />
larry stylinson leaked emails<br />
harry styles giraffe joke<br />
harry styles four nipple pics (<em>like, 4 times</em>)<br />
harry styles four nipple video<br />
niall horan crying<br />
niall horan crying at concert<br />
what does niall even do with all his money<br />
1d kissing booth (<em>IT'S A LEGITIMATE THING</em>)<br />
niall facts<br />
does harry styles have a thigh gap<br />
one direction harry potter crossover<br />
harry styles favourite food<br />
does zayn swear (<em>I'm really concerned with this, obviously</em>)<br />
where can i find a large one direction cutout in toronto<br />
burberry heart shirt, harry styles birthday shirt knockoff, burberry heart shirt knockoff (<em>None of this got me anywhere</em>)<br />
how many nipples does liam payne have<br />
what books does louis like, what books does louis tomlinson like<br />
harry styles butterfly tattoo (<em>This was before the good picture came out</em>)<br />
sassy harry<br />
niall horan shoes<br />
niall horan shitty baby<br />
does anyone hate harry styles<br />
harry styles eyes, WHAT COLOUR ARE HARRY'S EYES, WHAT COLOUR ARE HARRY STYLES EYES<br />
hardcore niall</p>
<p>And of course:</p>
<p><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/1ccefe601d574779c5d88ed0906fcbcd/tumblr_mjm3pyvHOi1qgs500o1_400.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>This really says a lot about me and I'm not sure it's stuff I want you to know, but, whatever, no shame, judge away. Nick Jonas ass.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/search-terms-part-3-one-direction-and-the-pope/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Things I miss about home</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/things-i-miss-about-home/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/things-i-miss-about-home/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 17:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quebec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3754</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I feel like I just stepped off the plane, but in reality I'm going to be boarding another one this evening. Provided I survive, by 9pm I will end up back in a place where over the course of seven weeks I'll have two midterms, one lab quiz, three papers, hundreds of pages of reading, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I feel like I just stepped off the plane, but in reality I'm going to be boarding another one this evening. Provided I survive, by 9pm I will end up back in a place where over the course of seven weeks I'll have two midterms, one lab quiz, three papers, hundreds of pages of reading, and four final exams, two of which are worth about 70% of my grade. Can't wait!</p>
<p>I do genuinely like where I live eight months of the year, and I mostly like university. But there are also some undeniable perks to being home, which I am really looking forward to taking full advantage of once I'm home for four months starting in May! Like&#8230;</p>
<h3>Other people cooking for me.</h3>
<p>You knew food was going to be a big part of it, riiiiight? I mean, this is me we're talking about, the girl who petitioned her parents to take the family to Italy because she wanted to eat authentic Italian food. (Like, among other reasons, but that was a large part of it.) Yeah. <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/cooking/" title="related post">I'm not an enormous fan of cooking</a>, nor am I that good at it, so eating other people's delicious food is a major perk for me. Plus, the less time I spend cooking meals, the more time I can spend baking desserts, which directly benefits those around me as I love to share.</p>
<h3>My favourite restaurants.</h3>
<p>18 years in the same city means some strong damn loyalty to various restaurants. Montreal has great food too, but I haven't found a proper substitute for my favourite sushi place, nor have I found anywhere that serves spicy beef pho. Whenever I'm in Toronto, my parents spoil me by trying to fit all my favourite restaurants into my limited visit &#8211; definitely an upside to visiting!</p>
<h3>My bed.</h3>
<p>I've slept in a double bed since I was, like, nine. And I've had the same pillows for probably the same amount of time, because I'm very particular about pillows. My room in res is tiny, and so I have a single bed. And only one pillow. It's not awful; I've adjusted to it, at least. But whenever I'm home I realize how much more comfortable I am with all that leg room and my favourite pillows.</p>
<h3>My cats.</h3>
<p>Well, duh. I'm a crazy cat lady.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/w2JBdSb.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<div class="caption">Cats are so stupid.</div>
<h3>My family and friends.</h3>
<p>They're probably important too. Not quite as much as my cats, but pretty important.</p>
<p>Things I do not miss: Toronto public transit, crappy snowless grey Toronto winters, Rob Ford.</p>
<p>And, for good measure, things I miss about Montreal when I'm not there: the city in general<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/things-i-miss-about-home/#footnote_0_3754" id="identifier_0_3754" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="it's probably a better city than Toronto if I'm being honest, although I think Toronto will always be home">1</a></sup>, my favourite prof<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/things-i-miss-about-home/#footnote_1_3754" id="identifier_1_3754" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="yes, really, I love him and his classes so much">2</a></sup>, my university friends, seeing my extended family regularly, my hair dryer<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/things-i-miss-about-home/#footnote_2_3754" id="identifier_2_3754" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="my mom's just does not cut it &#8211; she has really fine hair and mine is very thick">3</a></sup>, my frizz-taming shampoo that I never pack because I overpack anyway and don't have room in my checked bag for two bottles of shampoo.</p>
<p>Does this entry make me seem like a materialistic consumer? Yes, probably, but oh well, having frizz-free hair is very important to my wellbeing as a human.</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3754" class="footnote">it's probably a better city than Toronto if I'm being honest, although I think Toronto will always be home</li><li id="footnote_1_3754" class="footnote">yes, really, I love him and his classes so much</li><li id="footnote_2_3754" class="footnote">my mom's just does not cut it &#8211; she has really fine hair and mine is very thick</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/things-i-miss-about-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Badass female musicians</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/badass-female-musicians/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/badass-female-musicians/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3740</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's International Women's Day, yay! There are a lot of really great links I'd recommend checking out in light of this day, and I hope y'all will read some and think about the significance of the day &#8211; but today I'm going to keep it light all up in these parts and share with you [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's International Women's Day, yay! There are <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/03/08/opinion/gates-international-womens-day/index.html?hpt=hp_c3">a lot</a> <a href="http://www.randomhouse.ca/hazlitt/feature/what-got-us-feminism">of really</a> <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/kristi-york-wooten/international-womens-day_b_2828570.html?ncid=edlinkusaolp00000003&#038;utm_hp_ref=twitter&#038;comm_ref=global_motherhood&#038;comm_crv=">great</a> <a href="http://777voting.com/">links</a> I'd recommend checking out in light of this day, and I hope y'all will read some and think about the significance of the day &#8211; but today I'm going to keep it light all up in these parts and share with you some of my favourite female musicians, who also happen to be totally badass. Not only are these women extraordinarily talented, I look up to all of them for their strong convictions, the messages that they send, and their commitment to being true to themselves no matter what anyone thinks.</p>
<h3>Beyoncé Knowles</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/3CLnySD.png" alt="" class="fancyleft" /> <em>"Equality is a myth, and for some reason everyone accepts that women don’t make as much money as men. I truly believe that women should be financially independent from their men. And let’s face it, money gives men the power to run the show. It gives men the power to define value. They define what’s sexy. And men define what’s feminine. It’s ridiculous."</p>
<p>"It’s difficult being a woman. It’s so much pressure, and we need that support sometimes. We’re all going through our problems, but we all have the same insecurities and we all have the same abilities and we all need each other.”</em></p>
<p>It's hard to escape mentions of Beyoncé on the internet, and for good reason. She is pro-woman in tangible ways (such as her all-female band at the Super Bowl), and shows that it is completely possible (and not at all contradictory) to be a loving and devoted wife and mother <em>and</em> wildly driven and successful &#8211; and, as she often stresses, independent. She is outspoken and does not compromise for anyone. Even if her music isn't your cup of tea (it's certainly not in my main indie rock niche), she is such an inspiring woman!</p>
<h3>Claire Boucher</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/p4Cd0bT.png" alt="" class="fancyleft" /> <em>"How can you hate Beyoncé? She's changing the world. She stands for people of colour and women everywhere succeeding in a stifling patriarchy without compromising her morals. And she makes challenging, interesting art. She's always positive. She is everything good. And the fact that she is hugely successful is not a shitty thing. It's an important and amazing thing and she clearly works hard for it."</p>
<p>"Racism isn't over. Sexism isn't over. The only way things actually effect social change is by hitting the audience that perpetuates these ideas."</em></p>
<p>I'm still not entirely sure if Grimes' music is for me (though it is growing on me), but I really admire her no-nonsense attitude. She has her own style, both in terms of her music and how she presents herself physically, and she is completely unapologetic about it. She experiments aeshetically and doesn't care what anyone thinks of her. And she is outspoken and unabashed when it comes to speaking her mind.</p>
<h3>Emily Haines</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/AkdwF3b.png" alt="" class="fancyleft" /> <em>"I'm accepting I may not have it all. I may not have a husband and a family. I may have an adventure."</p>
<p>"I’ve noticed that when I write anything from the perspective of a girl it is automatically read as feminist commentary. I don’t really mind but I think it’s interesting. Most of the guys I know relate to my lyrics ‘cause we’re all asking similar questions."</em></p>
<p>Emily Haines is best known as the lead singer of Metric, although she's also worked with Broken Social Scene, and she has a (now defunct) side project called Emily Haines and the Soft Skeleton. In her large body of work, she explores themes like motherhood, sexual assault, the glass ceiling, and patriarchy with clarity and her signature wry style. She has immense confidence and stage presence and never does anything any way but her own. Her style is so distinctive, because she has carved out a little niche for herself, one that she fully owns.</p>
<h3>Florence Welch</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/sgZgobv.png" alt="" class="fancyleft" /> <em>"I think there’s definitely been a resurgence of late of strong, female figures as musicians and I think that’s an exciting thing. But yeah, people can’t really seem to get over it, even though there have been so many amazing artists through out history, you know [...] there’s been so much and so many wonderful women artists, but I think there is something quite beguiling about the female artist. [...] It’s the juxtaposition between femininity and power I think, and vulnerability and strength in female artists that I think people find really interesting."</p>
<p>"When I first started, especially because I got the Critics Choice before I’d released an album, there was a lot scrutiny on what my character was, what my background was, what colour my hair was. I fought quite hard for the music to overtake the personality aspect. I didn’t want to become a personality, I wanted to be a musician, but because I didn’t have an album to stand by yet it was hard for people to see that."</em></p>
<p>Florence Welch has a very recognizable aesthetic, musically and stylistically. With her flowy dresses and capes and red hair and overpowering, ethereal sound, she pretty clearly does what she wants. I love that she has such a clear sense of who she is as an artist, and that that comes across all the time. Although Florence is actually a lot more reserved than the persona she projects, it's pretty clear that she is completely confident in who she is, and very much in control of her image and music.</p>
<h3>Laura Marling</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/CxGkFIu.png" alt="" class="fancyleft" /> <em>"With the first two albums – Charlie produced Alas I Cannot Swim, and it's as much his album as it is mine, and with I Speak Because I Can, the style of the drumming and the bass playing is very much a representation of the characters who were playing on that album, and Ethan stepping in as well. This time I thought: 'Well, I've got the confidence now, and I know what I want it to sound like, so before anybody else gets their grubby mitts on it, why don't I put my stamp on it?'"</p>
<p>"I don’t think it’d be any surprise that the feminine characters in my songs are because I’m fascinated by women and womanhood. And the women that I meet, the ones that fascinate me the most, are the ones that have strengths that I kind of envy. Those are things in life that fascinate me, and I end up personifying, and they are the things I try to identify with, or would like to identify with."</em></p>
<p>Laura Marling is such a clear example of what a driven, talented woman is capable of doing. At the age of twenty-three, she has three critically-acclaimed LPs, with a fourth set for release in late May. She writes all her own music, which is absolutely incredible, especially considering her age. She released her first album at age eighteen &#8211; and while it's clear there's room for growth, it is still a remarkable offering. I'm eighteen now and I wish I could be half as poised, talented, and accomplished as Laura was at my age! After her first two albums, she realized that she was letting other people's opinions influence her music too much, so she made a conscious effort to make her third album exactly what <em>she</em> wanted. Laura's been around for six years already and accomplished so much, at an age where most people still have no direction.</p>
<h3>Marina Diamandis</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/W7oA3bi.png" class="fancyleft" alt="" /> <em>"If my label had tried to mould me into something I wasn't, I would have blown up. I'm against this pressure on artists, especially women, to conform to a certain ideal. Life is too short to worry about dieting."</p>
<p>"You're either a sexed-up dumb pop starlet or an artist who has integrity and depth and it seems like two can never cross. This relates to Electra Heart quite a lot, because I want that pop model to make my music reach a wider audience, but also write songs that actually have meaning."</em></p>
<p>I love Marina and the Diamonds' music because it's pop with substance &#8211; and some sort of otherworldly quality. Marina is also an unabashed feminist, and is not afraid to speak her mind on Twitter or in interviews. A lot of her songs definitely have pro-woman messages, reflecting her beliefs. She's wildly ambitious and goes after what she wants with determination &#8211; and it's paying off, since she's been nominated for (and won!) her fair share of awards (with many more to come, of course) and is breaking into mainstream pop consciousness. She's such an inspiration to me in every fathomable way!</p>
<h3>Tegan and Sara Quin</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dfM2Nxm.png" alt="" class="fancyleft" /> <em>"One thing I find in general is how little people truly understand what it means to be a feminist—and that it’s still a necessary movement, not a project that ended. I’m always telling people being a feminist is like being part of any human rights movement—it’s ongoing and should always exist, no matter how much has been accomplished."</p>
<p>"I remember deciding I wanted to be in a band, and telling my parents at 17 I was gay, and going to live an alternative lifestyle. There was friction and boundary-pushing, but not really. It wasn’t coming out of left field. Our mom practically gave us the manual of how to do it, which I think is a positive result of my mom’s feminism. I wanted to be exactly who I was and didn’t understand why I couldn’t make music for the masses as a queer, alternative woman."</em></p>
<p>Everyone's favourite musical twins are outspoken advocates of gender equality and LGBTQ rights. Their music has evolved a lot over their eighteen-year career, but what hasn't changed is the fact that they write songs with substance and are never afraid to stand up for social issues. Both twins are open lesbians and have never shied away from very frankly discussing LGBTQ rights and have done lots of work with LGBTQ advocacy groups. They have a successful (and ever-growing career) and are always willing to take a stand, and that's truly awesome.</p>
<p>What badass female musicians do you admire?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/badass-female-musicians/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drawing the line</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/drawing-the-line/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/drawing-the-line/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 17:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3736</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When it comes to sharing things on your blog, where do you draw the line? I ask "on your blog" as opposed to "online" in general because I think there are more private means to share personal information online, and that's a different issue to me. I have a lot of really close friends online [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to sharing things on your blog, where do you draw the line?</p>
<p>I ask "on your blog" as opposed to "online" in general because I think there are more private means to share personal information online, and that's a different issue to me. I have a lot of really close friends online who I've shared a lot of personal things with, but that's in private or semi-private venues. But when we're talking about a public personal blog, where is that line?</p>
<p>I'm still a bit hazy on my boundaries. I don't think they're exact. I think it's more of a gut feeling, and that feeling has caused my boundaries to shift a bit over the years. It's always been my policy not to write about anything overly personal, although I've made some exceptions. This is especially true when it comes to something somebody else is involved in: even though I attempt not to really give out any identifying information about people, I don't feel that it's my place to share most details about other people's lives.</p>
<p>I also tend not to use names, although I've definitely made some exceptions for that and I haven't been totally consistent. I have mentioned friends' names in passing, but I definitely do not name family members (when I even mention them, which is reasonably rare). I use nicknames for some people, but usually I just get away with generalities like "my cousin" or "my friend's boyfriend". I don't actually think names are some sacred thing that shouldn't be mentioned, and I don't feel that other bloggers necessarily cross a line when they use names, but it's definitely something I try not to do.</p>
<p>Another thing is pictures. I usually don't like to post pictures of other people here, although I did do that with my prom post in June (mostly because I was too lazy to <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-greatest-long-weekend/" title="related post">humourously cover all those faces with celebrities</a>, which I realize betrays my deep commitment to the cause). Again, this is definitely something I intend to rigidly keep up for my family members, especially my little cousins. (Although sometimes I'm really tempted to post a picture of me and Bighead and ask if we look similar, because we totally do, but my mom doesn't think so. We do, y'all. We are clearly siblings.)</p>
<p>I don't think these boundaries are exact or inflexible, especially when it comes to other people. There are so many bloggers and writers who use pictures of other people, names, and rather personal anecdotes in their work, and a lot of the time it doesn't bother me. I couldn't even tell you exactly when someone crosses over from "acceptable" to "oh, wow, you are grossing me out", although a large part of that definitely has to do with consent to be written about and knowledge that it's happening. (It's tricky, though. I read a lot of really good personal essays that would be nowhere near as honest if the author had asked involved parties for their permission to write about them.)</p>
<p>But there are definitely cases where I know, for sure, that a line has been crossed. Writing using identifying information with the intent to humiliate or mock someone is wrong. Writing in anger makes me uncomfortable; I think a crappy situation can be translated into good writing, but it's obvious when the person has written it while still really angry, and I always feel like it's a rash decision that they might regret. (I know I would. This is why when I'm mad at someone I ignore them for awhile &#8211; I know I'm likely to say something I can't take back otherwise.)</p>
<p>This also extends to other forms of writing &#8211; like lyrics. People connect with personal music, this is true. And a lot of people with high-profile relationships write about those relationships. Taylor Swift is probably the most obvious example of this &#8211; and while she's obviously not the only one to do it, she's one of the most overt and famous that I can think of. It's true that she gets a lot of shit for it where other people don't, which isn't fair &#8211; but I don't think it's unfair to be questioning how much she really needs to rub your face in the identity of whoever she's singing about. (For the record, I totally feel the same way about Katy Perry's post-Russell Brand songs, and you know I love her crappy pop music.)</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/G9eiUf5.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<div class="caption">Come on, Taylor, this is BLATANT.</div>
<p>So, what do you think? Where do you draw the line when it comes to writing about personal situations, especially those involving others? What do you think of other people's personal essays? Is it an invasion of privacy or is it just a part of being a writer?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/drawing-the-line/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The things you eat when you&#039;re a student</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-things-you-eat-when-youre-a-student/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-things-you-eat-when-youre-a-student/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 20:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3602</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There's actually a surprising amount of decent food you can make on a budget. I mean, not a truly shoestring budget, but a budget nonetheless. At least, that's how I view my budget, although I've never actually had a food budget before, so I don't have anything to compare it to. Anyway, what I'm trying [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There's actually a surprising amount of decent food you can make on a budget. I mean, not a truly shoestring budget, but a budget nonetheless. At least, that's how I view my budget, although I've never actually had a food budget before, so I don't have anything to compare it to. Anyway, what I'm trying to say here is that even though you can do decently on a reasonably modest budget, when you're a student, often you don't do decently. Because you're lazy and busy and constantly sick and sleep-deprived and and and. Excuses.</p>
<p>So! Here is what you eat when you're a student.</p>
<h3>Stir-fry</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/SfGHKAD.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>This is easily my favourite thing to eat, because not counting soaking the rice noodles for half an hour, it takes about ten minutes and I can put anything into it. Generally this involves a sauce made of peanut sauce, soy sauce, lemon or lime juice, and some honey and then a bunch of vegetables (which I buy frozen, natch; I like getting the "Oriental" bag because there's some variety and if I buy fresh vegetables I can never eat it all), garlic, onion, and sometimes protein &#8211; shrimp or chicken, depending on what I have on hand. It requires absolutely no measuring; it's easy and pretty much foolproof. And I can put it on a plate I got in Chinatown and pour myself a mango smoothie and pretend I'm having an Asian fusion meal even though it's really just "white girl throws a bunch of crap into a pan". Whatever, y'all. I'm classy.</p>
<h3>Pasta</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YA8BguJ.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>Pasta is another one that is easy and doesn't require actually doing much. You can just kind of sit back and browse Twitter on your phone and check it every so often. Also, there's endless variety. With all the different types of pasta and the bajillions of sauces, you can't really go wrong. Although the Super C keeps having fetuccine on sale, so I have like 5 boxes of it. And I <em>usually</em> don't make my own sauce. I usually get whatever sauce is on sale. Sometimes my grandma buys me fancy sauce, because she likes to foist food on me so she knows I'm eating a few good meals a week. (This is appreciated.) Occasionally I make my own out of 99¢ tins of tomato paste, to which I add onion and garlic. I am ALL ABOUT the onion and garlic, people.</p>
<h3>Fast food</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/tqDH7Wx.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<div class="caption">The proudest day of my life so far! Even though I don't drink coffee!</div>
<p>I really try not to eat crappy food too often. I may not put in a huge effort or be magnificently innovative, but I also don't like to stuff myself with endless fat and MSG. I mean, like, I do love junk food, but I <em>try</em>, okay? Someone's gotta be responsible here. But twice a week, I do treat myself to Tim Horton's, with my usual order coming in at just under $4, which is actually $0 thanks to my pre-paid meal plan. I also occasionally like to have Thai Express, even though I KNOW, okay? It's revolting. But oh so wonderful.</p>
<h3>Bagels</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/lSeCMkI.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>I figure if I'm a bagel snob living in the city that makes the best bagels in the world, why waste that opportunity, right?</p>
<h3>Canned soup</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/LJBOREE.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>It costs, like, $2 a can at most and takes about five minutes to heat up. Can't beat that!</p>
<h3>Ramen noodles</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/iPc1Aek.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>This is for when you want to be a student stereotype and also really, really amazingly happy. I <em>love</em> ramen like nobody's business. I mean, grocery store ramen. Four for a dollar ramen. Not real ramen. Well, I do like that too, but I'm not takling about it here. I'm talking about Mr. Noodles. I do try to avoid this as much as possible, because it's terrible for you and because I'd hate it if I had it too often. Therefore, 25¢ noodles are totally a treat and I won't hear otherwise.</p>
<h3>Meals other people buy</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dNhqJRx.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<div class="caption">Sometimes I eat sushi, and other times I eat adorable bite-sized desserts.</div>
<p>I see my uncle once every week or so for all-you-can-eat sushi, and my grandparents every weekend either for a home-cooked meal by my grandma or to go out together. So far we've had Italian, Indian, and Thai at five different restaurants (I think &#8211; I could be forgetting some). This is the ideal. If other people would make/buy me food every day, we'd be cooking with gas. Except, not literally, because <em>I</em> won't be cooking. That's the goal for when I'm rich and famous. I'll just bake endlessly.</p>
<h3>Cookies</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/qLSex70.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>Sometimes I bake cookies and then eat, like, 5 really fast, because they're so good fresh out of the oven when they're still gooey, and then I feel sick, but then I don't have to eat until dinner time, because I'm so full of butter and sugar. That's a legitimate thing, right? If you say no, it's probably because you've never eaten my cookies. <em>They're fucking amazing</em> is the thing you don't understand.</p>
<h3>Utter junk</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/yae7DTQ.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>You know when you're really sick and you don't feel that you can muster up the energy to make food or even to get out of bed and walk the three metres to the kitchen and then you realize that you have <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/christmas-2-0/" title="related post">delicious candy bars </a>sitting next to you? Yeah. That's a thing, occasionally. Too much of that and life begins to feel like it's not worth living, but a bit of it is inevitable. At least, I think it is. Maybe I'm just disgusting. Also, when you have to start storing all the food you care about (read: junk) in your wardrobe so your roommates don't eat it, it's just so easy to access! <em>Too</em> easy to access! But delicious.</p>
<h3>Pizza that I make myself in the shape of a cat but that doesn't have any cheese or facial features and generally sucks</h3>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/kNOuPyp.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>Self-explanatory. Also utterly disappointing.</p>
<p>(I'm home for reading week right now. I'm eating like a queen.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-things-you-eat-when-youre-a-student/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#039;m a stereotype: Winter edition</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/im-a-stereotype-winter-edition/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/im-a-stereotype-winter-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[i'm a stereotype]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3722</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Amanda wanted me to start a series proving how Canadian I am since I want you all to pick me as Miss Canada of the internet, and today it snowed so I thought this was a prime opportunity. Unfortunately, it was not the kind of snow that draws tourists from warm climates to Canada. It [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://jing-wen.com" title="Jingwen by Amanda">Amanda</a> wanted me to start a series proving how Canadian I am <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-2013-bloggies/" title="related post">since I want you all to pick me as Miss Canada of the internet</a>, and today it snowed so I thought this was a prime opportunity. Unfortunately, it was not the kind of snow that draws tourists from warm climates to Canada. It was the kind of snow that immediately turns to slush when it hits the ground, which actually ended up being fairly useful as I discovered that both of my winter boots, purchased a year ago, have massive leaks in them. I basically have gangrene now.</p>
<p>Here is a picture of me bundling up and trudging from my class to the metro. This was pre-gangrene, or, like, as I was in the middle of developing gangrene.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/BwGD7sO.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>This is an approximately 5-minute walk, and in that time my hair became so soaked that it has dried wavy, thus undoing all the hard work I went to in order to ensure that it <em>wouldn't</em> be wavy today, which is obviously the true tragedy of the situation. Also, as noted, my feet became soaked through within seconds, on account of the snow melting and creating a miniature version of <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/montreal/story/2013/01/30/montreal-quebec-flood-mcgill-water-main-rupture.html" title="flood article thing on CBC">the flood we had in January</a>.</p>
<p>Like all good Canadians, I am stubbornly unwilling to bundle up properly during the winter months. Up until grade 11, I insisted on wearing my Converse all through the winter. Now, I don't know if you know how effective canvas is against the elements, but the answer is "not all that effective", if by "not all that effective" I mean "it's a surprise I still have feet, to be perfectly frank". Anyway, when I turned 16 I was like, "You're an idiot" and started wearing boots, which was a fairly lifechanging moment, but I've never really been one to wear a parka and like seventeen layers of tights under my jeans and a thick sweater. Today I wore a flimsy cotton t-shirt, fairly thin jeans, and rather insubstantial socks, which, in retrospect, wasn't the best idea given the fact that the soles of my boots have essentially detached from their body, haha soul vs. body mind/body dualism Descartes I hate philosophy.</p>
<p>ANYWAY. McGill has a comparatively very high international population, and the joke is that the only people who wear <a href="http://www.canada-goose.com/" title="jackets I do not wear">Canada Goose jackets</a> are non-Canadians, so I'm just doing my part to contribute to the stereotype. Also, I think they're too big and puffy. Also, I generally am in denial about how bad winter will be and then I step outside and I'm legitimately worried that my face will fall off. And you'd think I'd, like, acquire a scarf or mittens or even wear my hat consistently, but no, I don't, because that is how Canadians live: dangerously. On the edge. Of glory. Thus, I perfectly embody Canada: dangerous, glorious, toeless.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/YhOuTIU.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<div class="caption">It's awful out. Canada sucks. Never come here. Wait, no, I'm supposed to be the blog ambassador of our country. Come here, the slush that fills your boots will build your character.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/im-a-stereotype-winter-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A study of what people mean when they call you a hipster</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/a-study-of-what-people-mean-when-they-call-you-a-hipster/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/a-study-of-what-people-mean-when-they-call-you-a-hipster/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 21:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arguably funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3711</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Guys, I am a Twenty-First Century Youth, and thus I have concluded that hipsters are the subculture of our time. But the thing is, like, not to get all philosophical on you, but what the hell is a hipster? Seriously. What is a hipster? Two years ago, I could have told you. Now, the definition [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guys, I am a Twenty-First Century Youth, and thus I have concluded that hipsters are the subculture of our time. But the thing is, like, not to get all philosophical on you, but <em>what the hell is a hipster</em>? Seriously. What is a hipster? Two years ago, I could have told you. Now, the definition has become so convoluted that I don't even know. I just know that people are constantly either accusing people of being hipsters or themselves being accused of being hipsters. So let's take a look at what they really mean:</p>
<p><strong>You wear some combination of the following: Plaid, chambray, skinny jeans, high waisted skirts, patterned tights, oversized sweaters, clothes with animals on them, oxfords, sleeveless button-ups, American Apparel hoodies, American Apparel bodysuits, American Apparel anything, etc etc etc.</strong></p>
<p>Have you ever been on a university campus? Seriously, have you? This is called youth fashion of the 2010s, not "hipster fashion". I mean, unless you think 83% of people in the 16-25 demographic are hipsters. Personally I think there's a bit more exclusivity to the whole hipster movement, although going by your definition people who aren't hipsters are less common than hipsters, and also far more irritating, self-righteous, and insufferable.</p>
<p><strong>You listen to bands like Vampire Weekend, Grizzly Bear, Mumford &#038; Sons, Los Campesinos!, Arcade Fire, Bon Iver, and Bright Eyes.</strong></p>
<p>No, stop, these are all "indie" bands that are actually really well known and have seen critical and commercial success. At the risk of sounding like a total jerk, these bands are all pretty mainstream. I don't mean that in a snobby way. I just mean that people know this music. This is standard music taste, okay? I can very easily find people on the internet and in real life who like any of those artists, including my mother. Sure, there's still the same old pop music that's always been around, and it's not like these bands are replacing that, but liking Mumford &#038; Sons doesn't mean you're a hipster. It means you're a sentient being and maybe that you watched the Grammys this year.</p>
<p><strong>You use Tumblr. Bonus if you reblog pictures with weird filters and unrelated text.</strong></p>
<p>Everyone and their mother is on Tumblr. If you think someone is a "hipster" for using it, you're just as bad as the special snowflake scene kids who freaked out when MTV mentioned Tumblr in passing one time or that one girl who told Cole Sprouse that he exploited the internet refuge of social outcasts. Tumblr is just a fusion of Pinterest and Twitter except its main demographic is teenage girls instead of crafty women and celebrities and people who want celebrities to follow them and play a show in Brazil. And the people who reblog those dumb text-covered pictures are thirteen-year-old girls who have not yet learned that they are entirely unremarkable even though they feel misunderstood, deep, and unusually intelligent. (I get it. I was that person once too.)</p>
<p><strong>You're a vegan or a feminist or an anti-capitalist or a pacifist.</strong></p>
<p>Except no, you're just young. And I don't mean "Oh, silly young people with their idealistic social principles," because I'm totally a ~*~PC wanktard~*~ who's into equality, intersectionality, and anti-oppression. I just mean that young people are generally comparatively progressive, and that these are social values that are coming more and more into public consciousness as society becomes more aware of inequality and such. ("Inequality and such" is totally what social justice is all about, right?)</p>
<p><strong>You like things ironically.</strong></p>
<p>You may have a point, but this just seems so culturally ingrained now that it's sort of anti-hipster. A true hipster would earnestly enjoy things in the face of the popularity of tacky sweaters and watching The Room every weekend.</p>
<p>In general, people tend to conflate youth trends with hipsterdom while hilariously and ironically<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/a-study-of-what-people-mean-when-they-call-you-a-hipster/#footnote_0_3711" id="identifier_0_3711" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="whoa, that's so hipster!">1</a></sup> projecting their inflated sense of self-worth on the rest of us. "Hipster" has become a meaningless and entirely ambiguous term that lacks any sort of salience or tract as a concept and that is now mostly used as an epithet by people who have adopted the very attitudes of the stereotypical, non-existent hipsters that they are fixated on mocking. Seriously, guys. Anti-hipsters are so much more insufferable and awful than actual hipsters.</p>
<p><em>Also, hi! <a href="http://breakthesky.net/2013/02/26/interview-clem-of-oh-clementine-2013-bloggies-nominee/" title="Interview on Break the Sky">Manda interviewed me on her blog</a> since <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/#canadian">I am a Bloggies nominee this year</a>, so you might like to read that!</em></p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3711" class="footnote">whoa, that's so hipster!</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/a-study-of-what-people-mean-when-they-call-you-a-hipster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
