<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Oh Clementine</title>
	<atom:link href="http://ohclementine.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://ohclementine.com</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 20:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>That&#039;s just my face</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/thats-just-my-face/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/thats-just-my-face/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 20:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are a lot of posts on the internet about chronic bitchface. It's like, you know, you just have a face that makes you look unpleasant, unapproachable, judgmental. That's just the way your features are arranged. I think I have chronic bitchface, but the thing is that I try to, because I don't want to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are a lot of posts on the internet about <a href="http://blog.krisatomic.com/?p=1617" title="chronic bitchface">chronic bitchface</a>. It's like, you know, you just have a face that makes you look unpleasant, unapproachable, judgmental. That's just the way your features are arranged. I think I have chronic bitchface, but the thing is that I <em>try</em> to, because I don't <em>want</em> to interact with strangers. I make myself look unapproachable on purpose, because, like, when strangers do talk to me usually it's either to make some inappropriate, degrading comment or to ask me to sign their petition against animal cruelty, and I'm not really into either of those things. I mean, I'm against animal cruelty, obviously, I just don't really want my name on PETA's mailing list, you know?</p>
<p>Then there's the chronic sadface. I don't think this is such a widely documented phenomenon, but it's a thing. There are people who are constantly asked if they're okay, just because they have a face that looks sad. I get this occasionally; when my face is in its neutral expression, my mouth is naturally a bit turned down, and a lot of the time when I yawn (which is, like, constantly, because I don't sleep) my eyes water, and people think I'm just really sad all the time, apparently.</p>
<p>But then there's this other thing, and I haven't seen people talking about it. It's chronic tiredface. Like, you always look like you haven't slept. This is definitely a thing for me, and part of it is because I don't sleep, but part of it is because I have eyebags and dark circles and they will always be there, quite prominently, even if I get an appropriate amount of sleep. It's just how I look.</p>
<p>Most people are tactful enough not to say anything about that, because, you know, pointing out somebody's purple eyebags is kind of rude. Even though I know all of y'all noticed, okay? I'm not an idiot. My family, however, well, they don't have as much tact. Or boundaries. Or they just don't care. And they're <em>always</em> really concerned about me being tired or sick or overworked. Which, like, I am all three of those things with relative frequency, but they always think I'm <em>especially </em>tired or sick or overworked.</p>
<p>The thing is that I don't think my parents know what I look like without makeup. I mean, obviously, they do, it's not like I wear makeup 24/7, but I'm pretty sure they just don't realize that when they think I look like I haven't slept in a weak it's because I'm not wearing concealer. Concealer doesn't really work miracles for me in terms of covering my dark circles, but it makes me look like I've kind of slept, you know? And it's, like, the one thing I have to wear everywhere I go, because there ain't no way I'm letting people see that shit uncovered. But sometimes my family sees me without it, because they're my family and I don't care about impressing them.</p>
<p>This first happened in December. We went to get our new phones from the mall, and I didn't feel like putting on makeup just for that (which is rare, normally I'm very adamant about my concealer routine), and as we were waiting for our phones to get activated, this happened:</p>
<p><strong>Mom</strong>: Are you really tired?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: No? I'm on vacation?<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: You look really tired.<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Oh, yeah, it's probably because I'm not wearing any makeup.<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: No, no, you look really tired.</p>
<p>And then, a few months later, over Skype, because I'm not going to put on makeup just to talk to my family on Skype:</p>
<p><strong>Mom</strong>: Are you sick?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Uh, no?<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: Were you up really late?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Uh, no?<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: Are you sure?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: It's because I'm not wearing any makeup.<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: No, you look sick.</p>
<p>Two weeks after that:</p>
<p><strong>Mom</strong>: Are you hungover?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: IT'S BECAUSE I'M NOT WEARING ANY MAKEUP.</p>
<p>Last week:</p>
<p><strong>Mom</strong>: Why are you Skyping us from bed?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Uh-<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: You look really tired. Were you out partying?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Uh, no, I'm just-<br />
<strong>Mom</strong>: How was that?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: THIS IS JUST HOW MY FACE LOOKS AND I WAS TOO LAZY TO CLEAN OFF MY DESK.</p>
<p>And today:</p>
<p><strong>Dad</strong>: Were you up really late?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Uh, not really?<br />
<strong>Dad</strong>: Did you just wake up?<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: Uh, no?<br />
<strong>Dad</strong>: Oh, because you look tired.<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: No, that's just how I look.<br />
<strong>Dad</strong>: I know how you look. I'm your dad.<br />
<strong>Me</strong>: THIS IS JUST HOW MY FACE IS.</p>
<p>So, the moral of the story is that I always look tired and sick and hungover and my father is mistakenly convinced that I am naturally fresh-faced because, contrary to his steadfast belief, he does not know how my face looks. It looks eyebaggy, okay? That's just my face.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/thats-just-my-face/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#039;s not talk about my employment prospects</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-not-talk-about-my-employment-prospects/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-not-talk-about-my-employment-prospects/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 20:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being an adult]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3811</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today I booked a one-way flight home and declared my major, which means the end of first year is nigh. In fact, today marks exactly three weeks until my last exam, and less than 48 hours later I'll be back in Toronto. But that's not what I want to talk about today. I want to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I booked a one-way flight home and declared my major, which means the end of first year is nigh. In fact, today marks exactly three weeks until my last exam, and less than 48 hours later I'll be back in Toronto.</p>
<p>But that's not what I want to talk about today. I want to talk about the other thing. You know, the declaring my major thing. I did what everyone was expecting and made the whole Anthropology idea official, and then I was like "YOLO", and, well:</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Qs6anNc.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>So, yeah, I'm an English major too. Kind of. I mean, it's Cultural Studies, which is sort of like a fusion of English/Film/Communications, but which counts as a BA in English. Or, if you want the official description:</p>
<blockquote><p>
The Cultural Studies option concentrates on analysis of forms of cultural expression and symbolic interaction, and of the various media through which these may be disseminated and transformed. Such study concerns symbolic form, aesthetically based forms of analysis, and the various modes of criticism and theory relevant to media which contain both verbal and non-verbal elements. The aim is above all to hone students' analytical and interpretive skills while introducing them to specific critical approaches to cultural studies.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Which, honestly, sounds kind of pretentious, but then I am kind of pretentious, so there you go.</p>
<p>So. Anthropology. That's apparently my primary major, which I guess makes sense because I actually have a quarter of the credits I need for it, whereas I have none of the credits I need for Cultural Studies. I've taken enough Anthropology classes now to know that I want to focus more on prehistory/archaeology/physical anthropology than ethnography or cultural anthropology. I'm really interested in the past and how we came to be. I'm less interested in how we currently are. Anthropology seems like a vaguely narcissistic field of study, but it's something that interests me. I like understanding things, and I think Anthropology is helpful in understanding humans at a fundamental level, if such a thing is ever possible. And apparently I like memorizing the subtle differences in skull morphology of various early hominins.</p>
<p>The main problem with Anthropology, and particularly the focus I've chosen is that, well, it's about as close to science as you can get without actually being science. I'm good at school in general, but memorizing hard facts isn't my forte. Analyzing and interpreting and arguing is. That's why I decided to add on the second major, even though I really wanted to avoid double majoring. This way they'll balance each other out. I haven't taken any Cultural Studies classes yet, so maybe I'll hate it, but that's where the whole YOLO thing comes in. Also, I kind of don't think I will hate it:</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/ioxYTfm.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>As <a href="http://wanderlustful.me" title="Wanderlustful by Aisy">Aisling</a> said, I'm basically majoring in Tumblr.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-not-talk-about-my-employment-prospects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How many songs do you have?</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/how-many-songs-do-you-have/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/how-many-songs-do-you-have/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 22:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[questions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3808</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's been well established that I listen to music pretty much every second that I'm conscious. I got really into music just over three years ago, over March Break when I was 15. Maybe that's a weird idea, to all of a sudden go from someone who doesn't really care about music to being obsessed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It's been well established that I listen to music pretty much every second that I'm conscious. I got really into music just over three years ago, over March Break when I was 15. Maybe that's a weird idea, to all of a sudden go from someone who doesn't really care about music to being obsessed with it, but that's what happened. I had just bought myself an iPod Touch with my hard-earned money, and I set up <a href="http://last.fm/user/clemmmentine" title="me on last.fm">a last.fm account</a> on a whim, and I put my iTunes on shuffle while I cleaned my room, and all of a sudden I was like, "Music. That's cool."</p>
<p>The thing is, everyone else I know who's as similarly interested in music as I am has a much bigger collection than me. I mean, you'd think if I'm listening to 8+ hours of music a day on average, I'd have a tonne of it. But I actually don't, really. Here's what iTunes helpfully says I have at the moment:</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/RqKVP1u.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>A lot of my friends with iPhones have separate iPods simply because of the storage issue. They can't get all their music on their phone and still have room for apps and photos and videos. Since upgrading to an iPhone, I've completely phased out use of my iPod, because having everything in one place is convenient and it totally all fits on my phone. In fact, even with all my photos, apps, and videos, I still have almost 10GB free &#8211; and that's with my entire music collection synced up, not just the stuff I listen to the most.</p>
<p>I have pared down my music collection a bit recently, and probably will continue to do so &#8211; but even then, I think at the most I only ever had about 1800 songs. I definitely foresee myself crossing the 2000 song threshold at some point, but that's still not much compared to all the music fanatics I know. I mean, guys, I know people who went out and bought an 80GB iPod only to have to upgrade it to the 120GB model mere months later because they had acquired so much new music in that time.</p>
<p>A lot of my friends' strategy when they're getting into a new artist is to just download their entire discography. As a result, they have, well, a lot of music. A lot of music that they definitely don't listen to. I was so surprised to find out that one of my friends has songs in his library that he's literally never listened to! He has many, many more songs that he's listened to a few times but doesn't actually listen to regularly, and this is the main difference in how we approach listening to music.</p>
<p>My music collection is small because, as pretentious as it sounds, I prefer to really engage with my music. I like to have a manageable collection so I can listen to everything regularly. Obviously it's not like I'm listening to every single song every day, or even most days. There are things I don't listen to during certain seasons<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/how-many-songs-do-you-have/#footnote_0_3808" id="identifier_0_3808" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="like I just broke out the Best Coast after months of ignoring them, because, y'know, winter">1</a></sup>, and sometimes I just forget about something for a really long time, or give it a break on purpose. (You guys know how good your favourite albums sound after, like, two months of not listening to them, right? If you haven't done that, you should. It's incredible.) But the point is that I do actually like everything I have in my library, and know what it sounds like, and listen to it regularly, and have plans to continue to listen to it regularly.</p>
<p>I add new things in small chunks. I've just recently added about five new albums, which means I'm probably going to sit on those for awhile and get a good feel for them before I add anything else in. This is partly just me being really particular, but when I add new albums I like to listen to a maximum of two a day, so the bulk of what I listen to is familiar to me. So if I add too many new things at once, it gets to be too much to manage. (I know, I approach music in a very specific way, but it works for me.) So not only is my collection relatively small, it's not growing at a particularly fast pace either.</p>
<p>What's your music collection like? Do you listen to everything fairly often? Could you do with a bit of a spring cleaning?</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3808" class="footnote">like I just broke out the Best Coast after months of ignoring them, because, y'know, winter</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/how-many-songs-do-you-have/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/spring/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/spring/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 01:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3804</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I felt good this winter. That's what I thought, at least. That's what I thought until suddenly, this past weekend, it became spring, temporarily. I felt spring breathing down my neck, at least, and I realized &#8211; no. I didn't feel good this winter, not at all. It's not even nice out right now. It's [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I felt good this winter. That's what I thought, at least. That's what I thought until suddenly, this past weekend, it became spring, temporarily. I felt spring breathing down my neck, at least, and I realized &#8211; no. I didn't feel good this winter, not at all.</p>
<p>It's not even nice out right now. It's April 3, and we had nicer days in March. But I've felt the spring in the air, and I can feel it coming, and I have the whole summer ahead of me, and I feel good. Like, really good. Not the good I thought I felt this winter, but the kind of good that makes me realize that I really didn't feel good these past few months, that I was just getting by. Compared to other winters, I guess, I felt good, because sometimes I don't even feel like I'm getting by. All that grey, all that cold, all those blustering winds, it's enough to really mess with my head.</p>
<p>I have so much residual exhaustion from the winter, all those nights where I would toss and turn and the dark mornings that I'd sit on the floor drinking my tea and trying to work up any amount of enthusiasm at all for the coming day. I didn't even feel tired then, but now the combination of the final few weeks of the semester and the fact that I'm coming out of my winter hibernation means I'm constantly tired. I am, generally speaking, sleeping a million times better than I ever do, than I ever <em>hope</em> to, but I'm still tired all day, mentally and physically. It's just past 9pm and I'm almost ready to pack it in, when normally I'm not asleep until 2 or 3 in the morning.</p>
<p>I think I'm making this sound a lot worse than it actually is, but my point is that I never even realize how awful winter is until spring arrives and everything inside of me just opens up all at once. It's like the unfurling leaves on the trees are somehow in sync with my inner workings, and everything that was all tightly coiled up during the long, dark, cold winter months just blossoms all of a sudden, and I feel so good.</p>
<p>(This day not withstanding. This day was one where I felt like an idiot in my too-early conference, had a twenty-minute nap that ended with me waking up feeling disoriented and confused about my identity and purpose on this earth because naps are always a bad idea and I never learn, and went to buy a teen magazine with enormous posters of One Direction dressed up like football players and had my card declined, which, honestly, is the most pathetic thing that's ever happened to me on like at least twelve levels probably. But seriously, I feel good, mostly.)</p>
<p>Happy spring.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/spring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favourite books: January to March 2013</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-january-to-march-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-january-to-march-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 17:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[favourite books]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3649</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[2012: January to March / April to June / July to September / October to December I have definitely slowed my reading pace a bit due to a fairly difficult second semester, but I am making as much time as possible for reading and still mostly consuming books at a rate I'm happy with. Although [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>2012</strong>: <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-january-to-march/" title="related post">January to March</a> / <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-april-to-june/" title="related post">April to June</a> / <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-july-to-september/" title="related post">July to September</a> / <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-october-to-december/" title="related post">October to December</a></p>
<p>I have definitely slowed my reading pace a bit due to a fairly difficult second semester, but I am making as much time as possible for reading and still mostly consuming books at a rate I'm happy with. Although <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/2012-in-review/" title="related post">my goal for the year</a> has to do with pages rather than number of books read, I did end up setting a book goal on Goodreads too. I'm aiming for 75 in 2013, which is quite a bit lower than 2012's total &#8211; but more realistic than trying for a repeat.</p>
<p>In this first quarter of 2013, I have read 18 books &#8211; not too shabby considering the fact that, aside from the very first week, I've been in school for the entirety of the year! Here are some of my favourites.</p>
<h3>The Casual Vacancy by JK Rowling</h3>
<p><em>When Barry Fairbrother dies in his early forties, the town of Pagford is left in shock. Pagford is, seemingly, an English idyll, with a cobbled market square and an ancient abbey, but what lies behind the pretty façade is a town at war. Rich at war with poor, teenagers at war with their parents, wives at war with their husbands, teachers at war with their pupils &#8230; Pagford is not what it first seems. And the empty seat left by Barry on the parish council soon becomes the catalyst for the biggest war the town has yet seen. Who will triumph in an election fraught with passion, duplicity and unexpected revelations?</em></p>
<p>In all fairness, JK Rowling is my queen and I don't know that I can ever detach my immense gratitude for how deeply she enriched my childhood from my enjoyment of her post-Harry Potter literary endeavours, but I really did enjoy The Casual Vacancy. I think it's impossible to enjoy fully if you don't do your very best to <em>not</em> constantly compare it to Harry Potter. That said, I think it's difficult not to have that in the back of your mind. However, while completely and utterly different from her most famous series, I really think that The Casual Vacancy proves that JK Rowling is amazingly talented at weaving a complex story. It's very character-driven, which is something I love when done properly &#8211; and I really did feel like I was in the heads of all these people, most of whom were at least a bit unlikeable. I liked the chain reaction premise, and I liked that Barry is central to much of the story although he's dead for 99% of it.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/434149484" title="review of The Casual Vacancy on Goodreads">Full review</a>.)</p>
<h3>American Gods by Neil Gaiman</h3>
<p><em>Shadow is a man with a past. But now he wants nothing more than to live a quiet life with his wife and stay out of trouble. Until he learns that she's been killed in a terrible accident. Flying home for the funeral, as a violent storm rocks the plane, a strange man in the seat next to him introduces himself. The man calls himself Mr. Wednesday, and he knows more about Shadow than is possible. He warns Shadow that a far bigger storm is coming. And from that moment on, nothing will ever he the same&#8230;</em></p>
<p><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/christmas-2-0/" title="related post">Ashley gave me this book for Christmas</a> and was a bit nervous about it, as it was my first time reading Gaiman and it's very much an odd book. I can see how it wouldn't be everyone's cup of tea, but I adored it. It's detailed, expansive, and atmospheric. And, despite the decidedly supernatural subject matter, it felt hyper-realistic. I could practically see Shadow's breath in the frigid town of Lakeside. There's constantly something going on this book, and it takes a long time to be able to see how it all fits together. It's such an impressive piece of work from a technical standpoint, and thoroughly enjoyable as a piece of art.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/506735751" title="review of American Gods on Goodreads">Full review</a>.)</p>
<h3>Macbeth by William Shakespeare</h3>
<p><em>Set in medieval Scotland and partly based on a true historical account, Macbeth charts the bloody rise to power and tragic downfall of the warrior Macbeth. Already a successful soldier in the army of King Duncan, Macbeth is informed by Three Witches that he is to become king. As part of the same prophecy, the Witches predict that future Scottish kings will be descended not from Macbeth but from his fellow army captain, Banquo. Although initially prepared to wait for Fate to take its course, Macbeth is stung by ambition and confusion when King Duncan nominates his son Malcolm as his heir.</em></p>
<p>I try not to post re-reads here, but the past few months have been almost entirely made up of re-reads and Shakespeare, so let's just go for one that is both a re-read <em>and</em> Shakespeare! <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/macbeth/" title="related post">We all know I love Macbeth</a>, so there's really not that much I can say about it, except, you know, witches and insanity and murder. Come <em>on</em>, guys. I'm no expert on Shakespeare, and I've still only read, like, 7 or 8 of his plays, but I compare everything to Macbeth because it's just the best. This paragraph has been meaningless. I'm sorry. Macbeth is the greatest.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/529122683" title="review of Macbeth on Goodreads">Full review</a>.)</p>
<h3>The Year of Secret Assignments by Jaclyn Moriarty</h3>
<p><em>Told entirely through letters, diary entries, emails, and other writing, Moriarty's novel introduces us to Emily, Lydia, and Cassie &#8212; all students at Ashbury High &#8212; who begin writing to their Brookfield High counterparts through the schools' organized pen pal project. Readers learn quickly that each girl has her own writing style and that at two of the Brookfield boys (Seb and Charlie) seem to be smitten with Lydia and Emily. The only trouble is Cassie's pen pal, Matthew, a shady character who first sends her short, threatening letters and then becomes strangely sweet toward her. Nobody can figure out why Cassie keeps writing to him, but after she has a crushing meet-up with Matthew, Cassie discovers &#8212; with the help of her friends and the Brookfield guys &#8212; that he hasn't been honest about his identity. All could be ended there, but when Charlie helps take revenge and Brookfield High gets mysteriously vandalized, the group comes together to deliver justice and save the endangered pen pal project.</em></p>
<p>This might be the book I've read the most times in the entire history of everything, and that's because it is really freaking good, and totally holds up the older I get. The entire series is innovative, funny, and touching at moments, but this one is my absolute favourite, because I love Cassie, Emily, and Lydia. They're developed, flawed, and totally enjoyable protagonists. The plot is the right balance of realistic and over the top; it's just so much fun, and really well-constructed on top of being incredibly enjoyable on a superficial level.</p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/536712461" title="review of The Year of Secret Assignments on Goodreads">Full review</a>.)</p>
<p>I have the month of April left to buckle down and work hard, and then I will have four blissful months of freedom in which to devour books at a hopefully alarming rate. 18 books in 3 months is definitely less than I'd like &#8211; hopefully I can bring this number up quite a lot over the summer!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/favourite-books-january-to-march-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cabane à sucre</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/cabane-a-sucre/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/cabane-a-sucre/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 23:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3793</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday I took full advantage of the fact that I live in Quebec, packing myself on a bus before 9am (on a Sunday! and this is me we're talking about!) to go to a cabane à sucre with my two sets of aunts and uncles and five cousins, who range in age from 21 months [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I took full advantage of the fact that I live in Quebec, packing myself on a bus before 9am (on a Sunday! and this is me we're talking about!) to go to a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cabane_%C3%A0_sucre" title="wiki page">cabane à sucre</a> with my two sets of aunts and uncles and five cousins, who range in age from 21 months to 10.</p>
<p>For those not in the know, the main attraction of these cabanes is the tire d'érable, which is simply maple syrup poured onto fresh snow and rolled onto a popsicle stick. The snow makes it harden, so it turns into sugary, sticky maple syrup toffee. The best cabanes also provide you with a full meal complete with a lot of meat. And fat. And maple syrup, obviously.</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ob875fu.png" alt="" class="fancy" /><br />
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/PqdMQQh.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>This particular cabane had a small collection of farm animals, including a horse-drawn carriage ride through a forest. We walked around the little petting zoo for awhile, although my one seven-year-old cousin was becoming very uneasy that the animals would charge the fences and attack us, and of course we went on the forest tour.</p>
<p>The biggest downside to this little adventure is that although we had a reservation at 12:30, we didn't actually get in to eat until 1:30, which, OBVIOUSLY, is awful. I hadn't eaten anything for breakfast that day, anticipating an absolute mountain of food at the cabane, so by the time I actually had food in front of me I was ravenous.</p>
<p>Luckily, the food was completely delicious. Traditional cabane à sucre food is pretty much just sugar and fat. I think the best thing I had was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cretons" title="wiki page">cretons</a>, which my uncle described as "meat butter". It's so gross but completely delicious. Rounding out this meal of lard was the heaping pile of salty, crispy <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oreilles_de_crisse" title="wiki page">oreilles de crisse</a>, which literally translates to "ears of Christ". Traditionally, you're supposed to pour maple syrup over all your food (which also includes eggs, ham, soup, and various vegetables), but I skipped on that because I knew I was already dangerously close to going into a sugar coma! Also, I don't think I've quite embraced Quebec culture enough to really appreciate maple syrup on my ham&#8230;</p>
<p>For dessert, we had three options. I sampled two, but skipped the sugar pie because I knew it would be too sweet for me. The first thing I had was what they called a pancake but was a lot crispier and more solid than the pancakes I'm used to. It was very simple and completely delicious. Then, I had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pouding_ch%C3%B4meur" title="wiki page">pouding chômeur</a>, which is just cake soaked in maple syrup, and which is as great as it sounds.</p>
<p>I actually skipped the tire, because I was already full and usually about two licks of it makes me feel sick. However, it was a super successful day overall, and I was really glad to go back to a legit cabane &#8211; the last time I went was in grade 8, when I went on a grad trip to Quebec City! I had a rather indulgent weekend, with ridiculous poutine for dinner on Saturday evening<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/cabane-a-sucre/#footnote_0_3793" id="identifier_0_3793" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="totally necessary, it went a long way in sobering me up after a day of belated St. Paddy's Day drinking">1</a></sup> and then my four thousand grams of lard and sugar at the cabane&#8230; but I think I've earned it. Or maybe I just don't care. When in Rome, right? If by "Rome" I mean "rural Quebec", which I definitely do. Rome doesn't even have meat butter, so I think I'm doing okay.</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3793" class="footnote">totally necessary, it went a long way in sobering me up after a day of belated St. Paddy's Day drinking</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/cabane-a-sucre/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nice things</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/nice-things/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/nice-things/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3782</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello. Did you know I am very stressed right now? No? Why not? Is it because we never talk? I guess that could be why. Or maybe you do know that I am very stressed right now, and that I'm at a point where every overwhelming emotion turns into tears, and most emotions become overwhelming, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello. Did you know I am very stressed right now? No? Why not? Is it because we never talk? I guess that could be why. Or maybe you do know that I am very stressed right now, and that I'm at a point where every overwhelming emotion turns into tears, and most emotions become overwhelming, and really it sounds a lot worse than it really is. I have, like, three weeks of classes left, you know?</p>
<p>Okay, but, I'm very stressed, and I'm sleeping horribly a lot of the time, not always because I'm an asshole and stay up until 4am reading fanfiction, sometimes just because I'm too stressed to sleep and have early conferences in which everyone makes jokes about absolutist regimes while I write a letter to my aunt about the weather. So, there you go. However, I have been trying to do small but nice things to take care of myself, because I tend to neglect myself in favour of everything else, and as L'Oreal says, I AM WORTH IT. <em>OKAY</em>? I AM. So, here are some of the things I have been doing to keep myself from curling into the fetal position and shutting down completely.</p>
<h3>Working out</h3>
<p>God, RIGHT? This is ME we're talking about. One day I had this history midterm, and the thing is that when I have things to do for school I will do almost literally anything before the thing I actually need to do, and I was just like, "I should work out," and so I did, and now I mainly do it to procrastinate, but sometimes I do it JUST BECAUSE I WANT TO. Like, I actively get a hankering to make myself sweat and cramp up. God, who <em>am</em> I?</p>
<p>But, really, even though in the moment sometimes I'm like, "I would rather nail my eyeballs to a wall than hold this plank for one second longer," when it's done I feel really good. And I am noticing an improvement, which is cool, because being able to feel tangible progress is one of the best ways to keep me motivated. So. I am this person now, and even though I know exercise is a good thing, I kind of hate myself for it because I spent so long not being this person, and now I work out BEFORE class sometimes. Whereas in the rest of the history of my life, anything BEFORE school was time to sleep or endlessly browse Tumblr, and everything AFTER school was when I did things. I think I've really started to achieve adulthood here.</p>
<h3>Drinking tea</h3>
<p>This one might seem kind of stupid and frivolous, but my morning cup of tea really helps me wake up in a good mood, and my evening (read: midnight) cup of tea helps me relax and get in the right frame of mind for bedtime. And then there are the supplementary cups of tea throughout the day, of course. I've always been a big tea drinker, but I used to keep it all confined to the evening. Now I just drink tea all day, and, honestly, it's really nice. I think part of it is just having a routine, but it's also good to have something enjoyable to associate morning with. Because, yeah, I may be a person who works out before class sometimes, but I don't know if I'll ever be a morning person. Ugh.</p>
<h3>Spending time on my makeup</h3>
<p>I used to be very strongly against the idea of my makeup routine taking more than about 10 minutes out of my morning, mostly because I liked sleeping a lot. (Okay, I still do. Obviously.) Also, I saw makeup more as something I <em>had</em> to do, so I did the bare minimum things that I thought were necessary in order to put my face out into the world. These days, it takes me about 20-30 minutes every morning to do my makeup. Past me would be appalled. So many people I know would be appalled. 20-30 minutes isn't even that long, compared to a lot of other people, but it's long enough that I know a fair amount of people are reading this being like, "Ugh, why?" I just really enjoy not rushing it, and having fun with it, and being a bit indulgent for awhile. Taking half an hour just for myself, to do something completely frivolous but that makes me happy, is a nice way to start my day. And these days I do it less because I feel like I have to, and more because there are so many possibilities. It's <em>fun</em> to pick colours and textures and line thickness, and I know some of you are like, "Yeah fucking right," but what can I say? I actually really like my morning routine lately.</p>
<p>A corollary to this is wearing bright lipstick regularly. I started doing this on days I had exams, just to pump myself up, and it made me feel so good about myself that I started doing it for no reason at all. Because, really, who even needs a reason to wear bright lipstick? I'M WORTH IT, remember? And bright lipstick is fucking awesome.</p>
<p>Also, I always have excellent nails, thank you for noticing.</p>
<h3>Decorating</h3>
<p>I didn't finish decorating my room until January, when I decided to just cover every surface with stuff. My room is very "university dorm room", with lots of cards, posters, and pictures of my favourite musicians (and X Factor bands, OF COURSE), and it's nothing special, but it actually went a long way in cheering me up this winter. (Which, honestly, is quite a feat, because <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/winter/" title="related post">winter kind of sucks my soul out</a>.) I've actually been adding new stuff to my walls pretty frequently, and even though it's not exactly impressive artwork or anything, having postcards from the cool places I've been, pictures of my friends, and my British teen idols staring at me is much preferable to being surrounded by four stark white walls!</p>
<p>What are some small things you do to take care of yourself?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/nice-things/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The term &quot;identity crisis&quot; is more dramatic than this really is</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 22:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[i like]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3775</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I want to know how people existed pre-internet, how people went through a "holy shit I'm turning 19 soon1 and will only have a year left of being a teenager" identity crisis if not publicly, for anyone to read, recorded in excruciating detail. Seriously, what did people do? How did people live before oversharing became [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to know how people existed pre-internet, how people went through a "holy shit I'm turning 19 soon<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/#footnote_0_3775" id="identifier_0_3775" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="like, in 3 months and one day">1</a></sup> and will only have a year left of being a teenager" identity crisis if not publicly, for anyone to read, recorded in excruciating detail. Seriously, what did people do? How did people live before oversharing became easier than just, you know, not doing that?</p>
<p>Here's a cool fun thing: I'm obsessed with my hair lately. Well, I mean, I always kind of am, I'm very vain about my hair because even though it has a tendency to frizz it's generally good hair. I was itching for a change, though, and I definitely thought I got that change out of my system in December <a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/i-have-no-hair-and-im-not-at-all-overdramatic/" title="related post">when I chopped off ten inches</a>, because, let's be real, that was a fairly big deal, even though by this point it's already grown out quite a bit.</p>
<p>But, no, since January 11 I have been in a deep state of flux, and inner turmoil, not in like an unnecessarily dramatic way, just in the way that I'm actually regressing, and it's fucking awful. I'm kidding, it's not awful at all. I love living the tween years I never had. But let's not talk about that anymore. Let's talk about my hair.</p>
<p>I decided, like maybe a week or so ago, that I wanted purple hair. It just started as a sort of hypothetical, mostly because I was looking at pictures of Perrie Edwards, which of course is a part of my regression. But, look, okay?</p>
<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/dYr8h3i.jpg" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>Of course, other people have done the lavender hair thing with varying degrees of success, like Kelly Osbourne and Katy Perry, and I thought it was nice, but I wouldn't say I was especially impressed with it or anything. But now Perrie is my teen idol, even though she's less than eleven months older than me, and I was just like, "I wonder if I could rock lavender hair," just really hypothetically, but now I can't expel that idea from my brain.</p>
<p>I don't even know if I could, but the thing is that I'm obsessed with the idea. I'm not doing anything about it right now, because I want to do it right (read: professionally) and I don't have the money, and also because I don't want it to affect my employment opportunities over the summer, and also because I don't want to rush into something like bleaching my entire head of hair and semi-permanently applying an unnatural colour on top of that, you know? I may be a nearly nineteen-year-old who acts like a pre-adolescent idiot, but I have that much common sense.</p>
<p>But I think I'm probably going to do it when the time is right, because, really, I should get this out of my system while I'm still a teenager with no real responsibilities, and also YOLO.</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3775" class="footnote">like, in 3 months and one day</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/the-term-identity-crisis-is-more-dramatic-than-this-really-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#039;s talk about that song</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 21:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arguably funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foolishness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I've touched on this before but never written a full post on it, and there's no time like the present! The present is 2:05am on a school night, but it's cool, sleep is so whatever, who even needs to do that, not me, and probably not Harry Styles either. If it's good enough for him [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've touched on this before but never written a full post on it, and there's no time like the present! The present is 2:05am on a school night, but it's cool, sleep is so whatever, who even needs to do that, not me, and probably not Harry Styles either. If it's good enough for him it's good enough for me.</p>
<p>Okay. That song. I hesitate to name it and prefer to just keep it at arm's length with a euphemism, like Voldemort. I'm afraid that if I name it a Death Eater will apparate and Avada Kedavra me, or whatever the Muggle equivalent is. </p>
<p>That awful song that you totally think about when you think of my name. <em>That</em> song.</p>
<p>Now, let me tell you something. This is nothing personal against you, and I'm sure you have many redeeming qualities like maybe you're really funny or you volunteer with puppies or you know how to graph a parabola, but if you meet me, hear my name, start singing that fucking song, and then wait for me to shower you with praise for your unprecedented wit, my entire body will be consumed with a potent rage and I will probably hate you. Because, one, that's not original, I get that all the time, do you really think that isn't something I put up with constantly, and two, HAVE YOU EVER PAID ATTENTION TO THE LYRICS OF THAT SONG? HAVE YOU? Because I have, and they're awful, and one time at my cottage we were having a campfire and my grandpa started singing it and I got so mad I burst into tears and ran away and it caused a lot of drama, and it all could have been avoided if only that song didn't exist. This is why we need time travel! So many people say if they had a time machine they'd kill Hitler, and I'm not saying that's not on my list, I'm just saying that my top priority would be preventing Percy Montrose from putting such a shitty song into the world.</p>
<p>The thing is that people don't realize what the song is. They only know the first line, you know, the one that uses a term of endearment. Like, why wouldn't I like to be called your darling? (Actually, fyi, it's kind of creepy. Only Harry Styles and Kat Dennings are allowed to call me their darling.) But the thing is that you need to listen to the lyrics that come next and realize that they are deeply unsettling on various levels.</p>
<p><em>Drove she ducklings to the water<br />
Ev'ry morning just at nine,<br />
Hit her foot against a splinter,<br />
Fell into the foaming brine.</em></p>
<p>Hmm, that's nice, it's a little girl named Clementine who likes to feed the ducks, nothing to see here, oh wait, shit, her dumbass fucking miner father<sup><a href="http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/#footnote_0_3768" id="identifier_0_3768" class="footnote-link footnote-identifier-link" title="who, by the way, I always picture as my own father, making it SO MUCH WORSE">1</a></sup> wasn't paying attention to her, and now she's drowning. That's lovely! Very nice! A heartwarming tune! But wait, there's more! (I should be an infomercial voiceover, totally my bag, why do I need a liberal arts degree again?)</p>
<p><em>Ruby lips above the water,<br />
Blowing bubbles, soft and fine,<br />
But, alas, I was no swimmer,<br />
So I lost my Clementine.</em></p>
<p>Oh, wow, lovely evocative imagery of a small child drowning, really super. A fucking plus, Percy Montrose, you piece of shit. OH, WAIT. Her idiot father doesn't know how to swim, so he just lets her drown. And then writes beautiful poetry about how her mouth looked as it gasped its dying breaths. So nice. I can see why this song has endured in the folk canon. Oh, come on, what the hell do you mean there's more, Jesus Christ.</p>
<p><em>How I missed her! How I missed her,<br />
How I missed my Clementine,<br />
But I kissed her little sister,<br />
I forgot my Clementine</em></p>
<p>This is repeated three times, just in case the vivid imagery of a drowning child wasn't holding your interest and you started nodding off, because it's very important to reinforce the fact that Clementine's father watched her drown and then forgot about her because he had another child, one who wasn't a shitty idiot who fell into the water while feeding the ducks. Outstanding!</p>
<p>Then there are like a million verses describing her grave, and then her dad dies of old age, which really is so unfair, karma should have made him drown, and then at the end they're like, "Hey, Boy Scouts, learn CPR so children don't have to die!"</p>
<p>Okay, so, the end, when you sing this song at me you are evoking a convoluted narrative in which a little girl bearing my name drowns because her father is too stupid to be alive, then is overshadowed by her younger sister instead of being properly mourned, and then you find out the whole upsetting story was just to teach a bunch of boys the importance of artificial resuscitation, and can you see why it's not endearing when you sing it at me? Bye.</p>
<hr /><ol class="footnotes"><li id="footnote_0_3768" class="footnote">who, by the way, I always picture as my own father, making it SO MUCH WORSE</li></ol>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/lets-talk-about-that-song/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Search terms, part 3: One Direction and the Pope</title>
		<link>http://ohclementine.com/entry/search-terms-part-3-one-direction-and-the-pope/</link>
		<comments>http://ohclementine.com/entry/search-terms-part-3-one-direction-and-the-pope/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 20:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohclementine.com/?p=3761</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello! It is time for the third installment in the "This is the dumb shit I Google" series. Once again, these are all things I have Googled, not things that people have Googled to find my site. Actually, those search terms are almost never funny. But this stuff is gold! very happy celebrities fat birds [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello! It is time for the third installment in the "This is the dumb shit I Google" series. Once again, these are all things I have Googled, not things that people have Googled to find my site. Actually, those search terms are almost never funny. But this stuff is gold!</p>
<p>very happy celebrities<br />
fat birds<br />
cat nose health<br />
what's the point of whiskers<br />
poetic names<br />
dog with piercing eyes, dog that paul ryan looks like<br />
dogs that look stupid<br />
cat anxiety, cat mental illness, cat mental illness signs, cat insanity test (<em>I worry about my cat a lot</em>)<br />
baby tomato, little tomato, what are little tomatoes called<br />
how many times were hogwarts exams cancelled<br />
mitt romney as a turkey<br />
nick jonas ass (<em>twice, ugh, I'm awful, I don't deserve the gift of life</em>)<br />
bird with lampshade head, bird with built in hat<br />
what if there were no stars, effects of not having stars<br />
homosexuality and teen wolf<br />
abe linc's son<br />
shovel teeth (<em>It's a legitimate thing, it's called sinodonty</em>)<br />
book with dragon and human performing mating ritual<br />
show where people sing with pigeons, show where people sing with scary things<br />
morrissey jokes<br />
mitt romney in a spiral of despair<br />
fun things to do on the inretnet when you adre durnk<br />
what's goin on with livejournal<br />
Siri how do you feel about Bill Gates<br />
metal horns clipart<br />
can you tattoo a cat<br />
joe biden smiling<br />
how many teens are pregnant in america (<em>I'm always concerned about real world problems, you know</em>)<br />
DANIEL DAY LEWIS LOOKS LIKE MORRISSEY (<em>he totally does, he does, he does, I will fight you on this</em>)<br />
ron jeremy but not disgusting<br />
bald eagles mating<br />
pope arrest<br />
is this a dagger which i see before me (<em>like 8 fucking times</em>)<br />
who was the youngest pope<br />
longest serving popes<br />
does benedict get to keep his name<br />
what do unbaptized peopel do at communion<br />
which mcgill residence did win butler live in<br />
how many days have i been alive<br />
what's wrong with justin bieber<br />
pope news<br />
incest in hamlet<br />
WHAT'S HAPPENING WITH THE POPE</p>
<p>And then, all of these, all within the last two months:<br />
does zayn malik swear<br />
when does 1d3d come out<br />
larry stylinson leaked emails<br />
harry styles giraffe joke<br />
harry styles four nipple pics (<em>like, 4 times</em>)<br />
harry styles four nipple video<br />
niall horan crying<br />
niall horan crying at concert<br />
what does niall even do with all his money<br />
1d kissing booth (<em>IT'S A LEGITIMATE THING</em>)<br />
niall facts<br />
does harry styles have a thigh gap<br />
one direction harry potter crossover<br />
harry styles favourite food<br />
does zayn swear (<em>I'm really concerned with this, obviously</em>)<br />
where can i find a large one direction cutout in toronto<br />
burberry heart shirt, harry styles birthday shirt knockoff, burberry heart shirt knockoff (<em>None of this got me anywhere</em>)<br />
how many nipples does liam payne have<br />
what books does louis like, what books does louis tomlinson like<br />
harry styles butterfly tattoo (<em>This was before the good picture came out</em>)<br />
sassy harry<br />
niall horan shoes<br />
niall horan shitty baby<br />
does anyone hate harry styles<br />
harry styles eyes, WHAT COLOUR ARE HARRY'S EYES, WHAT COLOUR ARE HARRY STYLES EYES<br />
hardcore niall</p>
<p>And of course:</p>
<p><img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/1ccefe601d574779c5d88ed0906fcbcd/tumblr_mjm3pyvHOi1qgs500o1_400.png" alt="" class="fancy" /></p>
<p>This really says a lot about me and I'm not sure it's stuff I want you to know, but, whatever, no shame, judge away. Nick Jonas ass.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohclementine.com/entry/search-terms-part-3-one-direction-and-the-pope/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
