<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
  xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
  xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:cc="http://web.resource.org/cc/"
  xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/">

<channel rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<title>Michael Smith News</title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/</link>
<description>Maureen&#39;s son, Katarina&#39;s husband and lapsed radio broadcaster&#39;s views.</description>
<dc:language>en-AU</dc:language>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T10:09:45+11:00</dc:date>
<admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://www.typepad.com/" />


<items>
<rdf:Seq><rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/sexual-assult-in-baulkham-hills.html" />
<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/testing-the-engine-mounts.html" />
<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/meet-pauline-vamos-shes-prepared-to-sacrifice-other-peoples-super-to-help-wayne-swan-in-a-time-of-ne.html" />
<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/your-super-yes-yours-as-in-belonging-to-you-it-would-be-nice-if-the-super-laws-were-just-left-untouc.html" />
<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/qantas-changes-inflight-meals-service-to-halal-pork-and-alcohol-removed-from-meals-on-board-.html" />
<rdf:li rdf:resource="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/come-back-robert-mcclelland-your-party-and-your-country-need-you.html" />
</rdf:Seq>
</items>

</channel>

<item rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/sexual-assult-in-baulkham-hills.html">
<title>Sexual Assult in Baulkham Hills</title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/sexual-assult-in-baulkham-hills.html</link>
<description>Sauce 10:05am A number of readers were concerned after the reported alledged sexual assult of a woman in Baulkham Hills last month. NSW Police have concluded their investigation and the media release below is self explanitory. It would seem the family has a few issues to deal with now. Police...</description>
<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Sauce 10:05am&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of readers were concerned after the reported alledged sexual assult of a woman in Baulkham Hills last month. NSW Police have concluded their investigation and the media release below is self explanitory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would seem the family has a few issues to deal with now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Police complete sexual assault investigation - Strike Force Mikkelsen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friday, 05 April 2013 09:29:50 AM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An investigation into the reported abduction and sexual assault of a teenage girl at Baulkham Hills last month is now complete after detectives determined the incidents did not occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police were told a 17-year-old girl was abducted and sexually assaulted by a number of males after leaving a party at Merindah Road, Baulkham Hills, about 1am on Sunday 3 March 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detectives from the Sex Crimes Squad and The Hills Local Area Command established Strike Force Mikkelsen to investigate the report and have conducted extensive inquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous people were spoken to during the course of those investigations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strike force has now been closed after it was determined the report was fabricated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inquiries into the actions of the 17-year-old girl are continuing and police continue to work with her and her family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police urge anyone who has been the victim of sexual assault to come forward, with the assurance that all reports are taken seriously and will be thoroughly investigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports can be made at any police station.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>



<dc:creator>Michael Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T10:09:45+11:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/testing-the-engine-mounts.html">
<title>Testing the engine mounts</title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/testing-the-engine-mounts.html</link>
<description>Sauce 9:47am Michael&#39;s taken the engine mounts for a short test drive down to Wagga Wagga for the weekend. The well organised man hit the road early and should be back online in the next couple of hours to talk a bit of Super.</description>
<content:encoded>Sauce 9:47am
Michael&amp;#39;s taken the engine mounts for a short test drive down to Wagga Wagga for the weekend.
The well organised man hit the road early and should be back online in the next couple of hours to talk a bit of Super.</content:encoded>



<dc:creator>Michael Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T09:55:31+11:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/meet-pauline-vamos-shes-prepared-to-sacrifice-other-peoples-super-to-help-wayne-swan-in-a-time-of-ne.html">
<title>Meet Pauline Vamos.   She&#39;s prepared to sacrifice other people&#39;s super to help Wayne Swan in a time of need.</title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/meet-pauline-vamos-shes-prepared-to-sacrifice-other-peoples-super-to-help-wayne-swan-in-a-time-of-ne.html</link>
<description>If you have made your retirement arrangements in good faith under the laws you were told would not be changed one jot or tittle by Labor, you might want to have a chat with Pauline Vamos - and if Pauline feels she&#39;s been misrepresented in what the SMH has attributed...</description>
<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have made your retirement arrangements in good faith under the laws you were told would not be changed one jot or tittle by Labor, you might want to have a chat with Pauline Vamos - and if Pauline feels she&amp;#39;s been misrepresented in what the SMH has attributed to her she ought to get on the phone to the SMH first up this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pauline is prepared to consider reduced or no tax concessions on your super account, offering your donation to Wayne Swan as a peace sacrifice. &amp;#0160; How big of her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smh.com.au/opinion/political-news/funds-offer-compromise-on-balances-20130404-2h9qu.html#ixzz2PW5Zy6m5&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;he language of the SMH&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peak body representing super funds has offered the Treasurer an olive branch, saying it would be prepared to consider reduced or zero tax concessions on super accounts with very high balances.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;The aim of the retirement income system is to have enough, it is not being able to amass millions and millions of dollars in a tax-free environment,&amp;#39;&amp;#39; Association of Superannuation Funds chief executive Pauline Vamos said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;If we could establish a size of fund that would guarantee a comfortable retirement, we could have a lifetime cap. Any good retirement system must have a ceiling. We are talking about tax concessions funded by the Australian community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Vamos said her association and the government were not far from an agreement. &amp;#39;&amp;#39;We&amp;#39;ve had constructive conversations.&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;

An olive branch to Swan? &amp;#0160; What for? &amp;#0160; What have high nett worth people done to justify handing over the olive branch? &amp;#0160; And what&amp;#39;s Swan done to deserve a peace offering?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#0160;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>



<dc:creator>Michael Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T05:26:29+11:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/your-super-yes-yours-as-in-belonging-to-you-it-would-be-nice-if-the-super-laws-were-just-left-untouc.html">
<title>Your super.   Yes, yours - as in belonging to you.   It would be nice if the super laws were just left untouched for a while wouldn&#39;t it?</title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/your-super-yes-yours-as-in-belonging-to-you-it-would-be-nice-if-the-super-laws-were-just-left-untouc.html</link>
<description>The Australian Tax Office posted this ad to youtube on 25 March, 2013. Your super, it&#39;s yours, it&#39;s going up from 1 July etc. I&#39;m surprised it&#39;s only has 1200 odd views. It also has a little of the party political about it. Kevin Rudd promised Labor wouldn&#39;t change the...</description>
<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The Australian Tax Office posted this ad to youtube on 25 March, 2013. &amp;nbsp; Your super, it&#39;s yours, it&#39;s going up from 1 July etc. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;m surprised it&#39;s only has 1200 odd views. &amp;nbsp; It also has a little of the party political about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/sC-fxBrOsIY&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Iframe Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/iframe/468x60.html&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Iframe Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Rudd promised Labor wouldn&#39;t change the laws, not one jot, not one tittle. &amp;nbsp;Who knows what&#39;s driving the current round of conjecture about what Gillard/Swan/Shorten/Emerson et al might do to your super. &amp;nbsp; No doubt the budget deficit is one element, but you can&#39;t help but think the ingrained class war and jealousies that the socialist warriors fondly embrace might have a fair bit to do with it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/opinion/wayne-swans-rich-targets-already-pay-the-bill/story-fnc2jivw-1226612818237&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;The Australian&#39;s Adam Creighton&lt;/a&gt; with some common sense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SO-CALLED super tax breaks might flow overwhelmingly to higher income earners - but so does the nation&#39;s tax bill.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest tax office data show the top 1 per cent of income earners pay about 17 per cent of all income tax, while the top 10 per cent pay almost half of the commonwealth government&#39;s annual income tax haul.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia&#39;s tax system is highly progressive, with a top marginal tax rate of 45 per cent - above New Zealand&#39;s at 33 per cent and the US at 35 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the top fifth of taxpaying households are the only net contributors to Australia&#39;s welfare state, once handouts and use of government services such as education and healthcare are taken into account. The more you earn the more you pay, and at an increasing rate. A chief executive earning $1 million a year is required to pay more than $423,000 in annual tax, almost 40 times as much tax as a high school teacher earning $60,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;A junior apprentice pays an average tax rate of a little over 9 per cent compared with 38.3 per cent for the successful barrister.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contribution of high earners, who typically invest relatively more in the sharemarket, is even greater when company tax is factored in, which is projected to raise about $75 billion this year, or almost a fifth of total government revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To claim there are $32bn in &quot;tax concessions&quot; for superannuation is also to misunderstand the purpose of super, which is not to redistribute income but to foster a national pool of savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existing tax structure was in large part the design of Labor treasurer Paul Keating, who recognised the advantages of keeping super tax rates low and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, very high earners are not manipulating their affairs to take advantage of the concessions. The Rudd and Gillard governments&#39; reduction in the maximum annual contribution caps to $25,000 means people earnings more than $277,000 have little incentive to put more money in super. The compulsory 9 per cent contribution in included in the $25,000 cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afr.com/p/national/shorten_scrambles_on_super_OpEwIh8XOwFKgQaQ108CnN&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;AFR&#39;s Philip Coorey reckons Bill Shorten&#39;s &lt;/a&gt;looking to wrap the uncertainty up as early as today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal government is accelerating efforts to end the damaging speculation surrounding superannuation and wants to announce the changes as early as Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As union-backed industry super funds joined retail funds in calling for the government to leave the superannuation system alone,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Australian Financial Review&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp; understands Superannuation Minister Bill Shorten, under mounting internal criticism for his handling of the issue, was being pressured to finalise a policy on Thursday and announce it on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Julia Gillard will fly to China on Friday, while Mr Shorten, who is also going to China as part of the delegation, will not leave until Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of late Thursday afternoon, no final decision had been made but there were furious negotiations behind closed doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources said there was a phone hook-up of cabinet planned for Thursday night to approve any changes and pave the way for a snap announcement. The urgency comes amid rising hostility from the super industry and the Industry Super Network (ISN), which represents union-backed industry funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will release a paper on Friday calling for a pause until after the election when there can be a more sober debate over policy changes canvassing the adequacy, sustainability, equity and flexibility of the current system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smh.com.au/opinion/political-news/funds-offer-compromise-on-balances-20130404-2h9qu.html&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;the Sydney Morning Herald story&lt;/a&gt; made me so damned angry I&#39;ve put it up as a separate post!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>



<dc:creator>Michael Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T05:26:07+11:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/qantas-changes-inflight-meals-service-to-halal-pork-and-alcohol-removed-from-meals-on-board-.html">
<title>Qantas changes inflight meals service to Halal - pork and alcohol removed from meals on board </title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/qantas-changes-inflight-meals-service-to-halal-pork-and-alcohol-removed-from-meals-on-board-.html</link>
<description>I have a simple question. Why can&#39;t Islam respect us? Pigs can&#39;t fly - Qantas bans pork on in-flight menu to respect Islam Angela Saurine and Peter Holmes The Daily Telegraph April 05, 2013 12:00AM Read the story at the Daily Telegraph QANTAS has removed pork from its in-flight menu...</description>
<content:encoded>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&#39;t Islam respect us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pigs can&#39;t fly - Qantas bans pork on in-flight menu to respect Islam&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Angela Saurine and Peter Holmes&lt;/cite&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/&quot;&gt;The Daily Telegraph&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;April 05, 2013&amp;nbsp;12:00AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/pigs-cant-fly-qantas-bans-pork-on-in-flight-menu-to-respect-islam/story-e6freuy9-1226612841997&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Read the story at the Daily Telegraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QANTAS has removed pork from its in-flight menu on flights to and from Europe as a result of its partnership with Middle Eastern airline Emirates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No food containing pork or pork products will be served on those flights - which now has a stopover in Dubai - because it is strictly forbidden in Islam and is considered &quot;unholy&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All meals offered on the route in first, business and economy classes will also be prepared without alcohol in keeping with the Islamic religion. A note on the Qantas menus on flights in and out of Dubai states that the meals do not contain pork products or alcohol. The airline has also introduced a mezze plate offering traditional Middle Eastern fare in its upper classes and has Arabic translations after in-flight announcements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Qantas spokesman said the decision to remove pork, ham and other related food items had had minimal impact on its menu and it was still offering the same meal choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Qantas in-flight catering often reflects the cultural and regional influences of the international destinations we fly to,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, Qantas has changed the rules for people who want to fly to Europe. &amp;nbsp; Qantas has said that it will now be done via the Emir&#39;s city of Dubai. &amp;nbsp; It&#39;s rubbish for Qantas to say that the inflight catering reflects the cultural and regional influences of its destinations - until last weekend, a flight to London was a flight from a free and tolerant western civilised country to a like country with similar traditions. &amp;nbsp;Qantas interposed the Islamist element. &amp;nbsp; Israelis are disadvantaged, Jews are disadvantaged, gay people, single women, people who like pork too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up with bacon and eggs in the morning. &amp;nbsp; I couldn&#39;t begin to count the number of Qantas bacon and eggs breakfasts I&#39;ve had. &amp;nbsp; It&#39;s what I eat. &amp;nbsp; Why do we have to change because of Islamic beliefs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Iframe Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/iframe/468x60.html&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Iframe Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;</content:encoded>



<dc:creator>Michael Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T05:25:46+11:00</dc:date>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/come-back-robert-mcclelland-your-party-and-your-country-need-you.html">
<title>Come back Robert McClelland, your Party and your country need you.</title>
<link>http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/04/come-back-robert-mcclelland-your-party-and-your-country-need-you.html</link>
<description>The field of candidates for the Federal Seat of Barton, due to be vacated by Robert McClelland at the next election is less than inspiring. Robert McClelland is a great loss to politics in Australia and it will take many years for any replacement to come near his wisdom and...</description>
<content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The field of candidates for the Federal Seat of Barton, due to be vacated by Robert McClelland at the next election is less than inspiring. &amp;nbsp; Robert McClelland is a great loss to politics in Australia and it will take many years for any replacement to come near his wisdom and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in this electorate. &amp;nbsp; I went to St Joseph&#39;s Rockdale and Marist Brothers Kogarah. &amp;nbsp; I played footy against guys who played for Arncliffe Scots - my dad was born at Arncliffe and his dad was a 50 something WW2 Sergeant at the depot at Arncliffe after serving in the trenches in WW1. &amp;nbsp; Mum grew up in Herbert Street Rockdale and still lives in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I scarcely recognise Arncliffe now. &amp;nbsp; Whoever does lock in the support of the Mosque as the SMH story notes, might see what its leaders can do to stop the persistent desecration of war memorials in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Battle for Barton will be decided by mosque&#39;s support&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;Date&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;April 5, 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race to replace former attorney-general Robert McClelland in the southern Sydney seat of Barton will hinge on which candidate locks in the support of Australia&#39;s largest Shiite mosque at Arncliffe.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Union-backed candidates Steve McMahon, former mayor of Hurstville, and Shane O&#39;Brien, the mayor of Rockdale, are expected to receive the most votes when Labor Party branch members vote on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALP sources said Mr McMahon, who won the blessing of Morris Iemma after the former NSW premier decided not to contest in Barton, has firmed as the favourite to win preselection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirsten Andrews, a former Labor worker backed by her former boss, Environment Minister Tony Burke, remains in contention. The 20 per cent loading she will receive as a female candidate and a preference swap deal she has struck with Mr McMahon means she could still prevail in the ballot of 272 votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;adspot-300x250-pos-3&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;Candidates and branch members said a bloc of 70 votes associated with NSW upper-house MP Shaoquett Moselmane and the Lebanese Muslim community were the key to winning Barton.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Moselmane&#39;s first cousin Sheikh Kamal Mousselmani presides over the Al-Zahra mosque at Arncliffe. His brother Kamel Mousselmani is an ALP preselector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group has been pushing for a youth centre to be built at Arncliffe Park, something the then premier Kristina Keneally promised if Labor was returned in 2011, and Rockdale City Council has considered adding it to its capital works agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidates have been asked to explain their support for a youth centre and what they could do from a federal level. There has been speculation the mosque wanted a Muslim-only youth centre but Sheikh Mousselmani said it would be for the entire community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He once courted controversy for his public support for the Iranian-backed terrorist group Hezbollah in 2007 but has since been a key voice for unity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read more:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smh.com.au/opinion/political-news/battle-for-barton-will-be-decided-by-mosques-support-20130404-2h9nu.html#ixzz2PWI7m9xh&quot;&gt;http://www.smh.com.au/opinion/political-news/battle-for-barton-will-be-decided-by-mosques-support-20130404-2h9nu.html#ixzz2PWI7m9xh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Iframe Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/iframe/468x60.html&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;60&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Iframe Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;</content:encoded>



<dc:creator>Michael Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-04-05T05:25:12+11:00</dc:date>
</item>


</rdf:RDF>

<!-- ph=1 -->
