<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <title>Michael Smith News</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/atom.xml" />
    <link rel="hub" href="http://hubbub.api.typepad.com/" />
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/" />
    <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:weblog-107014838110033675</id>
    <updated>2013-03-24T19:32:26+11:00</updated>
    <subtitle>Maureen&#39;s son, Katarina&#39;s husband and lapsed radio broadcaster&#39;s views.</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
    <entry>
        <title>Supplementary client acquisition report, immigration dept, 24MAR2013</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/supplementary-client-acquisition-report-immigration-dept-24mar2013.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/supplementary-client-acquisition-report-immigration-dept-24mar2013.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c380f60d9970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-24T19:32:26+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-24T19:32:26+11:00</updated>
        <summary>UNCLASSIFIED THE HON. JASON CLARE MP CABINET SECRETARY MINISTER FOR HOME AFFAIRS MINISTER FOR JUSTICE MEDIA RELEASE 24 March 2013 Border Protection Command intercepts vessel ACV Dame Roma Mitchell, operating under the control of Border Protection Command, intercepted a suspected irregular entry vessel east of Ashmore Islands yesterday. Initial indications...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>UNCLASSIFIED</p>
<div>
<div>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#0160;</span></p>
<p>THE HON. JASON CLARE MP</p>
<p>CABINET SECRETARY</p>
<p>MINISTER FOR HOME AFFAIRS</p>
<p>MINISTER FOR JUSTICE</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>MEDIA RELEASE</p>
<p>24 March 2013</p>
<p><strong>Border Protection Command intercepts vessel</strong></p>
</div>
<p>ACV&#0160;<em>Dame Roma Mitchell</em>, operating under the control of Border Protection Command, intercepted a suspected irregular entry vessel east of Ashmore Islands yesterday.<em></em></p>
<p>Initial indications suggest there are 18 passengers and two crew on board.&#0160;</p>
<p>The vessel was initially detected by Customs and Border Protection Dash 8 surveillance aircraft, operating under the control of Border Protection Command.</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>Border Protection Command will now make arrangements for the passengers to be transferred to Christmas Island, where they will undergo initial security, health and identity checks and their reasons for travel will be established.</p>
</div></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Immigration Department Client Acquisition Program Daily Marketing Report</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/immigration-department-client-acquisition-program-daily-marketing-report.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/immigration-department-client-acquisition-program-daily-marketing-report.html" thr:count="13" thr:updated="2013-03-24T16:49:46+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d423cdb83970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-24T12:46:02+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-24T12:46:02+11:00</updated>
        <summary>UNCLASSIFIED THE HON. JASON CLARE MP CABINET SECRETARY MINISTER FOR HOME AFFAIRS MINISTER FOR JUSTICE MEDIA RELEASE 24 March 2013 Border Protection Command intercepts vessel HMAS Broome, operating under the control of Border Protection Command, intercepted a suspected irregular entry vessel north-west of Ashmore Islands on Friday. Initial indications suggest...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>UNCLASSIFIED</p>
<div>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">&#0160;</span></p>
<p>THE HON. JASON CLARE MP</p>
<p>CABINET SECRETARY</p>
<p>MINISTER FOR HOME AFFAIRS</p>
<p>MINISTER FOR JUSTICE</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>MEDIA RELEASE</p>
<p>24 March 2013</p>
<p><strong>Border Protection Command intercepts vessel</strong></p>
<p>HMAS&#0160;<em>Broome</em>, operating under the control of Border Protection Command, intercepted a suspected irregular entry vessel north-west of Ashmore Islands on Friday.</p>
<p>Initial indications suggest there were 63 people on board the vessel.</p>
<p>Border Protection Command has transferred the passengers to Christmas Island, where they will undergo initial security, health and identity checks and their reasons for travel will be established.</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>People arriving by boat without a visa after 13 August 2012 run the risk of transfer to a regional&#0160;processing country.</p>
</div></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What Happened?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/what-happened.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/what-happened.html" thr:count="104" thr:updated="2013-03-24T17:48:34+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9abdfab970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-23T18:21:25+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-23T18:21:25+11:00</updated>
        <summary></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/0SAc2-GV_3o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;




&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Craig Thomson, Anthony Albanese and Julia Gillard with an elite, state of the art, world-class-excellence-style investment for the nation</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/craig-thomson-anthony-albanese-and-julia-gillard-with-an-elite-state-of-the-art-world-class-excellen.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/craig-thomson-anthony-albanese-and-julia-gillard-with-an-elite-state-of-the-art-world-class-excellen.html" thr:count="54" thr:updated="2013-03-24T17:08:02+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c38076384970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-23T14:08:18+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-23T16:42:02+11:00</updated>
        <summary>Come on, stop getting misty and nostalgic, pining for the good old days of pretzels, and Craig Thomson and beer. Those hazy, crazy, lazy days of a Gillard election campaign. Days when every marginal electorate whose candidate might have a developing sex-worker drama or two could count on an elite,...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Come on, stop getting misty and nostalgic, pining for the good old days of pretzels, and Craig Thomson and beer.</p>
<p>Those hazy, crazy, lazy days of a Gillard election campaign. &#0160; Days when every marginal electorate whose candidate might have a developing sex-worker drama or two could count on an elite, state of the art, world-class-excellence-radiating sports centre and pokies palace (with built in medical and dental facilities alongside Halal prayer room) to satisfy all tastes and some unstated prejudices.</p>
<p>Here&#39;s the Labor Party&#39;s announcement for the Craig Thomson Stadium back then.</p>
<p>

<script src="http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4236954b970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Craig thomson sports stadium" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4236954b970c image-full" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4236954b970c-800wi" title="Craig thomson sports stadium" /></a><br /><a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/millions-wasted-in-labors-soccer-play/story-fn59niix-1226603845012" target="_self">Anthony Klan from The Australian dropped by for some hydro-therapy and educational facility try-out during the week to check out progress 3 years down the track</a>.</p>
<h1>Millions wasted in Labor&#39;s soccer play</h1>
<ul>
<li><cite>ANTHONY KLAN</cite>&#0160;</li>
<li>From:<cite><a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/">The Australian</a>&#0160;</cite></li>
<li>March 23, 2013&#0160;12:00AM</li>
</ul>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<div>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em><strong>IN the final weeks of the 2010 federal election campaign, Julia Gillard announced a $10 million grant to go towards a $40m sporting and community complex on the NSW central coast, which was slated to be among the nation&#39;s best.</strong></em></p>
</div>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Today that project is in danger of collapse, with builders walking away from the development late last year over hundreds of thousands of dollars in unpaid debts, and very few of the community benefits spruiked by the government have actually materialised.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The Central Coast Mariners A-league soccer club&#39;s planned &quot;Centre of Excellence&quot; at Tuggerah was due to be completed early this year.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Instead the development sits idle with patches of over-grown glass spurting up between half-complete buildings, and stands as nothing more than a monument to government waste. With the Mariners club facing possible collapse - with players threatening to strike over unpaid wages and the Australian Taxation Office circling over unpaid debts - it has emerged the funding was tied not to the community benefits but a handful of facilities for the elite club.</em></p>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div><em>Both the club and the developer of the project - which are separate legal entities - were last night locked in ongoing negotiations with investor and IT businessman Mike Charlesworth in a bid to save the club and the developer from administration.</em></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Less than three weeks before the 2010 election, Ms Gillard and local member Craig Thomson - whose heavy lobbying for the grant brought it about - visited the site and announced the grand project billed as &quot;world class&quot;.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The development, they announced, would include a heated indoor aquatic centre, community gym, function centre, education facilities, a 150-room hotel, a museum, and community doctor and dental services.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The federal government was to inject $10m in the $39m project, which was to be completed by Mariners FC Developments, a company created for the purpose owned by three businessmen associated with the Mariners Football Club.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>The complex would provide &quot;state-of-the-art&quot; facilities for the Central Coast Mariners, and the raft of community services.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>It was, in the words of an August 2010 ALP campaign media release, an &quot;Elite Meets Community Sports Campus&quot;.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>However, more than $9m of that government grant has been handed over and the community side to the project is yet to materialise.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">&#0160;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/millions-wasted-in-labors-soccer-play/story-fn59niix-1226603845012" target="_self">Read more at The Australian.</a></p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p><br /><br /></p></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Gillard Government Routine Orders, 23MAR2013ZULU - Update to operating nomenclature Boarder Protection Command</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/gillard-government-routine-orders-23mar2013zulu-update-to-operating-nomenclature-boarder-protection-.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/gillard-government-routine-orders-23mar2013zulu-update-to-operating-nomenclature-boarder-protection-.html" thr:count="12" thr:updated="2013-03-24T12:57:46+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9aa5a75970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-23T13:25:22+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-23T13:28:13+11:00</updated>
        <summary>To recognise changed focus of maritime welcome and client attraction programs, today marks the official re-naming of the Commonwealth&#39;s sea-borne greeting, client-entertainment and shore-transfer operations. Please remove all reference to Border Protection Command and replace with Boarder Protection Command. To be promulgated for widest possible dissemination. (with thanks to reader...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>To recognise changed focus of maritime welcome and client attraction programs, today marks the official re-naming of the Commonwealth's sea-borne greeting, client-entertainment and shore-transfer operations.</p>
<p>Please remove all reference to Border Protection Command and replace with Boarder Protection Command.</p>
<p>To be promulgated for widest possible dissemination.</p>
<p>(with thanks to reader Muso who is a very funny bugger and keen observer of Gillard-directions)</p><!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com -->
<!-- Size: 468x60 -->
<script src="http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The best satellite simulation application you&#39;ll ever see from your computer.   And Stephen Conroy&#39;s folly as well.</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/the-best-satellite-simulation-application-youll-ever-see-from-your-computer-and-stephen-conroys-foll.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/the-best-satellite-simulation-application-youll-ever-see-from-your-computer-and-stephen-conroys-foll.html" thr:count="21" thr:updated="2013-03-24T16:45:41+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c38071a93970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-23T13:05:43+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-23T13:28:51+11:00</updated>
        <summary>I was privileged to be responsible for Australia&#39;s multi-million dollar investments in the Inmarsat satellite constellations for some years from the late 1990s. I saw the financing and operational plans for many satellite launches, and in a range of jobs I had executive responsibility for satellite earth station operations at...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was privileged to be responsible for Australia&#39;s multi-million dollar investments in the Inmarsat satellite constellations for some years from the late 1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the financing and operational plans for many satellite launches, and in a range of jobs I had executive responsibility for satellite earth station operations at Ningi, Queensland, Gnangara Perth and a range of other locations around the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://science.nasa.gov/realtime/jtrack/3d/JTrack3D.html/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;This little application is the greatest real-time satellite tracker on the web.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp; It shows you in real time where every satellite in orbit is, right now, above the earth. &amp;nbsp;You&#39;ll see the geo-synchronous birds about 35,000Ks out with their view over more than 25% of the earth, and the Low Earth Orbit birds like the Iridium and GPS satellites much close in, about 750 Ks away. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way out further you&#39;ll find the outer reaches of some of the elliptical orbits a very few polar satellites take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further yet, in the deeper reaches of vacuous empty space, you might encounter Stephen Conroy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9aa3469970d-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9aa3469970d image-full&quot; title=&quot;Conroy space  boy&quot; src=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9aa3469970d-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Conroy space  boy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://science.nasa.gov/realtime/jtrack/3d/JTrack3D.html/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;As you&#39;ll see when you click on the NASA real time tracker,&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; there are lots and lots and lots of satellites in space right now. &amp;nbsp; But rather like men who build very tall pointy buildings, there are lots more men who are very keen to prove themselves by launching lots more rockets pointing provingly upwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Conroy is one. &amp;nbsp; Shame that&#39;ll cost us so much money. &amp;nbsp;I&#39;d say it&#39;s better to buy services from other people happy to risk their own capital, than to fund a politician happy to risk ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Indonesian satellite plan a blow to NBN rollout&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BY:&lt;cite&gt;MALCOLM COLLESS&lt;/cite&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From:&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theaustralian.com.au/&quot;&gt;The Australian&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;March 23, 2013&amp;nbsp;12:00AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INDONESIA is negotiating to buy key satellite broadcasting slots covering Australia in a move that would be highly embarrassing for the federal government and a big setback in the rollout of its National Broadband Network.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;It would also be a major blow to the embattled Communications Minister, Stephen Conroy, who has been tenaciously driving the NBN policy, including enthusiastically endorsing the decision by the national broadband company to build and launch two of its own satellites at a cost of about $1 billion. The negotiations, which are believed to be at an advanced stage, are understood to have the support of the US government to enhance its relationship with Indonesia.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Weekend Australian has been told Indonesia wants to acquire the satellite facilities to deliver a government-owned television, broadband and education service across the Indonesian archipelago.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The negotiations involve the Australian satellite company KaComm, which has several orbital slots that could be used by NBN Co to deliver its service to regional and remote areas of the country where the installation of fibre cable would be too costly and impractical. When it decided to launch its own satellites some time ago, NBN Co awarded the $620 million contract to Space Systems/Loral, a big US satellite company. Loral subsequently invested in KaComm&#39;s satellite delivery plan. It is understood the negotiations with the Indonesian government are being run from the US and do not involve representatives of the Australian operation. KaComm&#39;s local chief executive, Gregory Clark, refused to comment when The Weekend Australian asked about the Indonesian negotiations.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this month NBN Co announced it had signed a $300m contract with the French aerospace company Arianespace to provide the two rockets that will carry the satellites for Loral.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about The Australian&#39;s article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/indonesian-satellite-plan-a-blow-to-nbn-rollout/story-fn59niix-1226603845356&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about men with tall building and rocket launch fascination in the comments section to this story when Mel and other learned commentators go to town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>



    </entry>
 
</feed>

<!-- ph=1 -->
