<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <title>Michael Smith News</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/atom.xml" />
    <link rel="hub" href="http://hubbub.api.typepad.com/" />
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/" />
    <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:weblog-107014838110033675</id>
    <updated>2013-03-25T20:45:19+11:00</updated>
    <subtitle>Maureen&#39;s son, Katarina&#39;s husband and lapsed radio broadcaster&#39;s views.</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
    <entry>
        <title>Here is some expert commentary about the unusual Development Application for the premises at 467 New Canterbury Road </title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/here-is-some-expert-commentary-about-the-unusual-development-application-for-the-premises-at-467-new.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/here-is-some-expert-commentary-about-the-unusual-development-application-for-the-premises-at-467-new.html" thr:count="25" thr:updated="2013-03-26T01:35:19+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9b9e9b3970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T20:45:19+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T20:45:19+11:00</updated>
        <summary>I&#39;ve received two written analyses on the DA for 467 New Canterbury Road - you can download a copy of the DA at the bottom of this post. I don&#39;t know the background of the first commenter - I do know and am familiar with the credentials of person number...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I&#39;ve received two written analyses on the DA for 467 New Canterbury Road - you can download a copy of the DA at the bottom of this post.</p>
<p>I don&#39;t know the background of the first commenter - &#0160;I do know and am familiar with the credentials of person number two. &#0160; He is a professional who is in the business of local government, town planning, development, inspections etc etc. &#0160; I value his professional expertise and the worth of his analysis.&#0160;</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<h3>Comments on the DA - person number one</h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em><span style="font-family: Arial; font-size: small;">A section 96 application to modify a development consent for a Thai massage&#0160;business.</span>
</em></p>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"><em><span style="font-family: Arial; font-size: small;">The Sec 96 Application requests two additional massage rooms to the rear of the&#0160;premises&#0160;on the basis they are needed due to “traffic noise” in the front rooms!!! Good grief….</span></em></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"><em style="font-size: 14px;"><strong>What happened to the easy solution most councils require to mitigate traffic noise?</strong>&#0160;<strong>“DOUBLE GLAZING”</strong>&#0160;</em></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"></div>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"></div>
<h3>Comments on the DA - person number two</h3>
<div style="padding-left: 30px;">
<div style="padding-left: 30px;"></div>
<div><span style="font-size: 14px;">I am some what gob smacked.&#0160;I see you have posted the actual section 96 application form. (excellent)</span></div>
<div>
<div><strong>Look at Q7.&#0160;<span style="font-size: medium;">reasons for proposed&#0160;modification</span></strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong><span style="color: #ac193d;">&quot;the main reason is to minimise noise from the main road which created problems for my customers&quot;</span></strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>WOW......what a scam....what a shifty way to &quot;intensify the use of the&#0160;business&quot;,&#0160;</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>Firstly- double glazing is the norm to mitigate traffic noise for the millions of premises on main roads.</strong></div>
<div><strong>did the council ensure double glazing was installed?</strong></div>
<div><strong>did the council planner assessing the application refer the same to the environmental officer for inspection, assessment and comment? if NO...WHY NOT?&#0160;</strong></div>
<div><strong>the entire pretext of the application is &quot;MINIMISE TRAFFIC NOISE&quot; and using this as justification to provide additional rooms...........what a farce........</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>Secondly- was the applicant asked to submit acoustic noise readings by a qualified acoustic engineer to validate the reason for the application&quot;</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>Thirdly- Did the assessing planner inspect the premises to make a routine onsite assessment of the NOISE?</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>Fourthly- did council impose conditions on the sec 96 approval &quot;prohibiting the use of the front rooms?&quot;&#0160;</strong></div>
<div><strong>If not they have allowed the intensification of the use without proper assessment or due diligence.</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>5th--question 8 left unanswered????????????? &#0160;where there any submissions attached to the application?</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>6th- &#0160;What is councils policy on &quot;delegated authority to approve sec 96 applications&quot; for massage parlor??</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div><strong>THIS IS ONE FOR ICAC!!!!</strong></div>
<div><strong><br /></strong></div>
<div>
<p><strong>WHAT TYPES OF MODIFICATIONS ARE ALLOWED UNDER SECTION 96?</strong><br /><br /></p>
<p>There are number of different types of modifications allowed under Section 96 of the Act. Council’s application form can be used to make an application for three of these types of modifications:</p>
<p>Section 96 (1) – Modifications involving minor errors, misdescription, or miscalculation.<br />There would be no change to the form of the development approved, and notification would not be required. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wrong plan numbers</li>
</ul>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>Section 96 (1a) – Modifications involving minimal environmental impact.<br />These are used for minor amendments. There is no impact on privacy, height, overshadowing, etc, and notification is generally not required. These might be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Internal design changes</li>
<li>Amended landscape plans</li>
<li>Drainage design amendment</li>
</ul>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>Section 96 (2) – Other modifications.<br />These are all other modifications where environmental impact is possible. They generally require notification. Typical changes include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Windows</li>
<li>Floor levels</li>
<li>Heights</li>
<li>Car parking generation</li>
<li>Roof design</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><br />NEW CONSTRUCTION CERTIFICATE?</strong><br /><br /></p>
<p>If you are seeking Construction Certificate approval from Council based on the proposed modifications, you will need to lodge a separate construction certificate application form. This may be lodged concurrently with this application or at a later date but cannot be processed until the modification application is determined.&#0160;</p>
<p><strong><br />WHAT IS REQUIRED WHEN LODGING AN APPLICATION?<br /></strong></p>
<p>The following items need to be prepared and submitted for all applications to modify development consent under Section 96 of the Act:</p>
<ul>
<li>A completed application form [link].</li>
<li>Owners consent<br />Consent from all the registered owners. If a company owns the property, the form must be signed by an individual acting with the Company’s Authority. If the building is subject to a strata scheme, consent of the body corporate is required</li>
<li>Amended plans<br />Seven (7) sets of plans (3 coloured) plus ten A4 set of plans, annotated to show changes (if amendments involve changes to the design).</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Drawings must be to scale - normally at 1:100 - and suitably numbered and dated.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Supporting documentation<br />Details of the proposed modification(s) and impact of changes</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3816b9ad970b"><a href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/files/467-new-canterbury-road-development-application.pdf">Download 467 New Canterbury Road Development Application</a></span></div>
<div></div>
<div>We&#39;ll have more tomorrow.</div>
</div>
<p>&#0160;</p></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My efforts to provide Anthony Albanese with the opportunity to comment on or correct my story today</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/my-efforts-to-provide-anthony-albanese-with-the-opportunity-to-comment-on-or-correct-my-story-today.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/my-efforts-to-provide-anthony-albanese-with-the-opportunity-to-comment-on-or-correct-my-story-today.html" thr:count="76" thr:updated="2013-03-26T00:33:30+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d42454e4a970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T18:42:54+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T18:42:54+11:00</updated>
        <summary>At 9.18AM this morning I phoned Anthony Albanese&#39;s mobile phone and left a comprehensive message informing him as to the content of the story I&#39;d proposed to run about him. I offered Mr Albanese the opportunity to discuss the story and any concerns as to accuracy he had about it...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>At 9.18AM this morning I phoned Anthony Albanese&#39;s mobile phone and left a comprehensive message informing him as to the content of the story I&#39;d proposed to run about him.</p>
<p>I offered Mr Albanese the opportunity to discuss the story and any concerns as to accuracy he had about it either on or off the record.</p>
<p>At 9.38AM I had a missed call on my mobile from Anthony Albanese&#39;s mobile with no message left for me. &#0160; I phoned him back at 9:38, 9:39, 9:40 and 9:43.</p>
<p>At 10.53AM I sent the Minister this text</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;"><em>&quot;Noticed missed call from you, I have a story ready to publish, would you like to read a copy first? &#0160;Would very much like to show you first and to seek your comments&quot;.</em></p>
<p>At 10.57AM I received a phone message from one of Minister Albanese&#39;s staff members.</p>
<p>I phoned the Minister&#39;s office and had a conversation with the staffer outlining the broad thrust of the story.</p>
<p>The Minister&#39;s staff member asked me to send an email to the Minister&#39;s office, I did that at 12.34PM and the email follows:</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;">Dear xxx,</p>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">Thank you for phoning me this morning. &#0160; </div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">&#0160;</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">I phoned Minister Albanese to let him know about my article this morning at 9.18AM and I left a fairly comprehensive message. &#0160; I see that I have a missed call from the Minister&#39;s mobile phone at 0938 - then I phoned the Minister back at 0938, 0939, 0940 and 0943. &#0160;</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">I texted this message to the Minister&#39;s mobile phone at 1053&#0160;</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"></div>
<div style="padding-left: 90px;"><em>Noticed missed call from you, I have a story ready to publish, would you like to read a copy first? &#0160;Would very much like to show you first and to seek your comments&quot;.</em></div>
<div style="padding-left: 90px;"><em><br /></em></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">I&#39;d still like the chance to speak with the Minister. &#0160; If he&#39;s not able to do that perhaps you might consider whether the Minister would answer these questions.</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">Was the Minister at a business known as True Thai Massage at 467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill during the afternoon of Friday 15 March, 2013?</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;">Is the Minister aware of the web-based advertising and reviews of True Thai Massage at sites like&#0160;</div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><a href="http://auxxxreviews.com/forum/f59/true-thai-massage-467-new-canterbury-rd-dulwich-hill-02-8021-9052-a-1149/index12.html" target="_blank">http://auxxxreviews.com/forum/f59/true-thai-massage-467-new-canterbury-rd-dulwich-hill-02-8021-9052-a-1149/index12.html</a></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><a href="http://www.parlourpages.com.au/blog/?p=2025" target="_blank">http://www.parlourpages.com.au/blog/?p=2025</a></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">If the services described in those websites are provided at the premises at 467 New Canterbury Road, Dulwich Hill is that legal?</span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Is the Minister aware of any Application made by the owners of the premises or business at 467 New Canterbury Road to Marrickville Council seeking approval to alter the building on the site? &#0160; Did the Minister have any role in discussions about any Development Application?</span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Did the Minister discuss his attendance at the True Thai Massage business or any other matter to do with the True Thai Massage business with a senior parliamentary Labor Party figure last week at the request of the senior Labor Party figure?</span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Thanks xxxx. &#0160; I have been told that the Minister reported to a colleague that he attended the premises on Friday 15 March 2013 for the purpose of receiving a therapeutic massage and I do not imply that anything other than a massage of a therapeutic nature took place between the Minister and the staff of the business.</span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Thank you for speaking with me,</span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><br /></span></div>
<div style="padding-left: 60px;"><span style="color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Michael Smith</span></div>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>At about 2PM this afternoon a different person whom I know to be a more senior member of Minister Albanese&#39;s staff phoned me and we discussed in general terms the content of the article that I proposed to publish. &#0160; I read a couple of pages of the article to the staffer and I offered to read more of the article but the staffer declined. &#0160; He told me that he understood &quot;where I was heading with the story&quot; and that he would get back to me shortly.</p>
<p>I phoned Minister Albanese&#39;s office a number of times during the afternoon and made calls to various mobile phones on issue to Minister Albanese and his staff. &#0160; I held off publishing the article in anticipation of some comment or answers from the Minister.</p>
<p>At 5.47PM I sent the following text to the mobile phone of the senior staffer on Minister Albanese&#39;s staff</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Jeff I waited for you - I presume you have no comment. &#0160; Michael</em></p>
<p>A few minutes later I received a text from that person that said, &quot;Correct.&quot;</p>
<p>I then published the story.</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>&#0160;</p></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Private Investigator&#39;s Report - visit to True Thai Massage, 467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill 25 March, 2013</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/private-investigators-report-visit-to-true-thai-massage-467-new-canterbury-road-dulwich-hill-25-marc.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/private-investigators-report-visit-to-true-thai-massage-467-new-canterbury-road-dulwich-hill-25-marc.html" thr:count="10" thr:updated="2013-03-26T00:06:48+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9b9454c970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T18:27:52+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T18:32:16+11:00</updated>
        <summary>This is a summary of the Private Investigator&#39;s report after attending True Thai Massage this morning. This morning we attended the premises at 467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill. We were greeted by a female and offered a variety of Thai massages with oils for $45 for 30 minutes. We...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a summary of the Private Investigator&#39;s report after attending True Thai Massage this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This morning we attended the premises at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a&gt;467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill&lt;/a&gt;. We were greeted by a female and offered a variety of Thai massages with oils for $45 for 30 minutes.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We inquired as to the range of services on offer, we were asked whether we had been there before. We were then told we could discuss other services with the woman who was doing the massage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We were then ushered into another room and joined by another female. &amp;nbsp;When we asked her about other services she offered oral sex for $45. &amp;nbsp;We made an excuse to leave to get some more cash. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We also noted 3 other men came into the place in a very short space of time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Anthony Albanese and his dangerously poor judgement </title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/anthony-albanese-and-his-dangerously-poor-judgement-.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/anthony-albanese-and-his-dangerously-poor-judgement-.html" thr:count="95" thr:updated="2013-03-25T23:55:04+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c38160eb6970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T18:23:54+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T21:02:54+11:00</updated>
        <summary>Introduction This article raises serious questions about the judgement of the Minister for Transport and Infrastructure Anthony Albanese in his patronage of the business known as “True Thai Massage” at 467 New Canterbury Road, Dulwich Hill. The article may provide some background for the events that led to the Labor...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong>Introduction</strong></p>
<p>This article raises serious questions about the judgement of
the Minister for Transport and Infrastructure Anthony Albanese in his patronage
of the business known as “True Thai Massage” at 467 New Canterbury Road,
Dulwich Hill.&#0160;&#0160; The article may provide some
background for the events that led to the Labor leadership-spill debacle last
Thursday and for Anthony Albanese’s absence from the field as a potential
deputy to Kevin Rudd. &#0160;</p>
<p>I am not suggesting that
Minister Albanese has acted unlawfully. &#0160; It&#39;s also clear that the services available from True Thai Massage include non-sexual massage services, notwithstanding the very openly available sexual services on offer at the premises (as confirmed at 10.20AM today by a private investigator who visited the business and was offered a sexual service for money without soliciting the offer).&#0160;&#0160; This story is about the Minister’s judgement in visibly
patronising an establishment of dubious repute without making the cursory enquiries that should have revealed the nature of the business conducted at the premises.&#0160;&#0160; The poor judgement is compounded by the fact
that Mr Albanese has in the past and will again from today have portfolio responsibility for local government, the
enforcement authority for brothels and other sex service premises in NSW.&#0160;&#0160; The article is also about the reaction of
some senior Labor Party figures to the news of Mr Albanese’s misjudgement.</p>
<p>From 3 December, 2007 to 14 September, 2010, Anthony
Albanese was the Federal Government’s Minister for Local Government.&#0160;&#0160; Minister Albanese ought to know well the
local government regulations that apply to brothels and sex service premises in
New South Wales.&#0160;&#0160; The Brothels Act was
proclaimed just before his appointment as the Federal Minister for Local Government
and the provisions for local government to regulate brothels and other sex
service premises were significant public issues in the early days of his
Ministry. </p>
<p>
<span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9b92040970d"><a href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/files/brothels-act-2007.pdf">Download Brothels act 2007</a></span></p>
<p>This article concerns itself with activities at just one “massage
parlour” in Minister Albanese’s electorate, True Thai
Massage, 467 New Canterbury Road, Dulwich Hill.</p>
<p>In correspondence with the Marrickville Council, the
business describes itself as having “premises which are used as a therape (sic)
massage and therapy centre”. &#0160; Clearly that description is incomplete.</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815eec8970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Premises use description" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815eec8970b image-full" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815eec8970b-800wi" title="Premises use description" /></a><br /><br /></p>
<p>In the bulk of the 173 client “reviews” at XXX
Reviews (dating back to 2010), the services described as being procured at the
premises constitute sexual services (explicit content warning, the client “reviews”
at these links are graphic and obscene).</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424564ad970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Auxxxreview" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424564ad970c image-full" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424564ad970c-800wi" title="Auxxxreview" /></a></p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p><strong>Sauce Warning</strong>: <em>the site below are triggering antivirus programs, screenshots are above, links cannot be clicked below (copy and paste only)</em></p>
<p>http://auxxxreviews.com/forum/f59/true-thai-massage-467-new-canterbury-rd-dulwich-hill-02-8021-9052-a-1149/index12.html</p>
<p>Similarly at http://www.parlourpages.com.au/blog/?p=2025</p>
<p>The NSW Brothel Act puts the enforcement of most brothel related regulations into the hands of local government.&#0160;&#0160; The Act defines brothels and other premises which are used for “related sex uses”.&#0160;&#0160; The definition of “related sex uses”
includes:</p>
<p>&#0160;
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9b92199970d-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Extract sex services" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9b92199970d" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9b92199970d-800wi" title="Extract sex services" /></a></p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p><strong>The events of Monday, 18 March,
2013</strong></p>
<p>On Monday morning, 18 March, 2013 I had a conversation
with a friend who is a reliable and well-connected media figure.&#0160;&#0160; My colleague asked if I knew about the “Albanese
photographs”, I said I did not.&#0160; I was
told that a constituent in Anthony Albanese’s electorate had seen Mr Albanese
enter a “house of ill repute” on New Canterbury Road, Dulwich Hill on the previous
Friday afternoon, 15 March.&#0160;&#0160; My colleague
told me the constituent described the premises as a Thai “knock-shop”, that is
a place at which sexual services are provided.</p>
<p>I was told the constituent had phoned a media outlet at the
time and that a photographer was despatched and was present when the Minister
emerged from the Thai massage premises one hour later.&#0160;&#0160; I was told that photographs were taken of
the Minister leaving, but that after discussions over the weekend no major
publisher would run the story.&#0160;&#0160; (This conversation
between me and my media colleague took place during the week that the Minister
Conroy’s media legislation was being fast-tracked through the parliament.)</p>
<p>I was told that a photographer who was involved in the
matter was very upset that in the context of media legislation coming before
the parliament, this story about a prominent Minister was “spiked”.&#0160;&#0160; I did not have an opinion about the rights
or wrongs of the matter but I agreed to speak with the photographer.</p>
<p>A little later that morning I had a conversation with a “paparazzi”
photographer who makes his living by taking photographs of celebrities and
selling those photographs to media organisations.&#0160;&#0160; He told me that he thought it was newsworthy
that a story and photograph that would (in his judgement) have ordinarily run
in the “gossip” columns of one of the major newspapers was “spiked” during the
week that the media legislation came before the parliament.&#0160;&#0160; He asked me to investigate and to find out
why.</p>
<p>I said I&#39;d like a detailed statement from him, the photographer if he was serious about me following the matter up. &#0160; At about midday on Monday, 18 March, I received the following statement
by email:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>At 3.45pm on Friday afternoon 15th March 2013, the married Federal
Member for Grayndler, Anthony Albanese, was at Traditonal Thai Massage, 467 New
Canterbury Road, Dulwich Hill, NSW which is within his local electorate. </em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>A
passer-by called the news outlets one of which managed to get images of him
leaving around 4.45pm. In&#0160;<a href="http://parlourpages.com.au/" target="_blank">parlourpages.com.au</a>&#0160;this is described as follows,
Escorts, Rub &#39;n tugs, body slides &amp; happy endings. It is not a legitimate
traditional Thai massage, but even so what is the married Federal Cabinet
minister doing at this place in light of other issues involving Federal Labour
MP&#39;s I.e. Craig Thompson. It shows a complete lack of judgment on his part. </em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Having regard to the pictures of him exiting the premises, [PUBLISHER’S
NAME REDACTED] decided to bury the story, [PUBLISHER NO 2’S NAME REDACTED] then
spoke to Albanese on Saturday, they didn&#39;t have the images, but he did in fact
confirm he was there. He told [PUBLISHER’S NAME REDACTED] he had just received
a traditional massage. </em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Given a week of issues involving Senator Conroy&#39;s planned media
legislation, [PUBLISHER’S NAME REDACTED] decided to pull the story, and without
the pictures [PUBLISHER’S NAME REDACTED] could not go anywhere with it. I am
aware they considered the possible political repercussion&#39;s if it appeared they
were going after him, public interest issues having been considered etc. </em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>This is clearly a matter in the public interest, when a cabinet
minister who is next week, opening a special ceremony for babies at
Marrackville West Public school and is married to MP Carmel Tebbutt. Federal
Labour has the media outlets running scared and they decided to bury to story,
particularly so at [PUBLISHER’S NAME REDACTED]. Albanese should not be going to
a place such at this, should exercise more discretion and be held to account
for a higher standard than the average bloke. This lack of judgment is being
talked about in newsrooms across the country. There is no doubt the PM knows
about this. What&#39;s the problem with reporting this as fact, he&#39;s admitted it
and it should be reported.</em></p>
<p>The paparazzi photographer who sent me that statement also
sent me an email with this photograph of a mobile phone screen showing what I
was told were web-based enquiries about the business situated at 467 New
Canterbury Road:</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815fa25970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Screen grab photographer&#39;s phone" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815fa25970b" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815fa25970b-800wi" title="Screen grab photographer&#39;s phone" /></a><br /><br /></p>
<p>I made certain enquiries to ascertain whether or not
photographs had been taken, whether a constituent in the electorate had expressed
concerns about the Minister’s visit to the premises and whether Mr Albanese had
spoken to a journalist about the matter and it seemed to me that all 3
assertions were true.&#0160;&#0160; I could
find no mention of the story being published anywhere.</p>
<p>I did not know why other media outlets had declined to publish
the story but I formed the opinion that I would not publish it, it did not interest me then as a news story.&#0160;&#0160; I was told that the photographs were for
sale and I said that I would not be interested in purchasing the photographs.</p>
<p>On the evening of Monday, 18 March I spoke with a senior Federal
Labor Party figure and asked if the Party was aware that the photographs and
story of Minister Albanese were being “shopped” around, that is to say being
offered for publication.</p>
<p><strong>Tuesday, 19 March,
2013</strong></p>
<p>On Tuesday, 19 March I made some further low-level enquiries
and had a couple of conversations with people about the matter but did not take
it any further than that.</p>
<p><strong>Wednesday, 20 March,
2013</strong></p>
<p>On the afternoon of Wednesday, 20 March I was sent some
information that led me to cause some enquiries to be made of the Marrickville
Council.&#0160;&#0160; As a result of those enquiries
I received a copy of an &quot;Application to Modify a Development Consent&quot; which
described proposed extensions to the premises at 467 New Canterbury Road, Dulwich
Hill.</p>
<p>This is a copy of the Application.&#0160;&#0160; It is a public document, available for
perusal at the Marrickville Council’s website http://www.marrickville.nsw.gov.au/Edrawer/DAInformation.asp?DANUM=DA200900093</p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d42452801970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Da 1" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d42452801970c image-full" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d42452801970c-800wi" title="Da 1" /></a><br /><br /></p>
<p>
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815fc28970b-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Da 2" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815fc28970b image-full" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815fc28970b-800wi" title="Da 2" /></a><br />
<a class="asset-img-link" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4245286d970c-pi" style="display: inline;"><img alt="Da3" border="0" class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4245286d970c image-full" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4245286d970c-800wi" title="Da3" /></a><br /><br /></p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p>&#0160;</p>
<p><strong>Thursday, 21 March,
2013</strong></p>
<p>On Thursday, 21 March, 2013 I watched with the rest of the
nation as Simon Crean put his name forward as Deputy Prime Minister and as he asked
Mr Rudd to challenge the PM.</p>
<p><strong>Friday, 22 March,
2013</strong></p>
<p>On Friday evening, 22 March, 2013 I received a message from
a senior Federal Parliamentary Labor Party figure that said words to the
effect, </p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong><em>“</em></strong><em>FYI</em><strong><em> - &#0160;[NAME REDACTED – a widely respected Federal Labor
Parliamentary figure] </em></strong><em>interviewed Albanese about the Thai establishment – And Albo
then quickly relinquished his Deputy PM aspirations”</em><strong><em>.</em></strong> </p>
<p>I had a conversation with my confidential source, a senior Federal
Labor Party figure that night, Friday, 22 March. &#0160; The source confirmed the content of the earlier message.&#0160;&#0160; I was told:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>[<strong>NAME REDACTED</strong> - a widely respected Federal Labor Parliamentary figure]
interviewed Anthony Albanese on Wednesday, 20&#0160;March and put a number of
matters associated with the Thai massage establishment to Mr Albanese.&#0160;&#0160; Mr Albanese confirmed that he was present at
the Thai massage business on Friday, 15 March.&#0160;&#0160;
He said that he was there for the purpose of receiving a therapeutic
massage and not for the purpose of receiving sexual services.&#0160;&#0160; Mr Albanese said he did not receive any
sexual services.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>I was told that other enquiries were made of Mr Albanese about the nature
of his relationship if any with the owners of the business and any knowledge he may
have about any Development Application submitted to the Marrickville Council by
the business.&#0160; Mr Albanese said that he
acted properly at all times and had done nothing wrong. </em></p>
<p>I reiterate that I make no allegations of unlawful behaviour
on Minister Albanese’s part – rather it is the Minister&#39;s poor judgement at issue, with his patronage of a dubious business widely known to provide sexual services for payment. &#0160; The most cursory enquiries on the internet reveal the nature of the sexual services offered at True Thai Massage. &#0160; A private investigator who attended the business this morning was offered sexual services quite openly without soliciting an offer of sexual service.&#0160;</p>
<p>I say that the business at that location is widely
known to carry on sexual services at its business premises, services which
it is not legally able to provide and which would render the use of the
premises unlawful.&#0160;&#0160; As a former Local
Government Minister and a current Federal Cabinet Minister I think it reflects
poorly on Mr Albanese’s judgement that he would patronise a business that is so
clearly the subject of controversy so far as its adherence to Local Government
regulations is concerned, particularly given he has been and is now the Federal Minister for Local Government.&#0160;&#0160; Mr Albanese’s
patronage could only give rise to unsavoury commentary and to questions about
his judgement.&#0160;&#0160; Further, I consider it
newsworthy that my source about the interview between Minister Albanese and the
senior Labor figure; and the source pointing to the Development Application are
Federal Labor Party sources.&#0160;</p>
<script src="http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js" type="text/javascript"></script></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Tactics watch - the Labor Party is recruiting for &quot;word of mouth&quot; spreaders of spin for its tele-marketing campaign</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/tactics-watch-the-labor-party-is-recruiting-for-word-of-mouth-spreaders-of-spin-for-its-tele-marketi.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/tactics-watch-the-labor-party-is-recruiting-for-word-of-mouth-spreaders-of-spin-for-its-tele-marketi.html" thr:count="47" thr:updated="2013-03-26T01:24:32+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c3815d571970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T17:34:26+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T17:47:39+11:00</updated>
        <summary>This email from Sam Dastyari today about Labor&#39;s plans to ruin your dinner and favourite TV shows with phone calls about how tough Julia is. This is going to be a tough election for Labor. More than ever, the efforts of volunteers, giving up their time to knock on doors...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This email from Sam Dastyari today about Labor&#39;s plans to ruin your dinner and favourite TV shows with phone calls about how tough Julia is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;This is going to be a tough election for Labor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;More than ever, the efforts of volunteers, giving up their time to knock on doors and phone their neighbours, will be critical to returning local Labor MPs to Parliament.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://campaigniq.communityengine.com/ch/32537/2cww8/1895853/4346d11nv2.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Will you help by giving just two hours a week?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you live in or near Sydney, we encourage you to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a title=&quot;Send To Friend&quot; href=&quot;http://campaigniq.communityengine.com/ch/32537/2cww8/1895951/4346dqwsx.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;join us&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the launch of Operation Word of Mouth at the new Parramatta HQ this week:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 6pm, Tuesday 26 and Wednesday 27 March 2013&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Level 5, Gough Whitlam Plaza, 20-24 Whitlam Plaza, Parramatta&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The only way to get Labor&#39;s message across is by word-of-mouth, and that&#39;s why we need the help of our valued members and supporters at our new phone bank.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just a few hours of your time can make a real difference in electorates that will come down to the wire.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Whether you live in the country or close to our new headquarters in Parramatta, please let us know if you can help by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://campaigniq.communityengine.com/ch/32537/2cww8/1895853/4346d11nv2-1.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;signing up here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam Dastyari&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;GENERAL SECRETARY&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: black; font-family: Tahoma; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Cambria; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://campaigniq.communityengine.com/ch/32537/2cww8/1895919/4346d10cxz.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #363636; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0f00f0;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Tahoma; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Cambria; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Send To Friend: Contact&#39;s Default Style&quot; href=&quot;http://campaigniq.communityengine.com/ch/32537/2cww8/1704008/4346dczz8.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;P.S. Please forward this email to your friends and neighbours who support Labor!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #222222; font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0f00f0;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #1155cc; font-family: Tahoma; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Cambria; font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#39;Century Gothic&#39;; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: small;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A 5PM update on that story we told you about</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/a-5pm-update-on-that-story-we-told-you-about.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/a-5pm-update-on-that-story-we-told-you-about.html" thr:count="19" thr:updated="2013-03-25T20:43:08+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d4244eb29970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-25T17:16:59+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-25T17:48:04+11:00</updated>
        <summary></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><center><object id="boo_embed_1289100" width="400" height="129" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" data="http://abfiles.s3.amazonaws.com/swf/fullsize_player.swf">
<param name="movie" value="http://abfiles.s3.amazonaws.com/swf/fullsize_player.swf" />
<param name="scale" value="noscale" />
<param name="salign" value="lt" />
<param name="bgColor" value="#FFFFFF" />
<param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" />
<param name="wmode" value="window" />
<param name="FlashVars" value="mp3=http%3A%2F%2Faudioboo.fm%2Fboos%2F1289100-albo.mp3%3Fkeyed%3Dtrue%26source%3Dembed&amp;mp3Title=Albo&amp;mp3Time=05.04pm+25+Mar+2013&amp;mp3LinkURL=http%3A%2F%2Faudioboo.fm%2Fboos%2F1289100-albo&amp;mp3Author=michaelsmithnews&amp;rootID=boo_embed_1289100" /><iframe vspace="0" title="Audioboo player" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: none; display: block; width: 400px; height: 145px;" src="http://audioboo.fm/boos/1289100-albo/embed" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" hspace="0" frameborder="0" cellspacing="0" allowtransparency="allowtransparency"></iframe>
</object>
<!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com -->
<!-- Size: 468x60 -->
<script src="http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --></center></div>
</content>



    </entry>
 
</feed>

<!-- ph=1 -->
