<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <title>Michael Smith News</title>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/atom.xml" />
    <link rel="hub" href="http://hubbub.api.typepad.com/" />
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/" />
    <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:weblog-107014838110033675</id>
    <updated>2013-03-26T21:20:05+11:00</updated>
    <subtitle>Maureen&#39;s son, Katarina&#39;s husband and lapsed radio broadcaster&#39;s views.</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.typepad.com/">TypePad</generator>
    <entry>
        <title>Analysis on the Development Application at 467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/analysis-on-the-development-application-at-467-new-canterbury-road-dulwich-hill.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/analysis-on-the-development-application-at-467-new-canterbury-road-dulwich-hill.html" thr:count="0" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424ca1c4970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-26T21:20:05+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T21:20:05+11:00</updated>
        <summary>Download Applications and Consents DA200900093 467 New Canterbury - redacted Mr Smith, A quick perusal of the application for the use of 467 Canterbury road raises some VERY serious questions. 1. The application is erroneous, incorrectly completed and incomplete. The First question, &quot;previous contact with council has not been answered????&quot;...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>
<span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9c0a1b9970d"><a href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/files/applications-and-consents-da200900093-467-new-canterbury---redacted-1.pdf">Download Applications and Consents DA200900093 467 New Canterbury - redacted</a></span></p>
Mr Smith,<br />
<div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>A quick&#0160;perusal&#0160;of the application for the use of 467 Canterbury road raises some VERY serious questions.</div>
<div>1. The application is erroneous, incorrectly completed and incomplete.&#0160;</div>
<div>The First question, &quot;previous contact with council has not been answered????&quot; this question must be answered, it goes to conflict of interest and upholds councils code of conduct.&#0160;</div>
<div>2. Q3 description of the Proposal is WRONG, it must be marked &quot;USE OF LAND/BUILDING&quot;, this applications as you will see, seeks to &quot;change the use of the building from office to massage.&quot;</div>
<div>3. Q4. Wow......this is totally erroneous.&#0160;</div>
<div>The&#0160;Development&#0160;Application FEE is calculated on a sliding scale that relies on the total cost of the proposed development. To suggest all the electrical work,&#0160;partitioning, fit-out, painting, furniture, waste disposal etc etc etc in addition to the essential services as required by the BCA (Building code of Australia) and required by the&#0160;development&#0160;consent approval will COST the grand total of $1550.00 is a&#0160;travesty ... that is totally absurd.&#0160;&#0160; &#0160;</div>
<div><span style="color: #5133ab;"><strong>How did any council officer accept and process the application when the existing floor plan clearly shows an open office area and the proposed floor plan shows a very extensive fit out for the grand sum of $1550.00</strong></span></div>
<div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">It is difficult to understand how this application made it all the way to approval been given:&#0160;</span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">the application is&#0160;incorrectly&#0160;completed,&#0160;</span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">the application is not fully completed,&#0160;</span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">the cost of the development is substantially understated and should have been no less than $30k - $50k depending on the quality of the fitout.&#0160;</span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">These are very serious errors that highlight serious flaws in&#0160;councils&#0160;internal&#0160;processes or worse still may have involved some sort of&#0160;Corruption.</span></div>
</div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></div>
<div>4. I note the description of the proposal on the application also includes&#0160;<span style="color: #8c0095;"><strong>&quot;PLUS STANDARD&#0160;DELUXE&#0160;MANICURE &amp; PEDICURE&quot;</strong>,</span>&#0160;this opens whole new&#0160;assessment&#0160;process in terms of Health&#0160;requirements. &#0160;</div>
<h1><a href="http://www0.health.nsw.gov.au/factsheets/environmental/nail_treatment_2012.html%0D%0A" target="_blank"><span style="font-size: small;">http://www0.health.nsw.gov.au/factsheets/environmental/nail_treatment_2012.html</span></a></h1>
<h1>Nail treatment (manicures and pedicures) - hygiene standards</h1>
<p><strong>Nail technicians can carry out a variety of different procedures, many of which involve &#39;skin penetration&#39;. Because &#39;skin penetration&#39; carries a risk of infection, the premises and procedures where skin penetration is conducted must comply with the Public Health Regulation, 2012. (open Link below)</strong></p>
<div>
<h2><span style="color: #8c0095;">ALSO &quot;Are these premises registered as required by law?????&quot;</span></h2>
<h2>Premises - registration, construction and materials</h2>
<p>•	All nail technicians that carry out skin penetration procedures, must be registered with the local council. Notification forms are available from the NSW Health Public Health Legislation webpage at:&#0160;<a href="http://www.health.nsw.gov.au/phact" target="_blank">www.health.nsw.gov.au/phact</a></p>
<div>5. What information was included with the application to satisfy council that the proposal would comply with the&#0160;latter&#0160;state health requirements?</div>
<div>What details were included of disposal of waste material?</div>
<div>What details were supplied for laundry of towels etc?</div>
<div>Is the premises registered as legally required?</div>
<div>have any inspections since the date of consent been conducted by council&#39;s health officer?</div>
<div>6. Q8 confirms the premises was previously an office.&#0160;</div>
<div>Why has the last question page 4 relating to the use of the building been ignored and left unanswered?</div>
<div>&#0160;</div>
<div>This application is legally &quot;for a change of use of the premises&quot; yet the applicant has avoided answering the questions on 2&#0160;occasions.?? &#0160;and has infact ticked the box marked OTHER.</div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">WHY has the assessing&#0160;</span>officer<span style="font-size: small;">&#0160;not asked for the application to be fully completed so it may be lawfully processes? officers?</span></div>
<div>In fact look at the description stated on the actual development consent granted by council&#0160;</div>
<div><span style="color: #5133ab;"><strong>&quot;Pursuant to Section 81 of the Act, notice is hereby given of the determination by the Council of&#0160;</strong></span></div>
<div><span style="color: #5133ab;"><strong>Development Application No. 200900093&#0160;<span style="font-size: medium;">to carry out alterations to the premises and to use&#0160;</span></strong></span></div>
<div><span style="color: #5133ab; font-size: medium;"><strong>the ground floor shop for therapeutic and remedial massage and a beauty salon relating to&#0160;</strong></span></div>
<div><span style="color: #5133ab; font-size: medium;"><strong>property situated at.......&quot;</strong></span></div>
<div><span style="color: #5133ab; font-size: medium;"><strong><br /></strong></span></div>
<div>&#0160;Quite&#0160;Bizarre as the applicant makes no mention of alterations or change of use and stated the cost of the development is $1550.00</div>
<div>7. Q9. Is not fully answered and it should have detailed that&#0160;building&#0160;work will be done to&#0160;facilitate&#0160;the fit out and contradicts the description in the consent</div>
<div>8. Q9. should have detailed the hours of operation correctly NOT &quot;as above&quot;</div>
<div>&#0160; &#0160; &#0160; &#0160; &#0160; &#0160;Also the questions to the number of employees is marked as two in one answer and then - &quot;indicating zero&quot;</div>
<div>9. Why has the waste management plan been accepted without the applicants signing the declaration????</div>
<div>&#0160; &#0160;&#0160;</div>
<div>10. Was a CONSTRUCTION CERTIFICATE application to cover the fit out of the premises lodged and approved??&#0160;</div>
<div>The Relevant Condition on the Development consent read as follows:</div>
<div>
<div>&quot;BEFORE THE ISSUE OF A CONSTRUCTION CERTIFICATE</div>
<div>For the purpose of interpreting this consent the Certifying Authority (Council or an&#0160;</div>
<div>Accredited Certifier) is that person appointed to issue the Construction Certificate.&#0160;</div>
<div>26. Before the issue of a Construction Certificate an amended plan shall be submitted to</div>
<div>and accepted by the Certifying Authority (Council or an Accredited Certifier) indicating</div>
<div>the existing building upgraded to comply with the provisions of the Building Code of</div>
<div>Australia in relation to:</div>
<div>a) smoke detection systems;</div>
<div>b) portable extinguishers; and</div>
<div>c) solid core doors.</div>
<div>Reason: To ensure the building is suitable for the proposed use.&#0160;</div>
<div>27. Before the issue of a Construction Certificate the owner or builder shall sign a written</div>
<div>undertaking that they shall be responsible for the full cost of repairs to footpath, kerb and</div>
<div>gutter, or other Council property damaged as a result of construction of the proposed</div>
<div>development. Council may utilise part or all of any Building Security Deposit (B.S.D.) or</div>
<div>recover in any court of competent jurisdiction, any costs to Council for such repairs.</div>
<div>Reason: To ensure that all damages arising from the building works are repaired at</div>
<div>no cost to Council&quot;</div>
</div>
<div>11. The section 96 application you posted on line purported to have been lodged to mitigate traffic noise as justification to use the rear rooms. This is totally is misleading, in reality it was an application to expand or intensify the business contrary to the following condition of consent on the original approval.</div>
<div>&#0160;</div>
<div><strong>Condition 2 of the consent make it very clear</strong></div>
<div>&quot;&quot;The area to be used for t<span style="color: #8c0095;">he&#0160;<strong>use approved in this consent being restricted to the ground&#0160;</strong></span><span style="color: #8c0095;"><strong>floor shop, with the remainder of the premises being used solely as a single dwelling&quot;.</strong></span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">The section 96 application that you posted, &quot;&quot;under description was legally required to state it in description of proposal &quot;it is an application&#0160;</span><span style="font-size: small;">to &quot;AMEND Condition 2 of the Development consent and expand the&#0160;business&#0160;to the rear flat&quot;</span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></div>
<div>This application appears legally FLAWED, council should now review this consent with a view of rescinding the entire approval.&#0160;</div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">The processing officer(s) and team leader need to be made to front to a disciplinary interview to&#0160;</span>respond<span style="font-size: small;">&#0160;to the above matters and ascertain why this incomplete&#0160;erroneous&#0160;application was approved let alone accepted in that form.</span></div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;"><br /></span></div>
<div>One would reasonably expect the team leader not to sign off on the consent and demand all these matters are addressed or simply reject the application.</div>
<div><span style="font-size: small;">NO Council is &quot;legally allowed to process any incomplete&#0160;or inaccurate application under any circumstances.</span></div>
</div>
<div>Who processed this application? &#0160; ... this is really wrong!!!&#0160;</div>
<div>I assumed from this plan the SEC 96 application was to use the area marked as &quot;TEA room&quot; to expand the business. &#0160;</div>
<div>Hence the conclusion it would constitute an&#0160;intensification&#0160;of a use that was the subject of development consent issued on an incomplete and&#0160;erroneous&#0160;application.</div>
<div>This MUST BE&#0160;REFERRED&#0160;TO ICAC.</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9c0a1b9970d"><br /></span></p></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Meanwhile, Julia Gillard was campaigning for the Senate. Or working at Slater and Gordon.   Or doing the weeding.  Or helping Bruce sell Kerr Street or something.</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/meanwhile-julia-gillard-was-campaigning-for-the-senate-or-working-at-slater-and-gordon-or-doing-the-.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/meanwhile-julia-gillard-was-campaigning-for-the-senate-or-working-at-slater-and-gordon-or-doing-the-.html" thr:count="14" thr:updated="2013-03-26T21:10:00+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381d1b3b970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-26T19:54:02+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T20:15:50+11:00</updated>
        <summary>Do other countries have this drama with their Prime Minister? Slater and Gordon is on the record - &quot;In September 1995 Ms Gillard took a leave of absence from Slater &amp; Gordon in order to campaign for the Senate&quot;. Remember Slater and Gordon made that statement on Sunday, 19 August,...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do other countries have this drama with their Prime Minister?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slater and Gordon is on the record - &quot;In September 1995 Ms Gillard took a leave of absence from Slater &amp;amp; Gordon in order to campaign for the Senate&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember Slater and Gordon made that statement on Sunday, 19 August, 2012. &amp;nbsp;Julia Gillard needed a cover story and Slater and Gordon delivered one. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Gordon and Nick Styant Browne are in accord that Gillard elected to resign after her disciplinary hearing on 11 September, 1995 - and not &quot;in order to campaign for the Senate&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 15 October, 1995 Ebru Yaman&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee94a11fc970d-pi&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;article about Gillard appeared in The Australian newspaper.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; Gillard said, &quot;I&#39;m still a partner with Slater and Gordon and I have no intention of leaving&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&#39;s look at her biographical notes, here are some extracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381cc103970b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381cc103970b image-full&quot; title=&quot;Gillard archives&quot; src=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381cc103970b-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Gillard archives&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, so the version for the archives says she started with Brumby in 1995 (while she was campaigning for the Senate). &amp;nbsp; And according to The Australian she was still with Slater and Gordon as a partner and had no intention of leaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bio is similar from the APH handbook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424be316970c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424be316970c&quot; title=&quot;Gillard parliamentary handbook&quot; src=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424be316970c-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Gillard parliamentary handbook&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And this one is from the APH website&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424be43e970c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424be43e970c image-full&quot; title=&quot;Gillard aph website&quot; src=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424be43e970c-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Gillard aph website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Right. &amp;nbsp; Not campaigning for the Senate. &amp;nbsp; Working for Brumby in 1995. &amp;nbsp; Except that&#39;s bulltish too, she started in May, 1996. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe she&#39;d tell the Young Lawyer magazine the truth - as an example to say aspiring women who might be looking for a role model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope - that&#39;s full of bulltish too. &amp;nbsp; This photo predates botox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381d16a0970b-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381d16a0970b image-full&quot; title=&quot;Gillard law journal before ravages of age&quot; src=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381d16a0970b-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Gillard law journal before ravages of age&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For sheer lying chutzpah, how&#39;s this exposition of the pain of making that decision to leave Slater and Gordon to campaign for the Senate, or to run Brumby&#39;s office or to watch Oprah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;asset-img-link&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; href=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424c3c11970c-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424c3c11970c&quot; title=&quot;When I first left Slater and gordon&quot; src=&quot;http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424c3c11970c-800wi&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;When I first left Slater and gordon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;CEOs who lie like this in their CVs generally get picked up. &amp;nbsp; Surely to God someone in the Labor Party checked and saw that she had something to hide!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How did Ms Gillard got away with it for so long!   How come no one called her out, it&#39;s so obvious.</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/how-did-ms-gillard-got-away-with-it-for-so-long-how-come-no-one-called-her-out-its-so-obvious.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/how-did-ms-gillard-got-away-with-it-for-so-long-how-come-no-one-called-her-out-its-so-obvious.html" thr:count="25" thr:updated="2013-03-26T21:11:40+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424bd403970c</id>
        <published>2013-03-26T18:03:10+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T18:56:35+11:00</updated>
        <summary>Last week we spoke about the weekend of 18/19 August 2012 when Hedley Thomas published the Slater and Gordon/Gillard record of interview, Paul Kelly and Peter Van Onselen hosted Ms Gillard on Australian Agenda on Sky - and then Slater and Gordon staff concocted a manifestly dubious media statement to...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="html" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
&lt;div xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week we spoke about the weekend of 18/19 August 2012 when Hedley Thomas published the Slater and Gordon/Gillard record of interview, Paul Kelly and Peter Van Onselen hosted Ms Gillard on Australian Agenda on Sky - and then Slater and Gordon staff concocted a manifestly dubious media statement to advance Ms Gillard&#39;s personal interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With her background of bulltish that weekend should have been it and it may well have been if Slater and Gordon&#39;s current management had not been so helpful with the media statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the links to last week&#39;s posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/what-slater-and-gordon-says-is-a-matter-for-slater-and-gordon-and-julia-gillards-former-flatmate-jul.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/gillards-co-ordinated-activity-with-slater-and-gordon-to-concoct-a-false-statement-made-to-her-benef.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/slater-and-gordon-response-regarding-its-media-statement-of-20-august-2012.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our last public correspondence with Slater and Gordon last week ended like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And finally, is the Slater and Gordon statement that Julia Gillard &quot;took a leave of absence in order to campaign for the Senate&quot; in 1995 a true statement?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Yes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Regards&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Hamish&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;Hamish Heard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Senior Media Advisor&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;SLATER &amp;amp; GORDON LAWYERS&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;485 La Trobe St, Melbourne VIC 3000T:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slatergordon.com.au/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;slatergordon.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/SlaterGordonAU&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;facebook.com/SlaterGordonAU&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/SlaterGordon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;twitter.com/SlaterGordon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I followed that email with this note to Slater and Gordon&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;Hamish,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Thank you for your speedy response.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;May I try to clear up Slater and Gordon&#39;s official position on the substantive reason for Ms Gillard leaving the firm?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;In late 1995, had Ms Gillard&#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;relationship with the equity partnership group become fractured, and trust and confidence evaporated&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;making it untenable that she continue in her employment?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was the firm&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&quot;&lt;strong&gt;concerned as to whether (Ms Gillard) had acted consistently with (her) obligations of utmost good faith with regard to her partners&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;and was her resignation accepted in those circumstances?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Did the partnership&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;consider terminating Ms Gillard&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;and in those circumstances did&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms Gillard elect to resign&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;and did the partnership&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&quot;accept her resignation without discussion&quot;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Was it&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;clear that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp; relationships had broken down irretrievably&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;between Ms Gillard and the remaining partners in the partnership&lt;em&gt;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Slater and Gordon&#39;s public statement of 20 August, 2012 gives the impression that the substantive underlying reason for Ms Gillard&#39;s absence from the firm from September 1995 was &quot;in order (for her) to campaign for the Senate&quot;. &amp;nbsp; Is that the major contributing reason for Julia Gillard&#39;s absence from the firm from September, 1995?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Finally, is Slater and Gordon aware of any reason, order or agreement of any nature that would restrict Ms Gillard from practicing as a lawyer at any time in Victoria?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here is some news! &amp;nbsp; As you know I was crook late last week, during that time Slater and Gordon have responded to our questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the response from Slater and Gordon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stand by the previous public statements we have made regarding this issue&quot;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have the law firm&#39;s current management coming in to work on a Sunday when Julia Gillard needs a positive media statement. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Together with Ms Gillard they concoct a statement that protects Ms Gillard. &amp;nbsp; Don&#39;t you wish they&#39;d just told the truth? &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we&#39;ll look closely at those 6 months that Slater and Gordon says Ms Gillard was campaigning for the Senate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;
&lt;!-- Size: 468x60 --&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Alan Jones with The Australian&#39;s Foreign Affairs Editor Greg Sheridan on 2GB this morning</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/alan-jones-with-the-australians-foreign-affairs-editor-greg-sheridan-on-2gb-this-morning.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/alan-jones-with-the-australians-foreign-affairs-editor-greg-sheridan-on-2gb-this-morning.html" thr:count="24" thr:updated="2013-03-26T21:02:15+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381c9152970b</id>
        <published>2013-03-26T17:24:25+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T17:24:25+11:00</updated>
        <summary></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><object data="http://abfiles.s3.amazonaws.com/swf/fullsize_player.swf" height="129" id="boo_embed_1291168" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="400">
<param name="movie" value="http://abfiles.s3.amazonaws.com/swf/fullsize_player.swf" />
<param name="scale" value="noscale" />
<param name="salign" value="lt" />
<param name="bgColor" value="#FFFFFF" />
<param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" />
<param name="wmode" value="window" />
<param name="FlashVars" value="mp3=http%3A%2F%2Faudioboo.fm%2Fboos%2F1291168-alan-jones-and-greg-sheridan.mp3%3Fkeyed%3Dtrue%26source%3Dembed&amp;mp3Title=Alan+Jones+and+Greg+Sheridan&amp;mp3Time=06.22am+26+Mar+2013&amp;mp3LinkURL=http%3A%2F%2Faudioboo.fm%2Fboos%2F1291168-alan-jones-and-greg-sheridan&amp;mp3Author=michaelsmithnews&amp;rootID=boo_embed_1291168" /><iframe allowtransparency="allowtransparency" cellspacing="0" frameborder="0" hspace="0" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="http://audioboo.fm/boos/1291168-alan-jones-and-greg-sheridan/embed" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: none; display: block; width: 400px; height: 145px;" title="Audioboo player" vspace="0"></iframe>
</object></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>No sex please - we&#39;re from Marrickville</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/no-sex-please-were-from-marrickville.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/no-sex-please-were-from-marrickville.html" thr:count="29" thr:updated="2013-03-26T21:01:01+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf952c970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-26T16:52:44+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T18:56:49+11:00</updated>
        <summary>Here is the entire contents of the file held by Marrickville council in the several applications to develop the building at 467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill. Download Applications and Consents DA200900093 467 New Canterbury - redacted This is what the applications say the place will be used for But...</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Here is the entire contents of the file held by Marrickville council in the several applications to develop the building at 467 New Canterbury Road Dulwich Hill.</p>
<span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017d424b8906970c"><a href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/files/applications-and-consents-da200900093-467-new-canterbury---redacted.pdf">Download Applications and Consents DA200900093 467 New Canterbury - redacted</a></span><br />
<p><span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf3a6c970d">This is what the applications say the place will be used for</span></p>
<p><span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf3a6c970d">
<a class="asset-img-link" style="display: inline;" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381c17a0970b-pi"><img class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381c17a0970b" title="Thai massage" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017c381c17a0970b-800wi" border="0" alt="Thai massage" /></a><br />But someone at the council felt the need to set this condition out explicitly</span></p>
<p><span class="asset  asset-generic at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf3a6c970d">
<a class="asset-img-link" style="display: inline;" href="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf8d00970d-pi"><img class="asset  asset-image at-xid-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf8d00970d image-full" title="Not as sexual services" src="http://michaelsmithnews.typepad.com/.a/6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bf8d00970d-800wi" border="0" alt="Not as sexual services" /></a><br /><br /></span></p><!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com -->
<!-- Size: 468x60 -->
<script src="http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<!-- MadAdsMedia.com Asynchronous Ad Tag For MichaelSmithNews.com --></div>
</content>



    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>An update on the Victoria Police investigation into the WILSON/GILLARD/BLEWITT matter</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/an-update-on-the-victoria-police-investigation-into-the-wilsongillardblewitt-matter.html" />
        <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/2013/03/an-update-on-the-victoria-police-investigation-into-the-wilsongillardblewitt-matter.html" thr:count="57" thr:updated="2013-03-26T20:36:29+11:00" />
        <id>tag:typepad.com,2003:post-6a0177444b0c2e970d017ee9bebe03970d</id>
        <published>2013-03-26T13:52:09+11:00</published>
        <updated>2013-03-26T13:56:20+11:00</updated>
        <summary></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Smith</name>
        </author>
        
        
<content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en-AU" xml:base="http://www.michaelsmithnews.com/">
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><object id="boo_embed_1290888" width="400" height="129" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" data="http://abfiles.s3.amazonaws.com/swf/fullsize_player.swf">
<param name="movie" value="http://abfiles.s3.amazonaws.com/swf/fullsize_player.swf" />
<param name="scale" value="noscale" />
<param name="salign" value="lt" />
<param name="bgColor" value="#FFFFFF" />
<param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" />
<param name="wmode" value="window" />
<param name="FlashVars" value="mp3=http%3A%2F%2Faudioboo.fm%2Fboos%2F1290888-update-on-the-police-investigation.mp3%3Fkeyed%3Dtrue%26source%3Dembed&amp;mp3Title=Update+on+the+police+investigation&amp;mp3Time=12.27pm+26+Mar+2013&amp;mp3LinkURL=http%3A%2F%2Faudioboo.fm%2Fboos%2F1290888-update-on-the-police-investigation&amp;mp3Author=michaelsmithnews&amp;rootID=boo_embed_1290888" /><iframe vspace="0" title="Audioboo player" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: none; display: block; width: 400px; height: 145px;" src="http://audioboo.fm/boos/1290888-update-on-the-police-investigation/embed" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" hspace="0" frameborder="0" cellspacing="0" allowtransparency="allowtransparency"></iframe>
</object>
<script src="http://ads-by.madadsmedia.com/tags/4387/3330/async/468x60.js" type="text/javascript"></script></div>
</content>



    </entry>
 
</feed>

<!-- ph=1 -->
