<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Wednesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/wednesday-open-thread-67/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/wednesday-open-thread-67/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 11:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124097</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Live life off the wall. Image source Wikimedia]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Live life off the wall.<span id="more-124097"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/tSiRRkwQ1GE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Image source <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Mostar_Old_Town_Panorama_2007.jpg" target="_blank">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/wednesday-open-thread-67/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Water off a Duck&#8217;s Back: RuPaul&#8217;s Drag Race Season 5, Episode 11</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/water-off-a-ducks-back-rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-11/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/water-off-a-ducks-back-rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-11/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 15:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Homoviper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homoviper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rupaul's drag race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[season 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water off a duck's back]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124086</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[And then there were three. This week the queens began with the puppet bitchery mini challenge. Jinkx and Alaska were [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rupaulsdragraceheader.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rupaulsdragraceheader.jpg" alt="rupaulsdragraceheader" width="510" height="220" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-118184" /></a><br />
And then there were three. This week the queens began with the puppet bitchery mini challenge. Jinkx and Alaska were both very funny. Detox was so-so, and Roxxxy was no-no. This kind of challenge requires a sense of humor, and Roxxxy doesn&#8217;t really have one &#8212; she&#8217;s too invested in being cruel.<span id="more-124086"></span></p>
<p>Alaska won the mini challenge, and then the queens were tasked with putting together three looks for the main challenge: a sweet sixteen look, an executive realness look and a look literally (at least partially) constructed from candy. In addition, the gworls had to do a choreographed &#8220;sugar babies&#8221; number to get things started. This is it, bitches.</p>
<p>Ultimately, Alaska won the main challenge. Jinkx and Detox lip synced for their lives, and Jinkx sent Detox packing. Let&#8217;s break it down in a bit more detail with a look at the updated Drag Race Index.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/drag_race_index_week11.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/drag_race_index_week11-1024x584.jpg" alt="drag_race_index_week11" width="654" height="372" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-124089" /></a></p>
<p>Click to enlarge! Jinkx and Alaska have not moved for five weeks. They are firmly in the 1 and 2 spots respectively. Boxxxy and Detox have also been static, but for only three weeks. Can the Index&#8217;s non-scientific methods predict our winner? Does it even matter? Okay, let&#8217;s break it down fish by fish.</p>
<h4>Jinkx Monsoon</h4>
<p>Jinkx stumbled a bit this week. I understand the judges&#8217; criticisms of her Sweet Sixteen look, but I also appreciate that Jinkx tries to bring a different perspective to the challenges, and frankly I knew girls who dressed like that when I was in high school. Her executive look was on point, but the big flub was her candy couture look. So why is she still in the top spot of the Index? Uh, helloooo, did you see that bitch lip sync? I&#8217;ll be honest, I was very nervous because I knew she would be in the bottom two, but as soon as the song started playing, I knew Jinkxyboo wernt going nowheres. That lip sync will go down as one of the best in Drag Race Herstory. Everything about that was perfection, while Detox&#8217;s bag of tricks was conspicuously empty.</p>
<h4>Alaska</h4>
<p>Hieeee. Alaska did really well this week. Things were looking scary for her when her candy couture look began to fall apart in the workroom, but she managed to hold that shet together (probably with sheer will) long enough to get it down the runway and back. Bob Mackie was absolutely right when he said that it was the only outfit that actually read as candy. I love me some Alaska, and I can&#8217;t wait to see her compete in the top three. She is now the only queen who hasn&#8217;t had to lip sync. Did you catch her Tyra Sanchez reference? Maybe she will sneak past the others to victory.</p>
<h4>Boxxxy Mandrews</h4>
<p>Oh em gee, I hate this cunt so much. Yeah, okay, she had a pretty good night, but Alaska&#8217;s candy couture look had it all over that tassel dress thing Boxxxy made. Every chance she had she was saying mean shet to Jinkx, taking all kinds of unnecessary jabs. Ugh. Boxxxy may have the Talent part of the equation, and I might even concede she has a bit of Nerve, but there&#8217;s nothing Unique about her, and she has <strong>zero</strong> Charisma. Sorry, Boxxxy, but America&#8217;s Next Drag Superstar needs to have all four to be a winner.</p>
<h4>Detox</h4>
<p>Sashay away, chicken lady. I like Detox, but in some sense I feel that she&#8217;s very lucky to have made it as far as she did.</p>
<p>What are your thoughts, children? Sound off in the comments below! Next week (April 22) will be the final challenge and so the last time we&#8217;ll take a look at the Drag Race Index. The following week (April 29) will be a clips show so there won&#8217;t be any recapping that week &#8212; I might do what we did last year, which was to host an open thread where we could go GIF crazy. May 6 will be the final episode, a reunion special during which America&#8217;s Next Drag Superstar (and Miss Congeniality) will be crowned, and I&#8217;ll do a final recap for that episode! Until next week, my lovelies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/water-off-a-ducks-back-rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tuesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-73/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-73/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124026</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Tuesday. Check out this cool, historical animation. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-73/"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Sumatran_Rhino_21.jpg" alt="Sumatran_Rhino_2" width="796" height="374" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124037" /></a></p>
<p>Happy Tuesday. Check out this <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/the_vault/2013/04/15/wladislaw_starewicz_the_director_created_first_stop_motion_animation_using.html">cool, historical animation</a>. <span id="more-124026"></span></p>
<p><object id="flashObj" width="480" height="270" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0"><param name="movie" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&#038;isUI=1" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="flashVars" value="videoId=2293911884001&#038;linkBaseURL=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.slate.com%2Fblogs%2Fthe_vault%2F2013%2F04%2F15%2Fwladislaw_starewicz_the_director_created_first_stop_motion_animation_using.html&#038;playerID=58264559001&#038;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAASoY90~,_gW1ZHvKG_0UvBsh7aZU7MXZe77OcsGq&#038;domain=embed&#038;dynamicStreaming=true" /><param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /><param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><embed src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&#038;isUI=1" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashVars="videoId=2293911884001&#038;linkBaseURL=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.slate.com%2Fblogs%2Fthe_vault%2F2013%2F04%2F15%2Fwladislaw_starewicz_the_director_created_first_stop_motion_animation_using.html&#038;playerID=58264559001&#038;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAAASoY90~,_gW1ZHvKG_0UvBsh7aZU7MXZe77OcsGq&#038;domain=embed&#038;dynamicStreaming=true" base="http://admin.brightcove.com" name="flashObj" width="480" height="270" seamlesstabbing="false" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" swLiveConnect="true" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash"></embed></object></p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Sumatran_Rhino_2.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-73/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boston Marathon Bombing Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-open-thread/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-open-thread/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 20:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>A Piece of the Continent</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124061</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There were two explosions today while the running of the Boston Marathon took place. Many casualties are reported. Investigation continues, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-124073" alt="200px-Bostonmarathonlogo" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/200px-Bostonmarathonlogo.jpg" width="200" height="183" /> There were two explosions today while the running of the Boston Marathon took place. Many casualties are reported. Investigation continues, though the official statement from the Marathon was that they were bombs.</p>
<p>Info and news sources after the jump.<span id="more-124061"></span></p>
<p><b>Good news sources on Twitter:</b></p>
<p>Boston: @Bostondotcom<br />
Reuters: @ReutersUS<br />
Boston PD: @Boston_Police<br />
Boston Globe: @BostonGlobe @GlobeMetro<br />
Boston Public Radio: @WBUR</p>
<p><b>Live Coverage</b></p>
<p><a href="http://www.wbur.org/listen/live">Boston Public Radio Live Coverage</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.wcvb.com/">WCVB TV Boston</a></p>
<p><a href="http://boston.cbslocal.com/live-video/">CBS Boston</a></p>
<p><a href="http://tunein.com/radio/WBZ-NewsRadio-1030-s27704/">WBZ Radio</a></p>
<p><b>Official News</b></p>
<p><a href="http://www.broadcastify.com/listen/feed/6254/web">Boston Police, Fire and EMS Live Audio Feed</a></p>
<p>If you are missing friends or family, please call (617) 635-4500<br />
Hotline if you have info: 1(800) 494-8477</p>
<p>Image source <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boston_Marathon">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-open-thread/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Game of Thrones Recap: &#8220;Walk of Punishment&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/game-of-thrones-recap-walk-of-punishment/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/game-of-thrones-recap-walk-of-punishment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 18:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game of Thrones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recaps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t!ts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walk of punishment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123956</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week we learn the price of war. Last week: Bran, Rickon, Osha, and Hodor added Jojen and Meera Reed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week we learn the price of war. <span id="more-123956"></span></p>
<p><b><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/game-of-thrones-recap-dark-wings-dark-words/">Last week:</a></b> Bran, Rickon, Osha, and Hodor added Jojen and Meera Reed to their party, giving Bran some sort of teacher in his newfound abilities. Robb and Catelyn Stark set off for the Tully holding of Riverrun to bury Catelyn&#8217;s father Hoster and get some more men. Jon Snow was accepted, albeit with caution, by the windings after killing Quorin Halfhand. The rest of the Night&#8217;s Watch was reduced in number and on the run from the White Walkers and their wights. Theon had a corkscrew through his foot. Arya and Gendry were held by the Brotherhood Without Banners after Sandor Clegane revealed Arya&#8217;s identity. Brienne and Jamie were captured by Bolton men, after trying to kill each other (Is it love?). Sansa was drawn further into the plans of the players around her, giving the Tyrells information about Joffrey while Littlefinger dangled hope in front of her. Joffrey was an idiot, again, and Margaery came out on top.</p>
<p><b>This week</b>: Tits! OMG, tits. Thank you. But first: the episode opens with the burial of Hoster Tully, with Catelyn&#8217;s brother Edmure&#8217;s (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0580014/?ref_=tt_cl_t7">Tobias Menzies</a>,<i>Rome</i>) fire arrows missing the funeral boat bearing his father&#8217;s body not once but three times. Hoster&#8217;s brother Brynden the Blackfish (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0751085/?ref_=tt_cl_t8">Clive Russell</a>, <i>Sherlock Holmes</i>) shoves him out of the way and takes care of business. I like him. Edmure&#8217;s poor skill with a bow turns out to be an indicator of his skill in war generally, as it is revealed that Edmure ignored Robb&#8217;s orders to wait for Gregor Clegane to come into their own territory and instead took a thoroughly useless mill and two equally useless Lannister captives, losing over 200 men and the chance to kill Gregor in the process.  Robb&#8217;s delivery of his reprimand to his uncle is clearly angry, but controlled. Kingly. </p>
<p>In contrast to some of the meetings earlier in Robb&#8217;s rule, Catelyn is left out of the discussion. She and her uncle Brynden discuss the fates of Bran and Rickon; Catelyn is convinced that she will never see them again, while Brynden tells her to keep hoping and remain strong for the son whose company she does still have.<br />
<div id="attachment_124039" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 525px"><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Small-council.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Small-council.jpg" alt="Sort of." width="525" height="260" class="size-full wp-image-124039" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The most powerful men in the realm.</p></div><br />
Meanwhile, at the small council meeting the seating chart becomes a thing of hilarity. The first 90 seconds of the scene are entirely without dialogue, but lacks nothing. Cersei puts on a show of dominance, claiming the empty side of the table opposite Varys, Littlefinger, and Grand Maester Pycelle for herself. Tyrion hilariously one-ups her by slowly and loudly dragging his own chair to the foot of the table, opposite his father. Perfect. But Papa Lannister is not happy, and the non-Lannisters look scared. Littlefinger has pulled off a victory. Having been made Lord of Harrenhal (which the Lannisters no longer hold), he has also been approved to wed Lysa Tully, which would make him the Lord of the Vale. Tyrion&#8217;s run of bad luck is continued when he is made Master of Coin because of Littlefinger&#8217;s impending departure to the Eyrie to woo Lysa Tully, to Tyrion&#8217;s horror and his sister&#8217;s delight.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Pod.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Pod.jpg" alt="Pod" width="173" height="250" class="alignright size-full wp-image-124050" /></a>Later, Ros digs out the king&#8217;s ledgers at Littlefinger&#8217;s brothers while Podrick admires her tits. Littlefinger tries to dig for leverage, but Tyrion refuses to give Littlefinger answers about why Cersei thinks that Tyrion had a &#8220;special relationship&#8221; with Ros. After going through the ledgers, Tyrion discovers that Littlefinger has been borrowing money from the Iron Bank of Braavos, across the Narrow Sea. Bad news, as the Iron Bank doesn&#8217;t play when it comes to repayment. Meanwhile, Podrick had been left in the brothel with not one but three women as a thank you from Tyrion (this is where the tits came in). When Bronn and Tyrion leave the squire he looks absolutely terrified. But when Pod returns to the castle from his playtime, <i>he has a full refund in hand</i>. The ladies wouldn&#8217;t take it because they liked him so much. Well. </p>
<p>Arya and Sandor are still being held by the Brotherhood. Arya, frustrated by her position as a &#8220;guest&#8221; of the Brotherhood, tries to confront the Hound, asking him if he remembers the last time they were there. <a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Arya1.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Arya1.jpg" alt="Arya" width="253" height="270" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-124056" /></a> She wants him to remember the butcher&#8217;s boy that he ran down in the aftermath of her confrontation with Joffrey. Being Sandor, he doesn&#8217;t. When the Brotherhood packs up and moves on, Hot Pie reveals that he is staying with the innkeeper, earning his keep as a baker. An awkward but oddly touching goodbye takes place after Hot Pie gives her a piece of bread allegedly shaped like a wolf as a farewell present, before calling Arya&#8217;s home &#8220;Winterhell&#8221; (&#8220;Winter<i>fell</i>,&#8221; &#8220;Are you sure?&#8221;). </p>
<p>Jon and the wildings come across a delightful and gory piece of horse head art left by the White Walkers at the Fist of the First Men. Mance sees opportunity and orders Jon to go with an advance party of wildings led by Tormund Giantsbane to scale the Wall. Meanwhile, the surviving men of the Night&#8217;s Watch make their way back to Craster&#8217;s keep. The old man lets them in, possibly more because he is outnumbered by desperate men than because he really wants to. In the background you can hear the cries of a woman in childbirth, for which Craster threatens to punch her. Charming. After Craster calls him &#8220;a walking feast&#8221; and asks why they haven&#8217;t butchered him for food, Sam walks out, and finds Gilly is the one in labor. When the babe comes out, the look on the midwife&#8217;s face tells it all.  The boy is destined as a sacrifice to the &#8220;real gods.&#8221; </p>
<p>Theon is let free by his unnamed rescuer, who sends him east to his sister on a horse. Theon&#8217;s ride eventually becomes a chase, and then a capture after he takes a heavy hit with a flail from a Bolton man and falls off his horse. They tear down Theon&#8217;s pants so that he can be raped. But once again, his rescuer comes through, putting arrows in all the men. Theon is still free for the moment. </p>
<p>At Storm&#8217;s End, Melisandre is leaving but will not tell Stannis where she goes, insisting that even she does not know. As they say goodbye there is some bad touching. Stannis wants another freaky shadowbaby (or maybe just to screw her again) but Melisandre says that he is too weak. <div id="attachment_124030" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 315px"><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Stannis.jpeg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Stannis.jpeg" alt="Please stop being so creepy." width="315" height="197" class="size-full wp-image-124030" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Please stop being so creepy.</p></div>There is another way to get him to the throne, she says; a sacrifice of someone with the king&#8217;s blood. She does not name the would-be sacrifice, but Stannis doesn&#8217;t look too happy at the thought of butchering a relative for the god. </p>
<p>Daenerys, Jorah and Barristan Selmy travel the Walk of Punishment, Astapor&#8217;s way of keeping their slaves in line. Offenders are whipped and nailed to crosses. Ser Barristan wants Dany to leave Astapor and find sellswords instead of slaves; Jorah wants Dany to do what has to be done to win the throne. And, he points out, as perfectly obedient slave-soldiers the Unsullied will not rape, plunder, or murder after they conquer a city unless they are ordered to do so. About her brother he says, &#8220;Rhaegar fought valiantly, Rhaegar fought nobly, and Rhaegar died.&#8221; As they continue to the palace of the masters of the city, she says, &#8220;I wish I had known him. He was not the last Dragon.&#8221; </p>
<p>Dany tells them she wants <i>all</i> the Unsullied, including the ones who have yet to finish training. As Dany sees slaves, including children, watching their negotiations from the roof, she makes a decision. She offers one dragon, her biggest, to the protests of both Ser Barristan and Jorah. After the deal is agreed upon, she takes the translator Missandei as well. After she walks out, she tells Selmy and Jorah to shut up with their disagreements in public, or find employment elsewhere. Queenly. She tells Missandei, &#8220;All men must die, but we are not men.&#8221; Dany, like Robb, seems to have come fully into her role as leader.</p>
<p>While tied back to back, Jamie and Brienne argue about who is a better swordsman/woman, and whose fault it is that they were taken. I think they like each other. The tone changes when Jamie raises the topic of rape for Brienne, which seems highly probable. For once, it doesn&#8217;t seem like Jamie&#8217;s intention is to piss her off. Jamie, despite himself, has come to care about what happens to Brienne. He advises her to refrain from fighting back, a tactic that he admits he himself wouldn&#8217;t take. After they stop for the night and their captor orders Brienne separated so that he can have privacy, Jamie thinks quickly as her screams grow louder, and more heart-rending.<a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Jamie.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Jamie.jpg" alt="Jamie" width="300" height="188" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-124048" /></a> He spins a completely BS story about Tarth being the source of all Westeros&#8217;s sapphires, telling Fuckface that Brienne&#8217;s father will ransom her for her weight in gemstones. Fuckface decides he&#8217;d rather have sapphires. Jamie, having negotiated the safety of Brienne along with food and comfort for himself, is feeling in control once again despite his restraints. Not for long. Fuckface decides to teach Jamie a lesson about his new status and cuts off his sword hand. </p>
<p><b>Thoughts:</b> If this episode was about anything, I think it was about the price of war. What nearly happened to Theon and Brienne, scenes that were horrifying enough in what they suggested, are sure to play out in the Seven Kingdoms on a large scale. The conversation in Astapor was clear enough about that, and we have seen such acts in previous seasons. Jamie&#8217;s hand was a casualty of his attempt to stop just one act of that kind of brutality. Arya has lost her childhood and her safety. Catelyn is faced with the loss of her sons and Stannis is faced with the loss of some member of his kin as the price for his success. Will he pay it? </p>
<p><i>All screen captures taken by the author.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/game-of-thrones-recap-walk-of-punishment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mad Men Post-Mortem: Collaborators</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/mad-men-post-mortem-collaborators/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/mad-men-post-mortem-collaborators/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>A Piece of the Continent</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123970</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You were given the choice between war and dishonor. You chose dishonor and you will have war. &#8211; Winston Churchill [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>You were given the choice between war and dishonor. You chose dishonor and you will have war. &#8211; Winston Churchill</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>WARNING: THIS THREAD WILL CONTAIN SPOILERS! IF YOU HAVE NOT SEEN THE EPISODE OR DO NOT WANT TO BE SPOILED, DO NOT PASS GO, DO NOT COLLECT $200. STAY OUT UNLESS YOU WANT TO BE SPOILED.<span id="more-123970"></span></strong></p>
<p>And now my random thoughts regarding the episode in no particular order.</p>
<p><em>Collaborators</em> took a major turn for the soap opera and I loved that it was even alluded to when Sylvia wasn&#8217;t sure if Megan&#8217;s miscarriage was something that happened in her life or a plot point from the character she plays. Everyone cheating on everyone and having secret miscarriages and spying on their step-mother schlepping their step-dad, oh my.</p>
<p>Another thing which really struck me this episode was that throughout the show a tapestry of significant historic events was woven into the background but each character was so wrapped up in their own lives they were barely paying attention. That actually struck me as fairly true to life. When we think of the era what comes to mind are the brazen activists and government machinery but I would imagine there was a fair amount of people for who the events of the time were not affecting their everyday life.</p>
<p>This week&#8217;s flashbacks were pretty straightforward and yet straight out of left field at the same time. The same austere Abigail Whitman who was outraged at having to raise a &#8220;whore&#8217;s son&#8221; is now having sex in a brothel with a random man? What? The writer&#8217;s took a pretty big leap in an effort to show what drove Don to associate shame with sexual arousal.</p>
<p>Fuck yeah, Trudy Campbell. Pete stands as one of the last bastions of a dying misogynistic era and Trudy isn&#8217;t going to stand for it anymore. As a side note to that story line, I&#8217;ve always been a Pete fan- I just want to take him and <em>fix</em> him- but when he paid that complement about the lipstick I became entirely convinced Pete is going to turn out to be a serial killer. You read it here first, kids.</p>
<p>Say it ain&#8217;t so, Peg. The one thing that has always been at the core of Peggy&#8217;s character was her loyalty. I&#8217;m really, sincerely hoping she won&#8217;t sacrifice that for her career. Perhaps instead this will be the impetus for her to go running back to Sterling Cooper this time with greater leverage to demand the respect she deserves? Fingers crossed.</p>
<p>And finally, footage from the original cast of <em>Hair</em>&#8216;s 1968 appearance on <em>The Tonight Show Starring Johnny Carson</em>. Can you imagine Pete in the audience?</p>
<p><center><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/tL96JU-ptfo" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></center>[<a href="http://blogs.amctv.com/photo-galleries/mad-men-season-6-episode-photos/episode-3-don.php">Image</a>]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/mad-men-post-mortem-collaborators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retro Liveblog: Joe Scarborough Whines About The President&#8217;s Taxes</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/retro-liveblog-joe-scarborough-whines-about-the-presidents-taxes/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/retro-liveblog-joe-scarborough-whines-about-the-presidents-taxes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Knight of the Burning River</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butthurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Scarboroug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pundits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123978</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Visit NBCNews.com for breaking news, world news, and news about the economy Today on Joe Scarborough&#8217;s Beltway Circlejerk, our intrepid [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div align="center"><object id="msnbc75a3a9" width="420" height="245" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="FlashVars" value="launch=51541399&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="wmode" value="transparent" /><param name="src" value="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/32545640" /><param name="flashvars" value="launch=51541399&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="pluginspage" value="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /><embed id="msnbc75a3a9" width="420" height="245" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/32545640" FlashVars="launch=51541399&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" allowScriptAccess="always" allowFullScreen="true" wmode="transparent" flashvars="launch=51541399&amp;width=420&amp;height=245" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" pluginspage="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /></object></p>
<p style="font-size: 11px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #999; margin-top: 5px; background: transparent; text-align: center; width: 420px;">Visit NBCNews.com for <a style="text-decoration: none !important; border-bottom: 1px dotted #999 !important; font-weight: normal !important; height: 13px; color: #5799db !important;" href="http://www.nbcnews.com">breaking news</a>, <a style="text-decoration: none !important; border-bottom: 1px dotted #999 !important; font-weight: normal !important; height: 13px; color: #5799db !important;" href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/3032507">world news</a>, and <a style="text-decoration: none !important; border-bottom: 1px dotted #999 !important; font-weight: normal !important; height: 13px; color: #5799db !important;" href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/3032072">news about the economy</a></p>
</div>
<p>Today on <i>Joe Scarborough&#8217;s Beltway Circlejerk</i>, our intrepid host had himself quite a fit about the President&#8217;s 2012 taxes. Personally, I found it rather sad, but also rife with opportunities to make jokes about Joe Scarborough &amp; Friends relative lack of understanding of the world outside of the $750-a-plate brunch crowd. To that end, let&#8217;s have a little liveblog fun-<span id="more-123978"></span></p>
<p>0:01- Joe wants all of us to know that Barack Obama, who makes less than Mitt Romney, is worth less than Mitt Romney, and pays a higher rate than Mitt Romney is still just <i>the worst</i></p>
<p>0:54- Joe &#8216;hears&#8217; that Barack Obama is worth $14 million dollars, with much contempt. Note, that is less than 5% of what Mitt Romney is reportedly worth.</p>
<p>1:50- Joe points out that the President pays <i>HALF</i> of what Joe S. and Will Geist pay, and that is a TRAGEDY. Joe conveniently leaves out the fact that his salary from &#8216;leftist&#8217; MSNBC was reportedly $4 Million last year, because how could that fact be relevant?</p>
<p>2:20- The problem with &#8216;liberals&#8217; and &#8216;rich guys on TV&#8217; who say we need taxes is that they ignore small business owners. Sounds like Joe just made a great argument for going after the carried interest loophole.</p>
<p>3:00- You can actually hear the vile contempt in Ol&#8217; Squnity&#8217;s voice here: &#8216;This guy?&#8217; Yes, Joe, this guy that majority of voters favored on these exact proposals. That is what he is proposing. Weird how that works.</p>
<p>3:30- Yeah, no, I &#8216;m pretty sure Joe Scarborough is doing about as much of his own tax prep as he is his own laundry or gardening.</p>
<p>3:45- &#8216;Limousine Liberal&#8217;? Jesus, I thought Reagan died over a decade ago.</p>
<p>4:15- If the President is watching this morning&#8230;.yeah, the leader of the free world just can&#8217;t get enough of Joe Scarborough and Ed Rendell yelling at people.</p>
<p>4:30- An important point from David Ignatius of <em>The Washington Post</em> here: BHO and Co. donated over $100K of $600K to charity last year, significantly denting that tax bill. And weirdly, he&#8217;s not even a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Kq7RwI91UU">Latter Day Saint</a>.</p>
<p>5:15- &#8216;Does anyone have the luxury of making so many charitable contributions?&#8217; The luxury? Seriously? Yeah, look the President doesn&#8217;t have a lot of expenses while he&#8217;s in office, we get that. Does anyone think that Joe Scarborough is paying for his own ride to and from the MSNBC studios everyday?</p>
<p>5:30- 18% is 18%? Weird, that didn&#8217;t seem to apply to Mitt Romney&#8217;s 14%</p>
<p>5:45- Ed Rendell, property of <del>Starve the Old and Poor</del> Fix the Debt, defends the President by stating that at least he was in favor of the Buffet Rule, which would have hit him. You know, except, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffett_Rule">not at all</a>.</p>
<p>6:00- Also, too, the Buffet rule doesn&#8217;t touch corporate rates.</p>
<p>6:30- Does Joe think he&#8217;d get a tax break under the Buffet Rule? I mean, I&#8217;m sure someone would figure it out, but, still, he just sounds dumb here.</p>
<p>7:00- Joe will rail on about &#8216;billionaires and hedge fund managers&#8217;, but he won&#8217;t propose going after their carried interest. He still has sponsors to keep happy, you know.</p>
<p>7:20- Joe think there are &#8216;lots of Republicans&#8217; who would agree that we need the Buffet Rule. If he can find 5, I&#8217;ll watch his show in its entirety for a whole week. Then, I&#8217;ll check into alcohol rehab. Do the math.</p>
<p>Honestly, I haven&#8217;t the slightest understand of who is watching this and thinking &#8216;Boy howdy, Joe Scarborough has a lot of good points&#8217;. For fun he brought on Marsha Blakburn-R-Fuckpoorpeopleistan, to make the wonderful point that the President <i>could</i> write a larger check to Treasury. Which is perfect, because giving back to a society which has provided the infrastructure and protections that allowed you to succeed should be totally voluntary.</p>
<p>That exchange, more than the video above, is symbolic of the entire clusterfuck in which this country finds itself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/retro-liveblog-joe-scarborough-whines-about-the-presidents-taxes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/monday-open-thread-75/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/monday-open-thread-75/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123958</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You can do this, P.S, Don&#8217;t forget your taxes. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can do this, <span id="more-123958"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Th-AqMvvBzE?list=UUflKJMyrnJNuD4eEvs9-5CA" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>P.S, Don&#8217;t forget your taxes.</p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:FA-18_Hornet_breaking_sound_barrier_%287_July_1999%29.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/monday-open-thread-75/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mad Men Open Thread: Season 6, Episode 3</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/mad-men-open-thread-season-6-episode-3/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/mad-men-open-thread-season-6-episode-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 01:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AMC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good tv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mad Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[still a million times better than smash]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123925</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome back, folks. Sad to see another weekend go by, but excited for a new episode of Mad Men. Last [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mad_Men_Season_6_Promotional_Poster.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-123222" alt="Mad_Men_Season_6,_Promotional_Poster" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mad_Men_Season_6_Promotional_Poster-197x300.jpg" width="197" height="300" /></a>Welcome back, folks. Sad to see another weekend go by, but excited for a new episode of Mad Men. Last week left us with so many questions (well, me at least anyways). I&#8217;m excited to see what &#8220;doorways&#8221; our characters go through this season and where each one leads them.</p>
<p>If you missed out because you don&#8217;t have cable, AMC has made the premiere available <a href="http://www.amctv.com/shows/mad-men/video#type=all&amp;filter=rb-video-browser-num_items%3D10%26module_id_base%3Drb-video-browser%26module_id%3Dcfct-module-092ef28b46f301a3225bce7acc2cd7c1%26rb-video-browser-episode%3D%257B%2522sh%2522%253A%252257%2522%252C%2522se%2522%253A%2522278%2522%257D%26rb-video-browser-content_type%3D&amp;page=1&amp;post_id=32639">online</a> until April 30, 2013.  My comments will be a little late this week since I&#8217;ll be headed back from the airport during the show, but they will be there!</p>
<p><strong>WARNING: THIS POST WILL CONTAIN SPOILERS! IF YOU DON&#8217;T WANT TO BE SPOILED, STAY OUT!<span id="more-123925"></span></strong></p>
<p>Image <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Mad_Men_Season_6,_Promotional_Poster.jpg">via</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/mad-men-open-thread-season-6-episode-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recipe Sunday: Orecchiette with Ground Turkey and Broccolini</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/recipe-sunday-orecchiette-with-ground-turkey-and-broccolini/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/recipe-sunday-orecchiette-with-ground-turkey-and-broccolini/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>GtCosita</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broccolini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ground Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orecchiette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe sunday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yum]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123945</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Pasta with bolognese sauce is a staple in our house, but as I&#8217;ve gotten &#8220;older&#8221;, I find that ground beef [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pasta with bolognese sauce is a staple in our house, but as I&#8217;ve gotten &#8220;older&#8221;, I find that ground beef sometimes sits heavy in my stomach after dinner, particularly if I go overboard with the garlic. I recently started substituting ground beef with ground turkey in my bolognese, and have been thrilled with the results. The ground turkey absorbs all the flavors of the onions and garlic, while making the sauce light, or as light as a bolognese can be. Even though this recipe is not a traditional bolognese, it has all the ingredients I love: onions, garlic, and tomatoes. Also, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broccolini" target="_blank">broccolini</a> gives it a nice splash of color and texture. <em>Serves 4.<span id="more-123945"></span></em></p>
<p><em>Ingredients</em></p>
<ul>
<li>1 lb ground turkey</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>1 bunch broccolini, stalks trimmed</li>
<li>2 garlic cloves, minced</li>
<li>1/4 white onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>2 plum tomatoes, chopped</li>
<li>splash of white wine</li>
<li>pinch of dried crushed red pepper flakes</li>
<li>salt and pepper to taste</li>
<li>8 ounces orecchiette</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Preparation</em><br />
Heat olive oil over medium heat. Saute onions until they are translucent, about 5 minutes. Add the tomatoes and cook for 5 minutes. Add garlic and cook for 1 &#8211; 2 minutes. Add the ground turkey and the wine, breaking up the turkey with a wooden spatula. Cook until the turkey is no longer pink. Add red pepper flakes, and season with salt and fresh cracked pepper. Meanwhile, bring a large pot of salted water to a boil. Add broccolini and cook for approximately 1 minute. Strain broccolini, and cook the orecchiette in the same pot of boiling water according to the package directions. Drain, reserving 1/2 cup of the cooking liquid. Add the broccolini, the orecchiette, and the cooking water to the ground turkey mixture and stir. Serve with freshly grated Parmesan cheese.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/recipe-sunday-orecchiette-with-ground-turkey-and-broccolini/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.421 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-17 07:04:27 -->
