<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:04:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part I</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-i/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-i/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xanga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122404</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122404"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Basically, I hate my boyfriend&#8217;s ex/now BFF. I hate that she makes pie-eyes at him whenever they are together, I hate that they make secret little plans for dinner (and gods know how often because they are secret plans), I hate that she has slept with him, I really hate that she likes to remind me of this, I hate that she hugged me at Christmas, I hate that she is a vegetarian, I hate her hair because it looks dirty all the time, I hate that she smokes and encourages others to do so because she is too poor to buy her own cigarettes, I hate that I have to endure stories about how hard it is for her to buy clothes because it is just so impossible to find a size zero. I cannot think of a redeeming quality.</p>
<p>Sure, this all makes me sound like a jealous psycho girlfriend, but so what? There are things that can be done to mitigate my admittedly strong reactions. Like, oh, not making secret plans to spend time at each other’s houses. Oh, and not fucking touching me. And stop telling me about the damn vibrator that he bought you whenever it was that you were fucking. Because I cannot stand to hear that story one more time.</p>
<p>You know what the worst part is? I’ve actually brought all of this crap up. To real people, including the ones concerned, not just the internets. (Ok, not to her, I’d rather hug a live snake) And do you think anything has changed? No. Not one fucking iota.</p></blockquote>
<p>It seems obvious that many of journal entries are about boyfriends and girlfriends, but this one gets to the heart of the issue of that whore of an ex girlfriend. You were never going to like her but does she have to be such a bitch about the fact that he still hangs around with her?</p>
<p>Sure, a more experienced person would just tell him that what he&#8217;s doing isn&#8217;t cool and you&#8217;d appreciate it if he&#8217;d put some distance between the two of them. But the online journals of your youth aren&#8217;t the place of people who have the emotional maturity to say something like that out loud to another human being, they&#8217;re about blind rage.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-i/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-69/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-69/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122438</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Come on. You know you want to. Photo is mine, all mine.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Come on. <span id="more-122438"></span></p>
<p>You know you want to.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oc-P8oDuS0Q" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Photo is mine, all mine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-69/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project Runway Season 11 Episode 9 Live Blog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-9-live-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-9-live-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CaptainSnarky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, this show was rainin&#8217; men! The Thunder From Down Under, an Aussie male band of stripping brothers, showed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-117875" alt="project-runway-26" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a>Last week, this show was rainin&#8217; men! The Thunder From Down Under, an Aussie male band of stripping brothers, showed up to have the remaining designers make some tear-away looks for them.</p>
<p>Children, the resulting looks were HOT MESSES, but no one was paying attention, as we were all ogling the man flesh parading around in front of us. I think someone got sent home, but for the life of me, I can&#8217;t remember who.<span id="more-122378"></span></p>
<p>Tonight, the designers apparently get real (pissy) with each other. I miss the Thunder From Down Under.</p>
<p>Anyway, join us in the comments as we snark, drink, and snark some more about the hot messes parading as fashion!</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:PRLogo12.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-9-live-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Economics of Marine Biology&#8221; Community Season 4 Episode 7 Live Blog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/economics-of-marine-biology-community-season-4-episode-7-live-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/economics-of-marine-biology-community-season-4-episode-7-live-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ManchuCandidate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chevy Chase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dean Pelton tries to lure a potential rich student (aka whale) to college and he&#8217;s enlisted some of Greendale&#8217;s favorite [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Pierce_the_Dickish.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122390" alt="Pierce_the_Dickish" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Pierce_the_Dickish.jpg" width="350" height="402" /></a>Dean Pelton tries to lure a potential rich student (aka whale) to college and he&#8217;s enlisted some of Greendale&#8217;s favorite human beings (Britta, Annie and Jeff) to help him to the dismay of Pierce Hawthorne aka Pierce the insensitive/Pierce The Dickish/Grandpa The Flatulent. Meanwhile Abed makes a new fraternity (The Timelords of Gallifrey?) and Troy and Shirley take a Phys Ed class.</p>
<p>Sorry about the mix up last week. There was a post ready but I didn&#8217;t alert anyone in time.</p>
<p>Last week&#8217;s episode wasn&#8217;t bad. It wasn&#8217;t great, but it wasn&#8217;t bad. You can&#8217;t &#8220;Chang&#8221; a Chang as Chang is still the same crazy ass mad dictator dressed as a Cuban Cab Driver and working with someone (Dean Spreck?) to get back at Greendale.  Jeff became the pariah (again) due to his dickish behavior at trying to uncover what Chang is really up to while Abed&#8217;s cameras capture the goings on in all their glory.<span id="more-122385"></span></p>
<p>It was interesting to see the former Mrs Chang show up. I don&#8217;t know what voodoo or mad skillz besides Salsa Dancing that Ben Chang used to land her, but I am really curious to find out (although I do realize that it is TV land where anything is possible.)</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://images.wikia.com/community-sitcom/images/2/21/Pierce_the_Dickish.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
<p>8:02 &#8220;Keep Your Damn Hands of My Lets/Letz&#8221;</p>
<p>8:04 Drunken School Board Guys on recruiting:  Hookers! Blow! Hookers!</p>
<p>8:08 Half Pipes and Hash Pipes Class?</p>
<p>8:13 I&#8217;ll Never Go to a School that has a class taught by Ed Hardy</p>
<p>8:17 Role Reversal for Troy</p>
<p>8:18 Poor Magnitude</p>
<p>8:23 Chang in shorts.  Not good for your eyes.</p>
<p>8:30 Kicking Britta out of bed for eating &#8220;Springles&#8221;?  I dunno.  Let&#8217;s Chips would have to taste like Perfection for me to even think about doing that.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/economics-of-marine-biology-community-season-4-episode-7-live-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Breakers Movie Review</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/spring-breakers-movie-review/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/spring-breakers-movie-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jarrod</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring Breakers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Spring Break, y&#8217;all. &#8220;Spring Breakers&#8221; is sun tan oil, beer, drugs, and an MTV beach house all rolled into one [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spring Break, y&#8217;all.</p>
<p>&#8220;Spring Breakers&#8221; is sun tan oil, beer, drugs, and an MTV beach house all rolled into one nice, over-indulgent package. For some, this movie will remind them of their past lives as partying co-eds while others will watch on with their mouths agape like peeping toms given a glimpse into a life that they were never meant to see.<span id="more-122316"></span></p>
<p>Either way, the film is pleasant and unsettling all at the same time. The camera spends equal time lingering on gyrating hips, breasts, and sun-kissed skin as it does on blood, beer bellies, and methed out faces. It also highlights the trashiness that is Florida with or without the spring breakers that visit once a year.</p>
<p>It is equal parts &#8220;Enter The Void&#8221; and &#8220;Magic Mike&#8221; with voiceovers that provide the most subtle hints of foreshadowing. The actors do a great job capturing the lightness of spring break while barely acknowledging the treacherousness that lies beneath.  Selena Gomez&#8217;s character is the bible beater of the bunch and acts accordingly but the other characters continue to surprise throughout the film. Sure, they don&#8217;t have many lines but Ashley Benson and Vanessa Hudgens both prove that they are ready for bigger and better things than just tween movies and tv shows. Also,Rachel Korine makes a lasting impression as the fair weather bad girl. James Franco takes the next evolutionary step up from his character in &#8220;Pineapple Express.&#8221; He is Alien, a drug-dealer with a heart of gold and mind for mischief, has so many great moments that you almost forget about his sleaziness and want him to succeed.</p>
<p>The film is composed by Cliff Martinez (Drive, Contagion) and Skrillex whose music provides the perfect backdrop to the raucous proceedings. There are even a few random gunshots thrown in for good measure. Another &#8220;star&#8221; of the film is Britney Spears&#8217; music, some of the most memorable scenes in the movie include her songs &#8220;Everytime&#8221; and &#8220;&#8230;Baby, One More Time.&#8221; Both are worth the price of admission, alone.</p>
<p>After all the debauchery of the film, the one thing that did surprise me was the ending. It wasn&#8217;t that far fetched but definitely changed my thoughts about the whole movie.</p>
<p>Overall, I&#8217;d give the film an eight out of ten with a few eye rolls thrown in for good measure.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/842836">morgueFile</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/spring-breakers-movie-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Made That: French Bread Pizza</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/i-made-that-french-bread-pizza/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/i-made-that-french-bread-pizza/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122343</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last weekend GloriousShoes shared a link with a recipe for French Bread Pizza. Looked easy enough. I&#8217;ve made pizza from [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend GloriousShoes shared a link with a recipe for <a href="http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2013/03/the-best-french-bread-pizza-recipe.html">French Bread Pizza</a>. Looked easy enough. I&#8217;ve made pizza from scratch before, so I know the dough is the hard part. I did a quick run down of the ingredients: garlic, butter, olive oil, red pepper, oregano, cheese, tomatoes and a few simple other things. I knew this would be part of my dinner menu this week.<span id="more-122343"></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;m a doofus and ended up buying stewed tomatoes instead of crushed and decided to add Italian sausage. Fixing my stewed tomatoes was easy &#8211; I threw them in the food processor until they were the right consistency for pizza sauce. Rouse&#8217;s didn&#8217;t have any ground Italian sausage so I bought the brat kind and just took the casing off. No big deal &#8211; I&#8217;ve done this before. Cooking the sausage (heh) added a little bit of time to this recipe that probably would have only taken 30 minutes.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-beginning.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122351" alt="pizza beginning" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-beginning.jpg" width="550" height="387" /></a></p>
<p>Other than that it was a pretty easy process. Preheat the oven to 425º. Cut the French bread in half as if you were going to make a sandwich out of it. Mince the garlic, melt the butter and olive oil in a sautee pan. Cook the garlic until it&#8217;s soft, but don&#8217;t brown it. Throw in the oregano and red pepper flakes with the garlic. Once the garlic is soft, put in the parsley/basil mix and a good pinch of salt. Stir it a little bit and then remove from heat. You should squish the bread a little bit with a cookie sheet. I guess you don&#8217;t have to do this, but the bread might curl up a bit in the baking process.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-middle.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122355" alt="pizza middle" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-middle.jpg" width="500" height="667" /></a></p>
<p>You want to brush about half of this garlic goodness on the slices of bread, then put some cheese on each slice. Put this in the oven until the cheese is a little melty. Meanwhile, add the tomatoes to the rest of the garlic/butter mixture. Let this cook until the tomatoes have reduced the sauce is rich. Probably about 10-15 minutes. Once the sauce has reduced, put some on each bread slice. My layering went like this: sauce, meat, cheese. Maybe next time I&#8217;ll do sauce, cheese, and then meat.</p>
<p>Let this bake until the cheese has melted/browned to your liking. Let it cool a bit and boom. You&#8217;ve got dinner.</p>
<p><strong>Was this recipe easy?</strong> Pretty easy, yes. I complicated it a bit by adding sausage and screwing up with the tomatoes.<br />
<strong>How long did it take?</strong> It was probably 45 minutes from the time I started cooking the sausage until I was eating.<br />
<strong>How did it taste?</strong> Really good. Dare I say it was even better when I ate it for leftovers. I put the leftover pieces in a toaster oven and the bread was the perfect amount of crunchy.<br />
<strong>Would I make this again?</strong> Sure thing. This was really easy and quick. I&#8217;ll add it to my &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to spend a lot of time cooking dinner&#8221; list of things to make.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-final1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122365" alt="pizza-final1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-final1.jpg" width="600" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>All photos courtesy of clarity83.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/i-made-that-french-bread-pizza/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wakey wakey Don&#8217;t get arrested. Photo courtesy of boobookitteh.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122344" alt="Iceland" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/iceland.jpeg" width="505" height="242" /></a><br />
Wakey wakey <span id="more-122341"></span></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get arrested.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/S7_vH3H8LPI" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><i>Photo courtesy of boobookitteh</i>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wednesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/wednesday-open-thread-64/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/wednesday-open-thread-64/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122148</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Burp. Yuk yuk yuk Photo courtesy of TS.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Burp. <span id="more-122148"></span></p>
<p>Yuk yuk yuk</p>
<p><iframe width="450" height="253" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-Rot9uaVO8s" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><i>Photo courtesy of TS.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/wednesday-open-thread-64/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smash Liveblog Season 2 Episode 7 &#8220;Musical Chairs&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-7-musical-chairs/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-7-musical-chairs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 01:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hatewatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liveblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another Tuesday, another shitty episode of this shitty TV show. Turns out NBC has finally figured out what we&#8217;ve known [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Smash_Title_Card.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-119857" alt="Smash_Title_Card" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Smash_Title_Card.jpg" width="550" height="228" /></a></p>
<p>Another Tuesday, another shitty episode of this shitty TV show. Turns out NBC has finally figured out what we&#8217;ve known about this show all along and has decided to <a href="http://tvline.com/2013/03/15/smash-season-2-series-finale-spoilers/">move it to Saturdays</a> starting April 6. So we&#8217;ve got this week and then next to suffer through this together. The show&#8217;s showrunner, Josh  Safran says the season finale will also be the series finale. (h/t to DottieB for the info.)</p>
<p>Anywho &#8211; this week&#8217;s episode is called &#8220;Musical Chairs.&#8221; I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s about Jimmy Who going to IKEA to pick out some new furniture for his apartment.<span id="more-122328"></span></p>
<p>Photo: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Smash_Title_Card.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-7-musical-chairs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Picking Your Crass NCAA Bracket for Fun and Profit</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/picking-your-crass-ncaa-bracket-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/picking-your-crass-ncaa-bracket-for-fun-and-profit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 20:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Robert Travers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butthurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Important note: The Grand Inquisitor does not follow college ball, so she is relying on the wisdom of Crassers Past [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Important note: The Grand Inquisitor does not follow college ball, so she is relying on the wisdom of Crassers Past (St. Patrick&#8217;s Year) to get you started. You can sign up for Crasstalk Funderdome brackets <a href="http://crasstalkfunderdome.mayhem.cbssports.com/e?ttag=13_cbspaste" target="_blank">here</a>. The team  password is “indianasucks” (without the quotes).</em></p>
<p>Today is Christmas wrapped in the Super Bowl surrounded by endless waves of Kentucky Derby roses for gambling professionals, casinos, Hoboken wise guys, and offshore sports books. This is the day when the non-gamblers gamble, the day when grandmas, toddlers, the comatose and Nepalese Sherpas all gather round the television and fill out an NCAA basketball tournament bracket without knowing the difference between Duke and Duquesne or a chance in hell of actually winning the office, school or neighborhood pool.</p>
<p>And the pros &#8211;also that skeezy guy from Tech Support who runs this thing every year&#8211;are lining up to take your bracket and your money. The only time you&#8217;ll hear from them again is through a weekly email between now and Easter showing you and your colleagues just  badly your bracket is progressing.<span id="more-122315"></span>But that&#8217;s all for other years. Yes friends, as Jim Nantz would say, this year, the odds are on your side. This year, you have the upper hand. Because this year, you are reading Crasstalk&#8217;s Guide to Bracket Glory. And you will finally learn the Secrets of the Sherpas, at least when it comes to picking Kentucky or Kansas. (Hint: Sherpas inexplicably love Calipari. Who knew?)</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll begin with the Unbreakable Laws of Bracketology. Do not violate them, it will only make you look silly. Sherpas will laugh at you in the breakroom. Well, they will if your office is at Everest Base Camp. Not many Sherpas in Midtown.</p>
<p>Here are ten simple rules to get you into April with a viable bracket:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do not pick a 15 or 16 seed to win a game. No 16 seed has ever won, only four 15 seeds have ever won even one game in the tournament.</li>
<li>Move all four Number 1 seeds to the Sweet Sixteen. Every now and then a Number 1 will lose the first weekend, but it&#8217;s rare.</li>
<li>Favor teams with senior guards. Choose schools with starting juniors and seniors generally. Mature leadership wins championships. Even a team with a great one-and-done player needs seniors.</li>
<li>In the first round pick at least one, but no more than two, number 12 seeds to knock off a number 5 seed. Just do it.</li>
<li>Go chalk from the Sweet 16 in. Pick the higher seeds. You won&#8217;t be sorry.</li>
<li>Definitely put one or two Number 1 seeds in your Final Four, but not all four number 1&#8242;s. That&#8217;s only happened once.</li>
<li>Pick Duke. They always win. I know, I know, we all hate them&#8211;and that school has <em>issues</em>. Real issues. But winning basketball games is not one of them. You&#8217;ll never go broke betting on Duke to win.</li>
<li>For your national champion, pick a school that has won it all prior to 2012. March Madness is like the NBA, not that many different champions. Since 1991, only four schools&#8211;Arkansas, Arizona, Syracuse, and Maryland&#8211;are one-time champions. All the rest&#8211;the Dukes, UNC&#8217;s, UConns, and Floridas&#8211;have won at least two.</li>
<li>Although it is popular, do not pick a winner in a toss-up game based on the school&#8217;s colors or who&#8217;s mascot could beat up the other. (Panthers eat Wildcats. Lions eat Cardinals. Cannibals eat Colonials, that sort of thing.) These are popular methods, but wrong.</li>
<li>What you want to do is pick the school a favorite ex-girlfriend attended, or pick against the school where that whore who dumped you in the Summer of 2005 went to grad school. Also, if a college accepted you, but you chose not to go there, pick them. They&#8217;re OK. If you applied and they denied you, screw &#8216;em. Out in Round Two. Even if they are a Number 1 seed. You have standards, damn it, and your essays kicked ass. Must have been some bullshit affirmative action thing. And those C&#8217;s in science and math. Trippin&#8217; high school teachers. But still&#8211;out in the second round.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t ever pick a directional school (Southeast Missouri State, Middle Tennessee, Inside Out Western North Dakota). They will only break your heart. Like that whore from 2005.</li>
<li>Do not select a school with two names. No George Masons, James Madisons, John Harvards, Dan Dartmouths or Oral Roberts. And nay to Charlie Sheen A&amp;M, no matter how much they&#8217;ve been winning.</li>
<li>Catholics over Protestants. They&#8217;ve been playing basketball longer and take it more seriously than anything other than the Eucharist itself or Friday night bingo. So yes to Notre Dame, St Johns, Xavier or Georgetown&#8211;no to SMU, TCU or Liberty. Not that any of them will be playing this year. But this is a good rule for future reference.</li>
<li>Finally, the most important rule of all: Choosing pro or con on your beloved alma mater. If your school is a 15 or 16 seed, I&#8217;m sorry, there is nothing I can do and you must kill them off in the first round. If they are a 13 or 14 seed, you have to go Dr Phil-style tough love and do the same. Out. Think of the laughing Sherpas. But&#8230;if your school is a 12 seed or higher, then quietly hum your fight song and take them to the Sweet Sixteen. Why not, you still owe them $80,000 in student loans, it can&#8217;t hurt. If your alma mater is a Top Four seed&#8211;<em>unless </em>it is also a Protestant school up against Catholics, from a state Romney won, directional, or that school that whore attended&#8211;then pick them to win the National Championship. Someone&#8217;s gonna win it. Let&#8217;s just hope it&#8217;s you and not Duke. Er, I mean, you and not <em>them</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Image via <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Rob_Jones_dunk_02.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/picking-your-crass-ncaa-bracket-for-fun-and-profit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.374 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-22 10:09:37 -->
