<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:15:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Theatre Notes With Botswana: The Acro-Cats Take Atlanta</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/theatre-notes-with-botswana-the-acro-cats-take-atlanta/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/theatre-notes-with-botswana-the-acro-cats-take-atlanta/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Botswana Meat Commission FC</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acro-cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat circus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performing cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training cats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122521</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to this installment of Theatre Notes with Botswana, where I take you inside the world of the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/acro-cats1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122529" alt="acro-cats" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/acro-cats1.jpg" width="600" height="543" /></a><em>Hello and welcome to this installment of Theatre Notes with Botswana, where I take you inside the world of the staged drama and offer my own critical perspectives on the neo-modernist theater scene. </em></p>
<p>You may not be aware, but since the mid 1960s, there has been an alternative movement <del>afoot</del> a-paw in the theater. This new approach fought against all the conventional norms of the theater establishment. Norms like &#8220;you should use people, not cats, as actors&#8221; and &#8220;your actors should try to stay on the stage and not run underneath an audience member&#8217;s chair in the middle of the show&#8221; were suddenly under assault by these young and hungry insurgents of the New Felinists movement. <span id="more-122521"></span></p>
<p>Today this formerly fringe movement is now part of the mainstream. Human actors are now considered old wave and today&#8217;s stars of Broadway and off-Broadway (and off-off-off-off-Broadway) are paid in catnip treats. This trend parallels changes throughout our society, where the cat is now the dominant species of all internet-based media including videos, photos, gifs and Cat Fancy profile pieces. It&#8217;s a cat actor&#8217;s world &#8212; we&#8217;re just offering treats in it.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no further proof of the ascendancy of the cat-based theater than <a href="http://www.circuscats.com/">The Acro-Cats&#8217; recent three day run in Atlanta</a>, where I was lucky enough to see the Acro-Cats live. And I do mean lucky &#8212; the titans of the Cat Stage sold out every show (prompting producers to add last-minute late shows over the weekend). The traditional distance between the avant-garde and the mainstream no longer exists. Art is dead. Death is art. Now please give the Mr. Buggles his salmon kitty treat before he claws our eyeballs out.</p>
<p>The Acro-Cats will shatter your preconceived notions about the dynamic space between the actor and the audience. For example at numerous times during the show, the cats exercise their free will as cats and suddenly bolt into the audience. Also, during the show I saw Sunday, the star Tuna decided to climb up a 15-foot ladder that was resting against a wall backstage. She spent most of the rest of the performance trying to figure out how to get down.</p>
<p>The Acro-Cats, for all their bluster, are no mere infantile revolutionaries of the stage. They are true professionals. They perform dozens of amazing tricks. They push shopping cars and roll balls across a rope and climb. And they fucking love climbing. Because they&#8217;re cats, goddammit. At one point the Acro-Cats actually compete in a game of bowling against a rather cute and smiley groundhog. This is the sort of inter-species recreational activity that would have scandalized audiences in a more conservative time, but in today&#8217;s rough and tumble cat theater world, audiences demand such innovation.</p>
<p>Does all this mean that I am ready to repudiate my past ideological assumptions about using cats as actors? Only so far as I must repudiate all theater movements that refuse to acknowledge the fact that cats can now do all forms of entertainment better than humans. A perfect example of this came during the show&#8217;s final act &#8212; a musical ensemble performance by &#8220;The Rock Cats.&#8221; The cats (plus one chicken named Gregory Peck) play all their own instruments. They refuse to bow to the simulacrum of today&#8217;s lip-synched, pre-fab pop music. Instead they play all their own instruments and weave a sound using dissonance and non-Western time signatures that reminds this critic of the visceral pleasures of Stockhausen and Glass. When the fluffy white kitty started playing the drums I felt I was ready to shuffle off this mortal coil.</p>
<p>So in conclusion&#8230; Cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats.</p>
<p><em>Photo taken by a friend of mine. All rights reserved. Or something.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/theatre-notes-with-botswana-the-acro-cats-take-atlanta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part II</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-ii/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-ii/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122418"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Mon, Feb. 27th, 2006, 10:59 pm &#8211; Stop the world, I&#8217;d like to get off</p>
<p>Last week, a guy I knew in high school died. It was very odd, mainly cause at the funeral, I realized that I didn&#8217;t know him as well as I thought I did. There were also alot of people that I haven&#8217;t seen in a long time, whom I felt the same about. But it was still good to see them, only it felt bad feeling good about that. I&#8217;ve been told that it&#8217;s not a bad thing and it&#8217;s actually good that we connected. Now if I can just bother to write them e-mails. . .</p>
<p>So that ended last week, on a rather . . . &#8220;um. . que?&#8221; note, only to have me work all day Saturday. For some reason I came home and slept for 5 hours, thinking &#8220;Hey! I&#8217;ll disco nap, clean, and go shake my ass at SoBe cause I need it!!&#8221; Didn&#8217;t happen. I woke up, wandered around, and watched some bad adaptation of a Jane Austen novel and went back to bed.</p>
<p>I checked out my calander, and it looks like life is going to be hell during march. Hopefully not at work, because the Skanky Bitch Whore has been moved. But she still comes up and tries to make scenes. HAHAHAHA&gt; YOU ARE A BITCH AND SHOULD DIE!!!! *calm* One of the fat ladies is getting bari surgery this week, so I&#8217;m hoping she can stop making comments about how I&#8217;m fat and haven&#8217;t lost any weight. Bullshit. I&#8217;ve had plenty of people comment on it. I just don&#8217;t crash diet like she does. And I&#8217;m trying to make an effort not to antagonize the other bitch. I was rather nice, for the most part, during the office clean up. I asked about everything, well, except when the manager came up and TOLD me to throw things away, but that&#8217;s the manager. Therapist tried to pass it off as I should have told her anyway, but . . . who is she kidding? She would have just tried to throw a wrench in it anyway. I am really over her bullshit. Maybe if I close my eyes and ignore her, she&#8217;ll go away.</p>
<p>All in all, I&#8217;m suffering from something akin to senioritis and this dreaded fear that I&#8217;ve fucked everything up, and that I&#8217;m 25, and it&#8217;s too late to start over.</p>
<p>Bullshit.</p></blockquote>
<p>Bullshit indeed. That skank needed to get told.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-ii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/monday-open-thread-72/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/monday-open-thread-72/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christ It's Monday Again]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music leonard washington would like]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yeah, it&#8217;s gonna be like that. Stay strong, kids. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/800px-SS_Austria_shipwreck1.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/800px-SS_Austria_shipwreck1.jpg" alt="800px-SS_Austria_shipwreck" width="769" height="396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122544" /></a></p>
<p>Yeah, it&#8217;s gonna be like that. Stay strong, kids.<span id="more-122507"></span></p>
<p><object width="500" height="375"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/MJCaFe1yamg?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/MJCaFe1yamg?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="500" height="375" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:SS_Austria_shipwreck.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/monday-open-thread-72/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recipe Sunday: Homemade Teriyaki Sauce</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-homemade-teriyaki-sauce/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-homemade-teriyaki-sauce/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Launie K.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe sunday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122480</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago my husband and I went out to dinner, which is a rarity for us. I write [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/teriyaki-sauce-crass-final.jpg"><img alt="teriyaki-sauce-crass-final" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/teriyaki-sauce-crass-final.jpg" width="1024" height="512" /></a></p>
<p>A few weeks ago my husband and I went out to dinner, which is a rarity for us. I write about food for paychecks, so I cook several times a day. Although what we have in the fridge by the end of the day may not make sense as a full meal, it&#8217;s generally what we stick with.</p>
<p>“What&#8217;s for dinner?”</p>
<p>“Well, we have tilapia piccata, cranberry maple granola and fresh barbecue sauce.”</p>
<p>“Sounds good.”<span id="more-122480"></span>So, when we went out for dinner, I ordered my favorite restaurant meal &#8211; teriyaki chicken. As we sat at the bar nursing drinks waiting to be seated, it occurred to me that I&#8217;d never made teriyaki sauce. When I told my husband that, he said, “It&#8217;s easy. It&#8217;s equal parts brown sugar, soy sauce, water and a ton of ginger.”</p>
<p>Well, why hadn&#8217;t I made that before? It couldn&#8217;t sound easier.</p>
<p>Then I made it Monday night and we devoured it along with chorizo lasagna and chocolate covered mango. (Again, we eat a unique conglomeration of food at the end of the day.) Then I made it again on Wednesday. When Friday rolled around I made it again. We couldn&#8217;t get enough of the sweet, salty and gingery sauce on chicken.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s so simple to make that it&#8217;s perfect for an insanely fast weeknight meal. And it goes well with just about anything.</p>
<p>Trust me on that.</p>
<p><b>Homemade Teriyaki Sauce </b></p>
<p>Serves 2.</p>
<p>Ingredients:</p>
<ul>
<li>½ cup of soy sauce</li>
<li>½ cup of brown sugar (light or dark)</li>
<li>½ cup of water</li>
<li>1 inch of grated ginger</li>
</ul>
<p>Instructions:</p>
<p>Combine all of the ingredients in a small saucepan and bring to a boil. Turn the heat down and let simmer until the sauce has reduced by half and resembles a syrup.</p>
<p>To make teriyaki chicken, take 2 tablespoons of the sauce and place it in a bag with chicken breasts. Marinate for half an hour and bake or grill. Serve with sauce.</p>
<p>(Photo by Launie K.)<em> </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-homemade-teriyaki-sauce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-86/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-86/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colleen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Crassholes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crassholes. <span id="more-122463"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/mxtFBqRThTQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-86/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-91/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-91/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Saturday. The Promise from Sam Molleur on Vimeo. Image via WIkipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Saturday. <span id="more-122449"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/57775588" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/57775588">The Promise</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/sammolleur">Sam Molleur</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Drymoreomys_albimaculatus_002.jpg">WIkipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-91/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>These Animals Are Illegal to Keep as Pets in New York City</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/these-animals-are-illegal-to-keep-as-pets-in-new-york-city/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/these-animals-are-illegal-to-keep-as-pets-in-new-york-city/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pigs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122453</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The AP has a deeply pun laden story about families who flaunt the law by keeping even toed ungulates, pigs [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pet_pig.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122456" alt="pet_pig" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pet_pig.jpg" width="350" height="233" /></a>The AP has a deeply pun laden <a href="http://www.sfgate.com/news/us/article/New-Yorkers-boldly-flout-law-to-keep-pigs-4375443.php">story</a> about families who flaunt the law by keeping even toed ungulates, pigs if you must, even though they are banned by the New York City health code.</p>
<p>To help potential pet owners in New York City determine which side of the law they fall on, here is the complete list of animals that are illegal to own in New York City. <span id="more-122453"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>All dogs other than domesticated dogs (Canis familiaris), including, but not limited to, wolf, fox, coyote, hyena, dingo, jackal, dhole, fennec, raccoon dog, zorro, bush dog, aardwolf, cape hunting dog and any hybrid offspring of a wild dog and domesticated dog.</li>
<li>All cats other than domesticated cats (Felis catus), including, but not limited to, lion, tiger, leopard, ocelot, jaguar, puma, panther, mountain lion, cheetah, wild cat, cougar, bobcat, lynx, serval, caracal, jaguarundi, margay and any hybrid offspring of a wild cat and domesticated cat.</li>
<li>All bears, including polar, grizzly, brown and black bear.</li>
<li>All fur bearing mammals of the family Mustelidae, including, but not limited to, weasel, marten, mink, badger, ermine, skunk, otter, pole cat, zorille, wolverine, stoat and ferret.</li>
<li>All Procyonidae: All raccoon (eastern, desert, ring-tailed cat), kinkajou, cacomistle, cat-bear, panda and coatimundi.</li>
<li>All carnivorous mammals of the family Viverridae, including , but not limited to, civet, mongoose, genet, binturong, fossa, linsang and suricate.</li>
<li>All bats (Chiroptera).</li>
<li>All non-human primates, including, but not limited to, monkey, ape, chimpanzee, gorilla and lemur.</li>
<li>All squirrels (Sciuridae).</li>
<li>Reptiles (Reptilia): All Helodermatidae (gila monster and Mexican beaded lizard); all front-fanged venomous snakes, even if devenomized, including, but not limited to, all Viperidae (viper, pit viper), all Elapidae (cobra, mamba, krait, coral snake), all Atractaspididae (African burrowing asp), all Hydrophiidae (sea snake), all Laticaudidae (sea krait); all venomous, mid-or rear-fanged, Duvernoy-glanded members of the family Colubridae, even if devenomized; any member, or hybrid offspring of the family Boidae, including, but not limited to, the common or green anaconda and yellow anaconda; any member of the family Pythonidae, including but not limited to the African rock python, Indian or Burmese python, Amethystine or scrub python; any member of the family Varanidae, including the white throated monitor, Bosc&#8217;s or African savannah monitor, Komodo monitor or dragon, Nile monitor, crocodile monitor, water monitor, Bornean earless monitor; any member of the family Iguanidae, including the green or common iguana; any member of the family Teiidae, including, but not limited to the golden, common, or black and white tegu; all members of the family Chelydridae, including snapping turtle and alligator snapping turtle; and all members of the order Crocodylia, including, but not limited to alligator, caiman and crocodile.</li>
<li>Birds and Fowl (Aves): All predatory or large birds, including, but not limited to, eagle, hawk, falcon, owl, vulture, condor, emu, rhea and ostrich; roosters, geese, ducks and turkeys.<br />
All venomous insects, including, but not limited to, bee, hornet and wasp.</li>
<li>Arachnida and Chilopoda: All venomous spiders, including, but not limited to, tarantula, black widow and solifugid; scorpion; all venomous arthropods including, but not limited to, centipede.</li>
<li>All large rodents (Rodentia), including, but not limited to, gopher, muskrat, paca, woodchuck, marmot, beaver, prairie dog, capybara, sewellel, viscacha, porcupine and hutia.</li>
<li>All even-toed ungulates (Artiodactyla) including, but not limited to, deer, antelope, sheep, giraffe and hippopotamus.</li>
<li>All odd-toed ungulates (Perissodactyla) other than domesticated horses (Equus caballus), including, but not limited to, zebra, rhinoceros and tapir.</li>
<li>All marsupials, including, but not limited to, Tasmanian devil, dasyure, bandicoot, kangaroo, wallaby, opossum, wombat, koala bear, cuscus, numbat and pigmy, sugar and greater glider.</li>
<li>Sea mammals (Cetacea, Pinnipedia and Sirenia), including, but not limited to, dolphin, whale, seal, sea lion and walrus.</li>
<li>All elephants (Proboscides)</li>
<li>All hyrax (Hydracoidea).</li>
<li>All pangolin (Pholidota).</li>
<li>All sloth and armadillo (Edentata).</li>
<li>Insectivorous mammals (Insectivora): All aardvark (Tubildentata), anteater, shrew, otter shrew, gymnure, desman, tenrec, mole and hedge hog.<br />
Gliding lemur (Dermoptera).</li>
</ul>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.nyc.gov/html/doh/downloads/pdf/zoo/zoo-animal-healthcode.pdf">NYC Health Code</a> / Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexyo1968/5237333618/">Flickr</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/these-animals-are-illegal-to-keep-as-pets-in-new-york-city/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part I</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-i/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-i/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xanga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122404</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122404"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Basically, I hate my boyfriend&#8217;s ex/now BFF. I hate that she makes pie-eyes at him whenever they are together, I hate that they make secret little plans for dinner (and gods know how often because they are secret plans), I hate that she has slept with him, I really hate that she likes to remind me of this, I hate that she hugged me at Christmas, I hate that she is a vegetarian, I hate her hair because it looks dirty all the time, I hate that she smokes and encourages others to do so because she is too poor to buy her own cigarettes, I hate that I have to endure stories about how hard it is for her to buy clothes because it is just so impossible to find a size zero. I cannot think of a redeeming quality.</p>
<p>Sure, this all makes me sound like a jealous psycho girlfriend, but so what? There are things that can be done to mitigate my admittedly strong reactions. Like, oh, not making secret plans to spend time at each other’s houses. Oh, and not fucking touching me. And stop telling me about the damn vibrator that he bought you whenever it was that you were fucking. Because I cannot stand to hear that story one more time.</p>
<p>You know what the worst part is? I’ve actually brought all of this crap up. To real people, including the ones concerned, not just the internets. (Ok, not to her, I’d rather hug a live snake) And do you think anything has changed? No. Not one fucking iota.</p></blockquote>
<p>It seems obvious that many of journal entries are about boyfriends and girlfriends, but this one gets to the heart of the issue of that whore of an ex girlfriend. You were never going to like her but does she have to be such a bitch about the fact that he still hangs around with her?</p>
<p>Sure, a more experienced person would just tell him that what he&#8217;s doing isn&#8217;t cool and you&#8217;d appreciate it if he&#8217;d put some distance between the two of them. But the online journals of your youth aren&#8217;t the place of people who have the emotional maturity to say something like that out loud to another human being, they&#8217;re about blind rage.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-i/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-69/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-69/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122438</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Come on. You know you want to. Photo is mine, all mine.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Come on. <span id="more-122438"></span></p>
<p>You know you want to.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oc-P8oDuS0Q" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Photo is mine, all mine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-69/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project Runway Season 11 Episode 9 Live Blog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-9-live-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-9-live-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CaptainSnarky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, this show was rainin&#8217; men! The Thunder From Down Under, an Aussie male band of stripping brothers, showed [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-117875" alt="project-runway-26" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a>Last week, this show was rainin&#8217; men! The Thunder From Down Under, an Aussie male band of stripping brothers, showed up to have the remaining designers make some tear-away looks for them.</p>
<p>Children, the resulting looks were HOT MESSES, but no one was paying attention, as we were all ogling the man flesh parading around in front of us. I think someone got sent home, but for the life of me, I can&#8217;t remember who.<span id="more-122378"></span></p>
<p>Tonight, the designers apparently get real (pissy) with each other. I miss the Thunder From Down Under.</p>
<p>Anyway, join us in the comments as we snark, drink, and snark some more about the hot messes parading as fashion!</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:PRLogo12.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-9-live-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.388 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-25 10:20:49 -->
