<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:00:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-92/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-92/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122682</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That sounds good. I&#8217;ll have that. EAT from Rick Mereki on Vimeo. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That sounds good. I&#8217;ll have that.<span id="more-122682"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/27243869?color=ffffff" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/27243869">EAT</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/rickmereki">Rick Mereki</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/651218">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-92/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Nature: The River</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/adventures-in-nature-the-river/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/adventures-in-nature-the-river/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ihatediamonds</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misspent Youth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Great Outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Sports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122806</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Summer of 2008: Bellevue, WA I was home after spending the last nine months traveling around the United States and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/640px-Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-122810" alt="640px-Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/640px-Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" /></a>Summer of 2008: Bellevue, WA</p>
<p>I was home after spending the last nine months traveling around the United States and Canada and working in an office full of my fellow 20-something travelers, booking next year&#8217;s adventures. We were a restless bunch. Constantly inventing games and contests to alleviate the boredom of spending eight hours in neighboring cubicles.<span id="more-122806"></span></p>
<p>One day, our ringleader suggested we all go tubing after work one afternoon. A day, in high summer, in the the Seattle-area, goes on until about 10pm, so there&#8217;s plenty of time in the evening for adventures.</p>
<p>Over the next week, we voted on locations. None of us were particularly outdoorsy or had any experience traversing the many major and minor waterways within a 30 minute drive from the comfortable suburb of Bellevue, but debate we did. We settled on the Tolt River, a tributary of the Snoqualmie River, about a forty minute drive into the foothills of the neighboring Cascade mountains. A couple days before the trip, three of us took a trip to a sporting goods store to procure inner tubes. Imagining that this would be a leisurely trip, down a lazy river, our purchases were geared more for style than durability or practicality. One friend, the weakest swimmer of the bunch, bought a flying saucer tube that came complete with built in water gun.</p>
<p>The day of our adventure was a rare, hot day in the Northwest and we were all excited to hit the river. We escaped en masse a bit early and headed east. Our caravan stopped in a tiny one stoplight town just before the turn off for the mountain road, to pick up an obscene amount of beer and cigarettes for spliffs. The dirty looks were plentiful. Rural Washingtonians don&#8217;t like city kids using their towns as rec rooms.</p>
<p>The drive up the hill should have tipped us off that this wasn&#8217;t going to be a lazy, warm trip down a calm water way. We could see brief glimpses of white water out of our windows and it was a fairly steep incline. But dumb people are dumb and once we arrived at what someone in the lead car randomly determined to be a good distance from where we left our base car, we all bounced out, eager to get going.</p>
<p>The water was cold. Not just cold but, &#8220;Fuck, this may be an incredibly terrible idea, oh jesus&#8230; FUCK&#8221; cold. Later research turned up that the Tolt was fed almost exclusively by glacier run-off. We slowly made our way in, no one wanting to be the one who cried reasonableness. You could tell from the rocky, steep bank, that made a terrible entrance point, the water was moving swiftly. My best friend Joe* was the first in and the water promptly took him with his t-shirt wrapped chicly around his head, expensive sunglasses perched on his nose, cigarette behind his ear, and his fancy tube filled with beer and flipped him ass over head and tangled hi tube in branches lining the far bank. I&#8217;ve never laughed so hard. He lost everything to the river and basically had to gnaw his tube free. By time he made his bedraggled way back into his tube, the rest of us were on our way.</p>
<p>It got real around the first bend.</p>
<p>None of us thought about packing life jackets or helmet and I was incredibly aware that at least one of us was an incredibly weak swimmer, and that person also had the flotation devise that was least equipped to deal with even slightly rough water and we were facing what looked like possibly a class two rapid directly ahead.</p>
<p>Though my raft was comically not suited for the task ahead, it was at least small enough that I could get enough of my arms in the water to paddle and steer. My girlfriends who had purchased bigger, fancier tubes were not so lucky. There was a lot of screaming and shouting. A lot of &#8220;Use your legs!&#8221; &#8220;Fuck!&#8221; when someone would slam into a submerged part of a boulder they thought they had avoided.</p>
<p>We all made it to the other side. Luckily our weak swimmer had somehow ended up flush against the far bank had had missed the worst of it. Everyone who wore flip flops into the water was now barefoot. The water was plaid now. We managed to scrounge up a beer for everyone and we all guzzled, relieved and a bit giddy. If only we knew what lay ahead in two bends.</p>
<p>This set of rapids was definitely a two. A tough two. A ton of boulders, lots of churn spots. And it came on quickly. I got caught on a boulder early and was bounced out of my tube. I was wearing Keens which had a thick rubber toe and as I quickly got sucked down the rapids away from my tube they actually provided a useful buffer, until I got stuck in a spot of churning water and my thick, rubber covered toe got caught in between two rocks. I&#8217;m a strong swimmer and I don&#8217;t panic in water, but I remember very clearly thinking that I was going to die. Then, of course, I managed to kick my foot free and somehow made it to the end and found my tube that someone had freed from the boulder.</p>
<p>There was no more beer to celebrate with or really any will to celebrate. Our weak swimmer was doubled up with one of the guys and everyone looked like they had also had their own moment with death and we still had one major hurdle to go. Our exit point was right at the point where the Tolt fed into the Snoqualmie. The water was fast and you had to bail and swim for the sandy bank fairly quickly or end up in the Snoqualmie which fed the eponymous fall not too far away. We lost some rafts, but everyone made it out safely.</p>
<p>While driving down the hill towards home, exhausted and shaken, we saw several emergency vehicles heading the opposite direction, sirens blaring.</p>
<p>&#8230;&#8230;</p>
<p>Later that night, while recovering with soup, I saw an ad for the local news that made me stay awake for the broadcast.  The second story was about a drowning. Three guys had decided to go tubing on the Tolt River just like us that day. They must have only been an hour or so  ahead of us. One of them didn&#8217;t make it out of the rapids.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.valleyrecord.com/news/27443774.html">Snoqualmie Valley Record</a></p>
<p>*Names changed to protect my fellow idiots.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03.jpg">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/adventures-in-nature-the-river/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flashback Friday: Foreigner Edition</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/flashback-friday-foreigner-edition/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/flashback-friday-foreigner-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[80s rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flashback Friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[why the mustache simon le bon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122777</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[No, not this Foreigner (well it could be), but any band or artist that came from beyond your own borders [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No, not this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=loWXMtjUZWM" target="_blank">Foreigner</a> (well it could be), but any band or artist that came from beyond your own borders and took your musical heart by storm. For Americans, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WHuRusAlw-Y" target="_blank">British invasion</a> hasn&#8217;t really stopped, though it seems to ebb and flow. The lads from Madness sent me crashing through my living room dancing to this many afternoons watching MTV after school.</p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/KwIe_sjKeAY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><br />
<span id="more-122777"></span></p>
<p>But it was my then future husband, Simon Le Bon, who sealed my love for English rock boys. I nearly broke my neck <a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MR.gif" target="_blank">dancing</a> to their music.</p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/18xwfGTgVRc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/flashback-friday-foreigner-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Allan J. Eastman, Aged 19</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Karyn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Respect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122626</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 29th is Vietnam Veterans Day.  It marks the day the last American combat troops were finally withdrawn from Vietnam, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-122629" alt="Vietnam" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Vietnam-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">March 29th is Vietnam Veterans Day.  It marks the day the last American combat troops were finally withdrawn from Vietnam, forty years ago.</span></p>
<p>Well, not all of them. 1600 troops are still officially missing in Vietnam.</p>
<p>I grew up with Vietnam hanging over my family. My grandmother was a Gold Star Mother, which is what the government calls you when you&#8217;ve lost a child in war. She never rode in the Veterans Day parades on that sad float with all the other mothers in Belmont, Massachusetts (not Mitt Romney&#8217;s side of town) who had lost their sons. But Uncle Allan&#8217;s name is etched in granite in the town square. <span id="more-122626"></span></p>
<p>My uncle, <a href="http://www.vvmf.org/thewall/Wall_Id_No=14521">Allan John Eastman</a>, was born in 1950. My grandmother and mother always spoke of him as a good boy, a saint. But there were stories. He famously &#8216;borrowed&#8217; an MTA bus left idling by a driver who stopped for a break and took it for a joyride up Trapelo Road towards Watertown, taking off down the side streets before the cops could catch him. Every time I ride the #71 bus out of Harvard Square, I imagine him giggling his ass off, running for home.</p>
<p>He enlisted in the Army and was sent out.</p>
<p>Uncle Allan was shot and died of malaria on November 9, 1969.  He was 19.</p>
<p>I finally got to Washington to see Uncle Allan&#8217;s name on<a href="http://thewall-usa.com/information.asp"> The Vietnam Veterans Memorial</a> a few years ago.  If you&#8217;ve never seen The Wall, it&#8217;s extraordinary.  It&#8217;s sweeping and dark and seems to go on forever, like that war did. There are 58,272 names engraved in the black granite. It seems impossible to find the person you&#8217;re looking for, but there are people there to help. Uncle Allan&#8217;s name is on Panel 16W, Row 50.</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">I touched his name, and told Uncle Allan I hoped he knew there were still people who remembered him. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Jesus,&#8221; said the man who helped me find him.  &#8221;To go all that way, and die at 19.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vietnam_Memorial_reflection.jpg">photo courtesy wikicommons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Put on your red shoes and dance the blues. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Put on your red shoes and dance the blues.<span id="more-122677"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/N4d7Wp9kKjA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/213072">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project Runway Season 11 Episode 10 Live Blog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-10-live-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-10-live-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CaptainSnarky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liveblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122737</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Darlings, we are at it again! Sadly, there were no hot men to help us through the wretched excess that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-117875" alt="project-runway-26" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a>Darlings, we are at it again! Sadly, there were no hot men to help us through the wretched excess that is this season of Project Runway.</p>
<p>Last week, the challenge demanded the designers produce ready-to-wear looks for Lord &amp; Taylor. The winning design will be featured by Lord &amp; Taylor and sold for way more than it&#8217;s actually worth! Of course, you know what that means&#8230;</p>
<p>Michelle won. Again. I hate everything.</p>
<p>Well, we&#8217;re at episode 10, and I&#8217;m pretty sure that the producers have demanded that the drama quotient be upped significantly. Let us snark in the comments!<span id="more-122737"></span></p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:PRLogo12.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-10-live-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Free is Your State?</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-free-is-your-state/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-free-is-your-state/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jason</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Going Galt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Think Tanks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122714</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You may be shocked to discover that your freedoms are being oppressed right now as you read this. This morning, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/eagle.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-122726 alignleft" alt="eagle" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/eagle.gif" width="384" height="288" /></a>You may be shocked to discover that your freedoms are being oppressed right now as you read this.</p>
<p>This morning, Twitter was buzzing about the Mercatus Center&#8217;s latest rankings of <a href="http://freedominthe50states.org">Freedom in the 50 States</a>. Rounding out the top 5 slots in descending order are Oklahoma, New Hampshire, Tennessee, and South Dakota. And the number one MOST FREE state according to this year&#8217;s rankings? The great shining beacon on the hill known as North Dakota! That&#8217;s right. North Dakota. <span id="more-122714"></span><a href="http://freedominthe50states.org/overall/north-dakota">As Mercatus explains:</a></p>
<blockquote><p>North Dakota, according to the freedom index, is the freest state in the United States. It scores exceptionally well on regulatory and fiscal policy. Moreover, North Dakota scores slightly above average on personal freedom. It is also the state that improved the most over the last decade. &#8230;</p>
<p><strong>North Dakota scores well in a few personal freedom areas but has much room for improvement.</strong> Gun control laws are fairly relaxed. Alcohol regulations are light, while tax rates on beer and wine are average and spirits taxes are fairly low. Cigarette taxes are low but smoking bans exist, with exemptions for bars and restaurants. Motorists also operate with relative freedom, except for sobriety checkpoints and (most notably) the personal injury coverage mandate.</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasis mine.</p>
<p>If you are curious about the personal freedom factor, you have to keep in mind that the &#8220;Freedom Index&#8221; basically measures how low taxes are, how little businesses are regulated and how often you can walk around brandishing your six-shooter. <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2013/03/26/1776431/north-dakota-abortion-threat-trap/">So the freedom to not have your uterus heavily regulated by the state</a> doesn&#8217;t rank very high, sorry.</p>
<p>But what about the bottom of the list? Basically it is all the heathen liberal states. Despite securing its soda freedom, New York is ranked dead last. They sort of acknowledge you can gay marry there, but beyond that it is basically Stalin&#8217;s Russia in the eyes of the Freedom Index. At <a href="http://freedominthe50states.org/overall/california">#49 is of course California</a>, because it &#8220;heavily taxes and regulates its economy&#8221; and &#8220;aggressively interferes in the personal lives of its citizens&#8221;(!), for example:</p>
<blockquote><p>California was the first state to enact a smoking ban in restaurants and bars, but the ban is slightly less strict than those since adopted in other states. Travel freedom is low due to a primary seat belt law, motorcycle and bicycle helmet laws, a statewide primary-enforcement cell phone driving ban, an open-container law, and sobriety checkpoints. Little gambling is allowed.</p></blockquote>
<p>Personal travel freedom is party infringed by a seat belt law and sobriety checkpoints? The Freedom Index has some hard calculus to break.</p>
<p>As you would expect, all the least free states are also the wealthiest and most populated while the most free are basically where no one wants to live. There&#8217;s also a user-generated &#8220;Bachelor Party&#8221; category where Massachusetts(???) tops the list.</p>
<p>The Mercatus Center is a classic market-orientated think tank; meaning it takes a libertarian approach to everything while hating taxes and supporting policies that benefit the wealthy. The Mercatus Center is part of public university of George Mason and affiliated with the Koch family, who at the time of this writing haven&#8217;t relocated to their businesses to North Dakota.</p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/eagle%20gif?language=nl_NL">Charmingelements</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-free-is-your-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part V</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-v/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-v/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122434</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122434"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Wednesday, May 02, 2007</p>
<p>&#8220;For awhile, it feels like every step you take is driving you further into the ground. And then one day it shifts and you realize that actually you&#8217;re climbing up, slowly. Slowly. And things will be alright again.&#8221;</p>
<p>If all the hurt that is inside me were able to get out, I&#8217;m not sure what it would do to the world. Would it be like a smoky fog, eliminating the rest of the world from view? Or would it be a raging battle? Would it split the Earth in two? Or &#8212; and this is the worst yet &#8212; would it go utterly unnoticed?</p>
<p>The latter is what I fear most, and it is what I feel is most likely true.</p>
<p>No one notices. No one notices that I feel like the ground has been pulled out from underneath me. No one knows that I try so desperately to integrate myself that I do things that only a year ago would have shocked me. No one knows. And I&#8217;m not going to tell them, of course. It shows through once in awhile. People ask if I&#8217;m okay, what&#8217;s wrong &#8212; but I won&#8217;t tell them. I say I&#8217;m tired, or I&#8217;m stressed. I don&#8217;t say that maybe I&#8217;m dying.</p>
<p>And the worst is when people act like they know me well enough to understand. You don&#8217;t understand, you can&#8217;t possibly understand. Please don&#8217;t act like you do. I don&#8217;t care how much you&#8217;ve been through or who&#8217;s hurt you or what your best friend&#8217;s neighbor&#8217;s dog went through that you heard all about (that one&#8217;s a bit of a stretch). It just doesn&#8217;t matter to me.</p>
<p>The actress in me keeps me okay. She is able to put on a face, go through life being okay. She hides the hurt, hides the guilt, hides the shame.</p>
<p>But no one can hide it from me. No one can hide the way that I cry at anything again, no one can hide how my stomach drops out of my torso at the thought of it.</p>
<p>No amount of telling me that it&#8217;ll be okay is going to help this.</p>
<p>And so people really need to knock that off.</p>
<p>Really, if I were any more selfish than I am, I&#8217;d run away and hide. But I also know that people need me here, and people are counting on me, and that running away isn&#8217;t going to solve it. It&#8217;s going to follow me.</p>
<p>Probably it always will.</p>
<p>And the horrible thing is how I don&#8217;t even know what I want anymore.</p>
<p>I need the crystal ball back again &#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>Some day somebody&#8217;s gonna make you want to turn around and say goodbye. Until then baby are you going to let them hold you down and make you cry? Don&#8217;t you know? Don&#8217;t you know things can change? Things&#8217;ll go your way if you hold on for one more day. Can you hold on for one more day? Things&#8217;ll go your way. Hold on for one more day.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-v/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-65-2/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-65-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122563</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey there, good looking. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey there, good looking.<span id="more-122563"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/X85R4QeB-vc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/218805">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-65-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Ace Your Next Phone Interview</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-to-ace-your-next-phone-interview/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-to-ace-your-next-phone-interview/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Anita Manbadly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Servicey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn from my mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phone interviews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hidey ho, jobseekers! I&#8217;ve been on the prowl for &#8220;the perfect job&#8221; for the last few years, and I&#8217;ve been [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/The_work_of_the_Auxiliary_Territorial_Service_at_a_Mixed_Anti-aircraft_Battery_England_UK_1942_D8287.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122696" alt="The_work_of_the_Auxiliary_Territorial_Service_at_a_Mixed_Anti-aircraft_Battery,_England,_UK,_1942_D8287" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/The_work_of_the_Auxiliary_Territorial_Service_at_a_Mixed_Anti-aircraft_Battery_England_UK_1942_D8287.jpg" width="754" height="599" /></a>Hidey ho, jobseekers! I&#8217;ve been on the prowl for &#8220;the perfect job&#8221; for the last few years, and I&#8217;ve been subjected to dozens of interviews. Phone interviews, that is. Phone interviews make sense from the hiring manager&#8217;s perspective, because they can be setup quickly, there&#8217;s no need for the candidate to travel to their office, they&#8217;re safer (no letting the crazies in the front door, thank you) and because the phone removes the interviewee&#8217;s physical presence, the interviewer can get a more accurate assessment of the interviewee&#8217;s personality.</p>
<p>Please learn from my mistakes with this list of hints and tips I have compiled.<span id="more-122695"></span></p>
<p><strong>Research</strong></p>
<p>You found the job listing on Careerbuilder, or Indeed, or Sologig. You filled out the online application, you attached your resume and a cover letter, and now you&#8217;re waiting for HR to select or reject you. Now is the time to do some online stalkery of your intended employer. Visit these websites and search for the company:</p>
<ul>
<li>LinkedIn, to see if you know anyone who works there.</li>
<li>Glassdoor, to learn what current and former employees have to say about the company.</li>
<li>Youtube, to discover if the company has produced any videos about their products, or their collaborations with other companies.</li>
<li>Facebook, to read any wall posts the company has produced.</li>
<li>Finally google &#8220;company name litigation&#8221; or &#8220;company name lawsuit&#8221; to see if they have done anything naughty. You don&#8217;t want to hitch your wagon to a company that might get sued to oblivion.</li>
</ul>
<p>One more tip &#8211; try to find any online communities or forums the company has setup and read through some of the posts there, so you can get an idea of what challenges they face from their customers.</p>
<p>If the job requires specific skills, be sure you are up to date on whatever skills are required. LinkedIn is a great resource to find communities of practitioners. You should also find and join other online communities for your profession. You don&#8217;t have to be the number one commenter there, but you should participate and read your community boards regularly, not only for job leads but also to stay aware of what&#8217;s going on in your profession.</p>
<p><strong>Physical preparation</strong></p>
<p>You got a call from HR. You were selected for an interview! Awesome! Schedule the interview for a Monday morning or Friday afternoon, as those are the best times to influence decision makers. Now it&#8217;s time to get your interview space ready.</p>
<p>I recommend taking the call in front of your computer. I don&#8217;t care if you have to take your laptop into a closet, just have your computer handy in case you need to google something during the interview. Also, I like to have several documents open before the interview starts: My resume, a list of accomplishments, a list of questions to ask the interviewer, and my notes from the research I did earlier.</p>
<p>Get a sturdy chair that doesn&#8217;t squeak when you move around and set it in front of a table in your interview space. If you don&#8217;t have a lamp nearby, find one and bring it in, because you want your space to be well-lit and cheery. Clear all clutter off of your table. No pens, pencils, cat-toys, nothing that can clatter or distract. Grab a water bottle or bottle of soda (if you&#8217;re so inclined). Do not make coffee or tea and do not pour a glass of any beverage, because you don&#8217;t want to knock it over mid-sentence and be distracted cleaning it up while you&#8217;re supposed to be telling someone how fabulous you are.</p>
<p>I suggest you invest in a phone that has a mute button, so you can cough (or type furiously) during the interview without the interviewer hearing you. Also, use a landline or a softphone (like Magicjack or Ooma) rather than a cellphone to receive the interviewer&#8217;s call. It would be horrible if the closest cell tower decided to flake out while you&#8217;re mid-interview, disconnecting the call or making you sound like a drowning Woody Woodpecker.</p>
<p>It goes without saying, but I&#8217;mma say it anyway. During the phone call: No smoking. No gum chewing. No eating anything. Banish pets, children, adults from the room for the duration of the call. Turn off the stereo, the TV, and anything else that makes background noise. Turn off your computer&#8217;s speakers.</p>
<p>A few minutes before the interview is scheduled to start, get up and walk around. Go up and down a flight of stairs a few times if you&#8217;ve got stairs handy. Physical activity will pump up your energy and burn off any pre-interview jitters.</p>
<p><strong>The Big Event</strong></p>
<p>When it&#8217;s time for the interview to start, sit upright in your chair, smile, and remember you&#8217;re talking to the person who you will be working with closely, if you&#8217;re selected for the job. The interview is a time for you to find out if this is someone you want to spend the majority of your waking hours talking to and working with. Do they have a nasty personality? Maybe you don&#8217;t want them to be your boss, after all.</p>
<p>You, on the other hand, have your best party manners on. Spend a minute or two asking the interviewer how their day is going, talking about the weather, and getting a read on their personality. Then dive right in with a summary of who you are and why you think you&#8217;re a good fit for the job.</p>
<p>When the interviewer asks questions, rather than imagining you&#8217;re being grilled by a judge and jury, take the attitude that your best friend is asking you what you have done in your career and how you might solve a problem they have. If you &#8220;flip the script&#8221; in your mind and imagine that the interviewer is your friend, you will come across as someone the interviewer wants to work with, a collaborator rather than a minion.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t stress how important it is to be friendly and approachable in your phone interview. When I interviewed people via phone, my biggest turn-offs were people who were taciturn or even downright rude. Answering questions with a plain &#8220;No!&#8221; or a grunt (I&#8217;m not kidding) caused me to terminate the interview immediately. If you&#8217;re in a bad mood at the time of the interview and feel you can&#8217;t &#8220;fake it till you make it&#8221; you might do better to answer the phone, tell the interviewer something has come up, and ask to reschedule.</p>
<p><strong>Closing The Deal</strong></p>
<p>At the end of the call, most interviewers will say &#8220;do you have any questions for me?&#8221; This is the time for you to mention some of the research you did on the company and ask questions about what you found. Definitely don&#8217;t mention pending litigation. Here are some questions you can use instead:</p>
<ul>
<li>What do you view as the most challenging part of this job?</li>
<li>Why is the last person who held this position leaving?</li>
<li>How would you describe the company culture?</li>
<li>What is the typical work week? Is overtime expected? How about travel?</li>
<li>What are the opportunities for advancement with the company?</li>
<li>Is there anything else can I tell you about my qualifications?</li>
<li>What are the biggest challenges facing the person in this position?</li>
</ul>
<p>When all your questions have been answered, thank the interviewer for their time, and if you&#8217;re interested in moving forward, ask what the next steps will be.</p>
<p><strong>After The Call Ends</strong></p>
<p>While the interview is still fresh in your mind, take a few notes on what was said and think about any additional questions you might have. Some jobs I&#8217;ve interviewed for in the last year have required five or six phone interviews with various people on the team, and referring to my notes from previous interviews for the same job really came in handy. In one case, it led to an offer, because I had taken what one interviewer had said was a concern, and mentioned it to the next interviewer down the line. They thought I had great insight into their situation, when all I had done was parrot back to them what they told me.</p>
<p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the top tips for your phone interview:</p>
<ul>
<li>Learn all you can about the company so you can speak intelligently about their business.</li>
<li>Be friendly towards the interviewer, because no one wants to work with a jerk.</li>
<li>Prepare your interview space so there will be no distractions or background noises, because who knows how those noises will be interpreted on the other end.</li>
<li>Ask questions at the end so you appear interested in the job and the company.</li>
<li>Smile!</li>
</ul>
<p>Image source: Wikimedia commons</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-to-ace-your-next-phone-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.358 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-30 11:05:28 -->
