<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 23:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Breakers Movie Review</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/spring-breakers-movie-review/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/spring-breakers-movie-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jarrod</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring Breakers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122316</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Spring Break, y&#8217;all. &#8220;Spring Breakers&#8221; is sun tan oil, beer, drugs, and an MTV beach house all rolled into one [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spring Break, y&#8217;all.</p>
<p>&#8220;Spring Breakers&#8221; is sun tan oil, beer, drugs, and an MTV beach house all rolled into one nice, over-indulgent package. For some, this movie will remind them of their past lives as partying co-eds while others will watch on with their mouths agape like peeping toms given a glimpse into a life that they were never meant to see.<span id="more-122316"></span></p>
<p>Either way, the film is pleasant and unsettling all at the same time. The camera spends equal time lingering on gyrating hips, breasts, and sun-kissed skin as it does on blood, beer bellies, and methed out faces. It also highlights the trashiness that is Florida with or without the spring breakers that visit once a year.</p>
<p>It is equal parts &#8220;Enter The Void&#8221; and &#8220;Magic Mike&#8221; with voiceovers that provide the most subtle hints of foreshadowing. The actors do a great job capturing the lightness of spring break while barely acknowledging the treacherousness that lies beneath.  Selena Gomez&#8217;s character is the bible beater of the bunch and acts accordingly but the other characters continue to surprise throughout the film. Sure, they don&#8217;t have many lines but Ashley Benson and Vanessa Hudgens both prove that they are ready for bigger and better things than just tween movies and tv shows. Also,Rachel Korine makes a lasting impression as the fair weather bad girl. James Franco takes the next evolutionary step up from his character in &#8220;Pineapple Express.&#8221; He is Alien, a drug-dealer with a heart of gold and mind for mischief, has so many great moments that you almost forget about his sleaziness and want him to succeed.</p>
<p>The film is composed by Cliff Martinez (Drive, Contagion) and Skrillex whose music provides the perfect backdrop to the raucous proceedings. There are even a few random gunshots thrown in for good measure. Another &#8220;star&#8221; of the film is Britney Spears&#8217; music, some of the most memorable scenes in the movie include her songs &#8220;Everytime&#8221; and &#8220;&#8230;Baby, One More Time.&#8221; Both are worth the price of admission, alone.</p>
<p>After all the debauchery of the film, the one thing that did surprise me was the ending. It wasn&#8217;t that far fetched but definitely changed my thoughts about the whole movie.</p>
<p>Overall, I&#8217;d give the film an eight out of ten with a few eye rolls thrown in for good measure.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/842836">morgueFile</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/spring-breakers-movie-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Made That: French Bread Pizza</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/i-made-that-french-bread-pizza/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/i-made-that-french-bread-pizza/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122343</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last weekend GloriousShoes shared a link with a recipe for French Bread Pizza. Looked easy enough. I&#8217;ve made pizza from [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend GloriousShoes shared a link with a recipe for <a href="http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2013/03/the-best-french-bread-pizza-recipe.html">French Bread Pizza</a>. Looked easy enough. I&#8217;ve made pizza from scratch before, so I know the dough is the hard part. I did a quick run down of the ingredients: garlic, butter, olive oil, red pepper, oregano, cheese, tomatoes and a few simple other things. I knew this would be part of my dinner menu this week.<span id="more-122343"></span></p>
<p>I&#8217;m a doofus and ended up buying stewed tomatoes instead of crushed and decided to add Italian sausage. Fixing my stewed tomatoes was easy &#8211; I threw them in the food processor until they were the right consistency for pizza sauce. Rouse&#8217;s didn&#8217;t have any ground Italian sausage so I bought the brat kind and just took the casing off. No big deal &#8211; I&#8217;ve done this before. Cooking the sausage (heh) added a little bit of time to this recipe that probably would have only taken 30 minutes.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-beginning.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122351" alt="pizza beginning" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-beginning.jpg" width="550" height="387" /></a></p>
<p>Other than that it was a pretty easy process. Preheat the oven to 425º. Cut the French bread in half as if you were going to make a sandwich out of it. Mince the garlic, melt the butter and olive oil in a sautee pan. Cook the garlic until it&#8217;s soft, but don&#8217;t brown it. Throw in the oregano and red pepper flakes with the garlic. Once the garlic is soft, put in the parsley/basil mix and a good pinch of salt. Stir it a little bit and then remove from heat. You should squish the bread a little bit with a cookie sheet. I guess you don&#8217;t have to do this, but the bread might curl up a bit in the baking process.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-middle.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122355" alt="pizza middle" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-middle.jpg" width="500" height="667" /></a></p>
<p>You want to brush about half of this garlic goodness on the slices of bread, then put some cheese on each slice. Put this in the oven until the cheese is a little melty. Meanwhile, add the tomatoes to the rest of the garlic/butter mixture. Let this cook until the tomatoes have reduced the sauce is rich. Probably about 10-15 minutes. Once the sauce has reduced, put some on each bread slice. My layering went like this: sauce, meat, cheese. Maybe next time I&#8217;ll do sauce, cheese, and then meat.</p>
<p>Let this bake until the cheese has melted/browned to your liking. Let it cool a bit and boom. You&#8217;ve got dinner.</p>
<p><strong>Was this recipe easy?</strong> Pretty easy, yes. I complicated it a bit by adding sausage and screwing up with the tomatoes.<br />
<strong>How long did it take?</strong> It was probably 45 minutes from the time I started cooking the sausage until I was eating.<br />
<strong>How did it taste?</strong> Really good. Dare I say it was even better when I ate it for leftovers. I put the leftover pieces in a toaster oven and the bread was the perfect amount of crunchy.<br />
<strong>Would I make this again?</strong> Sure thing. This was really easy and quick. I&#8217;ll add it to my &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to spend a lot of time cooking dinner&#8221; list of things to make.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-final1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122365" alt="pizza-final1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pizza-final1.jpg" width="600" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>All photos courtesy of clarity83.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/i-made-that-french-bread-pizza/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wakey wakey Don&#8217;t get arrested. Photo courtesy of boobookitteh.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122344" alt="Iceland" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/iceland.jpeg" width="505" height="242" /></a><br />
Wakey wakey <span id="more-122341"></span></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get arrested.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/S7_vH3H8LPI" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><i>Photo courtesy of boobookitteh</i>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wednesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/wednesday-open-thread-64/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/wednesday-open-thread-64/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122148</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Burp. Yuk yuk yuk Photo courtesy of TS.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Burp. <span id="more-122148"></span></p>
<p>Yuk yuk yuk</p>
<p><iframe width="450" height="253" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-Rot9uaVO8s" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><i>Photo courtesy of TS.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/wednesday-open-thread-64/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smash Liveblog Season 2 Episode 7 &#8220;Musical Chairs&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-7-musical-chairs/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-7-musical-chairs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 01:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hatewatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liveblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another Tuesday, another shitty episode of this shitty TV show. Turns out NBC has finally figured out what we&#8217;ve known [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Smash_Title_Card.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-119857" alt="Smash_Title_Card" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Smash_Title_Card.jpg" width="550" height="228" /></a></p>
<p>Another Tuesday, another shitty episode of this shitty TV show. Turns out NBC has finally figured out what we&#8217;ve known about this show all along and has decided to <a href="http://tvline.com/2013/03/15/smash-season-2-series-finale-spoilers/">move it to Saturdays</a> starting April 6. So we&#8217;ve got this week and then next to suffer through this together. The show&#8217;s showrunner, Josh  Safran says the season finale will also be the series finale. (h/t to DottieB for the info.)</p>
<p>Anywho &#8211; this week&#8217;s episode is called &#8220;Musical Chairs.&#8221; I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s about Jimmy Who going to IKEA to pick out some new furniture for his apartment.<span id="more-122328"></span></p>
<p>Photo: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Smash_Title_Card.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-7-musical-chairs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Picking Your Crass NCAA Bracket for Fun and Profit</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/picking-your-crass-ncaa-bracket-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/picking-your-crass-ncaa-bracket-for-fun-and-profit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 20:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Robert Travers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butthurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Important note: The Grand Inquisitor does not follow college ball, so she is relying on the wisdom of Crassers Past [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Important note: The Grand Inquisitor does not follow college ball, so she is relying on the wisdom of Crassers Past (St. Patrick&#8217;s Year) to get you started. You can sign up for Crasstalk Funderdome brackets <a href="http://crasstalkfunderdome.mayhem.cbssports.com/e?ttag=13_cbspaste" target="_blank">here</a>. The team  password is “indianasucks” (without the quotes).</em></p>
<p>Today is Christmas wrapped in the Super Bowl surrounded by endless waves of Kentucky Derby roses for gambling professionals, casinos, Hoboken wise guys, and offshore sports books. This is the day when the non-gamblers gamble, the day when grandmas, toddlers, the comatose and Nepalese Sherpas all gather round the television and fill out an NCAA basketball tournament bracket without knowing the difference between Duke and Duquesne or a chance in hell of actually winning the office, school or neighborhood pool.</p>
<p>And the pros &#8211;also that skeezy guy from Tech Support who runs this thing every year&#8211;are lining up to take your bracket and your money. The only time you&#8217;ll hear from them again is through a weekly email between now and Easter showing you and your colleagues just  badly your bracket is progressing.<span id="more-122315"></span>But that&#8217;s all for other years. Yes friends, as Jim Nantz would say, this year, the odds are on your side. This year, you have the upper hand. Because this year, you are reading Crasstalk&#8217;s Guide to Bracket Glory. And you will finally learn the Secrets of the Sherpas, at least when it comes to picking Kentucky or Kansas. (Hint: Sherpas inexplicably love Calipari. Who knew?)</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll begin with the Unbreakable Laws of Bracketology. Do not violate them, it will only make you look silly. Sherpas will laugh at you in the breakroom. Well, they will if your office is at Everest Base Camp. Not many Sherpas in Midtown.</p>
<p>Here are ten simple rules to get you into April with a viable bracket:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do not pick a 15 or 16 seed to win a game. No 16 seed has ever won, only four 15 seeds have ever won even one game in the tournament.</li>
<li>Move all four Number 1 seeds to the Sweet Sixteen. Every now and then a Number 1 will lose the first weekend, but it&#8217;s rare.</li>
<li>Favor teams with senior guards. Choose schools with starting juniors and seniors generally. Mature leadership wins championships. Even a team with a great one-and-done player needs seniors.</li>
<li>In the first round pick at least one, but no more than two, number 12 seeds to knock off a number 5 seed. Just do it.</li>
<li>Go chalk from the Sweet 16 in. Pick the higher seeds. You won&#8217;t be sorry.</li>
<li>Definitely put one or two Number 1 seeds in your Final Four, but not all four number 1&#8242;s. That&#8217;s only happened once.</li>
<li>Pick Duke. They always win. I know, I know, we all hate them&#8211;and that school has <em>issues</em>. Real issues. But winning basketball games is not one of them. You&#8217;ll never go broke betting on Duke to win.</li>
<li>For your national champion, pick a school that has won it all prior to 2012. March Madness is like the NBA, not that many different champions. Since 1991, only four schools&#8211;Arkansas, Arizona, Syracuse, and Maryland&#8211;are one-time champions. All the rest&#8211;the Dukes, UNC&#8217;s, UConns, and Floridas&#8211;have won at least two.</li>
<li>Although it is popular, do not pick a winner in a toss-up game based on the school&#8217;s colors or who&#8217;s mascot could beat up the other. (Panthers eat Wildcats. Lions eat Cardinals. Cannibals eat Colonials, that sort of thing.) These are popular methods, but wrong.</li>
<li>What you want to do is pick the school a favorite ex-girlfriend attended, or pick against the school where that whore who dumped you in the Summer of 2005 went to grad school. Also, if a college accepted you, but you chose not to go there, pick them. They&#8217;re OK. If you applied and they denied you, screw &#8216;em. Out in Round Two. Even if they are a Number 1 seed. You have standards, damn it, and your essays kicked ass. Must have been some bullshit affirmative action thing. And those C&#8217;s in science and math. Trippin&#8217; high school teachers. But still&#8211;out in the second round.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t ever pick a directional school (Southeast Missouri State, Middle Tennessee, Inside Out Western North Dakota). They will only break your heart. Like that whore from 2005.</li>
<li>Do not select a school with two names. No George Masons, James Madisons, John Harvards, Dan Dartmouths or Oral Roberts. And nay to Charlie Sheen A&amp;M, no matter how much they&#8217;ve been winning.</li>
<li>Catholics over Protestants. They&#8217;ve been playing basketball longer and take it more seriously than anything other than the Eucharist itself or Friday night bingo. So yes to Notre Dame, St Johns, Xavier or Georgetown&#8211;no to SMU, TCU or Liberty. Not that any of them will be playing this year. But this is a good rule for future reference.</li>
<li>Finally, the most important rule of all: Choosing pro or con on your beloved alma mater. If your school is a 15 or 16 seed, I&#8217;m sorry, there is nothing I can do and you must kill them off in the first round. If they are a 13 or 14 seed, you have to go Dr Phil-style tough love and do the same. Out. Think of the laughing Sherpas. But&#8230;if your school is a 12 seed or higher, then quietly hum your fight song and take them to the Sweet Sixteen. Why not, you still owe them $80,000 in student loans, it can&#8217;t hurt. If your alma mater is a Top Four seed&#8211;<em>unless </em>it is also a Protestant school up against Catholics, from a state Romney won, directional, or that school that whore attended&#8211;then pick them to win the National Championship. Someone&#8217;s gonna win it. Let&#8217;s just hope it&#8217;s you and not Duke. Er, I mean, you and not <em>them</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Image via <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Rob_Jones_dunk_02.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/picking-your-crass-ncaa-bracket-for-fun-and-profit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>George Saunders&#8217; &#8220;Victory Lap&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/george-saunders-victory-lap/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/george-saunders-victory-lap/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 16:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ska Hammer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture and Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Foster Wallace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Saunders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tenth of December]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122047</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here in 2013, American short-fiction author George Saunders is having a moment. His fourth collection of short stories, Tenth of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tenth-of-December-bookstack.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-122236" alt="Tenth of December bookstack" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Tenth-of-December-bookstack-300x265.jpg" width="300" height="265" /></a>Here in 2013, American short-fiction author George Saunders is having a moment. His fourth collection of short stories, <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0812993802/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;creativeASIN=0812993802&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=crasstalk-20">Tenth of December</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=crasstalk-20&#038;l=as2&#038;o=1&#038;a=0812993802" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></em>, was published in January. Wikipedia describes the book&#8217;s critical reception as &#8220;<a title="Link to Wikipedia page for George Saunders' _Tenth of December_" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tenth_of_December:_Stories" target="_blank">mixed to positive</a>&#8221; — but the positive end of that range seems remarkably intense: A recent <em>New York Times Magazine</em> interview with the author is titled &#8220;<a title="Link to 1/6/13 NYT interview with George Saunders " href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/06/magazine/george-saunders-just-wrote-the-best-book-youll-read-this-year.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=1&amp;" target="_blank">George Saunders Has Written the Best Book You&#8217;ll Read This Year</a>.&#8221; (Bold title for an article published during the first week of January.) And on a winter Sunday after yet another nor&#8217;easter had finished slamming New England, Saunders&#8217; Boston-area reading practically filled a local auditorium with his fans. <span id="more-122047"></span></p>
<p>Saunders&#8217; voice is mildly reedy, and when reading out loud he speaks quickly. This is not an optimal toolset for most types of public speaking. In fact I find it amazing how often writers struggle with handicaps when reading their work in public: poor voice projection, uncertain mannerisms, monotones. It&#8217;s a reminder, perhaps, that writers spend most of their productive time alone, or at least within their own heads.</p>
<p>(As an aside, British and Irish writers are a strong exception to this rule. They always seem to be projecting — as if they&#8217;ve spent years onstage training for the role of <em>AUTHOR</em>! Which maybe some of them have.)</p>
<p>But Saunders is nevertheless a highly enthusiastic public reader of his work. At Cambridge&#8217;s Brattle Theater, he amused the crowd by reciting different characters&#8217; internal monologues in different voices. He made jokes. And he kept the whole thing short. He introduced himself with an anecdote in which he received the following advice from an older Polish gentleman, his driver at an earlier stop on the tour: &#8220;Don&#8217;t read too long.&#8221; So on Sunday afternoon Saunders read twenty minutes into his gripping short story &#8220;Victory Lap&#8221; — and then simply stopped, at a cliffhanger no less. He claimed that this was another part of his marketing strategy.</p>
<p>Then Saunders took questions from the audience. This is one self-promotional task that American authors seem quite skilled at, perhaps because so many of them have teaching experience. Saunders even went out of his way to encourage reluctant questioners, by describing a specific (&#8220;Darwinian&#8221;) phenomenon he had supposedly observed in each city: The individuals who posed the first questions at each reading&#8230;were always the ones most extravagantly blessed with sexual energy.</p>
<p>Saunders gave complete answers to all queries, even when they simply rehashed the same topics which writers are always quizzed about (and which are sometimes comprehensively covered in bookchatty articles like January&#8217;s <em>New York Times</em> rave). After explaining that you should never try to write fiction based on dreams, he admitted that his story &#8220;<a title="Link George Saunders' story &quot;The Semplica Girls&quot; (in New Yorker)" href="http://www.newyorker.com/fiction/features/2012/10/15/121015fi_fiction_saunders?currentPage=all" target="_blank">The Semplica-Girl Diaries</a>&#8221; originated in a dream. He also briefly discussed his early work, confirming that he did indeed write the stories in his first book (<em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1573225797/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&#038;camp=1789&#038;creative=390957&#038;creativeASIN=1573225797&#038;linkCode=as2&#038;tag=crasstalk-20">CivilWarLand in Bad Decline</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=crasstalk-20&#038;l=as2&#038;o=1&#038;a=1573225797" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></em>) while working at his onetime day job as a technical writer.</p>
<p>(That answer was given in response to <em>my</em> question — which was the fourth one asked. So feel free to draw the appropriate conclusions about my own sexual energy.)</p>
<p>Since the venue for this reading was in Cambridge — in fact just a block from Harvard Square — it was inevitable that Saunders would be asked about David Foster Wallace. This question came next-to-last on the afternoon, from a long-haired young woman and probable graduate student who sat in the front row. (And speaking of extravagant sexual energy: Who can possibly compete with long-haired female grad students who sit in the front rows of literary events?) This query is fair game for Saunders: He teaches writing at Syracuse University, in the town where Wallace wrote much of his magnum opus, <em>Infinite Jest</em>. And Saunders was both closely acquainted with and often compared to Wallace. So on this afternoon Saunders generously shared his recollections of the late author of <em>A Supposedly Fun Thing I&#8217;ll Never Do Again</em>. But he was also careful to underline the two writers&#8217; differences: Although Saunders and Wallace may have tended toward similar writing styles and themes, in Saunders&#8217; view the two men approached those destinations from completely different directions.</p>
<p>I do think George Saunders has earned a place on the same literary team where David Foster Wallace was a longtime all-star. (Whose coach is probably Kurt Vonnegut. And whose general manager might be Thomas Pynchon.) Both writers share a distinct tone — deadpan absurdity — and an up-to-the-minute concern with the dehumanizing effects of capital and technology. But Saunders is by far the more approachable figure. He writes primarily short fiction and journalism: There is no daunting literary mountain, no <em>Infinite Jest</em> that one must conquer in order to grasp Saunders&#8217; oeuvre. And Saunders&#8217; father ran a pizza joint, instead of studying philosophy under one of Ludwig Wittgenstein&#8217;s most prominent American students.</p>
<p>The last question posed on Sunday afternoon was about the outpouring of acclaim that followed <em>Tenth of December</em>&#8216;s publication. Saunders explained that for a while, his only exposure to this praise was via e-mails that started appearing in his inbox. Everything else at his house in the Catskills (this was probably during Syracuse University&#8217;s semester break) stayed the same. He also admitted that if he had received this good press ten years earlier, he might have reacted somewhat neurotically to it. But now Saunders&#8217; philosophy was to treat this approval like an incredible cooking smell that one encounters wafting from a nearby house. You&#8217;d be an idiot if you didn&#8217;t linger for a few moments taking it in, he said. But you&#8217;d also be an idiot if you barged right into the house, looking for more.</p>
<p><em>Photo © 2013 by skahammer</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/george-saunders-victory-lap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smells Like Queen Spirit: RuPaul&#8217;s Drag Race Season 5, Episode 8</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smells-like-queen-spirit-rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-8/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smells-like-queen-spirit-rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-8/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Homoviper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rupaul's drag race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[season 5]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The queens are all emotionally spent when they enter the workroom after last week&#8217;s non-elimination and Roxxxy&#8217;s tearful, calculated confession. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rupaulsdragraceheader.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rupaulsdragraceheader.jpg" alt="rupaulsdragraceheader" width="510" height="220" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-118184" /></a><br />
The queens are all emotionally spent when they enter the workroom after last week&#8217;s non-elimination and Roxxxy&#8217;s tearful, calculated confession. Roxxxxxxxxxxy admits she had been projecting her issues at Jinkx and apologizes. Well, that&#8217;s something, I suppose. Detox is pissed that there was no elimination. Me too, gworl, me too. Alaska is frustrated that she still hasn&#8217;t won a challenge. And we&#8217;re off. Hit the jump to see my updated Drag Race Index! <span id="more-122250"></span></p>
<p>Best mini challenge ever! Any excuse to check out guys in their underwear is good enough for me. Thank you, Andrew Christian. After Ivy Winters won the underwear match game mini challenge, the queens were tasked with creating their own fragrances. Some struggled in the workroom and then again while filming their commercials in front of director Michelle Visage and guest twunt Aubrey O&#8217;Day. Of course that included some fakeout editing. In the end, Detox found her comedy groove again, and Alaska and Jinkx both nailed it as well. Alaska won the challenge. All the other queens did horribly. Ivy Winters lip synced against Alyssa before sashaying away. I haven&#8217;t fully recovered from this loss and will need some time to process the tragedy before I can pick up the pieces and move forward. I&#8217;m currently accepting flowers and baked goods to help me through this difficult time. <em>But please, no mylar balloons. They never deflate, and I just don&#8217;t have the heart to throw them away.</em> Anywhore, let&#8217;s break down this week&#8217;s Index one queen at a time, shall we?</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/drag_race_index_week8.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/drag_race_index_week8-1024x743.jpg" alt="drag_race_index_week8" width="654" height="474" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-122264" /></a></p>
<p>Click to enlarge!</p>
<h4>Jinkx Monsoon</h4>
<p>Water off a duck&#8217;s back. Water off a duck&#8217;s back. No need for that tonight, Jinkxyboo. Her perfume concept and commercial were hilarious and just so very Jinkx. Her flapper-ish look on the main stage was something signature we&#8217;ve come to expect from her, and yet she refined her techniques enough that she made Michelle Visage very happy for the second week in a row. I see great thing ins Jinkx&#8217;s future. I was glad that she stood up for herself when Coco (who has become extremely tiresome and loathsome, but more on that later) flipped her weave during <em>Untucked</em>. Jinkx, I know the negativity gets to you sometimes, but stay strong because you are the one to beat in this competition, and the rest of these bitches know it. The Jinkx/Ivy friendship may just be my favorite thing ever. I know we later found out that Jinkx has a major crush on Ivy, and I don&#8217;t know what will come of that, but the idea of these two queens being close &#8212; in any way &#8212; just warms my heart so much. </p>
<h4>Alaska</h4>
<p>Finally, Miss Alaska has won a challenge! Her commercial and concept were hilarious. She served them a classic Alaska look for the commercial, and then did something a bit different on the main stage so it was definitely her week to shine. I&#8217;m glad she finally got a win under her belt, and I remain confident in her ability to make it to the top three and compete for the crown in the finale.</p>
<h4>Detox</h4>
<p>Welcome back, Miss Detox. While her main stage look was a total misfire (she tried to reproduce a look she had  success with previously and failed), her perfume concept and commercial made up for it in spades. I was reminded that, yes, this bitch can be very fucking funny when she wants to be. With the elimination of Ivy this week, everything feels so up in the air, and it&#8217;s hard for me to say who will take the third spot in the top three. But. At this stage of the game? I <em>want</em> it to be Detox over the other bitches. Can she make it happen? We&#8217;ll see.</p>
<h4>Coco Montrese</h4>
<p>Oh, Coco. Bitter Coco. Tiresome Coco. Needs to go home soon Coco. Her commercial was a trainwreck. It was a leopard print-on-print crime against fashion. It was a confused and confusing derivation of RuPaul&#8217;s name and Grace Jones&#8217; Strangé character from <em>Boomerang</em>. It was bad and unfunny. She takes the fourth spot in the Index for two reasons: the other queens below her in the Index were actually that much worse than her, and her main stage look <em>was</em> fierce. As Santino said, she was a bit over-accessorized, but the dress was killer.</p>
<h4>Alyssa Edwards</h4>
<p>Her commercial and concept were turrible. Any time you catch Alyssa laughing at her own jokes, you know there&#8217;s going to be a problem, and she thought her &#8220;secret&#8221; was just the funniest thing! Ugh. Her main stage look was alright, but really, if you want to talk about not getting any variety from a queen, let&#8217;s have a talk about Miss Alyssa Edwards then because this bitch looks almost identical week to week. I think it&#8217;s nearly time for Miss Alyssa to get back on the turnip truck and go home. I admit that she completely out lip synced Ivy Winters &#8212; srsly, it was no contest &#8212; and it was so painful to watch.</p>
<h4>Roxxxy Andrews</h4>
<p>Time to go home, Boxy Mandrews. Her concept and commercial were godawful. When she talked about how excited she was to be doing something more in the wheelhouse of a pageant girl, I was ready to see this bitch shine. No. She started her commercial looking like an <em>Austin Powers</em> librarian and ended it looking like a garbage bag overfilled with potatoes. Her main stage look did her no favors, and I loved Aubrey O&#8217;Day&#8217;s reaction to it when the judges were deliberating. I&#8217;m glad she made her peace with Jinkx, but that doesn&#8217;t change the fact that I don&#8217;t think she has what it takes to go all the way in the competition. She is uneven at best in the main challenges, and she does not know how to dress herself. I am all for being proud of your body, and I completely understand that it&#8217;s a struggle to lose weight, but you should spend a minute understanding what looks good on you. The thing you want to wear, and the thing that looks good on your body are not always the same thing, and Roxxxy really needs to address that disconnect in the future.</p>
<h4>Ivy Winters</h4>
<p>Sashay away, sweet Ivy. We lost an extremely talented queen tonight. I think that despite being a performer by nature, Ivy had some shyness and insecurities when it came to performing in unfamiliar circumstances. She is gone much too soon for my taste, and I know many of you were fans as well, but I am happy that at least we were able to see her shine as she did in the singing challenge a couple weeks ago. She has a very bright future ahead of her, and I can&#8217;t wait until we get to the reunion show to find out the status of the Jinkx/Ivy freindship/possible relationship.</p>
<p>So what are your thoughts on last night&#8217;s episode? Does the loss of Ivy change your expectations going forward? Sound off in the comments, and I&#8217;ll see you next week!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/smells-like-queen-spirit-rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tuesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/tuesday-open-thread-69/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/tuesday-open-thread-69/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122258</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good day and welcome to Crasstalk. The Maghreb from Enrique Pacheco on Vimeo. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good day and welcome to Crasstalk. <span id="more-122258"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/60754449?portrait=0&amp;color=4a8596" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/60754449">The Maghreb</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/enriquepacheco">Enrique Pacheco</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Termit1.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/tuesday-open-thread-69/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyoncé Released a New Song And the Response Has Been&#8230;Confusion?</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/beyonce-released-a-new-song-and-the-response-has-been-confusion/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/beyonce-released-a-new-song-and-the-response-has-been-confusion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 23:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lauren</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beyonce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122242</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If there&#8217;s anything more baffling than the lives and daily motivations of celebrities and pop stars, it&#8217;s the public response [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/beyonce_image.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122243" alt="beyonce_image" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/beyonce_image.jpg" width="300" height="363" /></a></p>
<p>If there&#8217;s anything more baffling than the lives and daily motivations of celebrities and pop stars, it&#8217;s the public response that comes when they do new things. And Beyoncé is no exception. However, we&#8217;re going to go out on a limb and say that we kind of understand the media&#8217;s inability to make up its mind about this one. <span id="more-122242"></span></p>
<p>Last night Beyoncé released a new song, or rather a new song and a half called Bow Down/I Been On. Some reports say it&#8217;s a new song that&#8217;s set to go alongside Bey&#8217;s new &#8220;Mrs. Carter&#8221; Tour. Other reports have no idea what the impetus for this new song could be. The <a href="http://www.theatlanticwire.com/entertainment/2013/03/new-beyonce-song-bow-down-i-been-on/63217/" target="_blank">The Atlantic Wire</a> attempted to critique it using much of the negative reaction. And <a href="http://www.vulture.com/2013/03/beyonce-new-songs.html" target="_blank">Vulture</a> offered talking points in order to intelligently discuss it amongst other music-philes. </p>
<p>The one thing we can all agree on is that the song is boastful, brash, and in its full scope wants the listener to know that there is no one quite like Beyoncé so don&#8217;t even try to compare her, put her in a box, or relegate her to just being Hov&#8217;s wife. Could any of this have something to do with the recent spate of Beyoncé-centric news (not all positive) that&#8217;s hit the airwaves since she was accused of lip syncing at the presidential inauguration, that was then followed up by a pyrotechnic-laden Super Bowl performance some say put the lights out in the stadium, which then proceeded a self-directed docu/concert/mentary that aired on HBO? That&#8217;s a lot of Beyoncé in the last three months.</p>
<p>So now we have a new single that gives us a newer sound than we&#8217;ve heard from Beyoncé which finds her not only singing in small verse, but has her attempting a swagger-heavy, chopped and screwed sound made trendy again by more contemporary rappers like A$AP Rocky. Many reviewers are trying to figure out just what Beyoncé is trying to tell us in all her fabulousness. It&#8217;s not that she&#8217;s coveting the career of the likes of Nicki Minaj, or that she wants to perform a husband and wife hip-hop act with Jay Z, or that she&#8217;s feeling that her reign as one of the bigger stars in the world is up for debate &#8212; or is it? Is she feeling the urge to reinvent? To go after the haters in a way she hasn&#8217;t had to do before when her celebrity was more ubiquitous? After-all, she talks quite a bit about &#8220;bitches&#8221; in this single. We wonder who she&#8217;s targeting.</p>
<p>Then again, this could all mean nothing and it could just be Bey&#8217;s way to get everybody talking. To keep her name in the news, just one more way to keep fans in lockstep as she promotes a new tour. Possibly. But reality does tell us that reigning in the music business is not absolute. So maybe she&#8217;s just hedging all her bets. One thing is abundantly clear if the single&#8217;s <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/perpetua/beyonces-new-song-bow-down-is-hard" target="_blank">cover art</a> is any indication, Bey thinks you really should just &#8220;bow down.&#8221; There really are no other options since she&#8217;s been running the game since elementary school it would appear. </p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the new single(s). What do you think?</p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F82541328&#038;show_artwork=false"></iframe></p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Beyonce_Knowles_with_necklaces.jpg" target="_blank">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/beyonce-released-a-new-song-and-the-response-has-been-confusion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.385 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-21 19:22:28 -->
