<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 12:26:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Boston Marathon Bombing Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-open-thread-2/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-open-thread-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 12:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DontMakeMe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[All things Boston Marathon bombing investigation related go here. Fluffy stuff goes in regular OT.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All things Boston Marathon bombing investigation related go here. Fluffy stuff goes in regular OT.<span id="more-124281"></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/boston-marathon-bombing-open-thread-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/friday-open-thread-73/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/friday-open-thread-73/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124171</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Get it. General Observations of People &#124; No. 6 &#124; &#8220;The Holy Trinity&#8221; from Everynone on Vimeo. Image source Wikimedia]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Get it.<span id="more-124171"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/13967951?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/13967951">General Observations of People | No. 6 | &#8220;The Holy Trinity&#8221;</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/everynone">Everynone</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Image source <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Male_whale_shark_at_Georgia_Aquarium.jpg" target="_blank">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/friday-open-thread-73/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project Runway Season 11 Episode 13 Live Blog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/project-runway-season-11-episode-13-live-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/project-runway-season-11-episode-13-live-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 00:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CaptainSnarky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh, my god. There are TWO more episodes of this? What more can they have these hapless designers do? And [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-117875" alt="project-runway-26" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a>Oh, my god. There are TWO more episodes of this? What more can they have these hapless designers do? And last week&#8217;s episode was two hours, people. Really, the only good thing about that overlong episode was the elimination of Layana.</p>
<p>Wait&#8211;tonight&#8217;s episode is <em>also</em> two hours long. Thank the gods that <em>Scandal</em> is a repeat.<span id="more-124250"></span></p>
<p>Well, part one of this &#8220;finale event&#8221; has the designers designing One Last Time for the runway prior to Mercedes Benz Fashion Week, so we&#8217;ll get to see more crying, drama, and Salvadore Daniel with even <em>crazier</em> hair!</p>
<p>Since this is two hours long, we should have plenty of time to get our favorite adult beverages, get into the comments section, and let the snark fly!</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:PRLogo12.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/project-runway-season-11-episode-13-live-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Intro To Knots&#8221; Community Season 4 Episode 10 Liveblog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/intro-to-knots-community-season-4-episode-10-liveblog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/intro-to-knots-community-season-4-episode-10-liveblog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 23:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ManchuCandidate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Return of Foot Fetishist Cornwallis So here we are with episode 10, which is the season&#8217;s Xmas episode (thanks [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_124258" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 212px"><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Malcolm_McDowell_Cannes_2011.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-124258 " alt="Singing In the Rain" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Malcolm_McDowell_Cannes_2011-212x300.jpg" width="212" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Return of Foot Fetishist Cornwallis</p></div>
<p>So here we are with episode 10, which is the season&#8217;s Xmas episode (thanks for delaying it Ennn Beee Seee.)  This week&#8217;s episode synopsis (from wiki):  Community Season 4 Episode 10 &#8220;Intro to Knots&#8221; &#8211; Jeff (Joel McHale) organizes a lovely holiday gathering at his apartment but Annie (Alison Brie) secretly invites Professor Cornwallis (recurring guest star Malcolm McDowell), to get in his good graces. When it becomes apparent that Professor Cornwallis intends to give them a bad grade on their joint History paper, the atmosphere quickly deteriorates and the group takes decisive action.<br />
<em> </em></p>
<p>I thought last week&#8217;s muppet episode was quite entertaining especially the hallucinogenic berry scene with Brad Pitt wigged Jason Alexander (and the fact Britta was holding.)  Apparently, this is one of the episodes done after Chevy Chase&#8217;s uncomfortably racist comments and subsequent dismissal from the show.  Chevy&#8217;s lines were recorded as part of his agreement with the producers.  It&#8217;s Merry Xmas, Community fans. <span id="more-124255"></span></p>
<p>8:00 Annie&#8217;s bringing out her Inner Trudy minus the &#8220;I will destroy you.&#8221;</p>
<p>8:03 Pierce in sensitivity training.  Ha.</p>
<p>8:07 Oh Jeffery.</p>
<p>8:08 Crowned the smartest student at the dumbest school.</p>
<p>8:09 And Chang Britta&#8217;ed it.</p>
<p>8:14 Decided to go all &#8220;Teaching Mrs Tingle.&#8221;</p>
<p>8:20 Jeffery!  I can smell you&#8230;  Creepy.</p>
<p>8:26 Chang-spiracy!</p>
<p>8:30 Evil Annie is evil and hot.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Malcolm_McDowell_Cannes_2011.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/intro-to-knots-community-season-4-episode-10-liveblog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Traveling the Length of the Western Hemisphere by Bus</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/traveling-the-length-of-the-western-hemisphere-by-bus/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/traveling-the-length-of-the-western-hemisphere-by-bus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maxichamp</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[automobiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trains]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been on a quest to travel the length of North and South America by land. I just returned [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/securedownload-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124239" alt="securedownload-1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/securedownload-1.jpg" width="640" height="478" /></a>I have been on a quest to travel the length of North and South America by land. I just returned from my fifth trip&#8211; a bus ride from Guatemala City to Panama&#8217;s Darien Gap. For those of you counting at home, I am 88% done with my goal. Here are some highlights to give you a flavor of my experiences. I will be writing more posts on Crasstalk about my recent Central America trip.</p>
<p><span id="more-124237"></span><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/131567974.MjwRx480.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124240" alt="131567974.MjwRx480" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/131567974.MjwRx480.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Vehicles used:</strong> 20 buses, 6 vans, 2 taxis, 2 passenger cars, 1 trolley.</li>
<li><strong>Longest non-stop bus ride:</strong> Osorno, Chile, to Punta Arenas, Chile (28 hours, 15 minutes).</li>
<li><strong>Longest wait on a bus:</strong> 8 hours 37 minutes at ferry landing to cross Strait of Magellan due to wind. Had to return the next day for the crossing.</li>
<li><strong>Nicest bus:</strong> Double decker in Peru. Choice of beef, chicken, or vegetarian meal. Seats that reclined 160 degrees. Business center onboard with computer and printer.</li>
<li><strong>Coolest bus:</strong> Kia bus in Panama. Was a used tour bus from South Korea, festooned with Korean stickers everywhere. Curtains out of Maharaja&#8217;s sitting room. 42&#8243; TV with amps and tons of speakers.</li>
<li><strong>Most professional bus driver:</strong> Greyhound driver in Oregon. He had a black briefcase like an airline pilot would have. Inside, he had an apple and a can of grape soda.</li>
<li><strong>Multi-tasking bus driver:</strong> Dude in Tierra del Fuego. He was driving, smoking Marlboro Reds, talking on his cell, talking on his CB, and unscrewing cap of his Coke all at the same time.</li>
<li><strong>Sketchiest border crossing (Day):</strong> Mexico-Guatemala.</li>
<li><strong>Sketchiest border crossing (Night):</strong> Guatemala-El Salvador.</li>
<li><strong>Number of border crossings:</strong> 13.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/88097889.7JvExrzv.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124242" alt="88097889.7JvExrzv" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/88097889.7JvExrzv.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Smelliest bus station restroom:</strong> Greyhound Seattle.</li>
<li><strong>Worst onboard movie:</strong> <em>Fireproof</em> by Kirk Cameron.</li>
<li><strong>Chinese restaurants visited:</strong> 6 (Whitehorse, Yukon; Tapachula, Chiapas, Mexico; Antigua, Guatemala; Panama City; Lima, Peru; Santiago, Chile.</li>
<li><strong>Overturned vehicles spotted on side of road:</strong> 3 (2 tractor trailers in Mexico and a chicken bus in Guatemala).</li>
<li><strong>Weirdest passenger:</strong> Greyhound in the Yukon. At night, a man sitting across the aisle from me sat upside down. His feet were dangling over the headrest and his head was on the floor. He proceeded to fart.</li>
<li><strong>Number of evangelicals who tried to convert me:</strong> 3 (2 in Guatemala, 1 in Alaska).</li>
<li><strong>Best meal:</strong> Seafood stew in Iquique, Chile.</li>
<li><strong>Best drink (Cocktail):</strong> Fanschop in Chile (half orange Fanta, half lager).</li>
<li><strong>Best drink (Beer):</strong> Cerveza Austral&#8217;s El Calafate Ale.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/131568016.Z4NYrVUT.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124241" alt="131568016.Z4NYrVUT" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/131568016.Z4NYrVUT.jpg" width="800" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>Images source: Maxichamp</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/traveling-the-length-of-the-western-hemisphere-by-bus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IRL Friendships are Overrated</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/irl-friendships-are-overrated/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/irl-friendships-are-overrated/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 16:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ska Hammer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sex and Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teh Interwebz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a/s/l?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IRL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nonlocal acquaintances]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve had friends of various types throughout my life. But the first time I ever encountered the phenomenon of internet-only [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Link to tin-can image on Flickr page for user StockMonkeys" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/86530412@N02/8210762750/in/set-72157632009408719" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-124114" alt="8210762750_7642b21e39-500x333" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/8210762750_7642b21e39-500x333.jpg" width="500" height="333" /></a>I&#8217;ve had friends of various types throughout my life. But the first time I ever encountered the phenomenon of internet-only friends — &#8220;nonlocal acquaintances&#8221; — was about six years ago.<span id="more-124004"></span></p>
<p>It was via a message board used by candidates for the Chartered Financial Analyst exam. The CFA Institute offers candidates various online resources, including message boards keyed to certain topics: One for each exam level, one for career advice, and so on. Of course the most popular board was the one labeled &#8220;Off-Topic,&#8221; where anything went&#8230;until it didn&#8217;t, in the opinion of the board&#8217;s lone paid moderator (who was a CFA candidate just like the rest of us).</p>
<p>In response to this official rebuke, some of the more social &#8220;Off-Topic&#8221; participants created a separate, password-protected board. In this we were led by the youngest of our group, a twenty-four-year-old credit analyst who had attended boarding school and who was quite accustomed to keeping track of her far-flung friends via the internet.</p>
<p>These CFA folks were my first nonlocal acquaintances. There were about a hundred of us on the board. I wound up meeting about a dozen of them in person, because CFA types tend to come through Boston frequently (for jobs or conferences or what-have-you). But I came to know the others — the ones whom I never met in person, but only interacted with online — reasonably well too: their personalities, their significant others, their vacations. I read the jokes they posted every Friday, and followed their job searches through various industries and occasionally across continents. I would never meet most of these people in person, but that didn&#8217;t dampen our interactions at all.</p>
<p>Next up was Gawker, where I became a commenter during my first year of law school. This wasn&#8217;t the wisest timing, of course — but looking back, it was kind of foreordained. There I was in grad school, mostly isolated from my &#8220;regular&#8221; (&#8220;IRL&#8221;) friends, with a computer open in front of me basically every waking hour. Under those circumstances, making new friends online can seem like the most natural thing in the world.</p>
<p>And ah, yes, Gawker. This isn&#8217;t a full-fledged memoir — I&#8217;ll save that for my literary agent — but man, the social aspect of that website really sparkled in the old days. I &#8220;met&#8221; dozens of folks — in the comments, via private message, and occasionally via e-mail. On Gawker, you usually encountered someone&#8217;s sense of humor first. Which is a pretty powerful and alluring way to meet someone.</p>
<p>And it can also be a high predictor for compatibility — maybe sometimes. In two exceptional cases I wound up having real-life encounters with women whom I &#8220;met&#8221; via Gawker private messages. I guess you could refer to these meetings as dates: first dates, I guess, but with a lot of familiarity already built in. One encounter turned out to be absolutely thrilling and changed my life utterly (if only temporarily). While the other rendezvous was unutterably sad, and to this day I thank my lucky stars that I managed to dodge an even more unfortunate outcome there.</p>
<p>By the time I joined Facebook — after being cajoled into it by a particular (and particularly charming) Gawker commenter — the idea of pursuing a mostly-online social life was no longer foreign to me. I was still in graduate school, and still in front of a computer sixteen hours a day. Joining Facebook allows you to keep in contact with your IRL friends as well, of course. But for me, Facebook is my primary (and usually sole) opportunity to engage with my online-only friends — those people whose real lives are still mostly unknown to me.</p>
<p>So now I&#8217;ve listed three possible sources of nonlocal acquaintances — but a full taxonomy could run to dozens of categories. Maybe hundreds. How interesting a topic would that be to revisit in twenty years or fifty: Collected reminiscences of all the ways in which people connected with each other, during the first decade-plus when social media existed? Additional sources I could cite would include 4chan, Reddit, and the much-mourned Wordsmoker. But who knows which online communities might be cited by other folks? Comment sections on NYT or Slate articles? DeviantART or Fetlife? Twitter? Consumer-product lifestyle forums masquerading as tech-help boards? (Apple, Honda&#8230;Astrogilde?) And good God, what about <i>Tumblr</i>? Think of all the Tumblrs out there; all of that reblogging must lead to <i>something</i> else, occasionally.</p>
<p>But an even more interesting inquiry might be: What unique kinds of <em>relationships</em> tend to spring from these sources? Most connections are probably fleeting and barely deserve to be named. While others develop into the types of IRL acquaintance-ships familiar from the pre-internet world. But what about those connections which don&#8217;t fit into traditional categories — those enduring but online-only connections? Might these be a qualitatively new development in most people&#8217;s experience? Does maintaining such a connection require new rules of etiquette, new protocols, different habits of emotional hygiene? What expectations are reasonable? Which possible paths might such a relationship follow? In my view, we&#8217;re still blinking in the dawn of this new development in modern social life. Who knows what the landscape might look like when the sun finally comes up?</p>
<p><em>Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/86530412@N02/8210762750/">Flirckr</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/irl-friendships-are-overrated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2012-13 NBA Western Conference Playoff Preview</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/2012-13-nba-western-conference-playoff-preview/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/2012-13-nba-western-conference-playoff-preview/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go spurs go]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBA playoffs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Western Conference]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124157</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Despite the 27 (nope not possible) 15 hour time difference, two of your favorite Crasstalk NBA enthusiasts were able to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/basketball.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-124218" alt="basketball" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/basketball-300x231.jpg" width="300" height="231" /></a>Despite the <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">27 (nope not possible)</span> 15 hour time difference, two of your favorite Crasstalk NBA enthusiasts were able to get together over gchat (h/t to Bots for the idea) to talk about the upcoming NBA Playoffs. Here&#8217;s a transcript of the conversation I had with BaldwinP last weekend.<span id="more-124157"></span></p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: OK, so: the West to start with?</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: sure</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: For the sake of the readers: let us just say that this preview is totally not going to be biased towards the Spurs and the Heat.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Well, I&#8217;ll do what I can.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: First, we should address the gigantic elephant that just appeared in the room with the West playoffs- Kobe Bryant&#8217;s injury. Not that I believe the Lakers were going anywhere even if Kobe was fit and IF the Lakers make 8th, but still.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: So, Lakers keep the last spot or does it go to Utah?</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: I think the Lakers hang on- the rest of the team should fire up for the last 2 games and Utah seem incapable of helping themselves. I also think that either the Lakers or Utah get swept 4-0 by either the Thunder or Spurs.</p>
<p>Both conferences this year are great argument these days for having a wild card playoff for 8th&#8230; wouldn&#8217;t it better to see Dallas with a fit Dirk or Washington with a fit Wall in 8th rather than the lame ducks that will make it? But it is what it is. What do you think?</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: I have to agree that the Lakers won&#8217;t go anywhere in the first round. Too much drama all season long that affected their play. I think Thunder and Spurs stay 1 and 2. Thunder demolish the Lakers. What is this about a wild card playoff? I don&#8217;t like that for basketball.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: It&#8217;s a shame that the Thunder will finish top &#8211; we all wanted to see the Thunder against Harden&#8217;s Houston in the playoffs.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Yeah, that would have been awesome.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: Bill Simmons among others has suggested a playoff for 8th spot among the next few teams so that there&#8217;s more reason for a team to fight for 7th and for teams just out of the playoffs to keep fighting to the end as well. And so a team which was injured early and then comes good, like Washington this year, can be in the playoffs instead of a lousy team like the Bucks.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Yeah, I was surprised to see the Bucks where they are.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: Anyway, the West: yeah, Thunder to demolish the Lakers. Spurs to beat Houston 4-1. Houston takes more 3s than any team in the league, and at least one game they&#8217;ll go berserk from downtown. But ultimately the Spurs are too experienced and deep, even with Ginobili hurt and Jackson kicked off the team.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: That move totally shocked me, by the way.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: Me too. Couldn&#8217;t they cope with Captain Jack in the locker room for a couple more weeks? It&#8217;s playoff time!</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Ha! Though, now that I think about it, I was shocked when they re-signed him. Was that this year? Last year?</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: Last year- they got him in a trade for Richard Jefferson&#8217;s awful contract.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Oh, god. Yes, now I remember. How I want to forget all about Richard Jefferson.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP: </b>I bet Golden State wishes the same. At least this was Jack&#8217;s last year. Jefferson&#8217;s contract has another year to run. Denver is currently in 3rd&#8230; I think they&#8217;ll hang on and get a date with Golden State (segue!)</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: That should be a fun series to watch.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: All offense!</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Like, 250 points per game.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: They&#8217;re such weirdly different teams for all they&#8217;re all O no D teams. Denver basically drives on every possession and Golden State either jack up 3s or have Lee score in the post.</p>
<p>If not for injuries I&#8217;d say Denver for sure. Denver has so much quality cover for Gallinari, and Lawson returned yesterday, so I&#8217;m still saying Denver. Home court advantage at altitude&#8230; I think they have the equal best home record, with Miami, and just hard to go past that.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Yeah, I always forget about the altitude in Denver. They actually have a better home record that MIA by one game. I guess I&#8217;ll have to go with Denver, too. Clippers/Memphis: When I looked at the standings, I didn&#8217;t realize how high up the Grizz were. Then I remembered they were basically unstoppable at the beginning of the season</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: Once they got rid of Rudy Gay and the team got over moping about it, they&#8217;ve been really fantastic again. Jerryd Bayless must be in the running for the most weirdly relevant player on a contender. (ok, there&#8217;s also Reggie Evans at the Nets.) But the way the Grizz got better by losing a &#8220;star&#8221; like Gay says a lot about the real value of inefficient scorers. A lot of front offices will have taken notice.</p>
<p>As for who&#8217;s going to win&#8230; well, Clippers/Memphis went 7 last year and the Clips won. And that was with home court for Memphis, which they may or may not have this time. But that&#8217;s last year. I think both teams are better this year&#8230; very close call.</p>
<p>What do you think?</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: I think I have to go with the Clippers. (Jesus, I&#8217;m realizing now just how much I have not paid attention to basketball this year.) But, I still take the Clippers.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: I think I&#8217;ll take the Grizz, in 7, with Vinny Del Nergo fired and replaced by a Van Gundy. Their defense is just so good.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Oh, VDN. Way to fail upward.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: Watching the Clippers is just like&#8230; SO much talent, but so disorganized. It&#8217;s fashionable to rip on VDN&#8230; but there&#8217;s good reason. CP3 can run the offence but defensively they&#8217;re so random.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Honestly, his Bulls job was such a fluke. I was really surprised when he got ANOTHER head coaching job. I wish someone would have just hired him as an assistant or something so he could learn some things.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: He&#8217;ll do OK when the Clips fire him. A team like the Bucks or the Pistons will hire him on his win percentage.</p>
<p>Anyway&#8230; that gives us Thunder-Clips/Grizz and Spurs-Denver. How do you think the West shakes out then?</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: I think the Thunder are gonna win that series. And I have no idea what is happening with my Spurs. Too many injuries and losing to teams we should beat late in the season. I&#8217;d go with Denver to win that series in like 6 or 7. Thunder to win the West again, I think.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: I can agree with all that. The Thunder are so much better defensively this year than last year (so are the Spurs, actually). That has kind of got lost in all the talk about what they&#8217;ve lost offensively with Harden. When push comes to shove I can&#8217;t see them losing a 7 game series to anyone buy Miami, although I think both the Grizz and Denver can make it close.</p>
<p>Although I think you&#8217;re being pessimistic about the Spurs. I don&#8217;t think they care too much down this part of the season, but they&#8217;ll be &#8220;alright on the night&#8221; as they say. Duncan has been awesome this season.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Just Duncan being Duncan. I feel like every time he has a good year we just call it &#8220;vintage Duncan&#8221;</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: True. He should get some MVP votes (not first place votes, but down the ballot). Hard to split who has been the Spurs&#8217; best player, him or Parker.</p>
<p>A two-headed monster called &#8220;Punkan&#8221; maybe. Punkin&#8217; opponents every night. Sorry, that was awful. We should edit it out (<i>not happening Baldwin!</i>).</p>
<p>It wouldn&#8217;t surprise me if we end up with Thunder-Spurs again, but it would surprise me if the Spurs won this time. Just because I don&#8217;t see what&#8217;s changed since last year to put the Spurs ahead.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Not much has changed. Except we don&#8217;t have (Stephen) Jackson any more. I feel like he was a bit of a spark. Though, his numbers were down this season.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: And they don&#8217;t have James Harden. Which I guess is the wildcard- how the Thunder will play in playoffs basketball with Martin (who has bugger all playoff experience) instead of Harden.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: I would love to see a Thunder-Spurs rematch.</p>
<p><b>BaldwinP</b>: We could get it. Denver won&#8217;t have home court advantage over the Spurs and their defense is really bad. Ginobili should be OK by the 2nd round.</p>
<p><b>clarity83</b>: Yeah. So, East?</p>
<p>I got this ETA From Baldwin via email on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>Addendum to our NBA piece:  Thanks to Houston losing to PHOENIX, it turns out if the Rockets lose to the Lakers on April 17 the Rockets will end up in 8th against the 1st seeded Thunder.  This is too delicious to not happen.  I now have to cheer the Lakers.  Thanks so much to the Spurs, Rockets and Jazz whose terrible losses led to this scenario becoming possible.</p>
<p><em>Tomorrrow: Look for our thoughts on who wins the East, who takes it all and who wins all the awards.</em></p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/paukrus/4059718063/">Flickr</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/2012-13-nba-western-conference-playoff-preview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Trek vs Superman: A Tale of Two Trailers</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/star-trek-vs-superman-a-tale-of-two-trailers/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/star-trek-vs-superman-a-tale-of-two-trailers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CaptainSnarky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trailers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124208</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Both Man of Steel, the Superman movie franchise reboot, and Star Trek released their third and possibly final full-length trailers. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Both <em>Man of Steel</em>, the Superman movie franchise reboot, and <em>Star Trek</em> released their third and possibly final full-length trailers. As a die-hard fan of both Superman and Star Trek, I cannot help but notice that these trailers present very divergent understandings of their respective source material. I look at both these trailers and think that both are visual feasts, but only the <em>Man of Steel</em> trailer gets the essence of the source material, while JJ Abrams’s <em>Star Trek Into Darkness</em> trailer highlights action and adventure, but precious little else to distinguish it from any other large-scale space opera.<span id="more-124208"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="654" height="368" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/5ec_rPApKCA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>While <em>Star Trek</em> has almost always been full of action and adventure, the Abrams reboot of the Star Trek franchise appears to want nothing to do with the cerebral, contemplative aspects that undergirded the television series as well as the movies starring the original cast. As a master of showmanship, Abrams has had the fanboys and girls buzzing about Benedict Cumberbatch’s “John Harrison”—<em>is</em> he actually John Harrison, or is he playing some other re-imagined villain from Trek lore?</p>
<p>What we do know—and what this latest trailer reinforces—is that Harrison has some kind of mad-on about Starfleet, to the point that he is going to cause massive destruction. And I do mean massive. Instead of lens flares, Abrams will give us unending explosions. Everything’s blowing up, and exploding, and falling out of the sky, and growling that “Your world is not safe,” but I don’t know what makes this Star Trek. Sure, it’s great spectacle—the visuals from the trailer are gorgeous and I’m a sucker for Federation starships firing phasers and photon torpedoes, but I’m also a sucker for Captain Kirk, Mr. Spock, Dr. McCoy and Scotty, Uhura, Chekhov, and Sulu boldly going to other worlds and seeking out and finding new lifeforms and new civilizations. Or, as Q pointed out to Captain Picard, charting the possibilities of human existence. That is what makes Star Trek different from other science fiction franchises and appears to be sorely lacking in all of the promotion of <em>Into Darkness</em>.</p>
<p><iframe width="654" height="368" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/T6DJcgm3wNY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>And then there’s the new trailer for the Superman reboot. Fanboys and girls have been fairly anxious about <em>Man of Steel</em>, especially after Bryan Singer’s <em>Superman Returns</em> failed to become a super-blockbuster. Oh, sure, it did respectable box office, but too many people thought it was a slavish remake of Superman: The Movie, or that the movie was too somnolent, or that Brandon Routh was just plain dull as Superman/Clark Kent, or that there simply wasn’t enough action in the movie.</p>
<p>Well, not so with <em>Man of Steel</em>, if this final full trailer is any indication. Oh, yes, there will be explosions—lots of them, and there will be massive destruction. However, this trailer shows that while this movie will be a retelling of Superman’s origins and will have a villain we’ve seen before in the form of General Zod, this will be its own movie without sacrificing things that we know are necessary for a Superman movie to be faithful to the Superman mythos. Superman may be more angsty than in the Richard Donner movies, but he retains his altruism and isn&#8217;t stalking an engaged and miscast Lois Lane. Krypton may be re-imagined to be a futuristic medieval planet, but it is still doomed, and Kal-El is sent to Earth to be raised by Jonathan and Martha Kent. There are tweaks and changes here and there—most notably the hint that Lois Lane has been on Kal-El’s trail for a while and will meet Superman before Clark Kent starts working at the Daily Planet…assuming that Clark will even work at the Planet in these movies.</p>
<p>While the Star Trek trailer has lowered my expectations for <em>Into Darkness</em>, the latest <em>Man of Steel</em> trailer has raised my expectations and has allayed my reservations about this reboot. The images in this trailer are flashy, but they show promising and exciting balance between the super and the man. If the final product is anything like the trailer, <em>Man of Steel</em> may just raise the bar for science fiction/superhero movies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/star-trek-vs-superman-a-tale-of-two-trailers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/thursday-open-thread-73/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/thursday-open-thread-73/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=124174</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a test. Symmetry from Everynone on Vimeo. Image source Wikimedia]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a test.<span id="more-124174"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/22564317?title=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/22564317">Symmetry</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/everynone">Everynone</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Image source <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg" target="_blank">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/thursday-open-thread-73/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Abandoned Places</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/three-abandoned-places-6/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/three-abandoned-places-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>LaZiguezon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abandoned places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chacachacare Island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greece]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Republic of Trinidad and Tobago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ross Island in the Andaman and Nicobar Islands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spinalonga Island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urbex]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122826</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today’s installment in our series on abandoned places takes us to forsaken islands. Let the Lord of the Flies commentary begin. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today’s installment in our series on abandoned places takes us to forsaken islands. Let the <em>Lord of the Flies</em> commentary begin.<span id="more-122826"></span></p>
<p><strong>1. Spinalonga Island, Crete, Greece</strong></p>
<p>Oh Greece, I don’t think you’ve ever recovered for having murdered Socrates,* and I may have never rebounded from my philosophy 101 course. Instead, let us focus on an abandoned fortress island. Spinalonga was once part of the island of Crete until the Venetians arrived in the 15th century and carved out a section of the peninsula to establish an 8.5-hectare island. The fortified island was built to protect Venetian trade routes, particularly the entrance-way to the ancient port of Olous. Overtaken by the Ottoman Empire in 1715, Spinalonga eventually served as a Leper colony (1903-1957) following Crete&#8217;s independence. Unoccupied, the site remains a popular tourist attraction. The warmest of thanks to DaisyWalker for having suggested the bulk of the featured locations.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Spinalogka-panoramic.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123588" alt="Spinalogka- panoramic" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Spinalogka-panoramic.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Spinalonga_Island.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123596" alt="Spinalonga_Island" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Spinalonga_Island.jpg" width="550" height="413" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_123593" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 550px"><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Lion_of_St_Mark_in_Spinalonga_fort.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-123593" alt="Lion_of_St_Mark_in_Spinalonga_fort" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Lion_of_St_Mark_in_Spinalonga_fort.jpg" width="550" height="413" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color: #000000;">I wish I owned a real life version of whatever this is.</span></p></div>
<p><strong>2. Ross Island in the Andaman and Nicobar Islands, India</strong></p>
<p>Located in the Andaman archipelago, Ross Island acted as the residential headquarters for the British administration of the Indian Penal Settlement. The penal colony was established in 1857 for the sole purpose of jailing individuals who challenged British occupation. Rocked by an earthquake in 1941, the small island was divested of its administrative powers and now serves as a popular tourist spot.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ross_Island_Andaman.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123614" alt="Ross_Island_Andaman" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ross_Island_Andaman.jpg" width="550" height="413" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ross-Island-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123611" alt="Ross Island - 1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ross-Island-1.jpg" width="550" height="407" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ross-Island-3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123617" alt="Ross Island- 3" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Ross-Island-3.jpg" width="550" height="413" /></a></p>
<p><strong>3. Chacachacare Island, Republic of Trinidad and Tobago</strong></p>
<p>Chacachacare is a fantastic name for an island. Say it out loud. Go on. There&#8217;s just something Cha-ca-cha-care-ly-charming about it, no? Located northwest of Trinidad, the island was once used as a Spanish whaling station in the 17th century, a sugar, apple and cotton plantation in the 18th century, followed by a leper colony managed by Dominican nuns in the 19th century. Uninhabited except for a few lighthouse caretakers, Chacachacare is also believed to be haunted. Like by a creepy love-stricken lantern wielding nun. Let&#8217;s visit!</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Chacachacare-island.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123609" alt="Chacachacare - island" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Chacachacare-island.jpg" width="550" height="414" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Chacachacare-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123607" alt="Chacachacare-1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Chacachacare-1.jpg" width="550" height="413" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Chacachacare2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123603" alt="Chacachacare" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Chacachacare2.jpg" width="550" height="370" /></a></p>
<p>*I&#8217;m choosing to ignore the fundamental impact – well according to Wikipedia – of ancient Greek&#8217;s Hellenistic civilization. Boring.</p>
<p>For previous entries, please click <a href="http://crasstalk.com/tag/abandoned-places/">here</a>.</p>
<p>(Images c/o <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:20090620_Spinalogka_Elounta_panoramic_view_from_the_mountain.jpg">1</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Spinalonga_Island-8.JPG">2</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Lion_of_St_Mark_in_Spinalonga_fort.jpg">3</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ross_Island_Andaman_4140061.JPG">4</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pandiyan/3622076114/">5</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Ross_Island_Andaman_4140027.JPG">6</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Huevos_and_Second_Boca,_Trinidad.jpg">7</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Chacachacare.JPG">8</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mmorgan8186/3422465969/">9</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/three-abandoned-places-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.355 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-19 09:03:42 -->
