<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:00:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/monday-open-thread-73/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/monday-open-thread-73/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122943</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good day and welcome to Crasstalk. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Capri_Centre_Belvedere.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122946" alt="Capri_Centre_Belvedere" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Capri_Centre_Belvedere.jpg" width="800" height="390" /></a> Good day and welcome to Crasstalk. <span id="more-122943"></span></p>
<p><object width="560" height="315"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/P6zcSFA7ymo?version=3&amp;hl=en_GB"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/P6zcSFA7ymo?version=3&amp;hl=en_GB" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="560" height="315" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Capri_Centre_Belvedere.jpg">Wikipedia</a>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/monday-open-thread-73/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thoughts on the Day of Zombie Jesus</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thoughts-on-the-day-of-zombie-jesus/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thoughts-on-the-day-of-zombie-jesus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 21:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mean Ol Liberal</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Spirituality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122893</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This morning, I saw the following Facebook post from a relative whose worldview I admire: “This day commemorates the day [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This morning, I saw the following Facebook post from a relative whose worldview I admire:</p>
<p><i>“This day commemorates the day that everything changed in the world&#8230;the concept of putting others ahead of ourselves was born today, hope was born today.”</i></p>
<p>He was commenting on an <a href="http://www.summit.org/blogs/the-point/too-good-to-be-false/" target="_blank">article</a> he’d read with which he said he wholeheartedly agrees.<span id="more-122893"></span></p>
<p>For my part, as a Friend (Quaker), I address the question of Jesus’ divinity differently than that author does. Friends believe that god is a spirit that lives in <span style="text-decoration: underline;">all</span> human beings (the Light Within), Jesus of Nazareth included. We see him as exceptional among mankind only because we regard him as a person of perfect Light. As a Messiah of his time, he showed and told us all how to make life on earth a paradise for everyone. Christians aren&#8217;t to sit around waiting for paradise to materialize for them. They can follow Jesus&#8217; example and <em>make</em> it happen.</p>
<p>It doesn’t matter if Christians engage in this work together with persons of other faiths or with those for whom faith holds no interest. In fact, working across theological boundaries is the only way the maximum amount of good works could be accomplished. What matters most is that we act to ease the suffering of others as soon and as much as we can.</p>
<p>Live in peace. Heal the sick. Feed and help the poor. Clothe the naked. Visit the lonely. Befriend the oppressed. Love your enemies as you try to see things from their perspective. Love each other. These are the things Jesus commanded and did in the Gospels. Friends believe that this is the work laid out for us if we are to bring about our “salvation” &#8211; that is, <em>everybody&#8217;s</em> life in a peaceable kingdom. It’s not in some spiritual realm after death; it’s in the here and now.</p>
<p>But, as my cousin noted in his post this morning, these seemingly simple nations weren’t always. Siddhartha Gautama (Buddha) showed the world how to alleviate one’s <em>own</em> suffering. This was an important path to spiritual salvation too, but it was only part of the answer. Judaic law and practice gave the world an example of a people who worked together for the salvation of future generations, but, at the time, such was concentrated among their nation and theirs is not a missionary faith. </p>
<p>Even in the time of the Roman Empire, the social contract on which Rome had been built was borne more of the mutual benefit to equally predatory powers rather than a desire for improvements for the benefit of all mankind. Any improvements made to the lifestyles of the residents of occupied areas were of pure coincidence.  Rome was always at war, even during the <em>Pax Romana</em>. Within its borders, life was only slightly more secure for the average individual. Most within the borders lived in dire poverty. At the height of Roman power, a third of the empire&#8217;s population were slaves.</p>
<p>My cousin is right; the western world <em>changed</em> once Christianity took hold among the people who would embrace it. Through the Dark Ages, Europe slowly emerged from its history of constant war waged by warlords who sought to please their gods by being superior killers. The continent would evolve to a collection of nations led by men who were no less comfortable with violence than their predecessors had been, but who now seemed to care that they were viewed as better, more reasonable men. </p>
<p>The linked article&#8217;s author presents his beliefs as to why that might have been. My view is that it doesn’t matter why. What matters is that the message got through, no matter how slowly. No one is arguing that any ancient European king went from being a Viking conqueror to being Mother Theresa overnight. The fact remains that <em>something</em> happened to lead those kings away from their warlike gods with plenty of their own powerful magic and towards one who never used his magic for selfish ends and who preached a word of peace.</p>
<p>Many have argued that Jesus of Nazareth didn’t exist at all. I’ve come to the conclusion that it doesn’t matter if he didn’t. <em>Someone</em> came up with the principles embraced in the story of Jesus’ life. Those principles; Peace, Truth, Simplicity and Equality had not enjoyed widespread embrace in western mythology before the spread of the Gospels. My personal belief is that there was some Jewish reformer with a name like “Jesus” who lived in Judea at the time of Roman occupation and who spoke out against the wealthy and powerful exploiting the poor and weak with impunity. Even if it was all made up by some anonymous storyteller 200 years later, then those revolutionary values are <em>still</em> those of that author. What does it matter what his name was?</p>
<p>Many will argue that supernatural elements were inserted into the story in order to cater to an Iron Age audience to sell the story for the storyteller’s own ends. I’ll admit that I doubt much of the magic in the story myself. Maybe this story was built around a man who had better medical knowledge than others around him, so the authors saw the deeds as magical. Maybe it was all made up. But what would it matter if it were? The modern mind doesn’t need the supernatural elements to persuade it towards valuing a message of building a better world for ourselves. And what would have been the storytellers’ end, anyway? To spread a message of peace? I’m OK with that end.</p>
<p>Yes, men will exploit myths to enhance their own power over large populations, but clerics of the ancient religions did that too. Even during Christianity’s darkest periods of corruption in the Church, more people lived in peace while those same corrupt clerics threatened would-be war-making kings with ex-Communication should they wage their profit wars on the wrong country. Even when these power brokers merely wore the appearance of worship of a God of Peace, it meant a world of difference to hundreds of thousands of powerless individuals in their respective realms. Does the end justify the means?  Not always. But in this case, the desirable end of greater peace and stability for the greater number of people clearly defined better means as things went on. Witness:  In the modern world, there are millions of people who work for the betterment of humanity simply because they believe it’s what needs to be done.</p>
<p>So what are we to make of this lingering story of Jesus of Nazareth; tortured to death by the foreign power occupying his homeland all for the offense of his preaching a message of peace and equality? Did he really rise from the dead three days after his death, showing the world that he could conquer even physical death?</p>
<p>If the story contained in the Gospels is to be taken as fractionally true; that there really was a Jewish reformer with a name like “Jesus” who spoke out against the abuses of concentrated power and wealth; who pleaded for the value of the individual; and who was executed by the reigning power of the time – his <i>message</i> lived long past that execution, didn’t it?</p>
<p>What does it matter if the story of the resurrection is real or not? <em>All</em> of mankind’s revolutionaries die at some point. It&#8217;s when their message lives on that they could be said to have truly &#8220;conquered death&#8221;.  When I die, I fully expect that my body will remain dead for good. However, I hope to live my life in a manner that allows <em>me</em> to &#8220;conquer death&#8221; in much the same way that Jesus clearly did.</p>
<p>To celebrate Easter, a feast of rebirth and renewed life, that’s all I need to believe.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/145369">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thoughts-on-the-day-of-zombie-jesus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recipe Sunday: Steel Cut Oats with Berries</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-steel-cut-oats-with-berries/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-steel-cut-oats-with-berries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 14:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>GtCosita</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oatmeal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steel cut oats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yum]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122855</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have never been a fan of warm oatmeal. As much as I love including rolled oats in my cookies, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have never been a fan of warm oatmeal. As much as I love including rolled oats in my <a href="http://crasstalk.com/2011/02/recipe-sunday-double-chocolate-oatmeal-cookies/" target="_blank">cookies</a>, I could never get over the mushy texture and blandness of the typical oatmeal breakfast. I started hearing interesting things about steel cut oats, that the oatmeal was &#8220;nutty&#8221; and &#8220;crunchy&#8221;, so I decided to give them a try.<span id="more-122855"></span> The instructions in the back of the container do a good job of giving you very good oatmeal, but I decided to incorporate a few tips from <a href="http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/alton-brown/steel-cut-oatmeal-recipe/index.html" target="_blank">Alton Brown</a>, as well as add some mixed warm berries, to take this breakfast to the next level. Be warned that steel cut oatmeal will take up to 45 minutes to cook, but you can make a large batch in advance and reheat portions in the microwave. Just add a splash of milk before you hit Start. Serves 4.</p>
<p><em>Ingredients</em></p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup steel cut oats</li>
<li>3 cups water</li>
<li>1 cup milk</li>
<li>1 tablespoon brown sugar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon granulated sugar (optional)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon butter</li>
<li>1/2 cup mixed frozen berries (you can cut up fresh berries)</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Preparation</em><br />
Melt butter over medium heat. Add oats and stir for two minutes. Add the water and bring to a boil. Turn heat to low and keep the oats simmering for 30 minutes, stirring occasionally. Add milk and brown sugar, simmer for an additional 10 to 15 minutes. Meanwhile, place berries in a bowl, sprinkle sugar on top, and place in the microwave for 1 to 2 minutes. You want the berries to be mushy. Serve the oatmeal topped with the berries.</p>
<p>Photo: GtCosita</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-steel-cut-oats-with-berries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-87/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-87/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122688</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You don&#8217;t write me love songs. Upside Down, Left To Right: A Letterpress Film from Danny Cooke on Vimeo. Image [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You don&#8217;t write me love songs.<span id="more-122688"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/35688592?portrait=0&amp;color=ffffff" height="281" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/35688592">Upside Down, Left To Right: A Letterpress Film</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/dannycooke">Danny Cooke</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/84266">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-87/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>War Stories from the Front Line of College Admissions</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/war-stories-from-the-front-line-of-college-admissions/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/war-stories-from-the-front-line-of-college-admissions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>GloriousShoes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Servicey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entitlement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher Ed]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122758</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over at Crassparenting, I&#8217;ve shared my thoughts for parents about how to prepare their students for the college admissions process. Knowing [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over at Crassparenting, I&#8217;ve <a href="http://crassparenting.com/2013/03/getting-into-college-part-i/">shared my thoughts</a> for parents about how to prepare their students for the college admissions process. Knowing my audience, I thought that Crasstalkers would rather hear the war stories from my odd job.</p>
<p><strong>There are stupid questions: </strong>One father asked in front of 600 people if our food service had diet food because his fat daughter couldn&#8217;t afford to gain the Freshman 15. <span id="more-122758"></span> A mom asked me on a tour if undergrads could study in the law or med school libraries. The mom went on to explain that the boys on our campus weren&#8217;t that attractive, and that surely her daughter would date all the appropriately attractive boys well before she graduated. The mom also preferred that her daughter marry a doctor or lawyer.</p>
<p><strong>Not the time or the place</strong>: While touring UC-Berkeley, we stopped in front of the Free Speech Movement Cafe where the tour guide (the sweet, physics major, 19 year old tour guide who did this for his work study job) told the story of the Free Speech Movement. A dad started to go on a fairly epic and racist rant about Ronald Reagan, godless Berkeley, his tax payer money supporting this communism. The tour guide was flummoxed, so I turned to the dad and quietly said that he could probably save these comments for later. The dad started shouting at me that I was a communist feminazi. His kid, with his white kid dreds and sweet Bob Marley shirt, melted into the ground and the dad was escorted off the tour.</p>
<p><strong>Killing Dreams</strong>: I met with a family to assess the student&#8217;s record and college wish list. The student had a clear vision of herself as an applicant, the mother was more aspirational. I was shooting down ideas right and left. Not Stanford, not Harvard, not Brown or Williams. Maybe USC and Colgate. The mother started to sob and through her tears sneered at me, &#8220;They should change your job title from College Counselor to Dream Killer.&#8221; At the end of the school year, the mom brought me half-dead flowers, saying that the flowers represented her dreams for her daughter.</p>
<p><strong>The Holiday Card Party</strong>: A student was applying to her dad&#8217;s alma mater, an extremely selective college that was beyond her reach. Since she applied Early Decision to this college, the student would have the decision in mid-December, just in time for the family to send holiday cards. The mom decided to announce the student&#8217;s college decision via holiday card. The family posed for two holiday portraits, one with the student in the college&#8217;s sweatshirt, the other without. The mom had 300 of each card produced and addressed, and every day she would ask the student, &#8220;Which card are we going to send?&#8221; To raise the stakes, the mom thought it would be fun to throw a party around opening the college decision. The mom billed the event as the Holiday Card Party: come see which holiday card we&#8217;re going to send this year! So the student learned that he did not get into his father&#8217;s alma mater nor a favored state university in front of 30 people.</p>
<p><strong>My Shame Stings:</strong> I was on the phone with a mom whose daughter was admitted to Williams, Amherst, and Pomona, but shut out of the Ivies. It was May, and I thought that the mom had calmed down as the daughter was extremely happy to attend Amherst. I ended the phone conversation by telling the mom that I would see her at the honor society induction ceremony in which her daughter would be honored. The mom refused to attend. She said that her daughter had not earned the honor because she had not been admitted to an Ivy. The mom said, &#8220;My shame stings too much to be seen at school.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/war-stories-from-the-front-line-of-college-admissions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-92/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-92/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122682</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That sounds good. I&#8217;ll have that. EAT from Rick Mereki on Vimeo. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That sounds good. I&#8217;ll have that.<span id="more-122682"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/27243869?color=ffffff" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/27243869">EAT</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/rickmereki">Rick Mereki</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/651218">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-92/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Nature: The River</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/adventures-in-nature-the-river/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/adventures-in-nature-the-river/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 19:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ihatediamonds</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Misspent Youth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Great Outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Sports]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122806</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Summer of 2008: Bellevue, WA I was home after spending the last nine months traveling around the United States and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/640px-Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-122810" alt="640px-Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/640px-Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" /></a>Summer of 2008: Bellevue, WA</p>
<p>I was home after spending the last nine months traveling around the United States and Canada and working in an office full of my fellow 20-something travelers, booking next year&#8217;s adventures. We were a restless bunch. Constantly inventing games and contests to alleviate the boredom of spending eight hours in neighboring cubicles.<span id="more-122806"></span></p>
<p>One day, our ringleader suggested we all go tubing after work one afternoon. A day, in high summer, in the the Seattle-area, goes on until about 10pm, so there&#8217;s plenty of time in the evening for adventures.</p>
<p>Over the next week, we voted on locations. None of us were particularly outdoorsy or had any experience traversing the many major and minor waterways within a 30 minute drive from the comfortable suburb of Bellevue, but debate we did. We settled on the Tolt River, a tributary of the Snoqualmie River, about a forty minute drive into the foothills of the neighboring Cascade mountains. A couple days before the trip, three of us took a trip to a sporting goods store to procure inner tubes. Imagining that this would be a leisurely trip, down a lazy river, our purchases were geared more for style than durability or practicality. One friend, the weakest swimmer of the bunch, bought a flying saucer tube that came complete with built in water gun.</p>
<p>The day of our adventure was a rare, hot day in the Northwest and we were all excited to hit the river. We escaped en masse a bit early and headed east. Our caravan stopped in a tiny one stoplight town just before the turn off for the mountain road, to pick up an obscene amount of beer and cigarettes for spliffs. The dirty looks were plentiful. Rural Washingtonians don&#8217;t like city kids using their towns as rec rooms.</p>
<p>The drive up the hill should have tipped us off that this wasn&#8217;t going to be a lazy, warm trip down a calm water way. We could see brief glimpses of white water out of our windows and it was a fairly steep incline. But dumb people are dumb and once we arrived at what someone in the lead car randomly determined to be a good distance from where we left our base car, we all bounced out, eager to get going.</p>
<p>The water was cold. Not just cold but, &#8220;Fuck, this may be an incredibly terrible idea, oh jesus&#8230; FUCK&#8221; cold. Later research turned up that the Tolt was fed almost exclusively by glacier run-off. We slowly made our way in, no one wanting to be the one who cried reasonableness. You could tell from the rocky, steep bank, that made a terrible entrance point, the water was moving swiftly. My best friend Joe* was the first in and the water promptly took him with his t-shirt wrapped chicly around his head, expensive sunglasses perched on his nose, cigarette behind his ear, and his fancy tube filled with beer and flipped him ass over head and tangled hi tube in branches lining the far bank. I&#8217;ve never laughed so hard. He lost everything to the river and basically had to gnaw his tube free. By time he made his bedraggled way back into his tube, the rest of us were on our way.</p>
<p>It got real around the first bend.</p>
<p>None of us thought about packing life jackets or helmet and I was incredibly aware that at least one of us was an incredibly weak swimmer, and that person also had the flotation devise that was least equipped to deal with even slightly rough water and we were facing what looked like possibly a class two rapid directly ahead.</p>
<p>Though my raft was comically not suited for the task ahead, it was at least small enough that I could get enough of my arms in the water to paddle and steer. My girlfriends who had purchased bigger, fancier tubes were not so lucky. There was a lot of screaming and shouting. A lot of &#8220;Use your legs!&#8221; &#8220;Fuck!&#8221; when someone would slam into a submerged part of a boulder they thought they had avoided.</p>
<p>We all made it to the other side. Luckily our weak swimmer had somehow ended up flush against the far bank had had missed the worst of it. Everyone who wore flip flops into the water was now barefoot. The water was plaid now. We managed to scrounge up a beer for everyone and we all guzzled, relieved and a bit giddy. If only we knew what lay ahead in two bends.</p>
<p>This set of rapids was definitely a two. A tough two. A ton of boulders, lots of churn spots. And it came on quickly. I got caught on a boulder early and was bounced out of my tube. I was wearing Keens which had a thick rubber toe and as I quickly got sucked down the rapids away from my tube they actually provided a useful buffer, until I got stuck in a spot of churning water and my thick, rubber covered toe got caught in between two rocks. I&#8217;m a strong swimmer and I don&#8217;t panic in water, but I remember very clearly thinking that I was going to die. Then, of course, I managed to kick my foot free and somehow made it to the end and found my tube that someone had freed from the boulder.</p>
<p>There was no more beer to celebrate with or really any will to celebrate. Our weak swimmer was doubled up with one of the guys and everyone looked like they had also had their own moment with death and we still had one major hurdle to go. Our exit point was right at the point where the Tolt fed into the Snoqualmie. The water was fast and you had to bail and swim for the sandy bank fairly quickly or end up in the Snoqualmie which fed the eponymous fall not too far away. We lost some rafts, but everyone made it out safely.</p>
<p>While driving down the hill towards home, exhausted and shaken, we saw several emergency vehicles heading the opposite direction, sirens blaring.</p>
<p>&#8230;&#8230;</p>
<p>Later that night, while recovering with soup, I saw an ad for the local news that made me stay awake for the broadcast.  The second story was about a drowning. Three guys had decided to go tubing on the Tolt River just like us that day. They must have only been an hour or so  ahead of us. One of them didn&#8217;t make it out of the rapids.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.valleyrecord.com/news/27443774.html">Snoqualmie Valley Record</a></p>
<p>*Names changed to protect my fellow idiots.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Aberglaslyn_xWHR_MMB_03.jpg">Wikimedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/adventures-in-nature-the-river/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flashback Friday: Foreigner Edition</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/flashback-friday-foreigner-edition/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/flashback-friday-foreigner-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 16:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[80s rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flashback Friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[why the mustache simon le bon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122777</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[No, not this Foreigner (well it could be), but any band or artist that came from beyond your own borders [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No, not this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=loWXMtjUZWM" target="_blank">Foreigner</a> (well it could be), but any band or artist that came from beyond your own borders and took your musical heart by storm. For Americans, the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WHuRusAlw-Y" target="_blank">British invasion</a> hasn&#8217;t really stopped, though it seems to ebb and flow. The lads from Madness sent me crashing through my living room dancing to this many afternoons watching MTV after school.</p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/KwIe_sjKeAY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><br />
<span id="more-122777"></span></p>
<p>But it was my then future husband, Simon Le Bon, who sealed my love for English rock boys. I nearly broke my neck <a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/MR.gif" target="_blank">dancing</a> to their music.</p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/18xwfGTgVRc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/flashback-friday-foreigner-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Allan J. Eastman, Aged 19</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Karyn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Respect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122626</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 29th is Vietnam Veterans Day.  It marks the day the last American combat troops were finally withdrawn from Vietnam, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-122629" alt="Vietnam" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Vietnam-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">March 29th is Vietnam Veterans Day.  It marks the day the last American combat troops were finally withdrawn from Vietnam, forty years ago.</span></p>
<p>Well, not all of them. 1600 troops are still officially missing in Vietnam.</p>
<p>I grew up with Vietnam hanging over my family. My grandmother was a Gold Star Mother, which is what the government calls you when you&#8217;ve lost a child in war. She never rode in the Veterans Day parades on that sad float with all the other mothers in Belmont, Massachusetts (not Mitt Romney&#8217;s side of town) who had lost their sons. But Uncle Allan&#8217;s name is etched in granite in the town square. <span id="more-122626"></span></p>
<p>My uncle, <a href="http://www.vvmf.org/thewall/Wall_Id_No=14521">Allan John Eastman</a>, was born in 1950. My grandmother and mother always spoke of him as a good boy, a saint. But there were stories. He famously &#8216;borrowed&#8217; an MTA bus left idling by a driver who stopped for a break and took it for a joyride up Trapelo Road towards Watertown, taking off down the side streets before the cops could catch him. Every time I ride the #71 bus out of Harvard Square, I imagine him giggling his ass off, running for home.</p>
<p>He enlisted in the Army and was sent out.</p>
<p>Uncle Allan was shot and died of malaria on November 9, 1969.  He was 19.</p>
<p>I finally got to Washington to see Uncle Allan&#8217;s name on<a href="http://thewall-usa.com/information.asp"> The Vietnam Veterans Memorial</a> a few years ago.  If you&#8217;ve never seen The Wall, it&#8217;s extraordinary.  It&#8217;s sweeping and dark and seems to go on forever, like that war did. There are 58,272 names engraved in the black granite. It seems impossible to find the person you&#8217;re looking for, but there are people there to help. Uncle Allan&#8217;s name is on Panel 16W, Row 50.</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">I touched his name, and told Uncle Allan I hoped he knew there were still people who remembered him. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Jesus,&#8221; said the man who helped me find him.  &#8221;To go all that way, and die at 19.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vietnam_Memorial_reflection.jpg">photo courtesy wikicommons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Put on your red shoes and dance the blues. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Put on your red shoes and dance the blues.<span id="more-122677"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/N4d7Wp9kKjA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/213072">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.418 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-01 07:04:35 -->
