<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 13:00:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part III</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-iii/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-iii/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122422"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>October 22, 2005</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve come to the realization lately that we don&#8217;t fall in love. It&#8217;s more of a surrender to love than anything. People are not perfect. And part of the surrender is to realize that the person you are in love with is not perfect, but you love them anyway. We all have fairy-tale visions of the person we will fall in love with; we all have ideas of what we thought would make it impossible to love someone. But somehow, when you meet the right person, those things cease to matter. Although we cannot completely disregard our morals and our principles, love is a matter of give and take. A matter of compromise. Even if you swore up and down you could never love someone who doesn&#8217;t understand your deep love for crocheting covers for tissue boxes, sometimes the right person comes along. And sometimes that person believes that the box the Kleenex company used was fine and there is no need for another cover of any kind.</p>
<p>We may try to judge the love between two people, we may say that we have no idea how they work together. But until you have loved someone enough to say that you would do anything for them and meant it, you cannot understand.</p>
<p>Love can turn dangerous. Anyone who loves you will not try to control you, will not try to get you to bend to their every whim. Anyone who loves you with even one small tiny fraction of their heart will let you go off into the world to do as you please and welcome you with open arms when you come back. Anyone who loves you will want only your happiness, and will not try to limit your happiness in any capacity.</p>
<p>This is not to say, however, that we cannot try to help those we love to improve. Anyone who loves you will try to rid the world of any factor that may keep you from being the best you can be. But on the other side, anyone who loves you must sometimes realize that there is no changing you. That you are too happy (or too stubborn) to try to change. And true love will let that go.</p>
<p>When we surrender to love we forget all reason. Time seems to suddenly stand still and no longer are we living for tomorrow, but we are standing in the moment and we do not want that moment to end. The moment of a perfect kiss. The moment right before &#8220;I love you&#8221;. Happy moments, sad ones. We avoid tomorrow, shy away from it, in fear that as tomorrow takes away today it may also take away the wonder and magic we have suddenly found in the world.</p>
<p>True love may end, true love may be slow in coming. But during the time it is true and the time it is pure, true love does not falter, does not waver, is not questioned. It simply&#8230;is.<br />
And it is the greatest joy of the human heart.</p></blockquote>
<p>What is love?<br />
Oh baby, don&#8217;t hurt me<br />
Don&#8217;t hurt me no more<br />
Oh, baby don&#8217;t hurt me<br />
Don&#8217;t hurt me no more</p>
<p>What is love?</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-iii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tuesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/tuesday-open-thread-70/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/tuesday-open-thread-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[half past six]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kumbaya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my lord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hakuna Matata. Kumbaya. Photo courtesy of Six Thirty.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hakuna Matata. <span id="more-122552"></span></p>
<p>Kumbaya. </p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CuJTsStrifk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><em>Photo courtesy of Six Thirty.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/tuesday-open-thread-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>NCAA Tournament &#8211; Round of 64/32 Wrap-Up</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/ncaa-tournament-round-of-6432-wrap-up/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/ncaa-tournament-round-of-6432-wrap-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>MonkeyBiz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The first week of the 2013 NCAA Men&#8217;s Basketball Tournament is in the books, and the Sweet Sixteen is set. [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first week of the 2013 NCAA Men&#8217;s Basketball Tournament is in the books, and the Sweet Sixteen is set. For those of you that missed the action, here&#8217;s a recap of this weekend&#8217;s memorable moments, a preview of next weekend&#8217;s action, and an update on the Crasstalk Bracket Funderdome Challenge.</p>
<p>Before we begin, let us all recognize the efforts of the NIT 16-seed Robert Morris Colonials in bouncing the NIT 1-seed Kentucky Wildcats last Tuesday. Godspeed, Colonials.<span id="more-122537"></span></p>
<p>Starting with the South Region, the big story of the tournament so far is the emergence of Florida Gulf Coast University, who upset 2-seed Georgetown in the Round of 64 on Friday. The Eagles certainly live up to their name, featuring an immensely entertaining, high-flying offense that seems to openly flaunt the laws of physics. The FGCU Eagles went on to prove they&#8217;re not a fluke, smacking around the 7-seed San Diego State Aztecs in the Round of 32 on Sunday, earning a trip to the Sweet Sixteen. The Eagles are the first 15-seed to make it out of the first weekend in Tournament history.</p>
<p>11-seed Minnesota smacked around 6-seed UCLA in the Round of 64 before getting bounced by 3-seed Florida in the Round of 32, thus validating everyone&#8217;s &#8220;Obvious Upset As Soon As It Was Announced&#8221; pick.</p>
<p>The seemingly-annual &#8220;Roy Williams Revenge Game&#8221; was uneventful, with 1-seed Kansas beating 8-seed North Carolina in the Round of 32.</p>
<p>Moving to the Midwest Region, the Oregon <del>Nike Catalogs</del> Ducks upset 5-seed Oklahoma State in the Round of 64, then went on to upset 4-seed Saint Louis in the Round of 32. I thought the Ducks were underseeded, but I didn&#8217;t think they were THIS underseeded.</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">The West Region has been Upset City, with the 1, 3, 4, 5, 7, and 8 seeds all going down this weekend.</span></p>
<p>Gonzaga was the first 1-seed to go down, losing to 9-seed Wichita State in the Round of 32. What&#8217;s that, MonkeyBiz? Does this suggest that perhaps non-Power Six conference teams shouldn&#8217;t be given #1 or #2 seeds until a non-Power Six team wins a National Championship? Yes it does, Other MonkeyBiz. Yes it does.</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Ole Miss upset Wisconsin in the Round of 64. This is only an upset in the sense that it&#8217;s a round or two earlier than the Bo Ryan-coached Badgers usually get bounced.</span></p>
<p>The 14th-seeded Harvard Crimson upset 3-seed New Mexico in the Round of 64. The New Mexico Lobos were a popular Sweet Sixteen and Elite Eight pick, and an RPI favorite. The Crimson were promptly eliminated by 6-seed Arizona in the Round of 32, thus restoring balance to the universe and reminding everyone that RPI is awful.</p>
<p>13-seed La Salle beat 4-seed Kansas State in the Round of 64, then went on to eliminate 12-seed Ole Miss, winning a date with 9-seed Wichita State next weekend. 10-seed Iowa State smacked around 7-seed Notre Dame in the Round of 64, and gave 2-seed Ohio State a scare in the Round of 32 before being bounced on Aaron Craft&#8217;s virtually last second 3-pointer.</p>
<p>The East Region has been comparatively stable. 12-seed California upset 5-seed UNLV, and went on to lose to 4-seed Syracuse. 3-seed Marquette squeaked out wins versus 14-seed Davidson and 6-seed Butler, winning both games by a combined 3 points.</p>
<p>9-seed Temple upset 8-seed N.C. State, although calling it an upset is questionable. Temple went on to face 1-seed Indiana, where the Owls&#8217; Khalif Wyatt scored an astounding 31 points. Unfortunately for the Owls, three of Temple&#8217;s other starters went a combined 0-for-21, ultimately falling to Indiana in the final minute. After sinking the dagger 3-pointer, Indiana&#8217;s Victor Oladipo was overheard yelling at Owls guard Khalif Wyatt, saying &#8220;THIS ISN&#8217;T EVEN MY FINAL FORM!&#8221;. No further clarification from Hoosiers Coach Tom Crean is available, but Oladipo was sighted later, surrounded by an energy field, walking back to the team bus.</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Next weekend&#8217;s games are going to be very interesting. The East and West Regions will play on Thursday, with the Midwest and South Regions playing on Friday.</span></p>
<p>First up, out of Washington, D.C. we have 3-seed Marquette taking on 2-seed Miami, and 1-seed Indiana taking on 4-seed Syracuse. Can Marquette keep their string of miracle wins alive? Can Miami silence it&#8217;s critics and make it to the Elite Eight? Can Indiana solve Syracuse&#8217;s zone defense? Can Syracuse coach Jim Boeheim avenge his 1987 National Championship loss to Indiana? Will this be the weekend Indiana basketball finally gives me a heart attack and/or brain aneurysm?</p>
<p><strong>Biz&#8217;s Picks: Indiana over Syracuse, Miami over Marquette, MonkeyBiz over Problem Ded</strong></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">Next up, out of Los Angeles, we have 9-seed Wichita State takes on 13-seed La Salle, and 6-seed Arizona versus 2-seed Ohio State. I know nothing about Wichita State and La Salle, other than Wichita is where Sports Illustrated&#8217;s Peter King likes to set hypothetical football games. Also too, Arizona and Ohio State are playing.</span></p>
<p><strong>Biz&#8217;s Picks: Wichita St. over La Salle, Ohio State over Arizona</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong>The Midwest region is next, with 1-seed Louisville taking on 12-seed Oregon, and 2-seed Duke taking on 3-seed Michigan State. Between the Oregon <del>Nike Billboards</del> Ducks&#8217; well-known penchant as a testbed for Nike products and Louisville&#8217;s adoption of the Adidas &#8220;Adizero&#8221; (read: Zubaz) uniforms this postseason, I would highly recommend not watching the game as it may break your television and/or destroy your retinas. Meanwhile, the floor mops they use during games are currently being distributed to interns around the national sports media to handle the deluge of sportswriter slobber that&#8217;s about to inundate us all over Michigan State&#8217;s Tom Izzo and Duke&#8217;<span style="line-height: 16px;">s Mike Krzyzewski.</span></p>
<p><strong>Biz&#8217;s Picks: Louisville over Oregon, Michigan State over Duke, Zubaz over Good Taste, Sportswriter Slobber over Intern-Powered Court Mops</strong></p>
<p>Finally, the South Region will feature 1-seed Kansas versus 4-seed Michigan and 3-seed Florida versus 15-seed FGCU. If Michigan&#8217;s Trey Burke, Glenn Robinson III, and Tim Hardaway Jr. all show up, Michigan is going to roflstomp Kansas. Unfortunately for Michigan, they have a tendency to disappear from time to time, and the Jayhawks are too experienced to not take big advantage of it if they do. It&#8217;s fun to think about what could happen if FGCU beats Florida, but let&#8217;s be realistic: the Gators are gonna eat the Eagles alive. It&#8217;s not gonna be pretty. They&#8217;ll have to broadcast it with a Parental Advisory warning.</p>
<p><strong>Biz&#8217;s Picks: Michigan over Kansas, Florida and the Laws of Physics WAY over FGCU </strong></p>
<p>And now, your Crasstalk Bracket Funderdome standings after the first week:</p>
<p>1) I&#8217;m Waitin For Dolemite<br />
1) Jason<br />
1) Rina<br />
4) flaxen.vixen<br />
5) DrCaveat Lector<br />
5) Petulant Fucko<br />
5) Rhino Pienoceros<br />
8) BestLaidPLains<br />
8) Dogs OfWar<br />
8) Jarrod<br />
8) MonkeyBiz<br />
12) A Piece of the Continent<br />
12) KotBR<br />
12) Olivia Flammerhammer<br />
12) shesarainbow Xx<br />
16) daisy walker<br />
17) Amazon ww<br />
17) enesbit15<br />
19) Captain Badass<br />
19) Botswana Meat Commission<br />
19) La Ziguezon<br />
22) clarity83</p>
<p>Mock away, and Go Sport!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/ncaa-tournament-round-of-6432-wrap-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Theatre Notes With Botswana: The Acro-Cats Take Atlanta</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/theatre-notes-with-botswana-the-acro-cats-take-atlanta/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/theatre-notes-with-botswana-the-acro-cats-take-atlanta/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Botswana Meat Commission FC</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acro-cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat actors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat circus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat theater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cat tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performing cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[training cats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122521</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to this installment of Theatre Notes with Botswana, where I take you inside the world of the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/acro-cats1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122529" alt="acro-cats" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/acro-cats1.jpg" width="600" height="543" /></a><em>Hello and welcome to this installment of Theatre Notes with Botswana, where I take you inside the world of the staged drama and offer my own critical perspectives on the neo-modernist theater scene. </em></p>
<p>You may not be aware, but since the mid 1960s, there has been an alternative movement <del>afoot</del> a-paw in the theater. This new approach fought against all the conventional norms of the theater establishment. Norms like &#8220;you should use people, not cats, as actors&#8221; and &#8220;your actors should try to stay on the stage and not run underneath an audience member&#8217;s chair in the middle of the show&#8221; were suddenly under assault by these young and hungry insurgents of the New Felinists movement. <span id="more-122521"></span></p>
<p>Today this formerly fringe movement is now part of the mainstream. Human actors are now considered old wave and today&#8217;s stars of Broadway and off-Broadway (and off-off-off-off-Broadway) are paid in catnip treats. This trend parallels changes throughout our society, where the cat is now the dominant species of all internet-based media including videos, photos, gifs and Cat Fancy profile pieces. It&#8217;s a cat actor&#8217;s world &#8212; we&#8217;re just offering treats in it.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no further proof of the ascendancy of the cat-based theater than <a href="http://www.circuscats.com/">The Acro-Cats&#8217; recent three day run in Atlanta</a>, where I was lucky enough to see the Acro-Cats live. And I do mean lucky &#8212; the titans of the Cat Stage sold out every show (prompting producers to add last-minute late shows over the weekend). The traditional distance between the avant-garde and the mainstream no longer exists. Art is dead. Death is art. Now please give the Mr. Buggles his salmon kitty treat before he claws our eyeballs out.</p>
<p>The Acro-Cats will shatter your preconceived notions about the dynamic space between the actor and the audience. For example at numerous times during the show, the cats exercise their free will as cats and suddenly bolt into the audience. Also, during the show I saw Sunday, the star Tuna decided to climb up a 15-foot ladder that was resting against a wall backstage. She spent most of the rest of the performance trying to figure out how to get down.</p>
<p>The Acro-Cats, for all their bluster, are no mere infantile revolutionaries of the stage. They are true professionals. They perform dozens of amazing tricks. They push shopping cars and roll balls across a rope and climb. And they fucking love climbing. Because they&#8217;re cats, goddammit. At one point the Acro-Cats actually compete in a game of bowling against a rather cute and smiley groundhog. This is the sort of inter-species recreational activity that would have scandalized audiences in a more conservative time, but in today&#8217;s rough and tumble cat theater world, audiences demand such innovation.</p>
<p>Does all this mean that I am ready to repudiate my past ideological assumptions about using cats as actors? Only so far as I must repudiate all theater movements that refuse to acknowledge the fact that cats can now do all forms of entertainment better than humans. A perfect example of this came during the show&#8217;s final act &#8212; a musical ensemble performance by &#8220;The Rock Cats.&#8221; The cats (plus one chicken named Gregory Peck) play all their own instruments. They refuse to bow to the simulacrum of today&#8217;s lip-synched, pre-fab pop music. Instead they play all their own instruments and weave a sound using dissonance and non-Western time signatures that reminds this critic of the visceral pleasures of Stockhausen and Glass. When the fluffy white kitty started playing the drums I felt I was ready to shuffle off this mortal coil.</p>
<p>So in conclusion&#8230; Cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats cats.</p>
<p><em>Photo taken by a friend of mine. All rights reserved. Or something.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/theatre-notes-with-botswana-the-acro-cats-take-atlanta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part II</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-ii/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-ii/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122418"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Mon, Feb. 27th, 2006, 10:59 pm &#8211; Stop the world, I&#8217;d like to get off</p>
<p>Last week, a guy I knew in high school died. It was very odd, mainly cause at the funeral, I realized that I didn&#8217;t know him as well as I thought I did. There were also alot of people that I haven&#8217;t seen in a long time, whom I felt the same about. But it was still good to see them, only it felt bad feeling good about that. I&#8217;ve been told that it&#8217;s not a bad thing and it&#8217;s actually good that we connected. Now if I can just bother to write them e-mails. . .</p>
<p>So that ended last week, on a rather . . . &#8220;um. . que?&#8221; note, only to have me work all day Saturday. For some reason I came home and slept for 5 hours, thinking &#8220;Hey! I&#8217;ll disco nap, clean, and go shake my ass at SoBe cause I need it!!&#8221; Didn&#8217;t happen. I woke up, wandered around, and watched some bad adaptation of a Jane Austen novel and went back to bed.</p>
<p>I checked out my calander, and it looks like life is going to be hell during march. Hopefully not at work, because the Skanky Bitch Whore has been moved. But she still comes up and tries to make scenes. HAHAHAHA&gt; YOU ARE A BITCH AND SHOULD DIE!!!! *calm* One of the fat ladies is getting bari surgery this week, so I&#8217;m hoping she can stop making comments about how I&#8217;m fat and haven&#8217;t lost any weight. Bullshit. I&#8217;ve had plenty of people comment on it. I just don&#8217;t crash diet like she does. And I&#8217;m trying to make an effort not to antagonize the other bitch. I was rather nice, for the most part, during the office clean up. I asked about everything, well, except when the manager came up and TOLD me to throw things away, but that&#8217;s the manager. Therapist tried to pass it off as I should have told her anyway, but . . . who is she kidding? She would have just tried to throw a wrench in it anyway. I am really over her bullshit. Maybe if I close my eyes and ignore her, she&#8217;ll go away.</p>
<p>All in all, I&#8217;m suffering from something akin to senioritis and this dreaded fear that I&#8217;ve fucked everything up, and that I&#8217;m 25, and it&#8217;s too late to start over.</p>
<p>Bullshit.</p></blockquote>
<p>Bullshit indeed. That skank needed to get told.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-ii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/monday-open-thread-72/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/monday-open-thread-72/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christ It's Monday Again]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music leonard washington would like]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yeah, it&#8217;s gonna be like that. Stay strong, kids. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/800px-SS_Austria_shipwreck1.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/800px-SS_Austria_shipwreck1.jpg" alt="800px-SS_Austria_shipwreck" width="769" height="396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122544" /></a></p>
<p>Yeah, it&#8217;s gonna be like that. Stay strong, kids.<span id="more-122507"></span></p>
<p><object width="500" height="375"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/MJCaFe1yamg?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/MJCaFe1yamg?version=3&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="500" height="375" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:SS_Austria_shipwreck.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/monday-open-thread-72/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recipe Sunday: Homemade Teriyaki Sauce</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-homemade-teriyaki-sauce/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-homemade-teriyaki-sauce/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Launie K.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe sunday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122480</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago my husband and I went out to dinner, which is a rarity for us. I write [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/teriyaki-sauce-crass-final.jpg"><img alt="teriyaki-sauce-crass-final" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/teriyaki-sauce-crass-final.jpg" width="1024" height="512" /></a></p>
<p>A few weeks ago my husband and I went out to dinner, which is a rarity for us. I write about food for paychecks, so I cook several times a day. Although what we have in the fridge by the end of the day may not make sense as a full meal, it&#8217;s generally what we stick with.</p>
<p>“What&#8217;s for dinner?”</p>
<p>“Well, we have tilapia piccata, cranberry maple granola and fresh barbecue sauce.”</p>
<p>“Sounds good.”<span id="more-122480"></span>So, when we went out for dinner, I ordered my favorite restaurant meal &#8211; teriyaki chicken. As we sat at the bar nursing drinks waiting to be seated, it occurred to me that I&#8217;d never made teriyaki sauce. When I told my husband that, he said, “It&#8217;s easy. It&#8217;s equal parts brown sugar, soy sauce, water and a ton of ginger.”</p>
<p>Well, why hadn&#8217;t I made that before? It couldn&#8217;t sound easier.</p>
<p>Then I made it Monday night and we devoured it along with chorizo lasagna and chocolate covered mango. (Again, we eat a unique conglomeration of food at the end of the day.) Then I made it again on Wednesday. When Friday rolled around I made it again. We couldn&#8217;t get enough of the sweet, salty and gingery sauce on chicken.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s so simple to make that it&#8217;s perfect for an insanely fast weeknight meal. And it goes well with just about anything.</p>
<p>Trust me on that.</p>
<p><b>Homemade Teriyaki Sauce </b></p>
<p>Serves 2.</p>
<p>Ingredients:</p>
<ul>
<li>½ cup of soy sauce</li>
<li>½ cup of brown sugar (light or dark)</li>
<li>½ cup of water</li>
<li>1 inch of grated ginger</li>
</ul>
<p>Instructions:</p>
<p>Combine all of the ingredients in a small saucepan and bring to a boil. Turn the heat down and let simmer until the sauce has reduced by half and resembles a syrup.</p>
<p>To make teriyaki chicken, take 2 tablespoons of the sauce and place it in a bag with chicken breasts. Marinate for half an hour and bake or grill. Serve with sauce.</p>
<p>(Photo by Launie K.)<em> </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/recipe-sunday-homemade-teriyaki-sauce/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-86/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-86/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colleen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Crassholes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crassholes. <span id="more-122463"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/mxtFBqRThTQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/sunday-open-thread-86/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-91/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-91/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Saturday. The Promise from Sam Molleur on Vimeo. Image via WIkipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Saturday. <span id="more-122449"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/57775588" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/57775588">The Promise</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/sammolleur">Sam Molleur</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Drymoreomys_albimaculatus_002.jpg">WIkipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/saturday-open-thread-91/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>These Animals Are Illegal to Keep as Pets in New York City</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/these-animals-are-illegal-to-keep-as-pets-in-new-york-city/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/these-animals-are-illegal-to-keep-as-pets-in-new-york-city/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pigs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122453</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The AP has a deeply pun laden story about families who flaunt the law by keeping even toed ungulates, pigs [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pet_pig.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122456" alt="pet_pig" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/pet_pig.jpg" width="350" height="233" /></a>The AP has a deeply pun laden <a href="http://www.sfgate.com/news/us/article/New-Yorkers-boldly-flout-law-to-keep-pigs-4375443.php">story</a> about families who flaunt the law by keeping even toed ungulates, pigs if you must, even though they are banned by the New York City health code.</p>
<p>To help potential pet owners in New York City determine which side of the law they fall on, here is the complete list of animals that are illegal to own in New York City. <span id="more-122453"></span></p>
<ul>
<li>All dogs other than domesticated dogs (Canis familiaris), including, but not limited to, wolf, fox, coyote, hyena, dingo, jackal, dhole, fennec, raccoon dog, zorro, bush dog, aardwolf, cape hunting dog and any hybrid offspring of a wild dog and domesticated dog.</li>
<li>All cats other than domesticated cats (Felis catus), including, but not limited to, lion, tiger, leopard, ocelot, jaguar, puma, panther, mountain lion, cheetah, wild cat, cougar, bobcat, lynx, serval, caracal, jaguarundi, margay and any hybrid offspring of a wild cat and domesticated cat.</li>
<li>All bears, including polar, grizzly, brown and black bear.</li>
<li>All fur bearing mammals of the family Mustelidae, including, but not limited to, weasel, marten, mink, badger, ermine, skunk, otter, pole cat, zorille, wolverine, stoat and ferret.</li>
<li>All Procyonidae: All raccoon (eastern, desert, ring-tailed cat), kinkajou, cacomistle, cat-bear, panda and coatimundi.</li>
<li>All carnivorous mammals of the family Viverridae, including , but not limited to, civet, mongoose, genet, binturong, fossa, linsang and suricate.</li>
<li>All bats (Chiroptera).</li>
<li>All non-human primates, including, but not limited to, monkey, ape, chimpanzee, gorilla and lemur.</li>
<li>All squirrels (Sciuridae).</li>
<li>Reptiles (Reptilia): All Helodermatidae (gila monster and Mexican beaded lizard); all front-fanged venomous snakes, even if devenomized, including, but not limited to, all Viperidae (viper, pit viper), all Elapidae (cobra, mamba, krait, coral snake), all Atractaspididae (African burrowing asp), all Hydrophiidae (sea snake), all Laticaudidae (sea krait); all venomous, mid-or rear-fanged, Duvernoy-glanded members of the family Colubridae, even if devenomized; any member, or hybrid offspring of the family Boidae, including, but not limited to, the common or green anaconda and yellow anaconda; any member of the family Pythonidae, including but not limited to the African rock python, Indian or Burmese python, Amethystine or scrub python; any member of the family Varanidae, including the white throated monitor, Bosc&#8217;s or African savannah monitor, Komodo monitor or dragon, Nile monitor, crocodile monitor, water monitor, Bornean earless monitor; any member of the family Iguanidae, including the green or common iguana; any member of the family Teiidae, including, but not limited to the golden, common, or black and white tegu; all members of the family Chelydridae, including snapping turtle and alligator snapping turtle; and all members of the order Crocodylia, including, but not limited to alligator, caiman and crocodile.</li>
<li>Birds and Fowl (Aves): All predatory or large birds, including, but not limited to, eagle, hawk, falcon, owl, vulture, condor, emu, rhea and ostrich; roosters, geese, ducks and turkeys.<br />
All venomous insects, including, but not limited to, bee, hornet and wasp.</li>
<li>Arachnida and Chilopoda: All venomous spiders, including, but not limited to, tarantula, black widow and solifugid; scorpion; all venomous arthropods including, but not limited to, centipede.</li>
<li>All large rodents (Rodentia), including, but not limited to, gopher, muskrat, paca, woodchuck, marmot, beaver, prairie dog, capybara, sewellel, viscacha, porcupine and hutia.</li>
<li>All even-toed ungulates (Artiodactyla) including, but not limited to, deer, antelope, sheep, giraffe and hippopotamus.</li>
<li>All odd-toed ungulates (Perissodactyla) other than domesticated horses (Equus caballus), including, but not limited to, zebra, rhinoceros and tapir.</li>
<li>All marsupials, including, but not limited to, Tasmanian devil, dasyure, bandicoot, kangaroo, wallaby, opossum, wombat, koala bear, cuscus, numbat and pigmy, sugar and greater glider.</li>
<li>Sea mammals (Cetacea, Pinnipedia and Sirenia), including, but not limited to, dolphin, whale, seal, sea lion and walrus.</li>
<li>All elephants (Proboscides)</li>
<li>All hyrax (Hydracoidea).</li>
<li>All pangolin (Pholidota).</li>
<li>All sloth and armadillo (Edentata).</li>
<li>Insectivorous mammals (Insectivora): All aardvark (Tubildentata), anteater, shrew, otter shrew, gymnure, desman, tenrec, mole and hedge hog.<br />
Gliding lemur (Dermoptera).</li>
</ul>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.nyc.gov/html/doh/downloads/pdf/zoo/zoo-animal-healthcode.pdf">NYC Health Code</a> / Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/alexyo1968/5237333618/">Flickr</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/these-animals-are-illegal-to-keep-as-pets-in-new-york-city/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.368 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-26 09:00:58 -->
