<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Allan J. Eastman, Aged 19</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Karyn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Respect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122626</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 29th is Vietnam Veterans Day.  It marks the day the last American combat troops were finally withdrawn from Vietnam, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Vietnam.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-122629" alt="Vietnam" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Vietnam-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">March 29th is Vietnam Veterans Day.  It marks the day the last American combat troops were finally withdrawn from Vietnam, forty years ago.</span></p>
<p>Well, not all of them. 1600 troops are still officially missing in Vietnam.</p>
<p>I grew up with Vietnam hanging over my family. My grandmother was a Gold Star Mother, which is what the government calls you when you&#8217;ve lost a child in war. She never rode in the Veterans Day parades on that sad float with all the other mothers in Belmont, Massachusetts (not Mitt Romney&#8217;s side of town) who had lost their sons. But Uncle Allan&#8217;s name is etched in granite in the town square. <span id="more-122626"></span><!--more--></p>
<p>My uncle, <a href="http://www.vvmf.org/thewall/Wall_Id_No=14521">Allan John Eastman</a>, was born in 1950. My grandmother and mother always spoke of him as a good boy, a saint. But there were stories. He famously &#8216;borrowed&#8217; an MTA bus left idling by a driver who stopped for a break and took it for a joyride up Trapelo Road towards Watertown, taking off down the side streets before the cops could catch him. Every time I ride the #71 bus out of Harvard Square, I imagine him giggling his ass off, running for home.</p>
<p>He enlisted in the Army and was sent out.</p>
<p>Uncle Allan was shot and died of malaria on November 9, 1969.  He was 19.</p>
<p>I finally got to Washington to see Uncle Allan&#8217;s name on<a href="http://thewall-usa.com/information.asp"> The Vietnam Veterans Memorial</a> a few years ago.  If you&#8217;ve never seen The Wall, it&#8217;s extraordinary.  It&#8217;s sweeping and dark and seems to go on forever, like that war did. There are 58,272 names engraved in the black granite. It seems impossible to find the person you&#8217;re looking for, but there are people there to help. Uncle Allan&#8217;s name is on Panel 16W, Row 50.</p>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">I touched his name, and told Uncle Allan I hoped he knew there were still people who remembered him. </span></p>
<p>&#8220;Jesus,&#8221; said the man who helped me find him.  &#8221;To go all that way, and die at 19.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Vietnam_Memorial_reflection.jpg">photo courtesy wikicommons</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/allan-j-eastman-aged-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Put on your red shoes and dance the blues. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Put on your red shoes and dance the blues.<span id="more-122677"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/N4d7Wp9kKjA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/213072">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/friday-open-thread-70/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Project Runway Season 11 Episode 10 Live Blog</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-10-live-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-10-live-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CaptainSnarky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liveblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Runway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122737</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Darlings, we are at it again! Sadly, there were no hot men to help us through the wretched excess that [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-117875" alt="project-runway-26" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/project-runway-26-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a>Darlings, we are at it again! Sadly, there were no hot men to help us through the wretched excess that is this season of Project Runway.</p>
<p>Last week, the challenge demanded the designers produce ready-to-wear looks for Lord &amp; Taylor. The winning design will be featured by Lord &amp; Taylor and sold for way more than it&#8217;s actually worth! Of course, you know what that means&#8230;</p>
<p>Michelle won. Again. I hate everything.</p>
<p>Well, we&#8217;re at episode 10, and I&#8217;m pretty sure that the producers have demanded that the drama quotient be upped significantly. Let us snark in the comments!<span id="more-122737"></span></p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:PRLogo12.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/project-runway-season-11-episode-10-live-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Free is Your State?</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-free-is-your-state/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-free-is-your-state/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jason</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Going Galt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Think Tanks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122714</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You may be shocked to discover that your freedoms are being oppressed right now as you read this. This morning, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/eagle.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-122726 alignleft" alt="eagle" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/eagle.gif" width="384" height="288" /></a>You may be shocked to discover that your freedoms are being oppressed right now as you read this.</p>
<p>This morning, Twitter was buzzing about the Mercatus Center&#8217;s latest rankings of <a href="http://freedominthe50states.org">Freedom in the 50 States</a>. Rounding out the top 5 slots in descending order are Oklahoma, New Hampshire, Tennessee, and South Dakota. And the number one MOST FREE state according to this year&#8217;s rankings? The great shining beacon on the hill known as North Dakota! That&#8217;s right. North Dakota. <span id="more-122714"></span><a href="http://freedominthe50states.org/overall/north-dakota">As Mercatus explains:</a></p>
<blockquote><p>North Dakota, according to the freedom index, is the freest state in the United States. It scores exceptionally well on regulatory and fiscal policy. Moreover, North Dakota scores slightly above average on personal freedom. It is also the state that improved the most over the last decade. &#8230;</p>
<p><strong>North Dakota scores well in a few personal freedom areas but has much room for improvement.</strong> Gun control laws are fairly relaxed. Alcohol regulations are light, while tax rates on beer and wine are average and spirits taxes are fairly low. Cigarette taxes are low but smoking bans exist, with exemptions for bars and restaurants. Motorists also operate with relative freedom, except for sobriety checkpoints and (most notably) the personal injury coverage mandate.</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasis mine.</p>
<p>If you are curious about the personal freedom factor, you have to keep in mind that the &#8220;Freedom Index&#8221; basically measures how low taxes are, how little businesses are regulated and how often you can walk around brandishing your six-shooter. <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/health/2013/03/26/1776431/north-dakota-abortion-threat-trap/">So the freedom to not have your uterus heavily regulated by the state</a> doesn&#8217;t rank very high, sorry.</p>
<p>But what about the bottom of the list? Basically it is all the heathen liberal states. Despite securing its soda freedom, New York is ranked dead last. They sort of acknowledge you can gay marry there, but beyond that it is basically Stalin&#8217;s Russia in the eyes of the Freedom Index. At <a href="http://freedominthe50states.org/overall/california">#49 is of course California</a>, because it &#8220;heavily taxes and regulates its economy&#8221; and &#8220;aggressively interferes in the personal lives of its citizens&#8221;(!), for example:</p>
<blockquote><p>California was the first state to enact a smoking ban in restaurants and bars, but the ban is slightly less strict than those since adopted in other states. Travel freedom is low due to a primary seat belt law, motorcycle and bicycle helmet laws, a statewide primary-enforcement cell phone driving ban, an open-container law, and sobriety checkpoints. Little gambling is allowed.</p></blockquote>
<p>Personal travel freedom is party infringed by a seat belt law and sobriety checkpoints? The Freedom Index has some hard calculus to break.</p>
<p>As you would expect, all the least free states are also the wealthiest and most populated while the most free are basically where no one wants to live. There&#8217;s also a user-generated &#8220;Bachelor Party&#8221; category where Massachusetts(???) tops the list.</p>
<p>The Mercatus Center is a classic market-orientated think tank; meaning it takes a libertarian approach to everything while hating taxes and supporting policies that benefit the wealthy. The Mercatus Center is part of public university of George Mason and affiliated with the Koch family, who at the time of this writing haven&#8217;t relocated to their businesses to North Dakota.</p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/eagle%20gif?language=nl_NL">Charmingelements</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-free-is-your-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part V</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-v/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-v/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122434</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122434"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Wednesday, May 02, 2007</p>
<p>&#8220;For awhile, it feels like every step you take is driving you further into the ground. And then one day it shifts and you realize that actually you&#8217;re climbing up, slowly. Slowly. And things will be alright again.&#8221;</p>
<p>If all the hurt that is inside me were able to get out, I&#8217;m not sure what it would do to the world. Would it be like a smoky fog, eliminating the rest of the world from view? Or would it be a raging battle? Would it split the Earth in two? Or &#8212; and this is the worst yet &#8212; would it go utterly unnoticed?</p>
<p>The latter is what I fear most, and it is what I feel is most likely true.</p>
<p>No one notices. No one notices that I feel like the ground has been pulled out from underneath me. No one knows that I try so desperately to integrate myself that I do things that only a year ago would have shocked me. No one knows. And I&#8217;m not going to tell them, of course. It shows through once in awhile. People ask if I&#8217;m okay, what&#8217;s wrong &#8212; but I won&#8217;t tell them. I say I&#8217;m tired, or I&#8217;m stressed. I don&#8217;t say that maybe I&#8217;m dying.</p>
<p>And the worst is when people act like they know me well enough to understand. You don&#8217;t understand, you can&#8217;t possibly understand. Please don&#8217;t act like you do. I don&#8217;t care how much you&#8217;ve been through or who&#8217;s hurt you or what your best friend&#8217;s neighbor&#8217;s dog went through that you heard all about (that one&#8217;s a bit of a stretch). It just doesn&#8217;t matter to me.</p>
<p>The actress in me keeps me okay. She is able to put on a face, go through life being okay. She hides the hurt, hides the guilt, hides the shame.</p>
<p>But no one can hide it from me. No one can hide the way that I cry at anything again, no one can hide how my stomach drops out of my torso at the thought of it.</p>
<p>No amount of telling me that it&#8217;ll be okay is going to help this.</p>
<p>And so people really need to knock that off.</p>
<p>Really, if I were any more selfish than I am, I&#8217;d run away and hide. But I also know that people need me here, and people are counting on me, and that running away isn&#8217;t going to solve it. It&#8217;s going to follow me.</p>
<p>Probably it always will.</p>
<p>And the horrible thing is how I don&#8217;t even know what I want anymore.</p>
<p>I need the crystal ball back again &#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>Some day somebody&#8217;s gonna make you want to turn around and say goodbye. Until then baby are you going to let them hold you down and make you cry? Don&#8217;t you know? Don&#8217;t you know things can change? Things&#8217;ll go your way if you hold on for one more day. Can you hold on for one more day? Things&#8217;ll go your way. Hold on for one more day.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-v/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-65-2/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-65-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 11:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122563</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hey there, good looking. Image source]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey there, good looking.<span id="more-122563"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/X85R4QeB-vc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/218805">Image source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/thursday-open-thread-65-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Ace Your Next Phone Interview</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-to-ace-your-next-phone-interview/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-to-ace-your-next-phone-interview/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Anita Manbadly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Servicey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learn from my mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phone interviews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hidey ho, jobseekers! I&#8217;ve been on the prowl for &#8220;the perfect job&#8221; for the last few years, and I&#8217;ve been [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/The_work_of_the_Auxiliary_Territorial_Service_at_a_Mixed_Anti-aircraft_Battery_England_UK_1942_D8287.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122696" alt="The_work_of_the_Auxiliary_Territorial_Service_at_a_Mixed_Anti-aircraft_Battery,_England,_UK,_1942_D8287" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/The_work_of_the_Auxiliary_Territorial_Service_at_a_Mixed_Anti-aircraft_Battery_England_UK_1942_D8287.jpg" width="754" height="599" /></a>Hidey ho, jobseekers! I&#8217;ve been on the prowl for &#8220;the perfect job&#8221; for the last few years, and I&#8217;ve been subjected to dozens of interviews. Phone interviews, that is. Phone interviews make sense from the hiring manager&#8217;s perspective, because they can be setup quickly, there&#8217;s no need for the candidate to travel to their office, they&#8217;re safer (no letting the crazies in the front door, thank you) and because the phone removes the interviewee&#8217;s physical presence, the interviewer can get a more accurate assessment of the interviewee&#8217;s personality.</p>
<p>Please learn from my mistakes with this list of hints and tips I have compiled.<span id="more-122695"></span></p>
<p><strong>Research</strong></p>
<p>You found the job listing on Careerbuilder, or Indeed, or Sologig. You filled out the online application, you attached your resume and a cover letter, and now you&#8217;re waiting for HR to select or reject you. Now is the time to do some online stalkery of your intended employer. Visit these websites and search for the company:</p>
<ul>
<li>LinkedIn, to see if you know anyone who works there.</li>
<li>Glassdoor, to learn what current and former employees have to say about the company.</li>
<li>Youtube, to discover if the company has produced any videos about their products, or their collaborations with other companies.</li>
<li>Facebook, to read any wall posts the company has produced.</li>
<li>Finally google &#8220;company name litigation&#8221; or &#8220;company name lawsuit&#8221; to see if they have done anything naughty. You don&#8217;t want to hitch your wagon to a company that might get sued to oblivion.</li>
</ul>
<p>One more tip &#8211; try to find any online communities or forums the company has setup and read through some of the posts there, so you can get an idea of what challenges they face from their customers.</p>
<p>If the job requires specific skills, be sure you are up to date on whatever skills are required. LinkedIn is a great resource to find communities of practitioners. You should also find and join other online communities for your profession. You don&#8217;t have to be the number one commenter there, but you should participate and read your community boards regularly, not only for job leads but also to stay aware of what&#8217;s going on in your profession.</p>
<p><strong>Physical preparation</strong></p>
<p>You got a call from HR. You were selected for an interview! Awesome! Schedule the interview for a Monday morning or Friday afternoon, as those are the best times to influence decision makers. Now it&#8217;s time to get your interview space ready.</p>
<p>I recommend taking the call in front of your computer. I don&#8217;t care if you have to take your laptop into a closet, just have your computer handy in case you need to google something during the interview. Also, I like to have several documents open before the interview starts: My resume, a list of accomplishments, a list of questions to ask the interviewer, and my notes from the research I did earlier.</p>
<p>Get a sturdy chair that doesn&#8217;t squeak when you move around and set it in front of a table in your interview space. If you don&#8217;t have a lamp nearby, find one and bring it in, because you want your space to be well-lit and cheery. Clear all clutter off of your table. No pens, pencils, cat-toys, nothing that can clatter or distract. Grab a water bottle or bottle of soda (if you&#8217;re so inclined). Do not make coffee or tea and do not pour a glass of any beverage, because you don&#8217;t want to knock it over mid-sentence and be distracted cleaning it up while you&#8217;re supposed to be telling someone how fabulous you are.</p>
<p>I suggest you invest in a phone that has a mute button, so you can cough (or type furiously) during the interview without the interviewer hearing you. Also, use a landline or a softphone (like Magicjack or Ooma) rather than a cellphone to receive the interviewer&#8217;s call. It would be horrible if the closest cell tower decided to flake out while you&#8217;re mid-interview, disconnecting the call or making you sound like a drowning Woody Woodpecker.</p>
<p>It goes without saying, but I&#8217;mma say it anyway. During the phone call: No smoking. No gum chewing. No eating anything. Banish pets, children, adults from the room for the duration of the call. Turn off the stereo, the TV, and anything else that makes background noise. Turn off your computer&#8217;s speakers.</p>
<p>A few minutes before the interview is scheduled to start, get up and walk around. Go up and down a flight of stairs a few times if you&#8217;ve got stairs handy. Physical activity will pump up your energy and burn off any pre-interview jitters.</p>
<p><strong>The Big Event</strong></p>
<p>When it&#8217;s time for the interview to start, sit upright in your chair, smile, and remember you&#8217;re talking to the person who you will be working with closely, if you&#8217;re selected for the job. The interview is a time for you to find out if this is someone you want to spend the majority of your waking hours talking to and working with. Do they have a nasty personality? Maybe you don&#8217;t want them to be your boss, after all.</p>
<p>You, on the other hand, have your best party manners on. Spend a minute or two asking the interviewer how their day is going, talking about the weather, and getting a read on their personality. Then dive right in with a summary of who you are and why you think you&#8217;re a good fit for the job.</p>
<p>When the interviewer asks questions, rather than imagining you&#8217;re being grilled by a judge and jury, take the attitude that your best friend is asking you what you have done in your career and how you might solve a problem they have. If you &#8220;flip the script&#8221; in your mind and imagine that the interviewer is your friend, you will come across as someone the interviewer wants to work with, a collaborator rather than a minion.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t stress how important it is to be friendly and approachable in your phone interview. When I interviewed people via phone, my biggest turn-offs were people who were taciturn or even downright rude. Answering questions with a plain &#8220;No!&#8221; or a grunt (I&#8217;m not kidding) caused me to terminate the interview immediately. If you&#8217;re in a bad mood at the time of the interview and feel you can&#8217;t &#8220;fake it till you make it&#8221; you might do better to answer the phone, tell the interviewer something has come up, and ask to reschedule.</p>
<p><strong>Closing The Deal</strong></p>
<p>At the end of the call, most interviewers will say &#8220;do you have any questions for me?&#8221; This is the time for you to mention some of the research you did on the company and ask questions about what you found. Definitely don&#8217;t mention pending litigation. Here are some questions you can use instead:</p>
<ul>
<li>What do you view as the most challenging part of this job?</li>
<li>Why is the last person who held this position leaving?</li>
<li>How would you describe the company culture?</li>
<li>What is the typical work week? Is overtime expected? How about travel?</li>
<li>What are the opportunities for advancement with the company?</li>
<li>Is there anything else can I tell you about my qualifications?</li>
<li>What are the biggest challenges facing the person in this position?</li>
</ul>
<p>When all your questions have been answered, thank the interviewer for their time, and if you&#8217;re interested in moving forward, ask what the next steps will be.</p>
<p><strong>After The Call Ends</strong></p>
<p>While the interview is still fresh in your mind, take a few notes on what was said and think about any additional questions you might have. Some jobs I&#8217;ve interviewed for in the last year have required five or six phone interviews with various people on the team, and referring to my notes from previous interviews for the same job really came in handy. In one case, it led to an offer, because I had taken what one interviewer had said was a concern, and mentioned it to the next interviewer down the line. They thought I had great insight into their situation, when all I had done was parrot back to them what they told me.</p>
<p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the top tips for your phone interview:</p>
<ul>
<li>Learn all you can about the company so you can speak intelligently about their business.</li>
<li>Be friendly towards the interviewer, because no one wants to work with a jerk.</li>
<li>Prepare your interview space so there will be no distractions or background noises, because who knows how those noises will be interpreted on the other end.</li>
<li>Ask questions at the end so you appear interested in the job and the company.</li>
<li>Smile!</li>
</ul>
<p>Image source: Wikimedia commons</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/how-to-ace-your-next-phone-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 20 Most Mortifying Parts of Buzz Bissinger&#8217;s Insane Leather Fetish Essay</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/the-20-most-mortifying-parts-of-buzz-bissingers-insane-leather-fetish-essay/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/the-20-most-mortifying-parts-of-buzz-bissingers-insane-leather-fetish-essay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Botswana Meat Commission FC</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buzz Bissinger dominant leather master]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fright Night Frights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to dress like an asshole]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122649</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday we witnessed the greatest piece of journalism in the history of GQ. Friday Night Lights author (and frequent insane [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/buzz-bissinger.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122664" alt="buzz bissinger" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/buzz-bissinger.jpg" width="420" height="560" /></a>Yesterday we witnessed <a href="http://www.gq.com/news-politics/newsmakers/201304/buzz-bissinger-shopaholic-gucci-addiction?printable=true">the greatest piece of journalism in the history of <em>GQ</em></a>. <em>Friday Night Lights</em> author (and frequent insane sports commenter) Buzz Bissinger gave us a personal essay that was ostensibly about his haute couture shopping addiction and $500,000 Gucci habit. But the piece was really more about Buzz&#8217;s description of a midlife crisis that evolved into a bizarre S&amp;M leather fetish. Most men his age just buy a Corvette, but not this guy.</p>
<p>Buzz himself says his downward spiral came about after his three kids went off to college. Since seeing your dad write a six-page exploration of his leather fetish is basically the most embarrassing thing ever, let&#8217;s rank the various parts of his essay from least to most mortifying. <span id="more-122649"></span></p>
<h5>20. Buzz admits that his family doesn&#8217;t want to be seen with him.</h5>
<blockquote><p>Lisa in general liked the rocker look. But there were times I was too outrageous for her taste, and she began to feel like she was living with a hoarder. The kids liked the flair, maybe, but there were times they seemed embarrassed, or simply stunned.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>19. Buzz gets annoyed with the riff-raff at the Gucci flagship store.</h5>
<blockquote><p>The clothes hang like fantastic sex toys, but at this point I no longer bother with that. I am taken to a space at the back, away from the scrum that buys sunglasses and sneakers with the GG logo.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>18. So <em>that&#8217;s</em> what dad is doing in the bathroom.</h5>
<blockquote><p>If there was an item that I had somehow warded off in the morning, I bought it. If something caught my eye, gave me the slightest rush, I hit the &#8220;purchase now&#8221; button. I bought with my cell phone while waiting to have lunch with someone, or dinner, or a drink. I bought while I was <i>having</i> lunch with someone, or dinner, or a drink, happy when they went to the bathroom so I could finish the transaction without interruption.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>17. He won&#8217;t be saddled with debt, just daddy issues.</h5>
<blockquote><p>The approximate amount I spent on the four-day trip is $51,000. That is equivalent to roughly a full year&#8217;s tuition at my son&#8217;s college, Kenyon. I think about that. The self-indulgence is obvious. But it is my money, and I have paid his tuition for four years so he will not be saddled with any loans when he graduates this spring.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>16. Buzz is sizzling now. Yeah sizzling, bitch.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I like turning around and seeing the poor lost souls in the gulag of the higher rows. I hope they hate me, chattering chipmunks trying to figure out <i>who the fuck is this poseur, </i>or however it&#8217;s said in Fashion Italian. Then again, I don&#8217;t see them dressed to kill, in an $8,000 Gucci pony-hair jacket that no one else in the U.S. has and wax-coated black jeans, shiny and sheeny and sizzling.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>15. Some poor animal actually gave its pelt for this.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I hadn&#8217;t been to a dance club in thirty years. But I was revved up and decided to stay up all night, since the ride to the airport was at 5 a.m. I haven&#8217;t stayed up all night partying in thirty-five years. I was dressed in tight black faux-leather stretch pants, a black Gucci T-shirt, and a black leather Gucci jacket lined with shearling. I looked so hip that the owner of the club put us in the special VIP section overlooking the jammed dance floor.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">14. No one who is actually edgy calls themselves &#8220;edgy.&#8221;</span></h5>
<blockquote><p><span style="line-height: 1.5em;">If all I buy is Gucci, I will be fine. It has taken a while to figure out what works and what doesn&#8217;t work, but Gucci men&#8217;s clothing best represents who I want to be and have become—rocker, edgy, tight, bad boy, hip, stylish, flamboyant, unafraid, raging against the conformity that submerges us into boredom and blandness and the sexless saggy sackcloths that most men walk around in like zombies without the cinematic excitement of engorging flesh.</span></p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>13. Dad tries out his bolero-style leather jacket and knee-high Stuart Weitzman boots.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I bought an orange leather motorcycle jacket and matching orange leather pants from Alexander McQueen that made me look, well, very, very orange. The same went for a blue ensemble that made me look, well, very, very blue. I bought dozens upon dozens of leather jackets—bolero-style, waist-length, above the knee, below the knee—in which the gradations of difference were microscopic. I bought a pair of knee-length Stuart Weitzman boots and then two weeks later bought the exact same pair because I had forgotten I bought the first pair.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>12. Dusters, because no one has ever looked silly in a fucking duster.</h5>
<blockquote><p>Then I see a leather jacket of red burgundy with gold military buttons. It goes to the waist. I like it, but it isn&#8217;t quite distinctive enough. Something is missing, until I muse to the Perfect Shadow how great it would look if it could be lengthened into a full leather coat just above the knee, almost duster-style.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>11. Buzz is keeping close track of who compliments his outfits.</h5>
<blockquote><p>Before I started shopping with her at Gucci, I could count on one finger the number of compliments I got from strangers on what I was wearing. Now I get dozens, 99 percent of them from women and gays and African-Americans who appreciate go-for-it style. No wonder male heterosexual whites are aimed toward obsolescence, boring the rest of us to death.</p></blockquote>
<h5><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/buzz-bissinger-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122674" alt="buzz bissinger 2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/buzz-bissinger-2.jpg" width="420" height="560" /></a></h5>
<h5>10. The skull rings really set off the look.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I began to seek sexual expression in the form of high fashion, men&#8217;s because I liked the hardness and women&#8217;s because I liked the sexiness. Blended together, it became a rocker look, particularly with the three skull rings on each hand to fit my usual dark mood.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>9. Oh no, leave grandma out of this.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I had always been attracted to S&amp;M, even at an early age, when I didn&#8217;t know what it was. My mother wore leather gloves in springtime.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>8. It&#8217;s never good when Buzz refers to &#8220;the scene.&#8221;</h5>
<blockquote><p>I did engage in a relationship with a dominatrix after the failure of my second marriage. I left the scene after two years. But I clearly missed it, the trappings of leather increasingly irresistible. I liked extreme feelings of restraint and taking pain.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>7. Buzz was never <em>traditionally</em> sexy. Got it.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I never fit the traditional definition of a sexy male straight or gay—tall, ripped, six- packs within six-packs. I wanted the power that sex provides, all eyes wanting to fuck you and you knowing it, and both men&#8217;s and women&#8217;s clothing became my venue.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>6. Buzz tried to make himself gay but it didn&#8217;t stick.</h5>
<blockquote><p>Was I homosexual because so much of what I wore is associated with gays? I did experiment. And while I don&#8217;t think it is my sexual being, I can tell you that gay men as a group are nicer, smarter, have a shitload more fun than straight whites.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>5. Buzz Bissinger, dominant leather master.</h5>
<blockquote><p>Was I veering toward becoming a dominant leather master in the S&amp;M scene, the leather fetish an obvious influence in most of the clothing I purchased and in much of high fashion itself? I did experiment. Was I a closeted or maybe not so closeted transvestite? Tom Ford makeup is divine; the right foundation and cheek blush and eyeliner and lipstick can do wonders for the pallid complexion.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>4. That poor, poor UPS delivery guy.</h5>
<blockquote><p>Thigh-high boots add to any wardrobe, although walking on six-inch stilettos for hours is just a bitch and therefore confined to the privacy of my house, seen only by the UPS man, who at this point could not possibly be surprised by anything. But a dress or skirt just doesn&#8217;t look good on me, and I can&#8217;t ever do a thing with my hair. The look I was going for was more David Bowie androgynous. It  wasn&#8217;t successful.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>3. I really, really do not want to believe this actually happened.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I also went to Hong Kong and Macao with some friends. We went to sex clubs, many, many sex clubs with many, many women. We became tired. Four days seemed like four years.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h5>2. Buzz spends $20,000 on faux-leather leggings BECAUSE AMERICA.</h5>
<blockquote><p>The United States is a country that has raged against enlightenment since 1776; puritanism, the guiding lantern, has cast its withering judgment on anything outside the narrow societal mainstream. Think it&#8217;s easy to be different in America? Try something as benign as wearing stretch leather leggings or knee-high boots if you are a man.</p></blockquote>
<h5></h5>
<h5>1. Not sure if serious.</h5>
<blockquote><p>I turn out every day in the rocker look that has become totally comfortable. During the Gucci trip a fellow invitee said I looked like &#8220;Bon Jovi,&#8221; a compliment that at this point in my life means more to me than any piece of writing.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Photo via <a href="http://philadelphia.cbslocal.com/2012/11/07/buzzs-outfits/#photo-1">CBS Philly</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/the-20-most-mortifying-parts-of-buzz-bissingers-insane-leather-fetish-essay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anonymous Angst from the Online Journals of Your Youth &#8211; Part IV</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-iv/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-iv/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DogsOfWar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livejournal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122427</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-122413" alt="Emo-4" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Emo-4.jpg" width="300" height="262" /></a>Reading your old LiveJournal posts is way worse than looking at that picture of yourself as a freshman with a bad perm. Your words look into the truth of your little emo heart, that perm was just a bad decision that you&#8217;ll grow out of. Collected here are the anonymous journals of your youth brought forth from the depths of LiveJournal and Xanga. Instead of mashing them all together I&#8217;m going to string them out over a few posts.<span id="more-122427"></span></p>
<blockquote><p>Sun, Oct. 31st, 2004, 09:55 pm &#8211; Try the Priest</p>
<p>Been a long while since I updated.</p>
<p>Last week I went and saw &#8220;A Chorus Line&#8221; at TUTS. Even sat two rows behind George Bush and Barbara. This is the touring show that&#8217;s supposed to end up on Broadway, if I&#8217;m remembering Keely correctly. It was better then a high school version. The dancing was . . . ok, but it makes me rather. . . I dunno. I can dance rings around most of the people in that company, and am probably a better actor and maybe singer. So . . . why am I killing myself over ballet when I could go into musical theater? I have no idea. Bah.</p>
<p>I found it amusing that the director of TUTS said that we should all come to see the high school section of TUTS doing Pippin, and that it&#8217;s great fun for the whole family. I dunno what version of Pippin they have. . . but that&#8217;s not a family oriented play. Especially since it has a sex scene. . . I still want to see it.</p>
<p>Lesse. Had strep throat this week. Icky poo, but at least I got to have a five day weekend.</p>
<p>Rowdy came down this weekend and I made a kick ass beef stew.</p>
<p>While we were checking out the selection of DVDs at Hollywood, I came across a tape of Rainbow Brite and the Star Stealer. HAD to check it out. Rowdy and I wondered why the gay community hasn&#8217;t latched onto this icon of all that is gay and shiny. We broke it down.</p>
<p>Rainbow Land &#8211; where everyone lives. We think this is self explainatory.<br />
Rainbow Brite &#8211; The Ultimate Fag Hag. I think she&#8217;s bisexual.<br />
Red Butler &#8211; Suave, debonair gay guy. Like high society and martinis<br />
La La Orange &#8211; Lipstick lesbian. She&#8217;s the feminine counter point to . . .<br />
Canary Yellow &#8211; Short haired tomboy lesbian. The butch one in the relationship.<br />
Patty O&#8217;Green &#8211; Eco, vegetarian lesbian.<br />
Buddy Blue &#8211; Gym queen.<br />
Indigo &#8211; The token black lesbian.<br />
Shy Violet &#8211; Bookish, nerdy, &#8220;she&#8217;s all that&#8221; lesbian.<br />
Tickled Pink &#8211; club slut.<br />
Stormy &#8211; Drag Queen<br />
Murky &#8211; That annoying leather daddy who&#8217;s always up in your shit, wears clothes that are WAY too tight, and won&#8217;t take no for an answer.<br />
Lurky &#8211; His somewhat hugable, but equally idiotic bear boyfriend.</p>
<p>don&#8217;t even get me started on the fact that Rainbow Brite&#8217;s helper is named Twink.</p>
<p>I just saw something disturbing. Some baseball shoe is using anime in it&#8217;s commerical. Is there nothing sacred in all of nerd-dom?</p>
<p>*Sigh* Off to watch some TV and go to bed.</p>
<p>Lastly, Angela Landsbury singing about cannibalism is just . . .amusing.</p>
<p>Quotes for the day.<br />
&#8220;We&#8217;ve got spirit, yes we do. We are sandwhiches filled with poo!!&#8221;<br />
&#8220;If I have to choose between a douche and a turd, I don&#8217;t see the point of voting&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Rainbow Brite DVDs from Hollywood Video are absolutely the right choice. All the copies of Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind were probably checked out anyway.</p>
<p>Image: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Emo-4.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/anonymous-angst-from-the-online-journals-of-your-youth-part-iv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Prop 8/DOMA Open Thread Part Deux</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/your-prop-8doma-open-thread-part-deux/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/your-prop-8doma-open-thread-part-deux/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mattymcboy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay Equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SCOTUS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet Justice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122644</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday we heard the oral arguments for CA&#8217;s Prop 8 which audio of can be found here and a transcript here. I [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday we heard the oral arguments for CA&#8217;s Prop 8 which audio of can be found <a href="https://soundcloud.com/afer-3/oral-argument-at-the-supreme">here</a> and a transcript <a href="http://www.npr.org/2013/03/26/175351429/audio-supreme-court-arguments-on-california-gay-marriage-ban">here</a>. I would write a recap, but I&#8217;ll be the first to admit that 1) I suck at translating legal jargon into actual English and 2) I don&#8217;t want to get something wrong.<span id="more-122644"></span></p>
<p>Today we&#8217;re getting the DOMA or Defense of Marriage Amendment oral arguments. Background of which can be found <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defense_of_marriage_act">here</a>.</p>
<p>So many questions that I know you, my fellow Crassers have the answers to, so rather than flood the regular Open Thread with predictions and comments, let’s use this one for today.  Post links to whatever live feeds you are listening to.  GIFS and photos more than welcome.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/75905404@N00/394014265/sizes/l/">Photo Credit</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/03/your-prop-8doma-open-thread-part-deux/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.370 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-03-29 09:04:12 -->
