<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Crasstalk</title>
	<atom:link href="http://crasstalk.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://crasstalk.com</link>
	<description>Home Of The Web&#039;s Most Self-Aggrandizing Commenters</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 19:58:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Crasstalk’s Worst Internet Commenters Tournament 2013: The Final Four</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/crasstalks-worst-internet-commenters-tournament-2013-the-final-four/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/crasstalks-worst-internet-commenters-tournament-2013-the-final-four/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teh Interwebz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A Series of Tubes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unwarranted Self-Importance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123152</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well, round one is over and the people have decided. Let&#8217;s have a moment of silence for the horrible commenters [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/bracket-2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123154" alt="bracket 2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/bracket-2.png" width="813" height="511" /></a></p>
<p>Well, round one is over and the people have decided. Let&#8217;s have a moment of silence for the horrible commenters on <em>Craigslist</em>, <em>Twitter</em>, <em>The Blaze,</em> and <em>Huffington Post</em>. You were awful, but not awful enough. Now let&#8217;s talk about the winners. <span id="more-123152"></span></p>
<p><strong>Match #1: YouTube vs. Yelp</strong></p>
<p>YouTube handily won it&#8217;s last match against Twitter with a whopping 93% of the vote. No real surprise, their commenters really do suck. This means it will be a tough match for the Yelpers who had a pretty rough game against the Huffington Post&#8217;s Fighting Libtards who managed to hold 40% of the votes. Look for a match of brute stupidity against undeserved entitlement.</p>
<p><strong>YouTube:</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/YT-1-day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123158" alt="YT 1 day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/YT-1-day2.png" width="705" height="214" /></a><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yt2-day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123159" alt="yt2 day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yt2-day2.png" width="701" height="213" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Yelp:</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yelp1-day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123160" alt="yelp1 day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yelp1-day2.png" width="627" height="620" /></a><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yelp-vr.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123168" alt="yelp vr" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yelp-vr.png" width="668" height="274" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Match #2: Yahoo News vs. Facebook:</strong></p>
<p>This is a match up between two generations of the web. Yahoo the slow powerhouse who is going a little deaf. Facebook is the young guy at the office that everyone would really love to pop across the mouth. Facebook handily beat down Craigslist garnering 75% of the votes. Yahoo had a slightly tougher time, pulling in 68% of the vote against the perpetually confused commenters over at The Blaze. This match comes down to whether you like your craziness from people you know or from people you don&#8217;t know. Either way, America is doomed. Let&#8217;s look at a few samples.</p>
<p><strong>Yahoo News:</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Yahoo2-Day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123174" alt="Yahoo2 Day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Yahoo2-Day2.png" width="663" height="295" /></a><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Yahoo1-day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123175" alt="Yahoo1 day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Yahoo1-day2.png" width="668" height="160" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Facebook:</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/FB1-Day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123176" alt="FB1 Day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/FB1-Day2.png" width="576" height="173" /></a><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/FB2-Day2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123178" alt="FB2 Day2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/FB2-Day2.png" width="564" height="357" /></a></p>
<p>OK, make your choices. <strong>Voting closes at 5 PM EST on Sunday, April 7th.</strong> </p>
<div id="surveyMonkeyInfo">
<div><script src="http://www.surveymonkey.com/jsEmbed.aspx?sm=fJZZXDmF9ADnYB1gJb1AhA_3d_3d"> </script></div>
<p>Create your free online surveys with <a href="http://www.surveymonkey.com/">SurveyMonkey</a> , the world&#8217;s leading questionnaire tool.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/crasstalks-worst-internet-commenters-tournament-2013-the-final-four/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marc Maron Onstage: Faking It As a Matter of Integrity</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/marc-maron-onstage-faking-it-as-a-matter-of-integrity/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/marc-maron-onstage-faking-it-as-a-matter-of-integrity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 14:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ska Hammer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture and Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marc maron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[standup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WTF]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122986</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For dedicated fans of podcast savant Marc Maron, it can be a real challenge to list all the amazing aspects [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/287x500_5269885780_a3ba18d3b3-67pct.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-123024 alignleft" alt="287x500_5269885780_a3ba18d3b3 (67pct)" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/287x500_5269885780_a3ba18d3b3-67pct.jpg" width="192" height="335" /></a>For dedicated fans of <a title="Link to previous Crasstalk article about Maron" href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/02/podcast-savant-marc-maron-on-television-wtf/" target="_blank">podcast savant Marc Maron</a>, it can be a real challenge to list all the amazing aspects of his WTF podcast.</p>
<p>First there are the jokes; those are pretty good. Then there are the incredibly revealing interviews with comics and other performers.</p>
<p>Plus there&#8217;s the astonishingly consistent quality of those conversations: By now most of Maron&#8217;s guests know what to expect from the interviews, so they could easily prepare some boilerplate responses — but almost none of them does. Also there&#8217;s the incredible volume of podcast material available: <a title="Link to Marc Maron's WTF episode guide" href="http://www.wtfpod.com/guide" target="_blank">375 WTF episodes and counting</a>, each one an hour long or more. And there&#8217;s the fact that practically every WTF episode has been made available (temporarily) for free — which for a product of this impossibly high quality seems to defy not just the rules of show business, but of capitalism itself.<span id="more-122986"></span></p>
<p>So by now the WTF podcast exists in a realm beyond criticism. The only remaining question for the host is: How long can he keep it up? Producing all of this magnificent work — basically for free — must eventually take a toll on the man. And during Marc Maron&#8217;s appearance at Boston&#8217;s Wilbur Theatre on March 30, there were indeed some hints that the demands of this unique career were finally starting to catch up with the headliner.</p>
<p>Yet another remarkable fact about Maron&#8217;s WTF podcast is that he often approaches an interview subject with minimal-to-no advance preparation. You know this because Maron points it out regularly — or else his guest might allude to it, taking an opportunity in the charged atmosphere of the WTF studio (usually Maron&#8217;s garage) to throw another jab back at the host. But Maron&#8217;s lack of preparation does make some sense, in context. The man still has a standup act to polish, since he continues to tour as a working comic. And now he has a <a title="Link to IFC's link for _Maron_ show" href="http://www.ifc.com/shows/maron" target="_blank"><em>Portlandia</em>-style television series</a> to concentrate on as well: The show&#8217;s production might be complete, but as its premiere date (May 3) approaches he surely has some promotional work to do.</p>
<p>But on Saturday night at the Wilbur Theatre, Maron&#8217;s lack of preparation was a bit harder to understand. This show was taking place seven weeks later than originally planned: The previous date of February 8 had been moved due to a snowstorm. Yet in his standup gig at the Wilbur on Saturday (before the recording of a live WTF episode later that evening), Maron mostly discussed topics which seemed to occur to him right at that moment, stream-of-consciousness-style. Such topics included certain Boston neighborhoods&#8217; hardscrabble reputations — yeah, amirite, people? And Maron&#8217;s early career, which began with him driving all over New England to perform at low-rent comedy gigs. And in lieu of telling finished jokes, Maron simply dissected his joke-writing process; in fact his notebooks came right onstage with him.</p>
<p>Then Maron began doing what comics call &#8220;crowd work.&#8221; This occurs when a comic engages directly with audience members, transparently looking for topics to riff on. Audience members&#8217; unusual personal situations and vulnerabilities are fair game here. As near as I can tell, the main purpose behind crowd work is to allow the comic to search the audience for topics that he wants to discuss, but hasn&#8217;t written any specific jokes around yet.</p>
<p>(Also crowd work probably functions to keep heckling to a minimum. Because when a comic starts focusing his attention on individual audience members, I&#8217;ll bet everyone else feels relief that they&#8217;re not currently sharing the spotlight with the crazy person onstage.)</p>
<p>This might not sound very entertaining — watching an under-prepared comedian command a stage for ninety minutes while he casts around for something to talk about. And with most comics, that experience probably <em>would</em> be pretty dreary. But for Marc Maron, the act of working things out onstage still fits seamlessly into the overall theme of his comedy — due especially to the existence (and continued excellence) of his podcast.</p>
<p>WTF is billed as a &#8220;comedy&#8221; podcast — and it <em>is</em> pretty funny to listen to. In the usual comedic tradition, Maron&#8217;s most hilarious podcast moments occur when he&#8217;s not really trying to make jokes: For example, I get endless amusement out of picturing the prickly, one-sided conversations he claims to have with his cats. Meanwhile, guest comedians strive to avoid repeating their existing comic bits and instead let their humor emerge organically. And the non-comedian guests <em>really</em> seem to pull out the stops — as if they&#8217;ve been waiting their whole lives to show that they can be spontaneously funny too.</p>
<p>But WTF isn&#8217;t primarily an <em>example</em> of comedy. Instead it&#8217;s mostly <em>about</em> comedy: The business, the lifestyle, the competition. And not to be overlooked, it&#8217;s about jokes too: How to write them, how to tell them, how to know when they&#8217;re working and when to retire them. This &#8220;meta&#8221; approach to entertainment often signifies a lack of imagination and a fatal level of self-consciousness, in several genres: songs about music (sorry, Joan Jett), novels about writers, movies about moviemaking, television sitcoms about television. (This last item is why I can never be convinced to start watching <em>30 Rock</em>. No letters, please.)</p>
<p>But when it comes to comedy about comedy — with Marc Maron, anyway — there&#8217;s something different going on. Somehow it all manages to hang together. There&#8217;s nothing funnier than two professional comedians trying to figure out why something is funny&#8230;then giving up and admitting that in the end, it&#8217;s just mysterious.</p>
<p>So maybe Maron&#8217;s inside-out approach to comedy works because the occupation of &#8220;comedian&#8221; is already absurd to start with: Standing onstage in front of large crowds with the overt premise that you&#8217;re going to make them laugh. Or maybe it&#8217;s because comics are naturally analytical people who receive (brutally) immediate feedback on their successes and failures. Or maybe it&#8217;s just because despite everything else, the practitioners still manage to get off some good jokes once in a while.</p>
<p><em>Caricature of Marc Maron by DonkeyHotey/<a title="Link to Maron caricature in DonkeyHotey's Flickr stream" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/donkeyhotey/5269885780/" target="_blank">Flickr</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/marc-maron-onstage-faking-it-as-a-matter-of-integrity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thursday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/thursday-open-thread-71/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/thursday-open-thread-71/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123046</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to the first Thursday of April. Image via Wiki]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello and welcome to the first Thursday of April. <span id="more-123046"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uNMw34Z63Ck" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Field-yellow-daffodil-flowers_-_West_Virginia_-_ForestWander.jpg">Image via Wiki</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/thursday-open-thread-71/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crasstalk&#8217;s Worst Internet Commenters Tournament 2013</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/crasstalks-worst-internet-commenters-tournament-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/crasstalks-worst-internet-commenters-tournament-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 18:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teh Interwebz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butthurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the internets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Lamestream Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wingnuts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123048</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome weary citizens of the Internet! We all know how soul-sucking internet comments can be. Racism, stupidity, and harsh judgements [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome weary citizens of the Internet! We all know how soul-sucking internet comments can be. Racism, stupidity, and harsh judgements abound. The grammar is enough to make any intelligent person cry. However, not all awfulness is created equal. Some sites have comments that sink to a special level appalling and we here at Crasstalk are ready to determine just who really is the worst of the worst. <span id="more-123048"></span><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>How It Works:</strong> The tournament begins with eight competitors selected from a previous discussion in our Open Threads. There are four brackets.  Readers will vote for the winners in each match-up to determine who continues to the next round. Please support you choice by posting particularly dreadful comments or screenshots in the comments of this post.<br />
<strong><br />
Voting for this round closes at midnight EST tonight, April 3rd.</strong> The next round will be posted tomorrow morning. The final winner will be announced on Monday, April 8th at 8 PM.</p>
<p>Now, to our competitors:</p>
<p><strong>Bracket One: Twitter vs. YouTube</strong></p>
<p><strong>Twitter:</strong> Designed for the poor speller, Twitter is a way for people to communicate the most boring and mundane aspects of their lives and pretend that is some kind of viewpoint on existence. It also allows for shallow discussions about complex issues. Typical User: <a href="https://twitter.com/AnnCoulter/status/260581147493412865">Ann Coulter</a>. Typical Tweet:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ph.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123057" alt="ph" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ph.png" width="708" height="129" /></a><strong>YouTube: </strong>Want to read something racist? Watch a YouTube video about dolphins, or watch a YouTube video about anything. Under any video on the site there is about a 90% chance that there is something racist, sexist, or homophobic posted under it. Also, YouTube has lots of conspiracy nuts so any video about news, science, or politics will attract folks explaining to you about false flags and the lizard people. Typical User: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7DA8l-Pl9ig">VonHelton</a>. Typical Comment:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yt1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123060" alt="yt1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yt1.png" width="697" height="163" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Bracket Two: FaceBook vs. Craig&#8217;s List Rant and Raves</strong></p>
<p><strong>Facebook:</strong> Facebook is a site that allows us to stay in contact with the people we avoided before the invention of Facebook. Now instead of enduring these folks at family funerals or high school reunions, we get to see what they are thinking about every single day. Neat! Even the dumbest people can open a Facebook account, and it shows. Typical User: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sarahpalin?fref=ts">Sarah Palin</a>. Typical Post:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fb.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123067" alt="fb" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/fb.png" width="700" height="304" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Craigslist:</strong> Yeah, I know, old school, but they deserve a special shot for lifetime achievement. The very worst of the Internet flock to Craigslist to sell used furniture, get laid, or bitch in the Rant and Rave Section. All of the bitterness in the world seems to come here to breed and multiply. Typical User: The next serial killer they apprehend in your town. Typical Post:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/cl.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123072" alt="cl" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/cl.png" width="700" height="205" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Bracket Three: Yelp vs. The Huffington Post</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yelp: </strong>Yelp is a site that allows consumers to rate the places they go. Unfortunately, it turns out many consumers are spoiled, whiny, or just plain stupid. While this is a great idea in theory, in reality Yelp has become a way for customers to bully and harass business owners when they don&#8217;t get special treatment, and Yelp sales people have been accused of essentially <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-505123_162-42744374/inside-yelps-blackmail-lawsuit-ceo-stoppelman-seems-to-hate-his-advertisers/">blackmailing business owners who refuse to advertise</a>. Also, there are Yelp reviews for pretty much everywhere no matter how <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/us-post-office-new-york-10#query:post%20office%20washington%20heights">pointless</a>. Typical User: Comic Book Guy. Typical Post: <strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yelp.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123087" alt="yelp" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yelp.png" width="796" height="470" /></a></p>
<p><strong>The Huffington Post:</strong> News central for America&#8217;s less-inquisitive liberals, HuffPo has become a cash machine. While trying to be a source for political news the site still manages to add enough celebrity crap to attract the annoying people who would normally stay over at TMZ. Because teatards think HuffPo is a bastion of liberal thought they constantly show up to add their derp. They do have moderators, but the tide of fail is usually to strong for them to stem. Average user: Fucking Arianna. Typical Comment:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/huffpo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123100" alt="huffpo" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/huffpo.jpg" width="634" height="819" /></a>Note: This argument goes on for 70 more comments.</p>
<p><strong>Bracket Four: Yahoo News vs. The Blaze</strong></p>
<p><strong>Yahoo News:</strong> Yahoo News may be the worst place on the Internet to actually get news. The site seems to employ the absolute worst news writers just to spite its readers, and the stories are often lazy link bait. However, what really distinguishes Yahoo News is its absolutely batshit commenters. This is the news site that your creepy uncle Phil reads from his dilapidated assisted living facility in Boynton Beach. Since you blocked him on Facebook, he is over on this site telling all the racist jokes that got him banned from Thanksgiving a few years ago. No topic on this site, no matter how innocuous or unrelated, fails to elicit hateful responses about President Obama. Typical User: Someone on Medicare who hates the government, people who still bother with Yahoo email accounts. Typical Comments:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yn.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123106" alt="yn" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/yn.jpg" width="649" height="354" /></a></p>
<p><strong>The Blaze:</strong> In past years this spot would have been taken by the rabble over at Fox nation, but a new young competitor has overtaken them as the spot for wing nuts. Glen Beck&#8217;s The Blaze is an eclectic mix of xenophobia, gold advertisements, and weird PR pieces for Beck himself. If you want to know the conservative outrage of the day, head over to The Blaze. While Yahoo News may be the tested veteran, The Blaze has the moxie only an over-confident youngster can possess. Typical users: That guy with all the NOBAMA stickers on his about to be repossessed truck, oppressed white people. Typical Comments:</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/blaze1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123111" alt="blaze1" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/blaze1.png" width="589" height="190" /></a><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/blaze2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123112" alt="blaze2" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/blaze2.jpg" width="631" height="561" /></a></p>
<p>Now that you have the competitors place your votes and make the case for your picks below.</p>
<div id="surveyMonkeyInfo">
<div><script src="http://www.surveymonkey.com/jsEmbed.aspx?sm=MknqD4MXsSck33i6nrpG8Q_3d_3d"> </script></div>
<p>Create your free online surveys with <a href="http://www.surveymonkey.com/">SurveyMonkey</a> , the world&#8217;s leading questionnaire tool.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/crasstalks-worst-internet-commenters-tournament-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>QOTD: Would You Rather</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/qotd-would-you-rather/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/qotd-would-you-rather/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Anita Manbadly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[QOTD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[qotd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[would you rather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123034</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks for agreeing to come into the office today. Let&#8217;s talk about you for a minute. Just hop up on [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/qotd-would-you-rather/"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-123038" alt="qotd" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/qotd1.jpg" width="225" height="225" /></a>Thanks for agreeing to come into the office today. Let&#8217;s talk about you for a minute. Just hop up on the comfy couch, lean back, close your eyes and get yourself centered.</p>
<p>Today, we&#8217;re going to talk about life choices. Sometimes, the universe presents us with choices that we would rather not make. In some situations, we would prefer to make no choice at all, but we have to make choices anyway. Get ready to &#8220;steal the rice and roll the dice.&#8221; Read the questions, make some decisions and tell us why you chose the thing you did.<span id="more-123034"></span></p>
<p>First: Would you rather be rich and ugly or poor and good looking? We&#8217;re talking about fabulously rich, the type of rich where your money does things all by itself without you even thinking about it. And ugly, the kind of ugly that no surgeon&#8217;s knife can fix. On the other hand, you could be the kind of person whose physical appearance drives both men and women crazy, but also bone-stick-stone poor with no chance of earning a living wage. Which way would you go, and why?</p>
<p>Second: Would you rather go to jail for a year or live in your car for a year? Face it, you did something bad, really really bad. You can accept your punishment, hang out in the pokey for a year and hope you don&#8217;t get shiv&#8217;ed. Or, you can &#8220;live off the grid&#8221; and sleep in your car, running around with freegans for your meals. Either way, after a year, you can resume your old life.</p>
<p>Third: Would you rather work really hard at an interesting job or slack off at a boring job? You could be totally consumed by fascinating work, to the exclusion of starting a family or hanging out with friends. Or, you could show up day after day, find something to occupy your alotted hours, and then go home, never thinking about your job when you&#8217;re not there.</p>
<p>Which way will you go in this &#8220;choose your own adventure?&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/qotd-would-you-rather/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Abandoned Places</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/three-abandoned-places-5/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/three-abandoned-places-5/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>LaZiguezon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abandoned places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baltimore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canfranc Railway Station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Divine Lorraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philadelphia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skellig Michael]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urbex]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=121729</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another installment in our series on abandoned places in the world. 1. Divine Lorraine, Philadelphia, Baltimore, United States The 10-story [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another installment in our series on abandoned places in the world.<span id="more-121729"></span></p>
<p><strong>1. Divine Lorraine, Philadelphia, Baltimore, United States</strong></p>
<p>The 10-story Divine Lorraine was built between 1892 and 1894 and designed by architect Willis G. Hale. Initially serving as a high-end apartment complex, it was eventually purchased by Father Divine, leader of the Universal Peace Missions Movement, in 1948. Transformed into a hotel, the Divine Lorraine was the first of its class in Philadelphia to be racially integrated. Closed in 1999, the building was recently purchased by developer Eric Blumenfeld in 2012. Many thanks to Forty for this suggestion.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6849154206_8564bc95c2_z.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122759" alt="6849154206_8564bc95c2_z" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/6849154206_8564bc95c2_z.jpg" width="477" height="593" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Divine-Lorraine-interior.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122764" alt="Divine Lorraine - interior" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Divine-Lorraine-interior.jpg" width="477" height="716" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Divine-Lorraine.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122784" alt="Divine Lorraine" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Divine-Lorraine.jpg" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p><strong><strong>2. Canfranc Railway Station, Spain</strong></strong></p>
<p>Once considered the largest train station in Europe, Canfranc was designed by architect Fernando Ramírez de Dampierre. Linking the Spanish (Aragon) and French (Bearn) sides of the Pyrenees by railway, the Canfranc line was built between 1921-1925 and inaugurated in 1928. During WW2, the site was rumoured to have served as a transfer point for both German gold and British espionage. The station was abandoned in the 1970s when a bridge near L&#8217;Estanguet was destroyed, effectively ending the international link between the two regions.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/canfranc-exterior.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122775" alt="canfranc - exterior" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/canfranc-exterior.jpg" width="600" height="400" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/3182976139_6c8c762b4e_z.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122772" alt="3182976139_6c8c762b4e_z" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/3182976139_6c8c762b4e_z.jpg" width="466" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Canfranc-train.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122788" alt="Canfranc - train" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Canfranc-train.jpg" width="600" height="400" /></a></p>
<p><strong>3. Skellig Michael, Ireland</strong></p>
<p>Located 8 miles off the south-west coast of Ireland, Skellig Michael once served as a Christian Monastery between the 6th and 12th century. When not praying, the monks had constructed beehive huts, two oratories, a church, cross slabs, stone terraces, and some 200 meter flights of stone steps. Added to the Unesco World Heritage list in 1996, the site was abandoned during the 12th century when the monks relocated to the mainland&#8217;s abbey in Ballinskelligs. Seriously, aside from fish, sea birds and grass(?), what did the inhabitants eat?</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Skellig-Michael.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122792" alt="Skellig Michael" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Skellig-Michael.jpg" width="600" height="367" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Skellig-graveyard.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122804" alt="Skellig - graveyard" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Skellig-graveyard.jpg" width="600" height="400" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Skellig-huts.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-122801" alt="Skellig huts" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Skellig-huts.jpg" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>For previous entries, please click <a href="http://crasstalk.com/tag/abandoned-places/">here</a>.</p>
<p>(Images c/o <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/vandalog/6849154206/">1</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/naq/500498715/">2</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jbwendover/8316889318/in/photostream/">3</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/fernandoelia/4531943271/">4</a>, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thasarga/3182976139/">5</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Tren_abandonado_en_Canfranc.jpg">6</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Skellig_Michael02(js).jpg">7</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:St_Michael_Ballinskelligs_1996_08_16.jpg">8</a>, <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Skellig_huts.jpg">9</a>)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/three-abandoned-places-5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Midweek Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/midweek-open-thread-3/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/midweek-open-thread-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Grand Inquisitor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Good day and welcome to Crasstalk. Image via Wikipedia.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/midweek-open-thread-3/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-123083" alt="800px-Orlando-Ferguson-flat-earth-map_edit" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/800px-Orlando-Ferguson-flat-earth-map_edit.jpg" width="800" height="550" /></a></p>
<p>Good day and welcome to Crasstalk. <span id="more-123082"></span></p>
<p><object width="480" height="360"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/6UeCRY1wciA?version=3&amp;hl=en_GB"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/6UeCRY1wciA?version=3&amp;hl=en_GB" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="480" height="360" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></p>
<p>Image via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Orlando-Ferguson-flat-earth-map_edit.jpg">Wikipedia</a>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/midweek-open-thread-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smash Liveblog Season 2 Episode 9 &#8220;The Parents&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-9-the-parents/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-9-the-parents/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 01:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clarity83</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hatewatch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liveblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123013</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ok, folks. Here we go. The last Smash liveblog. Well, at least the last one that I&#8217;ll do as the [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Smash_Title_Card.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-119857" alt="Smash_Title_Card" src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Smash_Title_Card.jpg" width="550" height="228" /></a></p>
<p>Ok, folks. Here we go. The last Smash liveblog. Well, at least the last one that I&#8217;ll do as the show moves to Saturdays starting this Saturday, April 6. We had a good little run here and it definitely made the show more interesting to watch with company.</p>
<p>Tonight&#8217;s episode is called &#8220;The Parents.&#8221; I bet Gay Kyle gets pregnant. That ignorant slut.<span id="more-123013"></span></p>
<p>See you in the comments!</p>
<p>Photo: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Smash_Title_Card.jpg">Wikimedia Commons</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/smash-liveblog-season-2-episode-9-the-parents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telenovela Realness: RuPaul&#8217;s Drag Race Season 5, Episode 9</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-9/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Homoviper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don't fuck it up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[escandolo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homoviper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rupaul's drag race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[season 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telenovela]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=122991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The queens are all sad to see Ivy go, but none as much as Jinkx, who had formed a special [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rupaulsdragraceheader.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rupaulsdragraceheader.jpg" alt="rupaulsdragraceheader" width="510" height="220" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-118184" /></a><br />
The queens are all sad to see Ivy go, but none as much as Jinkx, who had formed a special bond with her. Srsly, we&#8217;re going to need an update on that unrequited crush thing when the reunion airs. Alyssa says if she has to lip sync all the way to the finale, she&#8217;ll do what she has to do. The other queens don&#8217;t like that she is not acknowledging that the challenges are important. Jinkx speaks up once more to defend herself blahblah comedy queen blahblah pageant queen. I know I&#8217;m not the only one tired of them playing that tune over and over again.<span id="more-122991"></span></p>
<p>For the mini challenge, the queens must cry on cue as if they&#8217;re stars in a telenovela. Alaska&#8217;s tip of the hat to <em>Suddenly, Last Summer</em> made my heart sing. The mini challenge is all fun and games until Detox tells the circle that her boyfriend died two years ago so she&#8217;s having a hard time being in character for the task at hand. As in she literally came home and found his dead body there. Fuck, that is so, so awful. It feels weird when Ru says she&#8217;s the winner of the mini challenge, but we don&#8217;t get much time to dwell on it. Alyssa also wins the mini challenge. The two winners of course pick teams for the main challenge, which will be to act in a telenovela.</p>
<p>Ro-laska-tox is reunited and pitted against Alyssa, Coco and Jinkx. Could there be a worse match up than those three? I don&#8217;t think so. It doesn&#8217;t matter because Jinkx is amazing and easily outshines the other two. Alaska and Roxxxy both do well on their team, better than Detox.  Also, Wilmer Valderrama is there for some reason. I know he&#8217;s gross and everything, but I totally would. Don&#8217;t judge me.</p>
<p>On the main stage, Roxxxy and Jinkx are clearly at the top of the pack, but Jinkx deservedly wins. Coco and Alyssa are forced to lip sync for their lives. The producers were totes popping champagne over the fact that they were able to get these two in a head to head lip sync. It is a fierce battle, but Coco prevailed. Finally, after her third time in the bottom, Alyssa was put back on the turnip truck and sent home to Texas.</p>
<p><a href="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/drag_race_index_week9.jpg"><img src="http://crasstalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/drag_race_index_week9-1024x682.jpg" alt="drag_race_index_week9" width="654" height="435" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-122994" /></a></p>
<p>Click to enlarge! With only five queens left after this week&#8217;s episode, things are mostly moving along as predicted. That third wildcard spot sees a change, and Coco continues to sink to the bottom after a brief elevation a couple weeks ago. Let&#8217;s break it down, shall we?</p>
<h4>Jinkx Monsoon</h4>
<p>This is Jinkx&#8217;s competition to lose. She is now the first queen to win two main challenges this season. Her look and acting were amazing in the main challenge. Knowing that Ru judges the queens independently even during group challenges, it was obvious that Jinkx had only to do something good on the main stage to take the win in this episode, and she did. Her Día de Muertos look was inspired! She surprised Ru in the best possible way and also had Michelle Visage admitting that she was confused but liked that Jinkx was keeping her on her toes. Boxy Mandrews &#8212; who once again felt comfortable dismissing Jinkx during the confessional interviews &#8212; better watch out because dismissing Jinkx will be the mistake that sends her home.</p>
<h4>Alaska</h4>
<p>Her look and acting in the main challenge were just so fucking good. I loved her. Yes, her main stage getup was cheap looking, but her personality sold the whole package to me. She stays firmly in the number two position of the Index this week because she is consistently a very strong competitor, and she proved it again this week. I really think this competition is going to come down to Alaska and Jinkx.</p>
<h4>Roxxxy Andrews</h4>
<p>Roxxxy had a good week. I have to admit this even though I hate her. Did you know I hate her? Did I forget to mention it last time? She did well in the telenovela challenge. It was reminiscent of what she was able to pull off in the children&#8217;s show challenge. I can&#8217;t deny how well she did on the main stage. This is word for word what I typed into my notes: &#8220;Roxxxy looks better than she ever has.&#8221; The clothing was right for her. Her makeunder was lovely &#8212; Santino was so right that her makeup has never looked better. Is she improving? Is she taking notes on what the judges say? We&#8217;ll see how she does with clothes and makeup next week.</p>
<h4>Detox</h4>
<p>Detox had a slightly off week. While her look for the main challenge was funny, she was definitely overshadowed by the other two on her team. Her main stage look seemed to be pretty good, but Michelle Visage felt the scale of the sombrero was off. Detox could easily reclaim the wildcard spot next week depending on how she does <strong>and</strong> how Roxxxy does. It&#8217;s definitely a tossup between those two for the third spot in the top three.</p>
<h4>Coco Montrese</h4>
<p>Coco once again proved she doesn&#8217;t have what it takes to keep her head in the game and do her best in a group challenge. Her performance as the maid was weak. Even Alyssa &#8212; who was terrible &#8212; did better in the main challenge than she did, I think. Coco&#8217;s main stage look <em>was</em> very nice, but it didn&#8217;t compensate for her main challenge failure, and frankly when people like Jinkx are pulling out looks like that Día de Muertos thing for the main stage? Your little jumpsuit ain&#8217;t gonna cut it, Coco.</p>
<h4>Alyssa Edwards</h4>
<p>Sashay away, dickvoice. Oh, Alyssa. I came to appreciate her eventually. I&#8217;m not saying I ever <em>liked</em> her, but the violent reaction I initially had to her was dialed way back over the weeks, and I felt I understood her better. She is a decent queen with a good look and dance moves that slay. She could lip sync for her motherfucking life. But she lacked the x factor that enables queens like Jinkx to do so well in the challenges, and that ultimately has to be part of what propels a queen to the finale.</p>
<p>So, chickens, what did you think of this week&#8217;s episode? Sound off in the comments, and also give us your top three! Who&#8217;s it going to be?</p>
<p>p.s. Did you catch the preview for next week? It&#8217;s the &#8220;make these totally butch guys into drag queens&#8221; challenge, and some of you probably remember from last year that I <em>hate</em> this challenge. But! Maybe it&#8217;ll be different somehow this time. (Or maybe not.) At least there will be hot guys to ogle, I guess, and I appreciate that they&#8217;re having military men on after the repeal of DADT.</p>
<p>See you next week.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/rupauls-drag-race-season-5-episode-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tuesday Open Thread</title>
		<link>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-71/</link>
		<comments>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-71/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dancing Queen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open Threads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crasstalk.com/?p=123001</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One way, or another. I&#8217;m gonna find you. MorgueFile]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One way, or another. I&#8217;m gonna find you.<span id="more-123001"></span></p>
<p><iframe width="480" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kGl6KK90kbc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.morguefile.com/archive/display/176581">MorgueFile</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crasstalk.com/2013/04/tuesday-open-thread-71/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.370 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2013-04-04 15:59:01 -->
