<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>OccupyWallSt News</title><link>http://occupywallst.org</link><description>News and information relating to the Occupy Wall Street movement</description><atom:link href="http://occupywallst.org/rss/news/" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 17:09:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Debt Strangles the 99%</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/debt-strangles-99percent/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://steadfastfinances.com/blog/2008/10/13/america-in-debt-24-of-american-families-are-debt-free/"&gt;76% of Americans are in debt.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://money.usnews.com/money/personal-finance/articles/2012/05/09/how-to-protect-yourself-from-criminal-debt-collectors"&gt;15% are being pursued by one or more debt collectors.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/economics/2010/07/31/number-of-the-week-default-repercussions/"&gt;22% of Americans are too impoverished to qualify for credit.&lt;/a&gt; That forces them into informal debt like payday loans or worse, which generate &lt;a href="http://blog.chron.com/thelist/2010/04/predatory-payday-lending-500-interest-is-wrong-and-hurts-families/"&gt;interest rates of up to 500%&lt;/a&gt;. So add that together and we have the 99%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="62% of bankruptcies" src="http://i.imgur.com/IPTVaJdl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://strikedebt.org/"&gt;Strike Debt&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://rollingjubilee.org/"&gt;Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a&gt; believe that no one should have to go into debt to cover basic human rights like health care, education, and housing. &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/28/debt-collectors_n_1307204.html"&gt;One in seven Americans is being pursued by a debt collector&lt;/a&gt;. Credit card debt is often the “plastic safety net” that covers for gaps in household budgets caused by financing such essentials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical debt is an area of personal debt that no one from outside the United States can even understand. &lt;a href="http://www.globalpost.com/dispatch/news/afp/130317/spanish-healthcare-workers-protest-over-cost-control-efforts"&gt;Spanish activists are campaigning against the privitization of their national single-payer health system&lt;/a&gt;. They see any payment for medical treatment as the breakdown of a decent society. The idea that people might be driven to bankruptcy by medical debt is literally incomprehensible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the United States, we find that no less than &lt;a href="http://articles.cnn.com/2009-06-05/health/bankruptcy.medical.bills_1_medical-bills-bankruptcies-health-insurance?_s=PM:HEALTH"&gt;62% of all bankruptcies involve medical debt&lt;/a&gt;. Of these people, three-quarters actually had medical insurance. So many drugs and procedures are not covered, and so high are the deductibles, that an insured person can easily find themselves unable to cover their medical bills. Two-thirds of working households do not have the resources to cover a $1000 emergency. One hour of a specialist doctor’s time can cost that alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even these stark figures conceal the discrimination built into health care for people of color, low-income workers and LGBTQ populations. &lt;a href="http://www.commonwealthfund.org/Publications/Fund-Reports/2011/Mar/Help-on-the-Horizon.aspx?page=all"&gt;More than half of African-Americans struggle to pay medical bills&lt;/a&gt;, compared with 34% of Hispanics and 28% of whites. &lt;a href="http://colorofchange.org/blog/2012/jun/30/supreme-court-upholds-affordable-care-act/"&gt;Black and Latino New Yorkers are more than twice as likely as whites to be uninsured&lt;/a&gt;. Despite some progress in recent years, &lt;a href="http://www.americanprogress.org/issues/lgbt/report/2009/12/21/7048/how-to-close-the-lgbt-health-disparities-gap/"&gt;LGBT individuals are less likely to have health insurance&lt;/a&gt;, more likely to delay seeking medical care and medication, and more likely to have a number of physical and mental health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ideas.repec.org/p/fal/wpaper/06001.html"&gt;The uninsured and the poor receive poorer quality care in different locations, at different times, and by less trained physicians than those who are privately insured.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Affordable_Health_Care_for_America_Act"&gt;Affordable Health Care Act (aka Obamacare)&lt;/a&gt; will not address most of these problems. It will certainly raise access—to expensive “under-insurance” plans with high deductibles and lots of out-of-pocket costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strike Debt believes that health care that covers all a person’s needs is not a “Cadillac” plan but a human right.&lt;/strong&gt; Such human rights should not be limited to top executives and members of Congress, who award themselves 100% health care coverage. No one should be driven into bankruptcy by an accident or an illness. In much of the developed world, these sentiments are just common sense. It’s a measure of how reactionary neo-liberalism has become in the United States that they are received here as radical. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Life or Debt” is the choice we are offered. We refuse. Strike Debt. You are not a loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3-1g7ffCaz8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 17:09:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/debt-strangles-99percent/</guid></item><item><title>All Out For Kimani!</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/all-out-kimani/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;div style="text-align:center"&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://strikedebt.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Kimani-March24th-300x273.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 3/24 3PM:

&lt;p&gt;Occupy Wall Street and Strike Debt

&lt;p&gt;Stand in Solidarity With the Community of East Flatbush

&lt;p&gt;and the Family of Kimani Gray

&lt;p&gt;March from 55th &amp; Church to the 67th Precinct
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

This Sunday, people of conscience from across the city will gather in East Flatbush, Brooklyn to show solidarity with the friends, family and community of Kimani “Kiki” Gray as they express their grief, voice their anger, and demand justice. Gray was killed on March 9th by the NYPD, the latest in a systemic pattern of police violence against black and brown communities across the United States. The officers who killed Gray have a documented history of abuse. In order to legitimize the killing, these officers claimed that Gray pointed a gun at them. Eyewitnesses to the killing contest this claim. Gray was shot seven times, three of which were in the back. According to witnesses, Gray was left lying on the ground pleading for his life–“please don’t let me die.”
&lt;p&gt;
 We call upon all Occupy networks and allies to participate in the Justice for Kimani event this Sunday as an intentional step to amplify this local community action, as well as the nation-wide movement against police violence, mass incarceration, and economic injustice. We stand with our allies who are organizing around Stop and Frisk, implementing Copwatch programs, conducting Know Your Rights trainings, and more. The crisis has been building, and the time is long overdue for people of all races, colors, and creeds to come together for racial justice. In the words of Martin Luther King, Jr., “Justice too long delayed is justice denied.”
&lt;p&gt;
 We also recall the words of Malcolm X: “You can’t have capitalism without racism.” This analysis remains as true today as it was three generations ago, even as oppression has taken on new forms. Predatory debt, public austerity, emergency restructuring, climate crisis: the disasters of Wall Street hit black and brown people the hardest, magnifying the history of racism in the United States and undoing the progress made after the Civil Rights movement. In our urban zones of emergency, there is no justice, only law enforcement; no prosperity, only poverty; no future; only prisons. The harassment, incarceration, and killing of young people like Kimani Gray, Shantel Davis, Oscar Grant, Manuel Diaz, Sean Bell, Ramarley Graham, Trayvon Martin, Amadou Diallo, and countless others bring the depths of this collective racial trauma into horrific relief. We refuse not to look when the NYPD tells us “move along, there is nothing to see here.”
&lt;p&gt;
 Things have come to a head in East Flatbush: riot gear, horses, helicopters, barricades, mass arrests, intimidation, divide-and-conquer tactics. Bloomberg and the NYPD want to sow fear and enforce silence – especially among the young friends of Kimani who had the courage to take the streets and confront the police on the night of March 14th.
&lt;p&gt;
The blood marking the streets of Flatbush, Bronx, Anaheim, Oakland, and beyond fuels a movement already in motion. The movement combines indignant rage with militant love. The actions in East Flatbush and other neighborhoods are sparking something big that strikes at the heart of the system.
&lt;p&gt;
The affirmation of life, healing, and community is the true threat presented by the movement, as it charts a path from protest to reconstruction–the repayment of debts owed to communities for generations of stolen lives and incalculable sums of stolen wealth. Why are there plenty of resources for the Stop and Frisk patrols, while physical spaces in the neighborhood lie fallow that could be used as commons for the community?
&lt;p&gt;
 Looking to the legacies of Frederick Douglass, Sojourner Truth, Marcus Garvey, WEB Dubois, Martin Luther King, Ella Baker, Fannie Lou Hamer, Malcolm X, James and Grace Lee Boggs, and untold freedom fighters throughout history, our shared dream is the worst nightmare of the 1%: a People’s City liberated from the violence of the police and the violence of Wall Street alike.
&lt;p&gt;
 Justice for Kimani!
&lt;p&gt;
Drop the Charges Against the Flatbush 45!
&lt;p&gt;
Another World is Possible!
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/all-out-kimani/</guid></item><item><title>International Week of Solidarity with the NATO 5: May 16–21</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/international-week-solidarity-nato-5-may-1621/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Free the NATO 5" src="http://i.imgur.com/6awi4gv.png?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://nato5support.wordpress.com/international-week-of-solidarity-with-the-nato-5/"&gt;via nato5support.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are calling on comrades around the world to help raise awareness of the NATO 5 cases and support funds for the defendants on the one-year anniversary of their preemptive arrests. Please read the call-out below and start planning your action or event today!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 16, 2012, Chicago cops raided an apartment in the Bridgeport neighborhood of Chicago in an all-too-common attempt to scare people away from the imminent protests against the NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organization) summit. With guns drawn, the cops arrested 11 people in or around the apartment and quickly disappeared them into the bowels of the extensive network of detention facilities in Cook County, Illinois.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few days, a few things started becoming clear: 2 of the arrested “activists” were actually undercover Chicago cops who had targeted the real activists for arrest, 6 of them were illegally held and released at the last possible minute before court action could be taken to force their release, and 3 had been charged with trumped-up, politically motivated terrorism charges. These three—Brent Betterly, Brian Jacob Church, Jared Chase—are now known as the NATO 3. They were ultimately charged with 11 felony counts, including material support for terrorism, conspiracy to commit terrorism, and creating Molotov cocktails. They face up to 40 years in prison and are expected to go to trial in September. Their lawyers recently filed a motion to dismiss the terrorism charges for being unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two other Chicago-area activists—Mark Neiweem and Sebastian Senakiewicz—were also preemptively arrested. Mark was arrested in a spectacular snatch-and-grab as he was leaving a restaurant. He was charged with soliciting materials for an explosive device and is facing up to 30 years in prison; his trial date has not yet been set. Sebastian was arrested in another spectacular house raid and charged with falsely making a terrorist threat for allegedly claiming that he had explosive materials and wanted to use them during the convention. Facing 15 years in prison followed by deportation to his native Poland after serving his sentence, he took a non-cooperating plea deal last November. He was sentenced to 4 years with a recommendation of 4 months in boot camp. He is expected to begin his immigration proceedings immediately after completing his sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the one-year anniversary of these preemptive, politically motivated arrests draws near, we are calling for a week of solidarity actions and fundraisers for the NATO 5. &lt;strong&gt;All five defendants have been incarcerated since their arrests last May.&lt;/strong&gt; Being held hostage in jail is extremely expensive for prisoners, as they are forced to purchase all their hygiene products, writing supplies, additional food to supplement the starvation portions given to them each day, and other basic necessities from the jail’s commissary at exorbitant prices. The legal defense costs for the defendants is also mounting, as their lawyers are working hard to help them win their freedom and there is a ton of evidence to sift through and other preparations to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This May, stand in solidarity with the NATO 5! Organize a house party, bake sale, silent auction, cabaret, raffle, rally, noise demo, art auction, street theater performance, concert…whatever you and your friends want! Send us an email at nato5solidarity(A)gmail.com to let us know what you have planned and then send us photos afterwards! You can also write the defendants to let them know what you have planned (&lt;a href="https://nato5support.wordpress.com/contact/"&gt;https://nato5support.wordpress.com/contact/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NATO 5 cases are linked by a few common threads. People around the world have come together to protest NATO’s role in worldwide military expenditures and operations, the organization’s penchant for wantonly killing civilians for the benefit of its member nations—particularly the United States—and its disregard for human rights. Additionally, undercover Chicago police officers targeted and entrapped the activists because of their politics, which is part of a broader pattern of state repression against political activists, in which charging activists as terrorists is one of many strategies being used to silence dissent and dismantle activist communities. Other recent cases in which activists have been targeted include the Cleveland 4 (&lt;a href="http://www.cleveland4solidarity.org/)"&gt;http://www.cleveland4solidarity.org/)&lt;/a&gt;, the Green Scare cases (&lt;a href="http://www.greenisthenewred.com/blog/"&gt;http://www.greenisthenewred.com/blog/&lt;/a&gt;), and the Pacific Northwest Grand Jury resisters (&lt;a href="http://nopoliticalrepression.wordpress.com/"&gt;http://nopoliticalrepression.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these prisoners need your financial support and solidarity as well. The Pacific Northwest Grand Jury resisters are calling for a week of solidarity actions from April 24–May 1 (&lt;a href="http://saynothing.noblogs.org/call-for-coordinated-week-of-solidarity-actions/"&gt;http://saynothing.noblogs.org/call-for-coordinated-week-of-solidarity-actions/&lt;/a&gt;) and the Tinley Park 5 are calling for a day of solidarity on May 19 (&lt;a href="http://www.anarchistnews.org/content/one-year-anniversary-arrest-tp5"&gt;http://www.anarchistnews.org/content/one-year-anniversary-arrest-tp5&lt;/a&gt;). And don’t forget about June 11th, the International Day of Solidarity with long-term anarchist prisoners Eric McDavid and Marie Mason (&lt;a href="http://june11.org/"&gt;http://june11.org/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make this spring and summer a time of solidarity for the NATO 5 and all targets of state repression!&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 16:24:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/international-week-solidarity-nato-5-may-1621/</guid></item><item><title>Proposal: Occupy National Gathering, Kalamazoo, Aug. 21-25 </title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/proposal-occupy-national-gathering-kalamazoo-aug-2/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Imgur" src="http://i.imgur.com/QWZW6fs.jpg?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;via &lt;a href="http://occupynationalgathering.net/proposal"&gt;OccupyNationalGathering.net:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, the National Gathering Working Group 2013 (NGWG2013), propose a National Gathering of the Occupy Movement, and peoples’ movements worldwide, in Kalamazoo Michigan, to collectively assemble and embrace our different ideologies and perspectives; to find our common visions; to share our strategies and actions; and to leave this gathering with steps we can all take in both agreement and diversity; for ourselves, our communities, our nations, and for all of us all over the world.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We further propose that our convergence begin on Aug. 21 and continue for five days of Community and Movement building exercises including speakers, teach-ins, and
free-flowing open discussion at a location to be determined by the Occupy Kalamazoo General Assembly.  We believe it’s time the people of the world spoke to each other about how to make a better world. We ask you to converge with us, to bring your ideas, your struggles, and your voice and come to Kalamazoo!
We already have networks on board with these broad areas of interest and welcome and need your suggestions, participation and contributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s2QDueRl3dWo32-DDzuY57aIImkiyNVo-XPyhV5AYAk/edit#bookmark=id.sey9xm5xuxj2"&gt;Fixing Fossil Fuels and Creating an Environmentally Sustainable Future.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s2QDueRl3dWo32-DDzuY57aIImkiyNVo-XPyhV5AYAk/edit#bookmark=id.m4xcgjsj0jkb"&gt;Economic and Trade Justice, Equal Access and Ending Corporate “Personhood”,   Asserting the    People’s Sovereignty.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s2QDueRl3dWo32-DDzuY57aIImkiyNVo-XPyhV5AYAk/edit#bookmark=id.79hej7ez1ty5"&gt;Making and Supporting Free, Unfettered Media.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s2QDueRl3dWo32-DDzuY57aIImkiyNVo-XPyhV5AYAk/edit#bookmark=id.lsqx5lky9kl9"&gt;Ending War and Our Police State, Building Peace and Cooperation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s2QDueRl3dWo32-DDzuY57aIImkiyNVo-XPyhV5AYAk/edit#bookmark=id.35fv66li7x75"&gt;Renew Kalamazoo and your community. Homeless Bill of Rights.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also encourage the creation of local, national and global processes to communicate, organize and converge.  We are meeting more and more on the internet, on mumble, on conference calls.  Global infrastructures are appearing, to bring more people together and able to participate worldwide. We are able as a people to organize worldwide protests and actions. We envision a day of concerted worldwide actions focused on very local issues that expose those local issues as part of the worldwide fight against systemic injustice.  We will gather and share this worldwide action through all the media tools and networks we continue to build through voluntary people power.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We embrace the value derived from face-to-face contact, and understand that no single gathering can be representative of our entire movement.  We recognize that attending in person will be challenging, or impossible for many, so we also commit to pursuing an online component through which anyone can participate via the Internet. We encourage the creation of local, national and global processes by which movement resources could be directed towards funding travel for active movement participants that otherwise would not be able to attend.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In keeping with principles of the Occupy Movement, the NGWG2013 will continue planning this gathering only if this proposal is ratified by a preponderance of General Assemblies from across the Movement.
We are committed to operating in an open, inclusive, and transparent way. Therefore, most planning will be done via direct democratic conference calls, hubs and collaborative tools through the InterOccupy.net platform. All are welcome to participate. We endeavor to convene an historic gathering that will require a great deal of organization, so we invite participants from all Occupys and friends to join us in the planning and facilitation of this effort.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you come to Kalamazoo Aug. 21 – 25.  We ask for your endorsement, and would be honored if you would join us, live, online or in solidarity actions, and become part of this beautiful expression of our collective will!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Gathering Working Group 2013&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The NGWG2013 is comprised of Occupy Kalamazoo on the ground, and other
Occupiers from across the Globe online, hopefully to soon include you! Please send your endorsement or intent of solidarity to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#110;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#50;&amp;#48;&amp;#49;&amp;#51;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;"&gt;&amp;#110;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#103;&amp;#97;&amp;#116;&amp;#50;&amp;#48;&amp;#49;&amp;#51;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; or comment on our website.  We hope to soon have a form on the website!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Info:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; NGWG Website: &lt;a href="http://www.occupynationalgathering.net"&gt;http://www.occupynationalgathering.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; NGWG Facebook:  &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/OccupyNationalGathering?ref=ts&amp;amp;fref=ts"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/OccupyNationalGathering?ref=ts&amp;amp;fref=ts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt; Twitter: @Ng2Kzoo #NatGat2  #natgat2  #NatGat2013  #natgat2013 #Natgat2@thezoo&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/em&gt; Occupy Carnival of Social Change:  &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/458980454155941/"&gt;http://www.facebook.com/events/458980454155941/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
* National Gathering Hub on InterOccupy:  &lt;a href="http://interoccupy.net/natgat2/"&gt;http://interoccupy.net/natgat2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join our Planning Call!  &lt;a href="http://interoccupy.net/blog/ai1ec_event/national-gathering-planning-call/?instance_id=3539210"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;.  We convene every Wednesday at 8 PM ET!&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:24:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/proposal-occupy-national-gathering-kalamazoo-aug-2/</guid></item><item><title>In Zurich, and Across Europe, Squatter Communities are Strengthening</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/squatter-communities/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://i.imgur.com/7IbqnLOl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.occupy.com/article/zurich-and-across-europe-squatter-communities-are-strengthening"&gt;via Occupy.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt; We can all stop wringing our hands about "the next Occupy." Whatever our reasons for doing so—worrying that it might sweep the globe with irresistible force, or worrying that it won’t—we can rest assured that it is coming, just in a form we haven’t imagined yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must remind ourselves that the global phenomenon we called "Occupy" was the (far from spontaneous) coalescence of various currents and codes based in self-organization that had already been around for decades—and are still around. This anarchistic ethos burst into the broader public consciousness in a new way, and though it was beaten back underground by astonishing state repression on a global scale, it will emerge again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if this coalescence called "Occupy" was in part a product of advances in communications, a brief moment when people were a step ahead of authorities—organizing using technologies not yet fully understood, monitored, or otherwise compromised by state power—the next global coalescence will be too. The democratization of communication technology continues to barge forward, and movements continue to develop in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are these movements, then, these communities and networks of self-organized resistance in opposition to the stronger-than-ever forces of militarized global neo-liberalism and corporate fascism?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right before our eyes, frankly. I can only speak to what I know: for example, in my hometown of Minneapolis, which I have been following with interest from afar, Occupy Homes has been active and successful in the ongoing struggle against evictions, sometimes using the tactic which their name describes and which has been practiced in Europe for decades: squatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in Switzerland, my activities with Occupy Zurich brought me in contact with the local squatter scene here. Note: the affinity between these movements is well expressed by the fact that the same German word is used for "occupy" and "squat:" besetzen. And it is worth briefly exploring these so-called "self-organized spaces," since my impression is that squatting is a phenomenon taken largely for granted in Europe, but relatively unknown in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seen as a threat, and threatened with extinction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autonomous communities and the buildings they occupy are a particularly pressing topic in Europe at the moment. As austerity sweeps the continent, squats—among the last remaining scraps of common space (Freiraum) and therefore burrs in the saddle of neo-liberalism’s charging horse, privatization—are being systematically cleared out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Greece, the wave of squat evictions has been largely driven by the need to eliminate real centers of active opposition that threaten the status quo (see my January portrait of Athens’ antagonist movements, &lt;a href="http://www.occupy.com/article/dispatch-greece-meeting-antagonist-movements"&gt;http://www.occupy.com/article/dispatch-greece-meeting-antagonist-movements&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.occupy.com/article/thank-god-fascists-dispatch-weimar-greece"&gt;http://www.occupy.com/article/thank-god-fascists-dispatch-weimar-greece&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Switzerland, however, the threat to the status quo by the existence and activities of autonomous communities is not as deeply felt; anarchists are seen as an amusing if sometimes annoying minority worth scant attention in the political sphere. But the moves to eliminate these communities here are equally hysterical and harsh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even self-organized spaces that have a widely recognized and appreciated function in city life—like the Autonomous School of Zurich (ASZ), which provides language courses and legal advocacy help for severely under-served migrant communities—are being threatened by encroaching "development" and often face disproportionate police violence when they resist eviction or attempt to squat new spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where there was a mysterious fire last month at Villa Rosenau, a squat beloved enough in Basel that supportive editorials even appeared in the right-leaning Basler Zeitung, the building was simply demolished by police with no warning or explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And last weekend, residents and supporters of Binz, Zurich’s longest-established squat (and the one more or less carrying the torch of the Freiraum movements from the late ‘60s and early ‘80s through today), were met with tear gas, rubber bullets and water cannons when a party turned into a march towards the city center to protest their imminent eviction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all reminds me very much of what I saw in Greece this past winter. Perhaps as a result of examples in Athens, there is a growing awareness and fear among Swiss authorities about what autonomous communities can become, should conditions be allowed to change. There seems to be a compulsion to "nip it in the bud," to crack down early while these groups are still small, disorganized and vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strength in numbers: Building networks, changing the narrative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these groups are in fact not small, disorganized, or vulnerable. That is, as long as they continue to explore new technologies and methods of communication, to network within countries and across borders in ways that were impossible only a short time ago. There has been a recent proliferation of facebook pages, blogs and hacktivist communities promoting solidarity and active cooperation among squats and autonomous zones all across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Villa Amalias squat in Athens was raided in late December of 2012, and completely shut down a month later, there were solidarity actions from Barcelona to London to Copenhagen, with squats throughout Germany and the former Yugoslavia showing particularly broad-based support. The ripples even reached Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And among the nearly 4,000 Binz supporters whom the police attacked last Saturday—turning Zurich’s city center into a soggy, stinking swamp of tear gas and trash fires—were not only former residents of Villa Rosenau in Basel, but a noticeably large number of German Autonomen. Solidarity was declared online, with astonishing speed, from Athens to Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This latter seems perhaps insignificant—a blog post or a lively discussion on facebook isn’t the same as a united continental front organized in credible opposition to the neo-liberal power structure. But it isn’t terribly unrealistic to say it is a step in that direction, and one that was unimaginable in the "old media" context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of "old media," the few major newspapers that carried stories about last weekend’s three-hour, city-disabling street battle in the heart of Zurich (which one would think deserves a bit of in-depth reporting) focused solely on the extent of damage caused by vandals and avoided any reference to the political underpinnings of the event—underpinnings which would have shown the interconnectedness of similar actions and reactions occurring all over Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same media narrative that has been changing the subject and discrediting anti-capitalist movements for nearly two decades. Reporting on the 1999 Battle in Seattle comes to mind; it goes nearly without saying that similar propagandist tactics were also employed in coverage of Occupy. And even the best attempts by proponents of these movements to reframe the conversation—Rebecca Solnit’s writing is a great example—have until recently been largely ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“10,000 Squats Against Their World of Depression!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, this is changing. The newspapers and networks will keep telling the same story. But with the explosion of online social networking and New Media, television and newspaper versions of events are becoming less and less relevant to the discourse actually occurring among people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The communication, coordination and solidarity becoming evident among previously insular squatter communities is a very promising sign. The next step will be to begin directing this communication from the movement outward—that it might become perceived as a movement, and therefore a movement that people can join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories are surfacing about pensioners in Germany squatting a senior center under threat of closure due to lack of funds; of Spanish indignados breaking into sealed, vacant apartment buildings not to squat themselves but to provide living space for recent evictees of all stripes; of Minnesotans fighting the banks and refusing to leave their homes; even of anarchist movements being forged in the current tumults of the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time appears ripe to begin introducing squatter philosophies such as self-organization and the struggle for Freiraum and community preservation into the broader public discourse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I will start now with an appeal, from Europe to the United States, to radicalize. It is often remarked how many houses stand vacant in America—enough to outnumber homeless families. What to do with all these homes? Move into them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move in, and use every New Media channel available—from social networking sites to blogs to podcasting to the still-emerging Commotion software—first to organize and to learn about the practicalities of squatting, then to make sure everybody knows why you're occupying the homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can expect solidarity and support from Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was written by Ed Sutton and is republished with permission from &lt;a href="http://www.occupy.com/article/zurich-and-across-europe-squatter-communities-are-strengthening"&gt;Occupy.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 22:25:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/squatter-communities/</guid></item><item><title>Rage in Brooklyn: Arrests at Third Day of Demonstrations for Teen Killed by NYPD</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/rage-brooklyn-arrests-third-day-demonstrations-tee/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kimani Gray memorial" src="http://i.imgur.com/SxCcICZ.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;via &lt;a href="http://occupywallstreet.net/story/rage-brooklyn-arrests-third-day-demonstrations-teen-killed-nypd"&gt;OccupyWallStreet.net&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16-year-old Kimani Gray was shot seven times – four times in the front of his body, and three times in the back – last Saturday. And for a third straight day demonstrators gathered in his neighborhood, East Flatbush, to protest New York Police Department brutality. After 100 people attended a candlelight vigil near Brooklyn's 67th Precinct,  as many as 50 people were arrested as a demonstration spread throughout the neighborhood. Thereafter, according to a range of bloggers and social media activists, East Flatbush became &lt;a href="http://uscop.org/the-nypd-declares-martial-law-in-brooklyn/"&gt;a "frozen area,"&lt;/a&gt; with media barred.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://rt.com/usa/police-flood-brooklyn-neighborhood-238/"&gt;RT&lt;/a&gt; reports, "Brooklynites were heard shouting "murderers!" at the massive police presence Wednesday as officers prohibited people from even stepping onto the street in one of New York's poorer neighborhoods while police helicopters circled overhead." Ray Kelly himself, the Police Commissioner, did not characterize the demonstration as a riot, as some local newspapers did, but he did describe the assembly as disorderly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police mistrust runs deep in a neighborhood disproportionately targeted by the NYPD's &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/02/11/nypd-muslims-stop-and-frisk-nyc-mayor_n_2664639.html"&gt;deeply unpopular&lt;/a&gt; Stop and Frisk policy, widely regarded as a &lt;a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/subjects/s/stop_and_frisk/index.html"&gt;racist&lt;/a&gt; practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franclot Graham told AP: "I'm not going to tell people don't be angry because we're all angry...It's OK to vent but you have to respect the family's wishes and be peaceful." Graham's teenage son, Ramarley Graham, was shot and killed after police chased him into his Bronx home last year. A New York police officer has since been charged with manslaughter in the death.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray's family maintains &lt;a href="http://blogs.villagevoice.com/runninscared/2013/03/kimani_gray_1.php"&gt;he wasn't armed&lt;/a&gt;. According to AP, a cousin of Kiki, Ray Charles, was still having trouble accepting the NYPD's official version of events: "My cousin was scared of guns...I honestly just want justice. They didn't need to shoot him like that...The real issue in Brooklyn is cops have been harassing us for a long time," he said. "It needs to stop."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;ON-THE-SCENE REPORTING FROM OCCUPY WALL STREET&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Occupy activist on the scene, Austin Guest, observed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the invitation of a comrade from Flatbush, I went down for the second straight night tonight to the protests surrounding Kimani Gray's murder at 55th &amp;amp; Church.  Out of a sea of over three hundred people, I was one of maybe a dozen white faces, most of them journalists.  For the the first time in over a year spent organizing non-stop demonstrations on Wall Street, I was at a protest, but I was just along for the ride – firmly and gladly ensconced in the back seat.  From that back-seat position, I witnessed one the most mind-blowing protests I have ever been to. I felt humbled and at times scared – in the presence of a deep, intense force surging up, demanding to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few moments that stick in my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A crowd of protesters being pushed aggressively out of the street in front of the 67th precinct by riot cops, turning on a dime, sprinting in the opposite direction, finding and surrounding a cop car, shoving it and hitting its windows, dispersed only by a barrage of pepper spray to their faces from the terrified cop inside the car&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A teenage girl staring down a line of riot cops and yelling "MURDERERS!" fearlessly at the top of her lungs into their stone cold faces&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The look of panic on the driver of a police van's face after the rear window of his van was smashed, seemingly from nowhere&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A crowd being pushed down a side street by scooter cops, followed minutes later by a shower of glass bottles flying from apartment buildings onto the heads of the scooter cops&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A car by Kimani's memorial blasting Bob Marley's "War" and a mass of quiet, somber people pulsing and bobbing their heads in slowly growing rage."&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tensions were high, but according to Yoni Brombacher Miller, "I wasn't worried about getting arrested myself; it was clear they (the NYPD) weren't interested in the non-people of color, or adults. They were clearly going after the youth."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brombacher Miller added, "How can we best amplify and strengthen their militant struggle for justice? Some, like Councilman Jumaane Williams argued that the 'youth should be controlled', and while he argues that they're right to be angry, he is also stifling their rage instead of agitating with them. The NYPD cannot and will not be part of the restorative process. The only steps that must be taken, are a demilitarized, reduced NYPD with expansion of social programs and services, which currently the NYPD is actively a part in preventing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I was roughly thrown over barricade by cops, but I'll be back tomorrow, and the night after and after, because this is truly historical, and Brooklyn's moment. The youth today were brave, and many more shall be inspired to join up."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To show solidarity with those arrested, call 311 and demand that everyone arrested at the Kimani Gray vigil be released from the NYPD 71st + 69th precincts in Brooklyn. Or call the precinct directly: 71st precinct (718) 735-0511, 69th precinct (718) 257-6211&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 20:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/rage-brooklyn-arrests-third-day-demonstrations-tee/</guid></item><item><title>Walmart: Always Low Wages</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/walmart-always-low-wages/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, on Black Friday, &lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/blog/171430/historic-walmart-strikes-hit-100-cities-final-update-920-pm"&gt;Walmart workers bravely went out on strike.&lt;/a&gt; The workers and their supporters held protests at over 1,000 stores across the country, shortly following an &lt;a href="http://www.labornotes.org/2012/10/strike-supporters-shut-down-illinois-walmart-warehouse"&gt;initial set of strikes by workers in Walmart’s warehouses.&lt;/a&gt; The actions were broadly hailed as historic, given &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2005/09/14/business/14walmart.html?_r=0"&gt;Walmart’s long-time practice of crushing the rights of workers at home and across the globe.&lt;/a&gt;
Walmart, predictably, wasted no time denying the importance of the strikes and protests. On Black Friday, Walmart downplayed the strikes, falsely claiming that &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2012/11/23/walmart-strike-protests-black-friday/1722551/"&gt;“…fewer than five workers walked off the job”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/23/walmart-best-black-friday_n_2178541.html"&gt;"less than fifty," in other sources.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://imgur.com/JH9GSQD.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The massive Walmart PR team continued with the spin to hide the truth of unrest bubbling from our neighborhoods. Even though the strikers had never called for a boycott, &lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2012/11/23/walmart-strike-protests-black-friday/1722551/"&gt;Walmart immediately released sales numbers in a nervous attempt to demonstrate that the workers hadn’t impacted its bottom line.&lt;/a&gt; In fact, it further added that despite the strikes and protests, the company had its &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/23/walmart-best-black-friday_n_2178541.html"&gt;best Black Friday ever.&lt;/a&gt;
Interestingly, recently leaked emails from Walmart executives tell another story about Walmart’s holiday season and sales following Black Friday. &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-02-15/wal-mart-executives-sweat-slow-february-start-in-e-mails.html"&gt;In the leaked emails&lt;/a&gt;, one executive asks, “Where are all the customers?” A look at Walmart’s fourth quarter sales reveals &lt;a href="http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2013/02/22/wal-mart-profit-weaker-than-it-looks.aspx"&gt;“anemic growth”&lt;/a&gt; in the market of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As result of these sales numbers, Walmart’s tune suddenly changed. &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/22/business/wal-mart-profit-climbs-but-outlook-is-wary.html?_r=0"&gt;“We didn’t finish quite as strong as we would have liked, primarily due to a little slower holiday season than we would have planned,” Walmart’s CFO told the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt; Of course, Walmart was prepared to blame the downturn on payroll taxes, but its self-reported Black Friday numbers appear more dubious than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Friday Walmart strikes mattered a great deal, because Walmart is the corporate goliath in the room. Walmart represents everything about modern life that is sustainable only to the cause of siphoning resources out of our neighborhoods and into the pockets of the Directors of the company. These strikes are yet another sign that people have grown weary of the inequality that plagues us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the wealth of the Walton family were invested in the workers &lt;a href="http://www.wisegeek.com/what-is-the-redistribution-of-wealth.htm"&gt;(or nationalized)&lt;/a&gt;, every worker at Walmart could have a full health plan, education, sick days, and a living wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember WalMart during your MayDay planning, and remember Walmart when you need a glaring example of everything that is wrong with our modern economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://i.imgur.com/zKn0480.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 00:12:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/walmart-always-low-wages/</guid></item><item><title>Climate Change Is Real</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/climate-change-real/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.learnstuff.com/climate-change/"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.learnstuff.com/assets/climate-change.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 20:59:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/climate-change-real/</guid></item><item><title>David Graeber: Some Remarks on Consensus</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/david-graeber-some-remarks-consensus/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="the medium is the message" src="http://i.imgur.com/Hc5ee4y.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of our recent series on Occupy and consensus, we are posting this timely piece by David Graeber, originally published at &lt;a href="http://occupywallstreet.net/story/some-remarks-consensus"&gt;OccupyWallStreet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a flurry of discussion around process in OWS of late. This can only be a good thing. Atrophy and complacency are the death of movements. Any viable experiment in freedom is pretty much going to have to constantly re-examine itself, see what's working and what isn't—partly because situations keep changing, partly because we're trying to invent a culture of democracy in a society where almost no one really has any experience in democratic decision-making, and most have been told for most of their lives that it would be impossible, and partly just because it's all an experiment, and it's in the nature of experiments that sometimes they don't work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this debate has centered around the role of consensus. This is healthy too, because there seem to be a lot of misconceptions floating around about what consensus is and is supposed to be about. Some of these misconceptions are so basic, though, I must admit I find them a bit startling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just one telling example. Justine Tunney recently wrote a piece called &lt;a href="http://occupywallst.org/article/occupiers-stop-using-consensus/"&gt;"Occupiers: Stop Using Consensus!"&lt;/a&gt; that begins by describing it as "the idea that a group must strictly adhere to a protocol where all decisions are unanimous"—and then goes on to claim that OWS used such a process, with disastrous results. This is bizarre. OWS never used absolute consensus. On the very first meeting on August 2, 2011 we established we'd use a form of modified consensus with a fallback to a two-thirds vote. Anyway, the description is wrong even if we had been using absolute consensus (an approach nowadays rarely used in groups of over 20 or 30 people), since consensus is not a system of unanimous voting, it's a system where any participant has the right to veto a proposal which they consider either to violate some fundamental principle, or which they object to so fundamentally that proceeding would cause them to quit the group. If we can have people who have been involved with OWS from the very beginning who still don't know that much, but think consensus is some kind of "strict" unanimous voting system, we've got a major problem. How could anyone have worked with OWS that long and still remained apparently completely unaware of the basic principles under which we were supposed to be operating?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, this seems to be an extreme case. But it reflects a more general confusion. And it exists on both sides of the argument: both some of the consensus' greatest supporters, and its greatest detractors, seem to think "consensus" is a formal set of rules, analogous to Roberts' Rules of Order, which must be strictly observed, or thrown away. This certainly was not what people who first developed formal process thought that they were doing! They saw consensus as a set of principles, a commitment to making decisions in a spirit of problem-solving, mutual respect, and above all, a refusal of coercion. It was an attempt to create processes that could work in a truly free society. None of them, even the most legalistic, were so presumptuous to claim those were the only procedures that could ever work in a free society. That would have been ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me return to this point in a moment. First,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1) CONSENSUS IS "A WHITE THING" (OR A MIDDLE CLASS WHITE THING, OR AN ELITIST FORM OF OPPRESSION, ETC)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to be said about this statement is that this idea is a very American thing. Anyone I mention it to who is not from the United States tends to react to the statement with complete confusion. Even in the US, it is a relatively recent idea, and the product of a very particular set of historical circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The confusion overseas is due to the fact that almost everywhere except the US, the exact opposite is true. In the Americas, Africa, Asia, Oceania, one finds longstanding traditions of making decisions by consensus, and then, histories of white colonialists coming and imposing Roberts Rules of Order, majority voting, elected representatives, and the whole associated package—by force. South Asian panchayat councils did not operate by majority voting and still don't unless there has been a direct colonial influence, or by political parties that learned their idea of democracy in colonial schools and government bodies the colonialists set up. The same is true of communal assemblies in Africa. (In China, village assemblies also operated by consensus until the '50s when the Communist Party imposed majority voting, since Mao felt voting was more "Western" and therefore "modern.") Almost everywhere in the Americas, indigenous communities use consensus and the white or mestizo descendants of colonialists use majority voting (insofar as they made decisions on an equal basis at all, which mostly they didn't), and when you find an indigenous community using majority voting, it is again under the explicit influence of European ideas—almost always, along with elected officials, and formal rules of procedure obviously learned in colonial schools or borrowed from colonial regimes. Insofar as anyone is teaching anyone else to use consensus, it's the other way around: as in the case of the Maya-speaking Zapatista communities who insisted the EZLN adopt consensus over the strong initial objections of Spanish-speaking mestizos like Marcos, or for that matter the white Australian activists I know who told me that student groups in the '80s and '90s had to turn to veterans of the Maoist New People's Army to train them in consensus process—not because Maoists were supposed to believe in consensus, since Mao himself didn't like the idea, but because NPA guerillas were mostly from rural communities in the Philippines that had always used consensus to make decisions and therefore guerilla units had adopted the same techniques spontaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does the idea that consensus is a "white thing" actually come from? Indigenous communities in America all used consensus decision-making instead of voting. Africans brought to the Americas had been kidnapped from communities where consensus was the normal mode of making collective decisions, and violently thrust into a society where "democracy" meant voting (even though they themselves were not allowed to vote.) Meanwhile, the only significant group of white settlers who employed consensus were the Quakers—and even they had developed much of their process under the influence of Native Americans like the Haudenosaunee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can make out the ideas comes out of political arguments that surrounded the rise of Black Nationalism in the 1960s. The very first mass movement in the United States that operated by consensus was the SNCC, or Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, a primarily African-American group created in 1960 as a horizontal alternative to Martin Luther King's (very vertical) SCLC. SNCC operated in a decentralized fashion and used consensus decision-making. It was SNCC for instance that organized the famous "freedom rides" and most of the direct action campaigns of the early '60s. By 1964, an emerging Black Power faction was looking for an issue with which to isolate and ultimately expel the white members of the group. They seized on consensus as a kind of wedge issue—this made sense, politically, because many of those white allies were Quakers, and it was advantageous, at first, to frame the argument as one of efficiency, rather than being about more fundamental moral and political issues like non-violence. It's important to emphasize though that the objections to consensus as inefficient and culturally alien that were put forward at the time were not put forward in the name of moving to some other form of direct democracy (i.e., majority voting), but ultimately, part of a rejection of the whole package of horizontality, consensus, and non-violence with the ultimate aim of creating top-down organizational structures that could support much greater militancy. It also corresponded to an overt attack on the place of women in the organization—an organization that had in fact been founded by the famous African-American activist Ella Baker on the principle "strong people don't need strong leaders." Stokely Carmichael, the most famous early Black Power advocate in SNCC, notoriously responded to a paper circulated by feminists noting that women seemed to be systematically excluded from positions in the emerging leadership structure by saying as far as he was concerned, "the only position for women in SNCC is prone."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a few years SNCC began to splinter; white allies were expelled in 1965; after a brief merger with the Panthers it split again, and dissolved in the '70s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tensions—challenges to horizontalism and consensus, macho leadership styles, the marginalization of women—were by no means peculiar to SNCC. Similar battles were going on in predominantly white groups: notably SDS, which ultimately ditched consensus too, and ended up splitting between Maoists and Weathermen. This is one reason the feminist movement of the early '70s, which within the New Left began partly as a reaction to just this kind of macho posturing, embraced consensus as an antidote. (Anarchists only later adopted it from them.) But one point bears emphasizing. It's important. None of those who challenged consensus did so in the name of a different form of direct democracy. In fact, I'm not aware of any example of an activist group that abandoned consensus and then went on to settle on some different, but equally horizontal approach to decision-making. The end result is invariably abandoning direct democracy entirely Sometimes that's because, as here, that is explicitly what those challenging consensus want. But even when it's not, the same thing happens, because moving from consensus sets off a dynamic that inevitably leads in a vertical direction. When consensus is abandoned, some are likely to quit in protest. These are likely to be the most dedicated to horizontal principles. Factions form. Minority factions that consistently lose key votes, and don't have their concerns incorporated in resulting proposals, will often split off. Since they too are likely to consist of more horizontally oriented participants, the group becomes ever more vertical. Before long, those who never liked direct democracy to begin with start saying it's what's really to blame for all these problems, it's inefficient, things would run far more smoothly with clearly defined leadership roles—and it only takes a vote of 51% of the remaining, much more vertical group, to ditch direct democracy entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the widespread perception of consensus process as white isn't just be a hold-over from events that took place forty years ago. A lot of the problem is that, since the '70s, consensus process has largely been developed among direct-action oriented groups, and, while there are certainly African-American-based groups operating in what might be called the Ella Baker tradition, most of those groups have been largely white. The reasons are pretty obvious. Those lacking white privilege face much higher levels of state repression, and (unlike, in say, Mexico, or India, where those who face the most repression are generally speaking already organized in semi-autonomous communities that operate at least partly by consensus), in the US, this limits the degree to which it's possible to engage in creating experimental spaces outside the system. Communities face immediate such practical concerns so pressing many feel working outside the system would be irresponsible. Those who don't often feel they have no choice but to adopt either strict, rigorous, MLK-style non-violence, or adopt revolutionary militarism like the panthers—both of which tend to lead to top down forms of organization. As a result, the culture of consensus, the style in which it's conducted, the sensibilities surrounding it, inevitably comes to reflect the white middle-class background of so many of those who have created and shaped it, and the result is that those who do not share these sensibilities feel alienated and excluded. Obviously this is something that urgently needs to be addressed. But the problem here is not with the principles underlying consensus (that all voices have equal weight, that no one be compelled to act against their will), but with the way it's being done—and the fact that the way it's being done have the effect of undermining those very principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2) RULES VERSUS PRINCIPLES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem here is a misunderstanding about what we're basically arguing about. A lot of people on both sides of the debate seem to think "consensus" is a set of rules. If you follow the rules, you're doing consensus. If you break the rules, or even do them in the wrong order it's somehow not. I've seen people show up to meetings armed with elaborate diagrams or flow-charts for some kind of formal process downloaded from some web page and insist that only this is the really real thing. So it's hardly surprising that other people put off by all this, or who see that particular form of process hit some kind of loggerhead, say "well consensus doesn't work. Let's try something else."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I'm concerned both sides completely miss the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll say it again. Consensus is not a set of rules. It's a set of principles. Actually I'd even go so far to say that if you really boil it down, it ultimately comes down to just two principles: everyone should have equal say (call this "equality"), and nobody should be compelled to do anything they really don't want to do (call this, "freedom.")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, that's it. The rules are just a way to try to come to decisions in the spirit of those principles. "Formal consensus process," in is various manifestations, is just one technique people have made up, over the years, to try to come to group decisions that solve practical problems in a way that ensures no one's perspective is ignored, and no one is forced to do anything or comply with rules they find truly obnoxious. That's it. It's a way to find consensus. It's not itself "consensus." Formal process as it exists today has been proved to work pretty well for some kinds of people, under some circumstances. It is obviously completely inappropriate in others. To take an obvious example: most small groups of friends don't need formal process at all. Other groups might, over time, develop a completely different approach that suits their own dynamics, relations, situation, culture, sensibilities. And there's absolutely no reason any group can't improvise an entirely new one if that's what they want to do. As long as they are trying to create a process that embodies those basic principles, one that gives everyone equal say and doesn't force anyone to go along with a decision they find fundamentally objectionable, then what they come up with is a form of consensus process—no matter how it operates. After all, it a group of people all decide they want to be bound by a majority decision, well, who exactly is going to stop them? But if they all decide to be bound by a majority decision, then they have reached a consensus (in fact, an absolute consensus) that they want to operate that way. The same would be true if they all decided they wanted to be bound by the decisions of a Ouija Board, or appointed one member of the group Il Duce. Who's going to stop them? However, for the exact same reason, the moment the majority (or Ouija board, or Il Duce) comes up with a decision to do something that some people think is absolutely outrageous and refuse to do, how exactly is anyone going to force them to go along? Threaten to shoot them? Basically, it could only happen if the majority is somehow in control of some key resource—money, space, connections, a name—and others aren't. That is, if there is some means of coercion, subtle or otherwise. In the absence of a way to compel people to do things they do not wish to do, you're ultimately stuck with some kind of consensus whether you like it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question then is what kind of decision making process is most likely to lead to decisions that no one will object to so fundamentally that they will march off in frustration or simply refuse to cooperate? Sometimes that will be some sort of formal consensus process. In other circumstances that's the last thing one should try. Still, there's a reason that 51/49% majority voting is so rarely employed in such circumstances: usually, it is the method least likely to come up with such decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine the city is about to destroy some cherished landmark and someone puts up posters calling for people to meet in a nearby square to organize against it. Fifty people show up. Someone says, okay, "I propose we all lay down in front of the bulldozers. Let's hold a vote." So 30 people raised their hands yes, and 20 people raise their hands no. Well, what possible reason is there that the 20 people who said no would somehow feel obliged to now go and lay in front of the bulldozers? These were just 50 strangers gathered in a square. Why should the opinions of a majority of a group of strangers oblige the minority to do anything—let alone something which will expose them to personal danger?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example might seem absurd—who would hold such a vote?—but I experienced something almost exactly like it a few years ago, at an "all-anarchist" meeting called in London before a mass mobilization against the G8. About 200 people showed up at the RampArts Social Center. The facilitator, a syndicalist who disliked consensus, explained that another group had proposed a march, followed by some kind of direct action, and immediately proceeded to hold a vote on whether we, as a group, wanted to join as. Oddly, it did not seem to occur to him that, since we were not in fact a group, but just a bunch of people who had showed up at a meeting, there was no reason to think that those who did not want to join such an action would be swayed by the result. In fact he wasn't taking a vote at all. He was taking a poll: "how many people are thinking of joining the march?" Now, there's nothing wrong with polls; arguably, the most helpful thing he could have done under the circumstance was to ask for a show of hands so everyone could see what other people were thinking. The results might even have changed some people's minds—"well, it looks like a lot of people are going to that march, maybe I will too" (though in this case, in fact, it didn't.) But the facilitator thought he was actually conducting a vote on what to do, as if they were somehow bound by the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could he have been so oblivious? Well, he was a syndicalist; unions use majority vote; that's why he preferred it. But of course, unions are membership-based groups. If you join a union, you are, by the very act of doing so, agreeing to abide by its rules, which includes, accepting majority vote decisions. Those who do not follow the group's rules can be sanctioned, or even expelled. It simply didn't occur to him that most unions' voting system depended on the prior existence of membership rolls, dues, charters, and usually, legal standing—which in effect meant that either everyone who had voluntarily joined the unions was in effect consenting to the rules, or else, if membership was obligatory in a certain shop or industry owing to some prior government-enforced agreement, was ultimately enforced by the power of the state. To act the same way when people had not consented to be bound by such a decision, and then expect them to follow the dictates of the majority anyway, is just going to annoy people and make them less, not more, likely to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's go back to Justine's first example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the first time I saw a block used at Occupy was at one of the first general assemblies in August 2011. There were about a hundred people that day and in the middle of the meeting a proposal was made to join Verizon workers on the picket line as a gesture of solidarity in the hope that they might also support us in return. People loved the idea and there was quite a bit of positive energy until one woman in the crowd, busy tweeting on her phone, casually raised her hand and said, "I block that". The moderator, quite flabbergasted asked why she blocked and she explained that showing solidarity with workers would alienate the phantasm of our right-wing supporters. Discussion then abruptly ended and the meeting went on. The truth was irrelevant, popular opinion didn't matter, and solidarity—the most important of all leftist values—was thrown to the wind based on the whims of just one individual. Occupy had to find a new way to do outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I was at this meeting, and I remember the event quite vividly because at the time I was one of the participants who was more than a little bit annoyed by the block. But I also know that this is simply not what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, as I remarked, OWS from the beginning did not have a system where just one person could block a proposal; in the event of a block, we had the option to fall back on a 2/3 majority vote. So if everyone had really loved the proposal, the block could have been simply brushed aside. While many felt the woman in question was being ridiculous (most of us suspected the "national movement" she claimed to represent didn't really exist), the facilitator, when she asked if anyone felt the same way, was surprised to discover a significant contingent–some, but not all, insurrectionist anarchists–did in fact object to holding the next meeting at a picket line, since they didn't want to immediately identify the movement with the institutional left. Once it became clear it was not just one crazy person, but a significant chunk of the meeting—probably not quite a third, but close (there weren't really a hundred people there, incidentally; more like sixty)—she asked if anyone felt strongly that we should move to a vote, and no one insisted. Was this a terrible failure of process? I must admit at the time I found it exasperating. But in retrospect I realize that had we forced a vote, the results might well have been catastrophic. Because at that point we, too were just a bunch of people who'd all showed up in a park. We weren't a "group" at all. Nobody had committed to anything; certainly, no one had committed to going along with a majority decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A block is not a "no" vote. It's a veto. Or maybe a better way to put it is that giving everyone the power to block is like giving the power to take on the role of the Supreme Court, and stop a piece of legislation that they feel to be unconstitutional, to anyone who has the courage to stand up in front of the entire group and use it. When you block you are saying a proposal violates one of the group's agreed-on common principles. Of course, in this case we didn't have any agreed-on common principles. In cases like that, the usual rule of thumb is that you should only block if you feel so strongly about an issue that you'd actually leave the group. In this sense I suspect the initial blocker was indeed being irresponsible (she wouldn't have really left; and many wouldn't have mourned her if she had.) However, others felt strongly. Had we held a vote and decided to hold our next meeting at a picket line over their objections, many of them would likely not have shown up. The anti-authoritarian contingent would have been weakened. Had that happened, there was a real chance later decisions, much more important ones, might have gone the other way. I am thinking here in particular of the crucial decision, made some weeks later, not to appoint official marshals and police liaisons for September 17. Judging by the experience of other camps, had that happened, everything might have gone differently and the entire occupation failed. In retrospect, the loss of one early opportunity to create ties with striking unionists now seems a small price to pay for heading off on a road that might have led to that. Especially since we had no trouble establishing strong ties with unions later—precisely because we had succeeded in creating a real occupation in the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of other issues that one could discuss. Above all, we desperately need to have a conversation about decentralization. Another point of confusion about consensus is the idea that it's crucial to get approval from everyone about everything, which is again stifling and absurd. Consensus only works if working groups or collectives don't feel they need to seek constant approval from the larger group, if initiative arises from below, and people only check upwards if there's a genuinely compelling reason not to go ahead with some initiative without clearing it with everyone else. In a weird way, the very unwieldiness of consensus meetings is helpful here, since it can discourage people from taking trivial issues to a larger group, and thus potentially waste hours of everyone's time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all this will no doubt will be hashed out in the discussions that are going on (another good rule of thumb for consensus meetings: you don't need to say everything you can think to say if you're pretty sure someone else will make a lot of the same points anyway). Mainly what I want to say is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our power is in our principles. The power of Occupy has always been that it is an experiment in human freedom. That's what inspired so many to join us. That's what terrified the banks and politicians, who scrambled to do everything in their power—infiltration, disruption, propaganda, terror, violence—to be able to tell the word we'd failed, that they had proved a genuinely free society is impossible, that it would necessarily collapse into chaos, squalor, antagonism, violence, and dysfunction. We cannot allow them such a victory. The only way to fight back is to renew our absolute commitment to those principles. We will never compromise on equality and freedom. We will always base our relations to each other on those principles. We will not fall back on top-down structures and forms of decision making premised on the power of coercion. But as long as we do that, and if we really believe in those principles, that necessarily means being as open and flexible as we can about pretty much everything else. &lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 20:37:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/david-graeber-some-remarks-consensus/</guid></item><item><title>Thursday: DC March To Protect Native Women&amp;#39;s Rights</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/thursday-dc-march-protect-native-womens-rights/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Representative Eric Cantor: Native Women Await Your Statement. #VAWA" src="http://i.imgur.com/6EwMk0A.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/Save.Wiyabi.Project"&gt;Save Wįyąbi Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday, February 28, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10:00am EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday, the House of Representatives will vote on their version of the Violence Against Women Act, which excludes protections for Native American women. Native women are more likely to be victims of violence than any other ethnic group in the United States. This is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be marching and round dancing in front of the House of Representatives to demand justice and safety for our sisters. 10AM on Thursday February 28, 2013, starting at the Capitol South metro station. Please join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please use #VAWA  #1BillionRising #SaveWiyabiProject for twitter hashtag support and spread the word! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 19:10:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/thursday-dc-march-protect-native-womens-rights/</guid></item><item><title>OWS Updates for the Week of February 20</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-february-20/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;Since their first issue in December 2011, Tidal has made it their practice to give name to our struggle, wrestling with the big ideas that propel us into the streets, with what we should do when we get there, and with where there in fact is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Friday, the folks at &lt;a href="http://occupytheory.org/"&gt;Occupy Theory&lt;/a&gt; will release their fourth issue of the magazine, featuring original pieces by organizers of Occupy Wall Street, Occupy Sandy, Strike Debt and Free University. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/414858031925416/"&gt;Join them that night&lt;/a&gt; for conversation as we move together towards the empowerment that greater clarity and the free exchange of ideas can bring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- from the ‘Your Inbox: Occupied’ team  (&lt;a href="http://salsa3.salsalabs.com/o/50112/p/salsa/web/common/public/signup?signup_page_KEY=7238"&gt;Sign up to get these updates straight to your email!&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Occupy in the News&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jennapope.com/2013/02/18/forward-on-climate-rally/"&gt;Jenna Pope&lt;/a&gt; documented last Sunday’s Forward on Climate Rally. Beautiful sights--the vistas of activists in D.C. to make their voices heard about climate change--beautifully captured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Gosztola writes at FireDogLake’s &lt;a href="http://dissenter.firedoglake.com/2013/02/18/obamas-choice-to-alienate-environmental-activists-and-approve-the-keystone-xl-pipeline/"&gt;The Dissenter&lt;/a&gt; blog about the recent history of climate change actions and points out just how high the stakes are. Our only hope to defeat the monstrosity of the Keystone XL Pipeline is continued, passionate action, that is to say, “...if everyone demonstrating channeled the spirit of the Occupy movement...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/les-leopold/wall-street-business-model_b_2665597.html"&gt;Les Leopold of the Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt; explains why “the raison d’etre for Occupy Wall Street is proving correct. Much of high finance is based on a ‘corrupt business plan.’” Proof of Wall Street’s corruption continues to mount, with ratings agencies on the take, money laundered for drug cartels, and rampant insider trading, among many other ethical and moral malignancies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href="http://www.occupywallstreet.net/story/world-without-financial-system"&gt;occupywallstreet.net&lt;/a&gt; Heather Marsh argues for a society with no financial system at all, a currency-free system in which the endless cycle of excessive consumption and meaningless busywork is ended. The proof that this could work already exists. “With no financial incentives,” Marsh says, “the internet has managed to create collaborative efforts which have pushed the potential of society far beyond what could have been possible before the internet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href="http://da.nycga.net/2013/02/18/spring-is-in-the-air/"&gt;OWS Direct Action Blog&lt;/a&gt;, Mark Adams gives us the push we need to meet, to talk, to plan for spring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Featured Occu-Project&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revisit Liberty Plaza in full swing in &lt;a href="http://www.matchlock.com/wwo/"&gt;Why We Occupy&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source book of interviews gathered in the park in 2011. See the park grow and change in real-time through the heartfelt words of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Occupy these Actions &amp;amp; Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, February 20th, 6:00-8:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/454247084648415/"&gt;Doc &amp;amp; Discourse Series Launch: The Square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Culture Project, 45 Bleecker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A panel discussion focusing on the inter-connectivity of global protest movements from Cairo to New York featuring acclaimed Director Jehane Noujaim (Control Room; Rafea; Solar Mama) and award-winning Producer Karim Amer. Join New York Civil Liberties Union Occupy Wall Street (OWS) Coordinator Katherine Bromberg. Extended clips from the 2013 Sundance Award-winning film, THE SQUARE, will be shown throughout the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday February 20th, 10:00p.m.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/374160599358187/"&gt;Occupy the Pipeline Cabaret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Living Theater, 21 Clinton Street, NY, NY&lt;/strong&gt; 
This is a special Occupy the Pipeline Benefit Cabaret featuring: magicians, performance artists, belly dancers, burlesque, two bands and the cheapest bar in downtown Manhattan. This evening of entertainment will benefit the activist/performers and sustain upcoming Occupy the Pipeline actions as we continue our fight against fracking in our beloved city and state!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday February 22nd, 5:30-9:00&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/414858031925416/"&gt;Tidal 4 Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
20 Cooper Square&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tidal 4 is being released this Friday evening. Come and pick up your own free copy! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 23rd, 4:00-6:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/412110012199815/"&gt;Discussion: "The 15M Movement"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bluestockings Bookstore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The assembly of the 15M Archive and friends in Madrid will be joining us at Bluestockings via Skype, moderated in New York by 15M and OWS activist Juan Escourido. We’ll talk about the history of the 15M Movement, the organization of its archive, and the politics shared by 15M and other social movements, including OWS. In Madrid, participants will gather at the occupied social center Patio Maravillas, coordinated by Vlad Teichberg and Nikky Schiller, communications activists for both the OWS and 29S movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, February 22, 6:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.nycga.net/events/malcolm-x-community-and-movement-coordination-assembly/"&gt;Malcolm X Community and Movement Coordination Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
60 Wall Street, the Atrium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join Occu-Evolve’s latest assembly commemorating Black History Month, discussing the significance and insight of Malcolm X to our struggles around a variety of issues that People of Color, Women, the Working Class, Poor People and all of the 99% face today. This event will be followed up on Sunday, February 24th, 4:00pm with an &lt;a href="https://www.nycga.net/events/occupy-gratitude-a-day-of-thanks-to-the-supporters-of-the-occupy-movement-occu-evolve-one-year-later/"&gt;Occupy-Evolve Day of Gratitude for its One Year Anniversary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, February 26th, 6:00-8:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.nycga.net/events/financial-firms-economic-crisis-discussion-with-former-goldman-sachs-vp/"&gt;Financial Firms and Economic Crisis: Discussion with Former Goldman Sachs VP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Greg Smith, former Vice President at Goldman Sachs and author of “Why I Left Goldman Sachs”, will discuss how banks behave behind the scenes and how those practices differ from the perception they convey to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, February 28th, 6:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/425191017568481"&gt;People’s Planning Meeting for May Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
310 W. 43rd St.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To build on last year’s powerful solidarity, 99 Pickets and Immigrant Worker Justice are calling a community-wide May Day planning meeting on Feb. 28. Let's create an open and inclusive space where we can coordinate planning and build momentum for an incredible May 1, 2013. &lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/peoples-planning-meeting-for-may-day-reunion-comunitaria-para-planear-el-1-de-mayo/"&gt;NYCGA.net event page is here.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, March 1st and Sunday March 2nd, 12-6pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/occupydata-hackathon/"&gt;Occupy Data Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Cuny Graduate Center, 365 5th Avenue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Data mining and visualization for the 99%. At the event, we’d like to focus on a few new data sets/projects. Occupy Sandy and Aaron Swartz’s work has come up, and generated a lot of interest. Any ideas, data resources you may know of or questions, please let us know: Occupy Data listserve or info@occupydata.nyc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, March 10th, 2pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/unorganized-workers-assembly/"&gt;Unorganized Workers Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Judson Memorial Church, 55 Washington Square South&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join the Occupy Your Workplace group for a discussion of strategy and tactics of workplace organizing. We'll have several folks present who have experience as workplace "salts" - workers who get jobs with the aim of organizing. Workers who are curious about organizing, experienced organizers and activists, union members, and all other workers and non workers welcome. RSVP for the event on Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, March 14, 2013&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/117461861757073/"&gt;Defend Education Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Campus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SDS/Occupy Colleges is hosting a National Day of Action against Tuition and Fee Hikes. Join to get updates on flyers, coordination calls and other distribution materials. Message Occupy Colleges and we will help promote your campus/ organizations demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save the Date: March 22nd - March 24th&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/342145305899991/"&gt;Organizing New York March 22-24&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
United Federation of Teachers, 52 Broadway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join hundreds of leaders, organizers, techies and activists to share our wisdom, skills, and talents. We will have workshops, discussions, consulting and networking opportunities, visionary speakers and a provocative debate around strategy and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.organizing20.org/organizingnewyork/"&gt;Over three days&lt;/a&gt; right by Wall Street, we will bring together a thousand people to learn from each other, share stories and strategies and build our skills, organizations and movements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an event that occupy organizers will be participating in to build and share their skills. It will assuredly build upon the success of last year’s OWS unconference that was held in collaboration with Organizing 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 20:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-february-20/</guid></item><item><title>On Consensus</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/on-consensus/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Consensus" src="http://i.imgur.com/wjopqqr.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor's note: This article was submitted to us in response to &lt;a href="/article/occupiers-stop-using-consensus/"&gt;Occupiers! Stop Using Consensus!&lt;/a&gt; and is part of the series &lt;a href="/article/consense-or-not-consense/"&gt;To Consense or Not To Consense?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Consensus_decision-making"&gt;Consensus&lt;/a&gt; is a group process by which people determine their own ideas and actions. &lt;strong&gt;It is the most democratic of all forms of decision-making for it negotiates conflict without the use of force.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as there have been people talking to one another there has been consensus. In what is now known as the United States, the earliest documented consensus process was by the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iroquois"&gt;Haudenosaunee&lt;/a&gt; in the 12th century. By the 16th century a league formed of the Mohawk, Oneida, Onondaga, Cayuga, and Seneca nations. This is often cited as the Iroquois League or Confederacy.  &lt;a href=""&gt;They used a council system with elders, who acted as delegates or “spokes” of the different nations and came to consensus on matters concerning the Great Lakes region. In times of war elder women had the ability to veto over the other elders.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in Europe, the Anabaptists were mounting opposition to the hierarchy of the Roman Catholic Church. By the 16th century there were many heretical sects the most prominent of which were the Quakers, who became known for their “rule of sitting down.” Rather than rely on priests or ministers they would sit in circles and listen to one another. It was thru this practice that they achieved divine revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern American Quakers claim to be inspired by both by the Iroquois and their own history of the Anabaptists. Throughout the 19th 20th century Quakers &lt;a href="http://www.philica.com/display_article.php?article_id=14"&gt;played an important role&lt;/a&gt; in U.S. social movements from abolition to women’s rights to every anti-war movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the early 1960s Quakers acted in solidarity with the civil rights movement and trained many of its early members in consensus including the founders of SNCC (Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee), which emerged out of the youth division of the NAACP.&lt;/strong&gt; SNCC went on and organized the freedom rides and lunch counter sit-ins using consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women’s liberation movement took inspiration from the Quakers in response to the top-down and patriarchal structures of the anti-war movement and adopted a consensus process. Consciousness-raising groups, modeled after the Quaker “listening” circles, were central to feminist practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time the Quaker Action Group gave birth to a national network called Movement for a New Society (MNS), which fostered both intentional communities and non-violent organizing campaigns. The group struggled to keep a balance in their work, and many became involved in the &lt;a href="http://abetterworldisprobable.wordpress.com/2011/07/08/a-living-revolution-andy-cornell-speaks-on-his-new-book-oppose-and-propose-lessons-from-the-movement-for-a-new-society-in-detroit/"&gt;anti-nuclear movement.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clamshell Alliance was the largest group of the anti-nuke network and coordinated decentralized shutdowns of various nuclear power plants throughout the 70s and 80s. The most infamous was the Seabrook Nuclear Power Plant shutdown of 1977 in which 2,000 people organized in affinity groups and blockaded the construction site. The network used a formal consensus process and affinity group spokes councils to plan their actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 80s and into the 90s an offshoot of the Clamshell Alliance formed &lt;a href="http://www.foodnotbombs.net/"&gt;Food Not Bombs&lt;/a&gt;, a viral network of cooking collectives, which also operated by consensus. &lt;strong&gt;The aim was to live off the waste of the capitalist system and enable people to feed themselves.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.foodnotbombs.net/"&gt;This became a staple of anarchist communities throughout the U.S.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 1999 the alter-globalization movement was beginning to take shape. In the U.S. a network of mostly young anarchists created the Direct Action Network (DAN) to shutdown the World Trade Organization (WTO) in Seattle. &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books/about/Direct_Action.html?id=PnTDEQkCoc4C"&gt;During the months leading up to the convergence activists were trained in consensus and formed affinity groups, which then descended on Seattle in a pie-like formation blocking access to the convention sites.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They successfully shut it down, which sparked a wave of similar actions under the banner of the Continental Direct Action Network (CDAN). These were all coordinated via affinity group spokes councils in the style of the anti-nuke movement. Unfortunately, internal divisions in CDAN, 9/11, and the following anti-war movement tore the network apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this collapse many vestiges have remained including an archipelago of bookstores, Info shops, Independent Media Centers, Food not Bombs chapters, and housing collectives. These institutions carried the culture of consensus and served the basis for the anti-authoritarian movement before Occupy Wall Street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 2nd, 2011 &lt;a href="http://nocutsny.wordpress.com/"&gt;New Yorkers Against Budget Cuts &lt;/a&gt;(NYABC), the group that had organized &lt;a href="http://bloombergvillenow.org/"&gt;Bloombergville&lt;/a&gt;, called a People’s General Assembly at the bull to coincide with the debt ceiling debate and organize around the &lt;a href="http://www.adbusters.org/campaigns/occupywallstreet"&gt;Adbusters call to “Occupy Wall Street.&lt;/a&gt;” At this convergence, NYABC, which was comprised of the authoritarian left including groups such as the ISO (&lt;a href="http://www.internationalsocialist.org/"&gt;International Socialist Organization&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://www.workers.org/"&gt;Workers World&lt;/a&gt;, held a rally with speakers, so a group of anarchists and other anti-authoritarians broke off and formed an assembly. It became known as the &lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/"&gt;New York City General Assembly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For weeks people met in &lt;a href="http://www.nycgovparks.org/parks/tompkinssquarepark"&gt;Tompkins Square Park&lt;/a&gt; and planned to “Occupy Wall Street” on September 17th. These meetings used a modified consensus process. We reached consensus on many points including a tactical plan for the day of action. After many weeks we grew to know one another thru face-face communication. We established a common set of principles including horizontality, participation, and autonomy. The intention was clear and the group was small enough that we were able to communicate effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 17th the action was the process. Upon arriving at the park we had hundreds of people in small groups talking with one another about the economic crisis. As the night went on the small groups formed one massive assembly of hundreds upon hundreds of people that consented to occupy. Thus began the occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, not everyone in the assembly actually occupied. There were roughly 50-100 people that stayed and held down the park in the first few weeks. We used consensus, because we had used it in the planning process, but it was also re-affirmed by additional people staying in the park. We drafted the Principles of Solidarity and the Declaration using consensus and set off a wave of other occupations that also used the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eventually, though, there were many challenges with using a consensus. Large groups are a logistical nightmare for consensus.&lt;/strong&gt; There is the underlying assumption that everyone will be able to speak but the reality that not everyone will be heard- at least not by the entirety of the group. &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books/about/The_Empowerment_Manual.html?id=lhHNo-Wm7RQC"&gt;Starhawk, the anarchist and feminist writes, “Consensus works best in smaller groups, where everyone has a chance to be part of discussions. In a large group, there simply isn’t enough time to let everyone speak.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As the weeks went on the original members did not find the assembly useful anymore. It was overrun by opportunists and tourists, who did not understand the meaning or context of the process. They modeled the hand signals, but reduced the assembly to a set of procedures. In a body of strangers there was no respect for one another.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starhawk &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B_QxiMmOEfwNeVp1U1VTVlFGd2M/edit"&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;, “Consensus works best in a group that cultivates respect, where people care not only what gets done but how we treat one another in the process. Consensus asks us to put aside our egos, our need to win and to be right and open our ears to listen, to appreciate the contributions of others and to co-create solutions to our problems.”This was sorely lacking in the assembly and later on in the OWS Operations Spokes Council. We fought over proposals, ¾ of which were about money. It became a competition rather than a collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Graeber and Andrej Grubacic &lt;a href="http://www.zcommunications.org/anarchism-or-the-revolutionary-movement-of-the-twenty-first-century-by-david-graeber"&gt;write&lt;/a&gt;, “Consensus is often misunderstood. In fact, the operating assumption is that no one could really convert another completely to their point of view, or probably should. Instead, the point of consensus process is to allow a group to decide on a common course of action.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In researching for this article I decided to focus on the American context, but I also found that in nearly every instance of consensus, regardless of cultural context, and over the course of a thousand years, there are two main problems: size and membership. Whether a Chinese village, Mayan jungle, or the streets of New York City these seem to be common threads, and they are always addressed by some sort of confederation or federation of small groups. These may be assemblies, working groups, or affinity groups. The terms change but the form has been essentially the same throughout history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As consensus is a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Process_%28collective%29"&gt;collective process&lt;/a&gt; I reached out to fellow occupiers on the question. A movement historian and day one occupier wrote, “In terms of OWS I think the issue may have actually been less about how our decision-making procedures work and more about who the people were that were making them.” His main concern was the heterogeneous nature of OWS and lack of participation. A well-respected Zuccotti Park facilitator in OWS said, “People weren’t stakeholders, so they didn’t really have to hear one another. We relied too much on rules and not enough on building culture.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we build a culture of consensus in Occupy Wall Street? This is the question that we face now. I hope that we engage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related:
&lt;a href="http://www.occupywallst.org/article/consense-or-not-consense/"&gt;To Consense or Not-to-Consense&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://occupywallst.org/article/occupiers-stop-using-consensus/"&gt;Occupiers: Stop Using Consensus!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 20:02:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/on-consensus/</guid></item><item><title>Occupiers! Stop Using Consensus!</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/occupiers-stop-using-consensus/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://i.imgur.com/O43rtyDl.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Consensus_decision-making"&gt;Consensus process&lt;/a&gt; (the idea that a group must strictly adhere to a protocol where all decisions are unanimous) is the absolute worst idea that has ever been introduced to the activist community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consensus process is the &lt;a href="http://livinginphilistia.blogspot.com/2010/04/tyranny-of-individual.html"&gt;tyranny of the individual&lt;/a&gt;. It is the most anti-social of all processes because it allows any one person to assert irrational authority over an entire group of people and block any sort of decision making. It has nothing do with anarchism (even the &lt;a href="http://www.iww.org/"&gt;IWW&lt;/a&gt; doesn't use consensus!) because it was invented by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quakers"&gt;Quakers&lt;/a&gt; for religious reasons. It's stood in the way of progress, destroyed social movements, &lt;a href="http://www.peopleofcolororganize.com/activism/critique-consensus-decisionmaking-discontents/"&gt;destroyed groups&lt;/a&gt;, destroyed communities, and relegated radicals to the fringes of American politics since the 70's when it was first popularized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consensus process is in many ways an attempt to formalize the act of resistance, which I suspect is what makes it so popular in activist communities. Let's compare this to democracy, a system which was invented to formalize dissent. With democracy, you could fight and disagree without resorting to violence. Feathers could be ruffled, progress could be made, and life moved on according to plan. &lt;strong&gt;Resistance on the other hand is when you're so angry at something, that you're willing to go on a crusade and use all available means to stop that thing from happening&lt;/strong&gt; Resistance knows no rules. It is something that should never happen, yet is the responsibility of any socially conscious individual. It's a wild beast which cannot be tamed. Now ask yourself what happens when you get a bunch of people in one room, people whose nature inclines them towards resistance, and then give them the power to resist with a simple hand gesture and a requirement that all others be subservient to their demand. You do the math.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give an example, the first time I saw a block used at Occupy was at one of the first general assemblies in August 2011. There were about a hundred people that day and in the middle of the meeting a proposal was made to join Verizon workers on the picket line as a gesture of solidarity in the hope that they might also support us in return. People loved the idea and there was quite a bit of positive energy until one woman in the crowd, busy tweeting on her phone, casually raised her hand and said, "I block that". The moderator, quite flabbergasted asked why she blocked and she explained that showing solidarity with workers would alienate the phantasm of our right-wing supporters. Discussion then abruptly ended and the meeting went on. The truth was irrelevant, popular opinion didn't matter, and solidarity—the most important of all leftist values—was thrown to the wind based on the whims of just one individual. Occupy had to find a new way to do outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as bad as that sounded, it was actually one of the most graceful instances I've seen of a block being used. This is because the proposal was actually dropped as though it never happened. Things don't always go so smoothly. Blocks have a tendency to bring out the worst in people. The thing they don't tell you about consensus, is that it only works if you're willing to exclude others from it. When faced with a block, it's common for people to use psychological manipulation, threats, invent process to deny that person a vote, or even pressure them to leave the group entirely. Oftentimes when such people don't get their way, they'll leave the group themselves. Consensus invites the most awful type of conflict because there can be no agreeing to disagree. But at the same time consensus also quells the more constructive forms of dissent because most considerate and rational people aren't masochistic enough to welcome the hatred and backlash inherent in blocking a proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consensus process can also be hacked.&lt;/strong&gt; This is because it leaves too much to interpretation, doesn't actually specify procedure, and doesn't make sense! Take for instance kicking someone out of your group. Do you need consensus to kick them out? Or do you need consensus to keep them on board? Oftentimes such things aren't clear, so the system becomes ripe for manipulation and exploitation. If you ever want to be evil and push a proposal through a consensus body, just make a compelling argument that you need consensus to not pass your proposal (rather than the other way around). If that doesn't work, try writing your proposal with the opposite language and blocking it yourself. If people call you out on your shenanigans, just accuse them of being authoritarians who refuse to follow process and demand that they either step down or reach consensus on creating a rule to forbid what you’re doing. Then block that proposal too. If they tell you that you’re not allowed to block then you can always complain that true consensus cannot be reached until there’s a quorum of every single group member present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grassroots activist groups also follow the spirit of consensus regardless of what process they use. This is because participation in occupy assemblies, working groups, and affinity groups is entirely voluntary. Generally speaking, these groups do not control any land or resources upon which their members depend, therefore making it nearly impossible to practice any real coercion. When freedom of association exists in the truest sense of the words, the act of participation in and of itself can be considered itself a form of a consent, even if decision-making power rests in the hands of the majority or an individual leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consensus should be reserved to teams (small groups where people work well together and trust one another) as de facto rather than official process. Many of us operate by implicit consensus without even realizing it. &lt;strong&gt;It’s a natural human behavior to not want to piss off and ignore other members of your team.&lt;/strong&gt; But when the occasional irresolvable conflict arises, a majority vote isn’t the end of the world. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Majority_rule"&gt;It’s called democracy.&lt;/a&gt; If those conflicts happen too often, then perhaps it’s time to reconsider why you’re working with such people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to deliberative process for larger groups that can’t be considered teams, start off with what's been known to work and has stood the test of time, like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%27s_Rules_of_Order"&gt;Robert's Rules of Order.&lt;/a&gt; It’s not the ideal system to prevent all forms of hierarchy, but it’s at least been proven to work in organizing democratic assemblies that are capable of functioning. Why must we reinvent the wheel? The only clear explanation is that it’s fun to fetishize process rather than accomplishing work. There are actually people who've devoted much of their careers as activists to unnecessarily reinventing process, and for years they've been using entire activist communities as guinea pigs in their experiments. Why must we allow ourselves to be pawns in someone else's game? &lt;strong&gt;Our goal should be fighting power and injustice, and we should settle for no less than the best tools for the job.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we also shouldn't have to follow Robert's Rules by the book all the time. Oftentimes people will forgo formal process entirely until it's needed.  It's also perfectly reasonable to borrow good ideas from other processes. One such example is the "&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_stack"&gt;progressive stack&lt;/a&gt;" which Occupy has used from its very first general assembly meeting. This means when you have a meeting and ten people want to speak at once, one person will be assigned to "take stack" by writing down the names of whoever has their hand raised. The person taking stack will then prioritize speaking order in favor of people belonging to groups whose voices have traditionally been marginalized. Examples of such groups include women, people of color, and the lgbtq community. This is great news if you're a queer trans woman of color, but not such great news for straight white middle class &lt;a href="http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/cisgender"&gt;cis men&lt;/a&gt; whose voices have far too often dominated discussion. Another great tool for facilitating collective thought is the temperature check, where everyone in the room &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals"&gt;twinkles their fingers&lt;/a&gt;to express how favorably they feel about the topic of deliberation. But in reality, that’s just a more fabulous variation of Robert’s Rules where the chair will try to gauge support for a proposal during deliberation by asking everyone in the room to  say aye / nay or give a show of hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only significant experimentation we should be doing with process at this time is trying to find ways to use modern technology to make democracy more democratic.&lt;/strong&gt; For the first time in the history of civilization, we are able to scale up conversations to span the entire globe. A deliberative assembly no longer must be limited to the number of people capable of fitting in a single room. Why are we not taking advantage of this? Several attempts have been made to develop such systems, but most of the existing solutions are either shoddy, hard to use, or focus on anonymous voting rather than deliberation. These systems also do not make an effort to define the procedural conventions to govern the aspects of software use which cannot be digitized. Engineers, please start teaming up with process experts to accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the follies of consensus, read the essays &lt;a href="http://www.connexions.org/CxLibrary/CX6187.htm"&gt;"Blocking Progress" by Howard Ryan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.academia.edu/1110507/fetishizing_process"&gt;"Fetishizing Process" by Mark Lance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is part of the series
&lt;a href="http://www.occupywallst.org/article/consense-or-not-consense/"&gt;To Consense or Not-to-Consense&lt;/a&gt;. To read a response to this article, see &lt;a href="http://occupywallst.org/article/on-consensus/"&gt;On Consensus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 23:16:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/occupiers-stop-using-consensus/</guid></item><item><title>To Consense or Not To Consense?</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/consense-or-not-consense/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;Since the inception of Occupy Wall Street in 2011, most public assemblies and working or affinity group meetings have adopted a formal or modified consensus model for decision making. This &lt;a href="http://www.consensusdecisionmaking.org/index.html"&gt;consensus model&lt;/a&gt;, as many general assembly participants are by now familiar, required all decisions passed by a “&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Popular_assembly"&gt;General Assembly&lt;/a&gt;” to enjoy the unanimous (&lt;a href="http://www.ic.org/pnp/ocac/"&gt;formal consensus&lt;/a&gt;) or 9/10ths (&lt;a href="http://www.consensusdecisionmaking.org/Articles/Using%20Modified%20Consensus%20in%20OWS.html"&gt;modified consensus&lt;/a&gt;) support of its participants. The goal of this consensus model was that of allowing all concerns participants might have around any issue to be decided by the assembly. In this situation, it is possible for a very small percentage of the collective group to “block” or table any motion brought before the body. Instead of an up or down vote, rejected proposals would require being refined and reworked until all objections had been addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many have questioned the operating premises of this consensus building model citing the ease with which the process can be hijacked, diverted, or taken hostage by participants not operating in good faith or with hidden agendas. Critics blame consensus decision making for contributing to the unnecessarily grueling and drawn out nature of OWS meetings, and a serious impediment towards growing the movement beyond activist circles. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is with the intent of opening up the debate around one of the most contentious issues within organizing the Occupy Wall Street community, that we are publishing a serious of articles exploring points and counterpoints on the limits, perils, and need for consensus as a decision making philosophy within the future of OWS. Please share widely, please contribute, and above all, please keep organizing, in whichever model most appeals to your organizing group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have global unfettered capitalism to defeat, and that is going to be much harder to fight, if we are fighting over the model with which to organize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/qOP2V_np2c0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 19:43:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/consense-or-not-consense/</guid></item><item><title>Radical Resistance Tour Ep 06: Tucson, AZ</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/radical-resistance-tour-ep-06-tucson-az/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;h2&gt;Episode 06: Tucson, AZ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a closer look at localized resistance based around ethnic studies, badass kids, border deaths, racist laws &amp;amp; the &lt;a href="http://www.derechoshumanosaz.net/"&gt;Derechos Humanos coalition.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/59234802" width="400" height="300" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://radicalresistancetour.tumblr.com/"&gt;The Radical Resistance Tour&lt;/a&gt; is an autonomous project by a group of Occupy Wall Street organizers. We're touring the United States and interviewing activists, people participating in direct actions, and people working to create a dual power model. We want to show people who aren't on the ground how people are being directly affected by decisions being made by corporations and governments that put profits over people and the environment. We want to inspire more people to fight back by featuring people who are already fighting back, and hopefully gain some shared wisdom by listening to how others are resisting. &lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 19:14:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/radical-resistance-tour-ep-06-tucson-az/</guid></item><item><title>OWS Updates for the Week of February 6th</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-february-6th/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hey 1% Pay Your Damn Taxes!" src="http://i.imgur.com/TZ65vSN.jpg?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Occupy Wall Street movement may have faded from the headlines in the aftermath of the eviction of Zuccotti Park more than a year ago, but the issues that originally sparked it and the activism it inspired remain very much alive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the opening to a blog post called &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ruth-milkman/occupy-wall-street-study_b_2626035.html?utm_hp_ref=tw"&gt;Who Were the 99 Percent?&lt;/a&gt; from co-authors of the recent study &lt;em&gt;Changing The Subject: A Bottom-Up Account of Occupy Wall Street in New York City.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regrettably, as reported by &lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/blog/172531/co-author-new-occupy-study-media-misled-harping-household-salaries"&gt;Allison Kilkenny in the Nation&lt;/a&gt;, many in the media have twisted the study’s findings regarding the makeup of OWS by dismissing the movement in an entirely new and spurious way: “this was a damned if they do, damned if they don’t moment for Occupy--they’re either poor, dirty hippies or the sons and daughters of the wealthy elite, but never, ever Americans exercising their First Amendment rights”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we don’t need outside justification to know that ‘We Are the 99%’, and as the study depicts, nothing will extinguish the flame compelling us to speak out and inspiring us to act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- from the &lt;a href="http://salsa3.salsalabs.com/o/50112/p/salsa/web/common/public/signup?signup_page_KEY=7238"&gt;‘Your Inbox: Occupied’&lt;/a&gt; team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Occupy in the News&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, &lt;a href="http://thebrooklynink.com/2013/02/03/51190-grassroots-volunteers-hold-summit-to-further-sandy-relief-efforts/"&gt;Stacia Georgi at Brooklyn Ink&lt;/a&gt; wrote quite the positive story about the People’s Recovery Summit held this past weekend. Check out &lt;a href="http://jennapope.com/2013/02/04/the-peoples-recovery-summit/"&gt;occupier and photo-journalist Jenna Pope’s&lt;/a&gt; album of the summit for the play by play. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://stopmotionsolo.net/a-corporate-marriage-at-federal-hall/"&gt;Stopmotionsolo.tv&lt;/a&gt; provides comprehensive coverage of the recent Citizens United wedding, including a brief history of the ruling and a discussion of his concerns about pushing for a constitutional amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pmarcuse.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/blog-27-the-alternatives-for-sandy-bankers-socialism-the-private-market-equity/"&gt;Professor Marcuse&lt;/a&gt; discusses options in responding to disasters like Sandy, including the wryly titled “Banker’s Socialism”--the “deprivatization of disaster response”--the Private Market Approach and the Equity Approach, which is “using public assistance to ameliorate the damage caused by disaster.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Featured Occu-Project: Flip the Debt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out how &lt;a href="http://occupywallstreet.net/story/time-flip-debt-new-debt-clock-shows-how-much-1-owes-us"&gt;Occupy Unveils a New Debt Clock that Shows How Much the 1% Owe Us&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This campaign to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/FlipTheDebt"&gt;‘Flip the Debt’&lt;/a&gt; aims to "flip the debate" over the national debt by shifting the focus to the global corporations and super wealthy actually responsible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your blood will boil as you watch the numbers tick up on their ingenious online &lt;a href="http://www.flipthedebt.org/"&gt;'Debt Clock'&lt;/a&gt; calculating the amount of taxes dodged by corporations every second. Moreover, each tick is reminder to the 1% that “It's time that you paid your damn taxes!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Occupy These Actions &amp;amp; Events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 9th, 7-9pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/discussion-energy-extraction-and-the-keystone-xl-pipeline/"&gt;Discussion: Energy Extraction and the Keystone XL Pipeline&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://bluestockings.com/"&gt;Bluestockings Bookstore&lt;/a&gt;, 172 Allen Street&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Leading mainstream scientist James Hansen has said if the Keystone XL pipeline proceeds it is “essentially game over for the climate.” Join us for a &lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/530824026950837"&gt;panel discussion&lt;/a&gt; about the Keystone XL pipeline and related energy extraction issues. We will skype in with activists down in Texas and Oklahoma, talk to an organizer who has been working at the Canadian Tar Sands oil extraction sight and with NYC Spectra Pipeline organizers. All proceeds from the night will go directly to the campaign to stop the Keystone XL pipeline. With a continued fundraiser after-party in Brooklyn. Featuring Gay Panic and Glittered and Mauled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 9th, 4:30PM - 6:30PM&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/414500698629780/"&gt;Strategic research workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Organization of Staff Analysts, 220 East 23rd Street, Suite 707&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join members of  NYC Radical Reference for the second in a series of strategic research workshops sponsored by the OWS Labor Outreach Committee. The workshops are open to all. In this event, we will explore what’s behind the legislation and policies that affect our lives as workers, as activists, and as citizens. We will see how to get the goods on candidates, lobbying, and political activity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, February 10th, 1:00-4:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/occupy-the-ferry-and-subway-outreach-golden-farm/"&gt;Occupy the Subways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
57th and 7th Avenue F Train Subway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In support  of the workers at Golden Farm Market in Kensington Brooklyn, we will be Occupying the Subways beginning at 1pm and meeting the Boycott/Picket of Golden Farm at 2pm and staying there until 4pm.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday, February 11th, 6:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/movement-monday-an-open-meeting-for-internal-planning-and-coordination/"&gt;Movement Mondays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Two Moon Art House and Cafe, 315 4th Avenue, Brooklyn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There are so many people and groups in the Occupy Wall Street ecosystem that are doing fantastic work. We learn about many of these projects as they’re happening or the day after. Let’s find out WHO is doing WHAT actions and events — well ahead of time! We can also serve as a focused incubation chamber for NEW ideas, strategize for the long term, and reflect upon our successes and failures so we can keep building and growing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, February 14th, 8:30am-5:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/trial-beginsjustice-for-dennis-flores-courthouse-rally/"&gt;Justice for Dennis Flores - Rally at the Court&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Brooklyn Criminal Court, 120 Schermerhorn Street&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Dennis is a long-standing member of Occupy Sunset Park, as well as community organizer. Dennis Flores was arrested for defending one of the Rent Strikers against an attack by the slumlord’s hired goon. Hard to believe, but he’s actually being taken to trial on utterly ridiculous charges. Show brother Dennis your support! Turn out for a rally the morning of his trial!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, February 14th, 12:00pm-2:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/valentines-day-message-to-megabanks-time-to-break-up/"&gt;Valentines Day Message to Megabanks: Time to Break Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
NY Public Library, 42nd st. and 5th ave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join us to give HSBC, Bank of America and other megabanks Valentine’s Day Break Up Cards. Rally to call for a break up of the megabanks who are Too Big to Fail, Too Big to Jail and simply Too Big.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 16th, 6:30p.m-11:00p.m&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/125299747642536/"&gt;Hot &amp;amp; Crusty Workers Victory Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Brecht Forum, 451 West Street&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Hot and Crusty Workers Association invites you to a celebration with food, drink. dancing, live music and great conversation. Bring friends, coworkers, classmates. A voluntary $10 donation is suggested. For more information, call Rosanna at 347-652-5724 or Sándor at 917-520-5368&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 16th, 7:00pm-10:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/480380172023332/?ref=2"&gt;Sandy Storyline Fundraiser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Cafe Dancer 96 Orchard Street, New York NY (b/w Broome &amp;amp; Delancey)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join us for a party and benefit to help raise funds for &lt;a href="http://sandystoryline.com/"&gt;Sandy Storyline&lt;/a&gt;, a participatory documentary project about Hurricane Sandy and its aftermath, told through the experiences of community members and volunteers. We are raising money to help support Sandy Storyline's projects, providing media education, community exhibitions and storytelling events for residents in Hurricane Sandy affected areas.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, February 17th, Noon Rally in DC. Buses Leave NYC at 7am.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://action.sierraclub.org/site/PageServer?pagename=forwardonclimate"&gt;Forward on Climate Rally&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The National Mall, DC - to the White House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join Occupy Sandy, Occupy the Pipeline, YANA, Rockaway residents and groups from around country for the  largest climate rally in the nation's capital. In November, we came together in New York and New Jersey to provide disaster relief. Now we come together to call for real action on Climate Change. The very first step is for President Obama to reject the Keystone XL tar sands pipeline.  Sign up here for a bus ticket (reduced fairs and scholarships available).  &lt;a href="http://f17nycbusbrigade.wordpress.com"&gt;http://f17nycbusbrigade.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday February 22nd, 17:30-21:00&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/414858031925416/"&gt;Tidal 4 Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
20 Cooper Square&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tidal 4 is being released this Friday evening. Come and pick up your own free copy! It will include original, commissioned contributions from many organizers of Occupy Wall Street, Occupy Sandy and Strike Debt, Collective pieces from the Tidal Team and friends and a Student Movement piece from Free University folks. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, March 1st and Sunday March 2nd, 12-6pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/occupydata-hackathon/"&gt;Occupy Data Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Cuny Graduate Center, 365 5th Avenue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Data mining and visualization for the 99%. At the event, we’d like to focus on a few new data sets/projects. Occupy Sandy and Aaron Swartz’s work has come up, and generated a lot of interest. Any ideas, data resources you may know of or questions, please let us know: &lt;a href="http://lists.occupy.net/lists/info/occupydata"&gt;Occupy Data listserve&lt;/a&gt; or info@occupydata.nyc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, March 10th, 2pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/162619767220129/"&gt;Unorganized Workers Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Judson Memorial Church, 55 Washington Square South&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join the Occupy Your Workplace group for a discussion of strategy and tactics of workplace organizing. We'll have several folks present who have experience as workplace "salts" - workers who get jobs with the aim of organizing. Workers who are curious about organizing, experienced organizers and activists, union members, and all other workers and non workers welcome.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 18:29:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-february-6th/</guid></item><item><title>Pack The Court: Stand Against NDAA</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/pack-court-stand-against-ndaa/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="stop NDAA" src="http://i.imgur.com/WXbNAve.jpg?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us and pack the court on February 6 at 10:00 am, 40 Foley Square, Room 1005. This is a critical step in our case, Hedges v. Obama, and the stakes are high. We need your presence in court to show that Americans care about their civil rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us in &lt;strong&gt;solidarity and support&lt;/strong&gt; of the named plaintiffs Chris Hedges, Daniel Ellsberg, Noam Chomsky, Brigitta Jónsdóttir, Jennifer “Tangerine” Bolen, Kai Wargalla, and Alexa O’Brien who are &lt;strong&gt;challenging&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;indefinite detention&lt;/strong&gt; provisions of the National Defense Authorization Act, &lt;strong&gt;NDAA&lt;/strong&gt;, before the 2nd Circuit Court of Appeals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court is located on 40 Foley Square, NY, NY in room 1505 on the 15th floor. All are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="http://www.stopndaa.org/"&gt;http://www.stopndaa.org/&lt;/a&gt; for more info and all court filings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook Event: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/123804614457311/"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/events/123804614457311/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 23:19:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/pack-court-stand-against-ndaa/</guid></item><item><title>Today: Strike Debt Bay Area Presents Oakland’s First Debtors’ Assembly</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/today-strike-debt-bay-area-announces-oaklands-firs/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="strike debt bay area 1st debtors&amp;apos; assembly poster" src="http://i.imgur.com/M6EIp7b.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 2, 2013 - 2pm&lt;br /&gt;
Eastside Arts Alliance, 2277 International Blvd.&lt;br /&gt;
Oakland, CA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, February 2nd, &lt;a href="http://strike-debt-bay-area.tumblr.com/"&gt;Strike Debt Bay Area&lt;/a&gt; will host Oakland’s first Debtors’ Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As individuals, families, and communities, most of us are drowning in debt for the basic things we need to live, including housing, education, and health care. Even those of us who do not have personal debt are affected by predatory lending. Our essential public services are cut because our cities and towns are held hostage by the same big banks that have been bailed out by our government. All of us are outraged that big banks don’t have to pay their debts, but we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debt keeps us isolated, ashamed, and afraid—of becoming homeless, of going hungry, of being crippled or killed by treatable illness, or of being trapped in poverty-level jobs. Those facing foreclosure, medical debt, student debt, or credit card debt feel alone, hounded by debt collectors, and forced into unrewarding work to keep up with payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strike Debt is building a movement to challenge this system while creating alternatives and supporting each other. At the Debtors’ Assembly we will come together as a community and begin to rethink debt, not as an issue of individual shame, but as a political platform for collective resistance and action. Come to the Assembly to learn about tools for escaping the closing walls of debt, to share resources and skills, and to magnify our assembled energy. As we share our experiences we can begin to take back from the financiers what they have taken from us: our freedom and our future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debt resistance is just the beginning. Join us as we imagine and create a new world based on the common good, not Wall Street profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ORGANIZATION INFO: Strike Debt Bay Area is the local chapter of &lt;a href="http://strikedebt.org"&gt;Strike Debt&lt;/a&gt;, an international movement of groups working to build popular resistance to all forms of unjust debt. Strike Debt has organized the &lt;a href="http://rollingjubilee.org"&gt;Rolling Jubilee&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://strikedebt.org"&gt;Debt Resistors Operations Manual&lt;/a&gt;, and local debtors’ assemblies. Strike Debt supports the creation of just and sustainable economies, based on mutual aid, common goods, and public affluence. We owe the financial institutions nothing. It is to our friends, families and community that we owe everything.&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 14:10:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/today-strike-debt-bay-area-announces-oaklands-firs/</guid></item><item><title>OWS Updates for the Week of January 30th</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-january-30th/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;From February 1st to the 3rd people from across the grassroots community--organizers, volunteers, activists and storm-impacted residents--will meet at &lt;a href="http://summit.peoplesrecovery.org/"&gt;The People’s Recovery Summit&lt;/a&gt; to address how we can rebuild a stronger, fairer and more sustainable New York City together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we strengthen access to good public schools for our children? How do we rebuild sustainably and equitably? How can we best organize our relief networks before the next time we need them? How do we make our communities healthier places?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us this weekend to explore these questions and participate in workshops, listen to speeches, attend trainings, share meals, hear music and help draft a unified people’s recovery statement. Restore power to the people - a better future is in our hands!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--from the &lt;a href="http://salsa3.salsalabs.com/o/50112/p/salsa/web/common/public/signup?signup_page_KEY=7238"&gt;‘Your Inbox: Occupied’ team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Occupy these Actions and Events&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, January 30th, 9:00am&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/mta-board-meeting-be-there-be-heard-no-fare-hike/"&gt;MTA Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt;, MTA Metro North Railroad, 347 Madison Ave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
March 1, 2013 the fare on the NYC subway will be increased yet again and this is only one of the many planned increases. Come to the last board meeting before the fare increase goes into effect with signs and speeches ready. Come on out and be heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, January 30th, 11:00am-2:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/protest-nypd-putting-body-scanners-on-nyc-streets/"&gt;Protest of NYPD's "Naked Body Scanners"&lt;/a&gt;, 1 Police Plaza&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The NYPD has announced that it will be putting naked body terahertz scanners on NYC streets and scanning people without their knowledge or consent. Join us at 1 Police Plaza as we peacefully express to the NYPD that we will not tolerate being treated like criminals. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/410778172333416/"&gt;RSVP on Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, January 31st, 6:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://99pickets.org/picket/roc-ny-celebrate-one-year-of-struggle-at-the-capital-grille/"&gt;99 Pickets and ROC-NY Celebrating One Year of Struggle&lt;/a&gt;, The Capital Grille, 155 E. 42nd St.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For the past year, workers at The Capital Grille have been organizing to change conditions in their workplace, alleging racial discrimination and wage theft, in addition to experiencing other exploitative conditions. Join us on the anniversary of launching the Dignity at Darden campaign, as we show Darden that Capital Grille workers will not rest until justice is had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday, February 2nd, 10:00am-1:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/sandywalk-for-democracy-and-justice/"&gt;Sandy Walk&lt;/a&gt;, Ends at Staten Island Community Hub, 1128 Olympia Blvd., Midland Beach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Join Staten Island resident Bill Johnsen for a walk on the first Saturday of the month leaving from Brighton St &amp;amp; Billopp Avenue, Tottenville, ending at St. Margaret Mary’s Church, The Occupy Sandy community hub in Staten Island.  The walk is in support of Uniting the Victims of Hurricane Sandy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, February 3rd, 1:00pm-4:00pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/occupy-the-subway-outreach-to-the-99-and-support-the-workers-of-golden-farm-and-occupy-queens-general-assembly/"&gt;Occupy the Ferry&lt;/a&gt;, St. George Staten Island Ferry Terminal&lt;br /&gt;
Staten Island, New York 10301 82nd Street-Jackson Heights / Roosevelt Avenue 7 Train&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As outreach to the 99% and in support The WORKERS at Golden Farm in Kensington Brooklyn we will be Occupying the Subways beginning at 1pm and meeting the Boycott/Picket of Golden Farm at 2pm and staying there until 4pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, February 1, 2013, 6:30pm-9:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/occupy-beyond-sandy-getting-back-to-what-us-to-occupy-wall-street-part-2/"&gt;Occupy Beyond Sandy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Atrium 60 Wall St.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Despite all the GREAT work of Occupy Sandy, the problems of both Sandy Victims and the 99% remain and will only get worse with the plans of the 1% to gentrify in the aftermath of Sandy. With the many issues that still remain before and after Sandy, it’s time we examine our work and continue to organize for the 99% to fight Wall Street and build the Occupy Movement. Please join us. We are involved in several continuous actions all around the city and attempting to build a mass movement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 1st, 2nd, and 3rd&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://summit.peoplesrecovery.org/"&gt;People's Recovery Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Church of St. Luke and St. Matthew, 520 Clinton Ave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The People's Recovery Summit is a three day event of workshops, trainings, horizontally facilitated discussions, and evening entertainment. Residents, activists, organizers, volunteers, and all concerned citizens will unite to build a more equitable and sustainable New York City post-Hurricane Sandy. Come participate for any and all parts of the weekend and help ignite a people-powered recovery! Breakfast, Lunch, and Dinner will be served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, February 5, 7pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://cooper.edu/events-and-exhibitions/events/divesting-fossil-fuels-conversation-bill-mckibben-and-nyc-students"&gt;Divesting from Fossil Fuels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Cooper Union, The Great Hall, 7 East 7th Street between 3rd &amp;amp; 4th Avenues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
America’s colleges and universities prepare the nation’s young people for their future. Yet those same institutions invest in the fossil fuel companies that are profiting enormously from the carbon that’s going to wreck the climate. Thousands of students are building a national movement demanding that university endowments divest from the fossil fuel industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, February 6th, 9:45am&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/call-to-pack-the-court-in-hedges-v-obama/"&gt;Flood the Court&lt;/a&gt;, 40 Centre St. (40 Foley Square)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The 2nd circuit court of appeals will be hearing oral arguments in the lawsuit against section 1021 of the NDAA. Your attendance will communicate that the public is invested in the outcome of this ruling and unwilling to sit idly by as due process rights are eroded. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/123804614457311/"&gt;RSVP on Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 20:22:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-january-30th/</guid></item><item><title>Feb 1-3: Peoples Recovery Summit</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/feb-1-3-peoples-recovery-summit/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="people recovery summit" src="http://i.imgur.com/U5Nxw2t.jpg?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Restore Power to the People!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A free 3-day gathering of workshops, panels, concerts and performances to unite for a more equitable and sustainable rebuilding in Sandy's wake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Feb 1-3&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Church of St. Luke &amp;amp; St. Matthew, Brooklyn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information or to register, see &lt;a href="http://summit.peoplesrecovery.org/"&gt;http://summit.peoplesrecovery.org/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/459329024120935"&gt;RSVP on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current Sponsors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;350.org&lt;br /&gt;
Bailey’s Cafe&lt;br /&gt;
Church of St. Luke and St. Matthew&lt;br /&gt;
Coalition for Public Education&lt;br /&gt;
Episcopal Diocese of Long Island&lt;br /&gt;
Greenpeace&lt;br /&gt;
NY Committee for Occupational Safety &amp;amp; Health&lt;br /&gt;
NYC Parents Union&lt;br /&gt;
Occupy Sandy&lt;br /&gt;
Occupy Faith&lt;br /&gt;
Occupy The Hood&lt;br /&gt;
Our Schools NYC&lt;br /&gt;
Paul Robeson Freedom School&lt;br /&gt;
People for Jelani&lt;br /&gt;
The Peoples Network&lt;br /&gt;
Recover.org&lt;br /&gt;
US Uncut&lt;br /&gt;
Workers Justice Project&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 17:33:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/feb-1-3-peoples-recovery-summit/</guid></item><item><title>Support Take The Square - A Documentary Film</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/support-take-square-documentary-film/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;iframe frameborder="0" width="560" height="315" src="http://www.dailymotion.com/embed/video/xvlsoj"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/video/xvlsoj_tts-full-eng_news" target="_blank"&gt;TTS-FULL-ENG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;by &lt;a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/OXYGENPROD" target="_blank"&gt;OXYGENPROD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/mCt4FUj.jpg" style="float:right; padding-left:1em"/&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tahir Square, Puerta del Sol, Syntagma Square, Wall Street…Cairo, Madrid, Athens, New York…as many cities, as many places where different nations started camping to take the streets over, take public spaces back, take democracy back. This documentary tells the story of a movement that first took place on the banks of the Nile to spread across the world and try to change democratic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie Take the Square was shot in 2011, covering the various social movements (Arab Spring, Occupy Wall Street, Indignados…) which unsettled the planet. &lt;a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/video/xvlsoj_tts-full-eng_news#.UPZRCW_vFX0"&gt;Watch the trailer here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.touscoprod.com/en/project/produce?id=423"&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to donate. The money won’t be debited unless the goal (6000 €) is reached by March 2013. In case of failure, your money will be given back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the financial aspect, you can help in many ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Share the info in your networks (social, emails)
– Translation (English, Spanish, Egyptian arabic) and retranscriptions
– Also looking for people who can help with releasing the film in different theaters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for sharing the information among your contacts and, for those who can financially help, see you on touscoprod.com. You can use &lt;a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/video/xwyqu7_english-tutorial-take-the-square_creation#.UQgDWW9ZWTJ"&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can email us here: takethesquarethemovie@gmail.com. Follow our updates on &lt;a href="http://takethesquarethemovie.blogspot.fr/"&gt;our blog&lt;/a&gt; or on the project’s &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TakeTheSquaredemocratie20?ref=hl."&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trailer for your &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/51734249"&gt;Spanish-speaking friends&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 17:08:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/support-take-square-documentary-film/</guid></item><item><title>Seven Brides For Seven Corporations</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/seven-brides-seven-corporations/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;Days before the third anniversary of the Citizens United v. SEC Supreme Court case ruling, Occupy Wall Street organized an extravagant piece of political street theater: a wedding in which seven brides were to marry seven corporations in a ceremony across the street from the New York Stock Exchange. &lt;a href="http://www.revbilly.com/"&gt;The Honorable Reverend Billy from The Church of Stop Shopping&lt;/a&gt; presided over the ceremony. One of the brides, Monica Hunken, in a wedding dress bedazzled with real dollar bills, interrupted the ceremony just as her betrothed was about to take her hand in marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/yJOXUhB2uRA"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/yJOXUhB2uRA" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why protest against the Citizens United Supreme Court Decision?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday, January 21, 2013 was the third anniversary of the Supreme Court’s favorable ruling for Citizens United against the Federal Election Commission that has opened the floodgates for a truly pornographic amount of money into our political process. Don’t get me wrong; I am not suggesting that we wax poetic about the glory days before 2009 when the U.S. political process was paramour of virtue. The Citizens United ruling has become a symbol for what the Supreme Court has been doing for about 100 years, slowly empowering corporations until they have now been granted personhood status and putting how money is spent in elections on par with free speech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;img src="http://imgur.com/hKKIFbE.jpg" width="518" height="800"/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How did this happen?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One does not think of corporate shills as activists, but that is label that one of the most powerful corporate shills in the world, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Roberts"&gt;Justice John Roberts&lt;/a&gt;, has earned in his short time heading the Supreme Court: An activist judge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What other word is there to describe the brazen behavior of the Roberts’ Supreme Court that looked at the vast wasteland of cases seeking to be heard in the Fall of 2009 and picked a little case brought by a corporate front group – &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizens_United_%28organization%29"&gt;Citizens United&lt;/a&gt;- and then rewrote the complaint to reframe the question completely? Then convened court a month earlier than was the usual, giving lawyers who had to prepare oral arguments, only a month to deal with the new, large, and obscene question of whether corporations had constitutionally protected electioneering rights- like people? As a result of the Supreme Court’s Citizen United decree, unlimited and unreported sums of corporate money are now allowed in all US elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: The elite ruling class and corporate political interests have rendered the individual citizen nearly obsolete in the electoral process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that corporate power has been constitutionalized via this Supreme Court precedent, how long will it be before all elected officials are 21st Century versions of the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Manchurian_Candidate"&gt;Manchurian Candidate&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Stepford_Wives"&gt;Stepford Wives&lt;/a&gt; mindlessly regurgitating talking points programmed by the ultra rich?&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 23:40:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/seven-brides-seven-corporations/</guid></item><item><title>OWS Updates for the Week of January 25th</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-january-25th/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;Last week's &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/01/17/1179886/-OWS-Fighting-Back-Against-the-Lies"&gt;petition delivery action&lt;/a&gt; was a great success, delivering a clear message that OWS would not stay silent while the New York Post lied about us yet again. People from Occupy Faith and concerned activists spoke with humor and eloquence against a backdrop of banners printed with the names of the thousands of people who signed the petition. Music was played and songs were sung, but we’re still waiting on our apology, let alone a thank you note for the good time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--from the &lt;a href="http://salsa3.salsalabs.com/o/50112/p/salsa/web/common/public/signup?signup_page_KEY=7238"&gt;‘Your Inbox: Occupied’ team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;OWS in Media&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brides were blushing, the grooms oddly impersonal, as the third anniversary of the Supreme Court’s Citizens United ruling was marked with a magical &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;amp;v=yJOXUhB2uRA"&gt;direct action wedding&lt;/a&gt; on the steps of Federal Hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion at Strike Debt’s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IOXIHulWHIk"&gt;MLK day event&lt;/a&gt; at Judson Church was enormously stimulating. If you missed it, take a look at Strike Debt’s &lt;a href="http://strikedebt.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Visioning-Workbook.pdf"&gt;Visioning Workbook&lt;/a&gt; to get up to speed with the issues raised that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York City school bus drivers have been out on strike since Wednesday, January 16th and as is now standard treatment for striking workers, have been smeared and vilified for it. Our featured blog post &lt;a href="http://year0.org/2013/01/17/strike-lessons/"&gt;"Strike Lessons"&lt;/a&gt; offers up a refreshing alternative in an analysis of the situation that explains why we can and must strike, as well as a list of picket locations so that we can show some on-the-ground solidarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Occupy these Actions and Events&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, January 25, 8pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/118981598278371/?ref=2"&gt;Debt Resistors Dance Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
207 Starr Street, Bushwick, Brooklyn; Off Jefferson L train stop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A caravan of 13 people is heading out to Detroit Feb 1st-4th to reach out to movements and struggles in Detroit and folks from Strike Debt Detroit. Our goal is $1,000 to cover the entire trip for 13 people for 4 days. This will cover gas and emergency funds. We are seeking to learn what people are doing in terms of alternatives that can help us un-plug from the system and develop new bonds and relations with one another. Come dance all night to the best jams - no corny stuff. Hear more about Strike Debt and how you can get involved. $5 at the door. 1 Free beer. BYOB allowed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, January 27, 3pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/216375728499708/"&gt;Occupy the Climate: Hurricane Sandy, Eco-activism and the Vegan Option&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Jivamuktea Café @ Jivamukti Yoga School&lt;br /&gt;
841 Broadway, 2nd floor, (212) 353-0214&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A gathering/teach-in and an urgent call-to-arms on Post-Sandy life. Climate change contributed to the impact and aftermath of Hurricane Sandy and the number one cause of human-created greenhouse gases is the global animal by-products industry. Mickey Z. will help you do the math!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday, January 27, 1pm&lt;br /&gt;
Screening of &lt;a href="http://werenotbrokemovie.com/"&gt;“We’re Not Broke”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Unitarian Church of All Souls, Reidy Hall, 1157 Lexington Avenue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Screening of a film by Karin Hayes and Victoria Bruce. “The story of how U.S. corporations have been able to hide over a trillion dollars from Uncle Sam, and how fed-up Americans from across the country have taken their frustration to the streets.” With special guest J.A. Myerson,  founding member of UncutNYC and early participant in the occupation of New York City, Zuccotti Park. Free and open to the public. Refreshments served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, February 1, 2013, 6:30pm-9:30pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.nycga.net/events/occupy-beyond-sandy-getting-back-to-what-us-to-occupy-wall-street-part-2/"&gt;Occupy Beyond Sandy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Atrium 60 Wall St.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Despite all the GREAT work of Occupy Sandy, the problems of both Sandy Victims and the 99% remain and will only get worse with the plans of the 1% to gentrify in the aftermath of Sandy. With the many issues that still remain before and after Sandy, it’s time we examine our work and continue to organize for the 99% to fight Wall Street and build the Occupy Movement. Please join us. We are involved in several continuous actions all around the city and attempting to build a mass movement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 1st, 2nd, and 3rd&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://summit.peoplesrecovery.org/"&gt;People's Recovery Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Church of St. Luke and St. Matthew, 520 Clinton Ave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The People's Recovery Summit is a three day event of workshops, trainings, horizontally facilitated discussions, and evening entertainment. Residents, activists, organizers, volunteers, and all concerned citizens will unite to build a more equitable and sustainable New York City post-Hurricane Sandy. Come participate for any and all parts of the weekend and help ignite a people-powered recovery! Breakfast, Lunch, and Dinner will be served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, February 5, 7pm&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://cooper.edu/events-and-exhibitions/events/divesting-fossil-fuels-conversation-bill-mckibben-and-nyc-students"&gt;Divesting from Fossil Fuels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Cooper Union, The Great Hall, 7 East 7th Street between 3rd &amp;amp; 4th Avenues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
America’s colleges and universities prepare the nation’s young people for their future. Yet those same institutions invest in the fossil fuel companies that are profiting enormously from the carbon that’s going to wreck the climate. Thousands of students are building a national movement demanding that university endowments divest from the fossil fuel industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occupy Sandy Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Occupy Sandy is looking for individuals and groups for food preparation, canvassing, muck-out, mold remediation, construction, driving, coordinatoing volunteers and more. To find out more about how to get involved please email OccupySandyVolunteers@gmail.com or call 347-770-4520. For more information go to occupysandy.org. Support local businesses by using the &lt;a href="http://occupysandylocalregistry.com/"&gt;Occupy Sandy Local Registry&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 17:02:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/ows-updates-week-january-25th/</guid></item><item><title>Who&amp;#39;s the Terrorist?</title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/whos-terrorist/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Qf8s4.jpg" width="359" height="332" style="float:right; padding-left:1em"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, December 31st, Rupert Murdoch’s New York Post reported that weapons and high explosive powder were found in the home of a Greenwich Village couple. New York Post reporter Jamie Schram claimed that the accused is an "Occupy Wall Street activist", sans a single source (not even an anonymous one) for the OWS connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so as the &lt;a href="https://press.nycga.net/2012/12/31/nypd-media-reports-attempt-to-link-ows-to-crime-again/"&gt;OWS PR working group&lt;/a&gt; was forced to call the press to account: &lt;a href="http://press.nycga.net/2012/12/31/nypd-media-reports-attempt-to-link-ows-to-crime-again/"&gt;"We urge members of the media to refrain from spreading rumors and misinformation," emphasizing in the immediate aftermath of the story that "There is nothing… to support a link between OWS and the individual arrested."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after, this was &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/01/nyregion/manhattan-couple-stored-bomb-making-items-police-say.html?_r=1&amp;amp;"&gt;confirmed by the NYPD in the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which acknowledged there was no evidence the accused was active in any political movements whatsoever. Within another day, &lt;a href="http://www.nypost.com/p/news/local/manhattan/baby_break_for_village_bomb_gal_dsI4TJwX6gVx48G33vmvIM"&gt;Schram himself was forced to write an update which struck any mention of Occupy from the record.&lt;/a&gt; The Village Voice documented the lies in &lt;a href="http://blogs.villagevoice.com/runninscared/2013/01/new_york_post_h.php"&gt;New York Post Helps NYPD Slander Occupy Wall Street (Again)&lt;/a&gt;, followed by FAIR's account of the &lt;a href="http://www.fair.org/blog/2013/01/04/phony-occupy-link-to-weapons-cache/"&gt;phony link&lt;/a&gt; between Occupy and the arrests, and another Voice headline: &lt;a href="http://blogs.villagevoice.com/runninscared/2013/01/more_misreporti.php"&gt;More Misresporting on the West Village Explosive Arrests.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href="http://www.alternet.org/story/152890/cops_blame_occupy_wall_street_for_surge_in_shootings_but_city_wastes_money_policing_nonviolent_protesters"&gt;far from the first time&lt;/a&gt; that the Post has &lt;a href="http://blogs.villagevoice.com/runninscared/2012/07/questions_raise.php"&gt;distorted the facts&lt;/a&gt; of a story in order to associate the movement with violence. As Your Inbox: Occupied, has noted, the results of media misinformation have contributed to &lt;a href="http://salsa3.salsalabs.com/o/50112/t/0/blastContent.jsp?email_blast_KEY=1234695"&gt;"the marginalization of constituencies and views that deserve respectful treatment by reporters, documented police violence, and unconstitutional domestic spying activities."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Nick Pinto of the Village Voice notes, "a full two days after the Occupy link had already been debunked, CBS This Morning ran &lt;a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-505263_162-57561549/police-nyc-couple-who-had-terrorist-encyclopedia-face-weapons-charges/"&gt;a segment&lt;/a&gt; doubling down on the false claim," going so far as to bring on Mitchell Silber of K2 Intelligence, a corporate investigation firm. "It's unclear why CBS doesn't bother to identify him as such," writes Pinto, "but &lt;a href="http://www.k2intelligence.com/person/mitchell-silber/"&gt;well into 2012&lt;/a&gt;, Silber was the Director of the Analytic and Cyber Units in the NYPD's controversial Intelligence Division, where he was &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/new-york/nypd-terror-expert-mitchell-silber-leave-job-private-sector-article-1.1085413"&gt;associated&lt;/a&gt; with the division's program of &lt;a href="http://www.ap.org/Index/AP-In-The-News/NYPD"&gt;widespread surveillance of Muslim Americans."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple times this year it has become clear that the effort to cast aspersions of criminality over this movement for equity and democracy portends an escalation in repression. When we first called attention &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/video-scary-crackdown-on-ndaa-occupy-wall-street-protest-2012-1"&gt;to the National Defense Authorization Act,&lt;/a&gt; we were seeing frightening signs that violent elements acting outside of Occupy Wall Street and against our principles, will be marshaled to justify a future crackdown heralding from the inner sanctum of the Executive. And the scope of this problem has recently &lt;a href="http://interoccupy.net/blog/fbi-documents-reveal-it-monitored-occupy-as-a-criminal-and-terrorist-threat/"&gt;become even more pronounced&lt;/a&gt; through disclosures that the "FBI and the Department of Homeland Security are treating protests against the corporate and banking structure of America as potential criminal and terrorist activity. These documents also show these federal agencies functioning as a de facto intelligence arm of Wall Street and Corporate America." This pathetic, yet extremely damaging example of collusion between Rupert Murdoch's Wall Street tabloid and elements within the FBI, proves the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need ideas to start moving from behind your screens and into the streets, we recommend that you start at the &lt;a href="http://nvdatabase.swarthmore.edu/browse_methods"&gt;nonviolent database of direct action from Swarthmore College.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://occupywallstreet.net/story/whos-terrorist"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reprinted with edits from OccupyWallStreet.net&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:55:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/whos-terrorist/</guid></item><item><title>Occupy University: The People&amp;#39;s Reconstruction Series </title><link>http://occupywallst.org/article/occupy-university-peoples-reconstruction-series/</link><description>

&lt;div class="article-feed"&gt;
  
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="occupy university banner" src="http://i.imgur.com/ElHEx.jpg?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://peoplesreconstruction.wordpress.com/"&gt;The People’s Reconstruction Series&lt;/a&gt; is a sequence of educational encounters, organized by &lt;a href="http://university.nycga.net/"&gt;Occupy University&lt;/a&gt;, that address several issues related to Hurricane Sandy. Each encounter will gather at &lt;a href="http://bluestockings.com/"&gt;Bluestockings&lt;/a&gt; (172 Allen St. New York, NY 10002) and feature a presentation followed by horizontal discussion. We hope to provide a space for people to collectively reflect on the politics of climate disaster in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/315352931909332/"&gt;RSVP on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter 1, “Rising Water”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, January 8, 2013&lt;br /&gt;
*What are the politics of climate change at local, national, and international levels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter 2, “Individual Consequences”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thursday, January 17, 2013&lt;br /&gt;
*How are individuals affected financially, emotionally, and otherwise by climate change? Specific emphasis will be given to communities in New York City impacted by Hurricane Sandy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter 3, “Community Response”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thursday, January 24, 2013&lt;br /&gt;
*What can communities do to address immediate threats and consequences of climate change as well as address systemic injustices disasters like Sandy uncover.&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">OccupyWallSt</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 18:48:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://occupywallst.org/article/occupy-university-peoples-reconstruction-series/</guid></item></channel></rss>