<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Dream Euro Trip</title>
	
	<link>http://www.dreameurotrip.com</link>
	<description>Planning and Budgeting your EuroTrip adventures</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 22:41:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.3.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/DreamEuroTrip" /><feedburner:info uri="dreameurotrip" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>DreamEuroTrip</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>London’s Vibrant Theater Scene</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/mIs8G4Nl2s8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/theater-scene-london/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 15:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[England]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=3092</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; When it comes to the theatre scene, you simply can’t beat London.  Nowhere else on earth boasts the rich theatre history associated with the city of London, and nowhere else has a theatre district as large as the city’s West End. With such rich quality, history, and variety, the London theatre scene is a [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/West-End-Theatre.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3094" title="West-End-Theatre" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/West-End-Theatre.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When it comes to the theatre scene, you simply can’t beat London.  Nowhere else on earth boasts the rich theatre history associated with the city of London, and nowhere else has a theatre district as large as the city’s West End. With such rich quality, history, and variety, the London theatre scene is a must-see on any trip to England!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">West End Theatre</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The term “West End Theatre” refers to the mainstream professional theatre that is staged in the bigger theaters in London’s West End, also known as “Theatreland”. It’s similar to the “Broadway” scene in New York City. One of the best qualities about the West End is its terrific variety of shows; the West End puts on plays ranging from Shakespeare to children’s shows, dances, musical, operas and more. If you’re travelling with children, consider catching one of the family-friendly shows, such as  “Charlie and the Chocolate Factory” at Drury lane (opening in June 2013), “Matilda the Musical” at the Cambridge Theater, or “The Lion King” at the Lyceum Theater. Other successful shows being performed this year include “1984” (which will be finishing its run in June 2013), “And in the End- the Life and Death of John Lennon” (also closing up in June 2013), and the ever-popular “Billy Elliot: The Musical”.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Off-Beat Theatre</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you’re looking for theatre that is slightly less mainstream than the West End scene, London offers many choices. The Southwest Playhouse on Newington Causeway frequently showcases new writers, focusing on the next generation of theatre makers. Other great bets include The Almedia in Islington, and The Orange Tree in Richmond (The Orange Tree is known for celebrating up-and-coming writers, and dealing with contemporary, relevant issues).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">The Globe Theater</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is no theater more famous than London’s Globe Theater. In 1599, it was constructed by William Shakespeare’s playing company, the Lord Chamberlain’s Men. Unfortunately, it was destroyed by a fire in 1613, leading to the construction of a second Globe Theater on the same site. The second Globe Theater closed down by the Puritans in 1642 (along with many other theaters in London. Over 300 years later, in 1997, a modern reconstruction of the theater (roughly based on the original design) was built a couple hundred meters from the original theater.  The new Globe Theater is the stage for top-notch theater productions; the 2013 season includes Shakespearean plays such as “The Tempest”, “A Midsummer Night’s Dream”, and “MacBeth”, as well as new plays making their world-premiere, such as “Blue Stockings” by Jessica Swale (directed by John Dove) and “The Lightning Child” by Ché Walker (directed by Matthew Dunster).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">How to Get Theater Tickets in London</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are many ways to get tickets to the theatre in London. Check out London Theater Breaks in 2013, and embrace first class performances all year round. They provide comprehensive <a href="http://www.justlondontheatrebreaks.com">hotel and theatre London</a> packages so you can get better value for your money hassle-free.</p>
<p>Other options include the TKTS booth in Leicester Square that sells West End theatre tickets. The booth sells tickets for the day of the show, and up to a week in advance. It is open from 10am to 7pm from Monday to Saturday, and from 11am to 4pm on Sundays.</p>
<p>Another good option is the Theatre Passport, which allows the bearer access to the best available seats in the house for participating shows and musicals; this is an especially sensible option for those who want to see a show, but aren’t sure which one to see. If you’re interested in getting tickets on a show held at the Globe Theater, information can be obtained on the Shakespeare’s Globe Theatre website.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.lolstudent.com/2013/01/enjoy-student-life-london-west-end.html" target="_blank">Image Credit</a></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/mIs8G4Nl2s8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/theater-scene-london/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/theater-scene-london/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Most-Loved Sightseeing Locations in Paris</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/QK1iWLBMMbw/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/top-5-most-loved-sightseeing-locations-in-paris/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 18:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=3072</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Paris is an exciting place to visit, especially for the first time. Everyone has different ideas on how to invade the city. I was overwhelmed myself on my first visit there during my epic backpacking Europe trip. What I normally do in big cities is visit the top tourist sites first and then just be spontaneous [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/louvre-cover.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p>Paris is an exciting place to visit, especially for the first time. Everyone has different ideas on how to invade the city. I was overwhelmed myself on my first visit there during my epic <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/" target="_blank">backpacking Europe trip</a>. What I normally do in big cities is visit the top tourist sites first and then just be spontaneous the rest of my days. To help you wing it on your first days in <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/france/paris/" target="_blank">Paris</a>, here are 5 of the most-loved sightseeing locations in Paris:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Eiffel Tower</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The top landmark and symbol of Paris, the Eiffel Tower is incredible from a distance and even more so when standing underneath it or taking the tour. The tower has 3 levels of observation decks. Options of an elevator or a stairway lead to and from the first 2 levels. Only an elevator is provided to and from the top level, and lines waiting at that lift can be long.</p>
<p>Seen from any viewpoint and at any time of day, the Eiffel Tower is beautiful. Note that the splendour of the view of Paris at sunset from the second and third levels is unmatched from any other place in the city. If you are taking the city bus to visit the tower, be sure to know the time of the last bus stopping at the landmark.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img title="Eiffel Tower Light Show" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_9802.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /><p class="wp-caption-text">just another cliche Eiffel Tower photo at night</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">The Louvre</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Opens at 9:00 AM every day of the week except Tuesday, this grand museum houses numerous collections and around 400,000 items on show. Days are needed to see everything in this venue, but you can choose sections that are of particular interest to you if your time is limited. On my first visit at the Louvre, I was only able to see a few sections of it. You don&#8217;t have to see everything inside but if you&#8217;re a museum freak then better allocate around a week for the Louvre alone. All exhibit descriptions and signs are in French, but you can purchase an audio guide in your preferred language.</p>
<p>Travel tip: bring your student ID! Entrance to the museum is free for students and young people among others. Check out the full list <a href="http://www.louvre.fr/en/hours-admission/admission" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img title="The Lourve at dusk" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_9449.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /><p class="wp-caption-text">view of the Louvre from one of its top chambers</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Montmarte</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How could you go to Paris and not visit Montmarte? Montmarte has a special place in my heart because one of my favorite films, Amelie, was shot here. I even did a DIY Amelie tour on my own when I was back in Paris last September. What&#8217;s in Montmarte? For a start, there&#8217;s the Sacred Heart Basilica of Montmarte (pictured below) which is gorgeous and has a breathtaking view of Paris. You can also see Moulin Rouge here which I thought is overrated. There are also a lot of cool shops, cozy cafes and interesting nooks and crannies in Montmarte. I love it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_3079" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3079" title="Sacred Heart Basilica of Montmarte" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_2806.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Me workin&#39; it at the Sacred Heart Basilica of Montmarte</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Notre Dame Cathedral</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>About the second most famous landmark in the city, the magnificent Notre Dame Cathedral is a classic illustration of Gothic architecture. Built in the 1100s, this church is definitely worth a visit to see the interior, the architecture and the lovely stained glass art. Admission is free, but a fee is charged to climb the tower. An excellent time to visit is on Sunday morning during Mass when the gigantic organ is playing and the choir is singing.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img title="Notre Dame winter" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_9367.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Notre Dame Cathedral in the summer</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Catacombs</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Open daily from 10:00 in the morning until 5:00 in the evening, the Catacombs are underground tombs where around 6 million people were laid to rest. A vast historic system of tunnels, this maize of routes under the city are fascinating and sobering. Self-tours let visitors see as much as they want to explore. Wearing walking shoes and bringing along drinking water are important for meandering through the passages viewing the arrangements of skulls, bones and other intriguing sites.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you’re <a href="http://www.hostelbookers.com/hostels/france/paris/">looking for budget accommodation in Paris</a> check out the HostelBookers website. A good tip for visiting the main and popular attractions in the city is to come early. When arriving at least a half an hour before opening times, you avoid an hour or more wait at the entrance later in the day. Another thing to remember is that holidays like Easter find the main sites of the city so crowded that even early comers must wait 2 or 3 hours.</p>
<p>Did I miss anything in this list? What are your top attractions in Paris?</p>
<div></div>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/QK1iWLBMMbw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/top-5-most-loved-sightseeing-locations-in-paris/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/top-5-most-loved-sightseeing-locations-in-paris/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>13th Annual Weblog Awards’ Best European Weblog</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/AQ-6hMvJhMw/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/13th-annual-weblog-awards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 02:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=3044</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; I still can&#8217;t believe that my relatively new eurotrip travel blog is nominated as one of the Best European Weblogs at the 13th Annual Weblog Awards aka 2013 Bloggies. This is kind of major. Well, to begin with, the Bloggies is the longest running blog awards on the Internet and every year they recognize [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_0884.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><div id="attachment_3050" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3050" title="IMG_08771" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/IMG_08771.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /><p class="wp-caption-text">DJ in Gamla Stan, Stockholm</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I still can&#8217;t believe that my relatively new <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com" target="_blank">eurotrip travel blog</a> is nominated as one of the <strong>Best European Weblogs</strong> at the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/#european" target="_blank">13th Annual Weblog Awards</a> aka 2013 Bloggies.</p>
<p><strong>This is kind of major.</strong></p>
<p>Well, to begin with, the Bloggies is the longest running blog awards on the Internet and every year they recognize amazing blogs in many different categories. There are many fantastic blogs on the Internet, and the Bloggies is here to honor them. So this is like the Oscars of the blogverse. It&#8217;s such an honor to be nominated.</p>
<p>I am quite flattered and happy since I really don&#8217;t know how I got there. There was a nomination process and then a voting process from the most-nominated blogs and then the top 5 best blogs of each category was revealed which is how I came to know about it.</p>
<p>I suddenly had a surge of traffic from the Bloggies website and only after a few days did I realize that my blog was nominated as top 5 Best European Weblog. *confetti confetti*</p>
<p>To those who nominated me, thank you thank you.</p>
<p>And here is where you come into the picture. The last step is voting for the best blog in each category. If my blog has helped you in anyway, please vote for me as Best European Weblog. You can do it in 3 easy steps in under 30 seconds! The last day of voting is on March 17, TOMORROW!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Step 1: Head over to the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/#european" target="_blank">2013 Bloggies website</a> and tick off Dream Euro Trip.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3047" title="Picture 2" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Picture-2-1024x435.png" alt="" width="600" height="258" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Step 2: Scroll down at the bottom to enter your email and submit your nomination.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Step 3: Check your inbox and confirm your vote!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3048" title="Picture 3" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Picture-3-1024x458.png" alt="" width="600" height="272" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thank you so much for voting!</p>
<p>P.S. 1 vote = 1 email, which means you can use all your other emails to vote and I will love you forever and send you amazing karma right now.</p>
<p>DJ</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/AQ-6hMvJhMw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/13th-annual-weblog-awards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/13th-annual-weblog-awards/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Paris in the Spring? 5 Reasons Why May is Ideal for a Paris Getaway</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/zF1c3P675-s/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/paris-in-the-spring-5-reasons-why-may-is-ideal-for-a-paris-getaway/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 19:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=3002</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Audrey Hepburn once remarked that Paris is always a good idea. Judging by the millions of people who travel there every year, that statement is true. Like any city, some times of the year are better than others for visiting. One of those times is the month of May for a number of reasons. [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/cover-photo-paris1.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p><img class="size-full wp-image-3006 aligncenter" title="Paris Spring" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_2641.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Audrey Hepburn once remarked that <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/france/paris/" target="_blank">Paris</a> is always a good idea. Judging by the millions of people who travel there every year, that statement is true.</p>
<p>Like any city, some times of the year are better than others for visiting. One of those times is the month of May for a number of reasons.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">1. Fewer Crowds</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thanks to its reputation as one of the most romantic cities in the world, the month of February, specifically Valentine’s Day, sees an influx of visitors. In the summer months, when children are out of school and families take their annual vacations, the city is overrun by tourists angling for the best view of the Mona Lisa and the Eiffel Tower. While May marks the beginning of summer, and crowds increase throughout the month, on most days you’ll be able to enjoy the city sights without long waits or large crowds.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">2. Pleasant Weather</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Parisian weather in May tends to be on the cooler side. The average temperature is 57 degrees Fahrenheit, but it’s generally sunny. You might encounter a stray rain shower or two, but overall the days are sunny and mild with cooler nights. This means that when you are walking the streets or traipsing up the many stairs of the Metro, you’ll be comfortable.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3007" title="Gare du Nord Paris" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_2733.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">3. Festivals and Events</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/france/" target="_blank">France</a> observes two national holidays in May. May 1 is Labor Day, honoring workers, and May 8 is Victory Day, marking the end of World War II. On these days most of the major tourist attractions and many businesses are closed, but visitors can still experience events and ceremonies commemorating the holidays. Paris is alive with activity throughout the month, hosting several major festivals and events. Tennis fans flock to Paris every May for the French Open tennis tournament and it’s possible to purchase same-day tickets to watch some of the world’s best tennis players.</p>
<p>Paris also celebrates Museum Night each May. On one night, all of the museums in the city are free to the public and offer special exhibits and events as well as extended hours, often well past midnight. Music lovers will enjoy the Saint-Germain-des-Pres Jazz Festival, a two-week celebration of jazz that takes place in clubs and venues around the city, with a number of free or low-cost concerts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">4. Relatively Cheaper</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Paris is one of the more expensive European cities for tourists, but rates in the month of May tend to be lower than average. Flights and hotel prices are lower in the earlier part of the month than later, when the crowds start to build. Overall, May tends to be a cheaper month for travel. You can always find <a href="http://www.expedia.com/Cheap-Flights-To-Paris.d179898.Travel-Guide-Flights" target="_blank">cheap flights to Paris</a> during this month as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3008" title="Yummy food Paris" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/IMG_9470.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">5. Paris at its Best</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Paris is a beautiful city at any time of the year, but in May the landscape is truly spectacular. The gray and dreary days of winter give way bright sunshine, and the many parks and gardens burst with color. It’s possible to pack a picnic lunch — picking up a bottle of wine, some bread and cheese at one of the many markets — and spend an afternoon soaking up the atmosphere. In fact, a leisurely afternoon in one of Paris’ gardens is arguably Paris at its finest.</p>
<p>While a true Francophile can make a case for visiting Paris at any time, for a first-time visitor, it’s hard to beat Paris in May. From the pleasant temperatures and lower crowds to the festivals and flowers, it is an ideal time to visit and soak up the beauty, culture and romance that is distinctly Paris.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/zF1c3P675-s" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/paris-in-the-spring-5-reasons-why-may-is-ideal-for-a-paris-getaway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/paris-in-the-spring-5-reasons-why-may-is-ideal-for-a-paris-getaway/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>How much does it cost to travel in Spain for 7 days?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/V3j5S35zR7E/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-much-does-it-cost-to-travel-in-spain-for-7-days/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 16:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Budget Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain travel cost]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=2879</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just recently finished a 3-month eurotrip and went to Spain for a week as my first stop. I went to Valencia for 3 days, Albacete for 2 days and Madrid for 3 days. How much does it cost to travel in Spain for a week? See all Europe Travel Cost Reports per city and [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Picture-3.png" width="240" />
		</p><p style="text-align: center;"><img title="Buget Spain 7 days" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Picture-3.png" alt="" width="604" height="373" /></p>
<p>I just recently finished a <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-plan-a-euro-trip-itinerary-strategy/" target="_blank">3-month eurotrip</a> and went to Spain for a week as my first stop. I went to <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/spain/valencia/" target="_blank">Valencia</a> for 3 days, <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/spain/albacete/" target="_blank">Albacete</a> for 2 days and <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/spain/madrid/" target="_blank">Madrid</a> for 3 days. How much does it cost to travel in Spain for a week?</p>
<p><a href="http://dreameurotrip.com/category/budget-report/">See all Europe Travel Cost Reports per city and country</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2881" title="Budget Spain 1 week" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Picture-4.png" alt="" width="582" height="319" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How much does it cost to travel in Spain for 7 days? Mine came down to 163.70 euros or 23.38 euros per day. The detailed explanation follows:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Spain Food Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How much does it cost to eat out in Spain? Around 10 euros. Good deals can be had at lunch if you eat the menu del dia or menu of the day. It can be higher if you eat more stuff. There are other cheaper options like buying ready-to-eat food in the supermarket or in the mercado or buying stuff and preparing your own food. For me, I spent 64.6 euros for food in my one-week trip in Spain. It’s not that expensive because I ate out and prepared my own food as well. There are so many <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/alt-spain-gypset-guide-spain-most-underrated-food-and-drinks/" target="_blank">amazing and delicious tapas and drinks in Spain</a>.</p>
<p>You can also try going to the mercato (or the local market) to buy your jamon and cheeses!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Spain Transportation Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Transportation in between cities by train in Spain can be quite expensive. Sometimes, it’s even cheaper to travel by plane. Other alternative way is to do <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/ridesharing-in-spain-the-blablacar-experience-infographic/" target="_blank">carpooling in Spain</a>. I’ve tried this on my trip to Valencia from Madrid and I’ve saved a lot of money. You can also check out the buses because they are usually cheaper than the train. But if you are pressed for time then choose between flying or taking the train.</p>
<p>As for city transport cost, you’re looking at 1 euro for a ride in the train. You can save a bit by buying the daily pass or 3-day pass tickets. If you’re in the center anyway, walk. It’s good for your health and your pocket.</p>
<p>I spent around 61.6 euros for my bus tickets and carpooling in between the cities and also for my city transport. It’s also important to note that I walked a lot that’s why I also didn’t spend more for transportation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Spain Accommodation Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Accommodation in Spain would cost you around 20-50 euros if you’re staying in backpacker hostels. If hotels is your thing then be ready to pay more. I was visiting friends during my entire trip so I didn’t really spend anything for accommodation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Spain Party Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It’s not that expensive to go out in Spain. A glass of beer with tapas would cost you between 1.5 &#8211; 2.5 euros. Spanish people also love to have a botellon which is basically a group of people drinking outside in public, usually in parks. It’s cheap because you get to buy your drinks from the supermarket or beer store. People then head out to the bars and club around 2am or so.</p>
<p>Parties usually start late in Spain. I recommend you to go out around 1am or 2am. In some places that’s even early! I spent 31.50 for going out and drinking when I was in Spain. It’s mostly hanging out in bars and parks with my friends. No crazy partying for me in this trip.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Spain Miscellaneous Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For me this includes the cost of using my phone to contact my friends which cost me around 6 euros. This can also include your travel insurance and shopping. You can compare prices of travel insurance at <a href=" http://www.insurancetown.com/" target="_blank">insurance town</a>. Shopping cost, meanwhile, will vary person to person.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>See all the <a href="http://dreameurotrip.com/category/budget-report/">travel budget reports</a>.</p>
<p>Next up, budget expenses for a week in Norway!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Happy travels!</p>
<p>DJ</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/V3j5S35zR7E" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-much-does-it-cost-to-travel-in-spain-for-7-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-much-does-it-cost-to-travel-in-spain-for-7-days/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>This Old Town is Fake!</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/ttZMmwIp1Jc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/warsaw-old-town-fake/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe in Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warsaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stare miasto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warsaw old town]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=2828</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; One of the things I love about Europe is the beautiful twilights in autumn. The sun sets earlier than usual and the cities are cloaked in a nice hue, the buildings and shops all lighted in warm yellow. Twilights in Warsaw, Poland during the fall is no exception. It feels great to walk around [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/Warsaw-Old-Town.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p><img class="aligncenter" title="Zygmunt's Square" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_1639.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>One of the things I love about Europe is the beautiful twilights in autumn. The sun sets earlier than usual and the cities are cloaked in a nice hue, the buildings and shops all lighted in warm yellow.</p>
<p>Twilights in <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/poland/warsaw/" target="_blank">Warsaw, Poland</a> during the fall is no exception. It feels great to walk around the Old Town (Stare Miasto in Polish) with the crisp autumn chill on your face and then drinking some home-brewed beer in places like Browarnia. Or pig out on Polish pierogi and hearty zurek soup at Zapiekanka restaurant in the corner.</p>
<p>But I digress.</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">What&#8217;s so special about the Old Town of Warsaw?</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all fake! If you didn&#8217;t know, Warsaw was one of the most destroyed cities in Europe during World War II. The city was almost flat and bombed into nothingness. So the Old Town you&#8217;re looking at right now is just a post-war reconstruction&#8230;of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:POL_Krakowskie_Przedmieście_Street_in_War" target="_blank">painting of the original Old Town</a> by this Italian dude better known in this parts as Canaletto. Crazy no? But it&#8217;s true!</p>
<p>And look how beautiful it is!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2831" title="Castle Square" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_1654.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2836" title="Old Town Warsaw" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_3505.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2837" title="Stare Miasto Warszawa" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_3506.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2834" title="Stare Miasto Warsaw" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_1667.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2833" title="King Zygmunt" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_1664.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2835" title="people walking at the Old Town" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_1672.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2832" title="Zygmunt's Square" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_1661.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600" /></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/ttZMmwIp1Jc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/warsaw-old-town-fake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/warsaw-old-town-fake/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 4 Most Popular Backpacker Destinations in Europe</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/rBRthG77rGc/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/top-4-most-popular-backpacker-destinations-europe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 02:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=2749</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Europe has an undeniable reputation for being a backpacker’s paradise. Whether you are looking to immerse yourself in the culture of the region, gaze upon historical artefacts or embark on the party of a lifetime, you’ll find it all in the cities and countries of Europe. For some great inspiration, when planning your next backpacking adventure, be sure [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Euro-Trip.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p>Europe has an undeniable reputation for being a backpacker’s paradise. Whether you are looking to immerse yourself in the culture of the region, gaze upon historical artefacts or embark on the party of a lifetime, you’ll find it all in the cities and countries of Europe. For some great inspiration, when planning your next backpacking adventure, be sure to check out these four top European destinations.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Berlin, Germany</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2751" title="Berlin Dom" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Berlin-Dom.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>One of my favorite cities in Europe. It has everything you&#8217;ll ever need: rich history, vibrant culture, amazing parties, local and international cuisine, and interesting residents. If you really want to visit a city that just won&#8217;t tell you when to sleep, head to Berlin. The city is big, beautifully scruffy and unbelievably cheap. It is super hyped up but for good reasons. So go and have your own adventures in one of the coolest cities in Europe.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Rome, Italy</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2754" title="Rome" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Rome.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For backpackers who are looking to immerse themselves into the rich culture and history of Europe, Rome will be your chosen destination. A day tour to the Colosseum will see you embarking on a journey of discovery, as you gaze down into the chambers where ancient warriors prepared for battle. St Peter’s Basilica is another major point of interest for many travellers, with the unique architecture of this Roman Catholic Church enabling you to take a step back in time to the early 1500s.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Amsterdam, Netherlands</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2750" title="Amsterdam Canal" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Amsterdam-Canal.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="455" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/essential-guide-amsterdam-budget/" target="_blank">Amsterdam</a> is the place to go when you want to party all day and all night – there is no rest for the wicked in this city. Famed around the world for being the destination where ‘anything goes’, backpackers will be thrown into a world of all things elicit and out of the ordinary. Party goers will find that Amsterdam is like heaven, with some of the world’s best DJs calling the clubs and bars home. If you are looking for a holiday to remember, <a href="http://www.flightcentre.com.au/flights/product/amsterdam" target="_blank">find flights to Amsterdam</a> and get the party started today!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Paris, France</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2753" title="Paris Montmarte" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Paris-Montmarte.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>While it may be a little more on the pricey side for some backpackers, Paris is the epicentre for culture in Europe. From a day at the Louvre to discovering the Arc de Triomphe and everything in between, your money is well spent in this captivating city. Photo opportunities are endless with the Eiffel Tower being visible from most areas of the city, whilst dining on delectable pastries is sure to be a treat from the regular backpacking food.</p>
<p>It’s easy to see that Europe truly is one of the best places for backpackers to visit. Whether you are travelling on a shoestring budget or have a little extra cash to spend, there is an abundance of free sightseeing options available, that will truly take your breath away.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/rBRthG77rGc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/top-4-most-popular-backpacker-destinations-europe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/top-4-most-popular-backpacker-destinations-europe/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>How much does it cost to travel in Madrid, Spain for 3 days?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/qGUn_FEUJC8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-much-does-it-cost-to-travel-in-madrid-spain-for-3-days/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 22:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Budget Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Madrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madrid travel cost]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=2730</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Here is my travel expenses breakdown for my 3-day trip in Madrid, Spain in my 3-month summer eurotrip adventure. I hope the information helps in budgetting your trip to Madrid! I also keep a record of my actual travel costs in various European cities. Click the link below to see all the other reports. [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Picture-3.png" width="240" />
		</p><p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2731" title="Madrid Travel Cost" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Picture-3.png" alt="" width="600" height="374.3" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Here is my travel expenses breakdown for my <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/category/spain/madrid/" target="_blank">3-day trip in Madrid</a>, Spain in my <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-plan-a-euro-trip-itinerary-strategy/" target="_blank">3-month summer eurotrip adventure</a>. I hope the information helps in budgetting your trip to Madrid! I also keep a record of my actual travel costs in various European cities. Click the link below to see all the other reports.</p>
<p><a href="http://dreameurotrip.com/category/budget-report/" target="_blank">See All Europe Travel Cost Reports</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" title="Madrid Travel Cost Breakdown" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Picture-6.png" alt="" width="584" height="321" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How much does it cost to travel in Madrid for 3 days? Mine came down to 65.85 euros or 21.95 euros per day. The detailed explanation follows:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Madrid Food Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Most of my cost of food in Madrid was spent in the supermarket where I bought most of the stuff I ate in Madrid. I was visiting my Brazilian friend, Fabio, who is based in Madrid so he prepared dinner for me and I&#8217;ve also prepared dinner for him. My travel partner, Michael, came to Madrid to meet me before we headed to Norway. Sharing the cost of food definitely lowered down this part of my travel expenses. Eating out in Madrid would cost you around 10 euros. Menu del dia (menu of the day) is a cheaper, popular option at lunch in restaurants and would save you significant amount of money.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Madrid Transportation Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This cost includes the cost of going from Madrid Barajas Airport to the center of Madrid (4.50 euros), bus tickets from Albacete to Madrid (17.85 euros) and all the single metro tickets I used in the city which cost 1.50 euros each. I walked alot in Madrid so I didn&#8217;t spend much on transportation cost in the city.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Madrid Accommodation Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I was visiting my friend Fabio who hosted us in Madrid so I didn&#8217;t really spend anything for accommodation. But I don&#8217;t have friends in Madrid, you say. You can <a href="http://www.trivago.com/madrid-32027/hotel" target="_blank">compare prices and find cheap hotels in Madrid</a> instead. There are many accommodation options to choose from. You can budget between 20-100 euros per day for your accommodation cost depending on where you stay.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Madrid Party Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/watching-spain-versus-france-euro-cup-2012/" target="_blank">watched Spain versus France in Marca sports bar</a> in the city center and paid 5 euros for the entrance. The cost also includes our beers and our expenses when we were out having botellon (Spanish culture wherein people drink outside in groups) in the park which was actually forbidden or something. Fabio was saying that we should hide our beer every time we see police coming. It was funny because it was so obvious that 90% of the people in the park where drinking and all the cans and bottles disappear once a policeman was in sight. Haha. Fun times!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Madrid Miscellaneous Cost</span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is mostly the prepaid cost of my cellphone which I used to communicate with Michael and Fabio. I didn&#8217;t spend money when we went to the amazing Musel del Prado because students are free (although I&#8217;m not a student anymore haha but it worked when I showed my student ID).</p>
<p><a href="http://dreameurotrip.com/category/budget-report/" target="_blank">See All Europe Travel Cost Reports</a></p>
<p>&#8212;-</p>
<p>Next budgeting post will be my total travel expenses from my one-week trip in Spain. Watch out for that!</p>
<p>Want to know how much your backpacking trip in Europe would cost? Use the free online EuroTrip calculator found at the sidebar.</p>
<p>Have questions? Feel free to post a comment or email me.</p>
<p>Happy travels!</p>
<p>DJ</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/qGUn_FEUJC8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-much-does-it-cost-to-travel-in-madrid-spain-for-3-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-much-does-it-cost-to-travel-in-madrid-spain-for-3-days/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Apply for a Tourist Schengen Visa at the Dutch Embassy and get it in 2 weeks</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/3Z9XmRDWriQ/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-apply-for-a-tourist-schengen-visa-at-the-dutch-embassy-and-get-it-in-2-weeks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 11:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[EuroTrip Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planning a Euro Trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schengen Visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch embassy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schengen visa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schengen visa fee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schengen visa requirements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=2676</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are many ways to get a Schengen visa and there are definitely different offices where you can apply for one. I have previously written how to apply for a tourist Schengen visa at the German Embassy and French Embassy. To continue this Visa Series, I interviewed one of my good friends, Angel, who is [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Andres-282.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p>There are many ways to get a Schengen visa and there are definitely different offices where you can apply for one. I have previously written how to apply for a <a href="http://dreameurotrip.com/how-to-apply-for-a-schengen-visa-7-days/" target="_blank">tourist Schengen visa at the German Embassy</a> and <a href="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-apply-schengen-visa-french-embassy-get-in-5-days/" target="_blank">French Embassy</a>.</p>
<p>To continue this Visa Series, I interviewed one of my good friends, Angel, who is now based in the Netherlands to help us out on the intricacies of applying for a tourist Schengen visa at the Dutch Embassy in Manila for Philippine passport holders. If you&#8217;re not a Filipino, no worries, the process is pretty much almost the same wherever you apply so read on.</p>
<p>NOTE: This article will focus only on tourist Schengen visa application. If you&#8217;re going to the Netherlands to study or marry, you need to prepare a set of other documents. Please check the <a href="http://philippines.nlembassy.org/services/consular-services/visa" target="_blank">Dutch embassy website</a> for more info.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2693" title="schengen visa netherlands" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/schengen-visa-netherlands.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="401.5" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">When can I apply for a Schengen visa at the Dutch embassy?</span>
<p>You can apply as early as 3 months before your planned entry.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">How do I apply for a Schengen visa in the Dutch Embassy?</span>
<p>You need to make an appointment through a call centre before applying for a visa at the Embassy in Manila. An appointment can be arranged not earlier than 3 months before your planned date of departure. Make sure to allot some time for gathering and preparing the required documents, this requires some planning in advance.</p>
<p>Phone numbers:</p>
<p>For PFF or PLDT/digitel/smart subscribers 1-909-101-3456</p>
<p>For Globe/Innove/Touchmobile subcribers 1-900-101-3456</p>
<p>For Bayantel subscribers 1-903-101-3456</p>
<p>You can contact the call centre between 8:00 am to 6:00 pm from Monday thru Saturday. See the <a href="http://philippines.nlembassy.org/services/consular-services/visa" target="_blank">Dutch Embassy website</a> for all important information.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">What are the requirements for a Schengen visa?</span>
<div>
<p>Basically:</p>
<ul>
<li>documents showing your ability to pay your travel and accommodation expenses;</li>
<li>hotel reservations, an invitation from private individuals or business connections, a legalised letter of invitation, or a guarantor’s declaration; (more details below)</li>
<li>documents showing that you intend to return to your country of origin (such as an employer’s declaration or the deeds to your home);</li>
<li>a medical travel insurance policy that will cover any costs of repatriation on medical grounds, urgent medical care, or emergency hospital treatment. The insurance policy must be valid for the entire Schengen Area and the entire duration of your stay, and it must provide minimum cover of €30,000. If you cannot make an advance arrangement with your insurance provider that the costs will be repaid if the visa is refused, you will not have to produce this insurance policy until you collect your visa.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In detail:</p>
<ul>
<li>Schengen visa application form, downloadable online at the <a href="http://www.minbuza.nl/binaries/content/assets/postenweb/j/jemen/embassy-of-the-kingdom-of-the-netherlands/import/products_and_services/consular_services/visa/visumcode-visumaanvraagformulieren" target="_blank">Dutch Embassy website</a></li>
<li>Valid Passport</li>
<li>All previous passports</li>
<li>Two recent passport-size (3.5 by 4.5 cm) photograph, against light background (e.g. White)</li>
<li>A flight-reservation upon submission of your application. Do not purchase your ticket before your visa application has been approved!</li>
<li>Medical travel insurance (details above), you can get it at any travel agency or online</li>
<li><strong>Supporting Documents</strong></li>
<ul>
<li><strong>For Employees</strong>: Proof of employment: a recent employer’s statement that should mention salary, date of entry and duration of absence,</li>
<li><strong>For private businessmen</strong>:a photocopy of SEC or DTI business registration of your company, Mayor’s business permit + tax-paying certificate &#8220;ITR&#8221; and a photo copy of bank statements of the last three months.</li>
<li><strong>For students:</strong> registration from a school or university and if travelling during study period, certificate from school or university with permission of absence.</li>
<li><strong>For minors travelling without both parents:</strong> DSWD Travel Clearance.</li>
<li><strong>For unemployed or retired citizens</strong>:, a photo copy of bank statements of the last three months.</li>
<li>If travelling as a tourist:</li>
<ul>
<li>Proof of hotel reservations</li>
<li>Confirmed hotel reservation for the whole travel period, including all other countries that you are going to visit, to be faxed by the hotel directly to the embassy (fax no +63 2 7866644).</li>
<li>*Income of applicant: As available means an applicant should have €34,&#8211; per day to spent when he or she will provide own expenses for the trip</li>
</ul>
</ul>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>If travelling to visit family/friends in the Netherlands:</strong></li>
<ul>
<li>An invitation letter, in Dutch language, from the referent (host/sponsor) in the Netherlands, mentioning the duration and period of your intended stay.</li>
<li>An original legalised guarantee statement from the referent/host in the Netherlands (obtainable from the Town Hall of the place where the referent resides). Please make sure the name of the invitee is mentioned in the letter.</li>
<li><strong>For the referent/host:</strong></li>
<ul>
<li><em>For employees</em><strong>:</strong> proof of employment,salary slips of the last three months**, which indicate date of entry, a contract of employment.</li>
<li><em>For private businessmen</em>: a extract of the company from the Chamber of Commerce, bank statements of private bank and your company’s account of the last three months.</li>
<li>A photo copy of the (Dutch) passport or residence permit for the Netherlands of the host</li>
</ul>
</ul>
</ul>
</ul>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">How much is the Schengen visa processing fee?</span>
<div>
<p>60 Euros converted to Philippine Pesos, depends on the current exchange rate. Bring the exact amount.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">What should I wear to the interview?</span>
<p>Be yourself but the best, “most respectable” version of you. Perhaps think of the visa interview as a job interview, but skip the stiff tie and the formal blazer! Wear something that makes you feel confident about yourself. You should be relaxed on that day. Usually, wearing something that you particularly like (your favorite dress or your lucky shirt) makes you feel more confident. <img src='http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">How is the interview like?</span>
<div>
<p>First, the security guard will ask for your details and lead you to the waiting room (which is super cold, so bring a jacket!) Be prepared to wait long, one time I waited for more than 2 hours for my turn. I recommend bringing a book or some magazines (you&#8217;re not allowed to use your phone in the waiting room). During the interview, be prepared to answer questions regarding your application. They usually double check if the answers you gave on the form/supporting documents are true (for example, how much your salary is, where will you be staying in Holland, how did you meet your host, where you work, etc.) Know your facts!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Are the interviewers really scary?</span>
<div>
<p>Depends on the person who is interviewing you. Some of them can be a bit intimidating, but it&#8217;s all just part of their jobs. As long as you have your facts straight, and you&#8217;re not planning on not coming back, then you have nothing to be afraid of. Breathe in, smile and answer their questions as best as you can!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">How long does it take for the Schengen visa to be released?</span>
<p>15 calendar days but some exceptional cases may take up to 30 or 60 days. You will receive a letter anyway to inform you about this.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">My Schengen visa application is denied. What can I do next?</span>
<p>“If the visa-granting authority refuses your application, it will send you a copy of the decision explaining why. You may object to this decision in writing (not email) within four weeks of its issue (details of where to send your objection are enclosed with the decision). You may also authorise a person to object to the decision on your behalf or to represent you in any hearing. This person must have written authorisation (in Dutch, French, German or English) to do so, signed by you.</p>
<p>The visa-granting authority will then decide on your objection. If it decides in your favour, it will authorise the mission to issue you with a visa. If it decides against you, it will send you a copy of its decision, explaining why your objection has been denied. The objection procedure usually takes some months.”</p>
<p>For more info, check the <a href="http://philippines.nlembassy.org/services/consular-services/visa/visas-for-the-netherlands-schengen-visas/visas-for-the-netherlands-schengen-visas/minbuza%3Ashare/applying-for-a-schengen-visa.html" target="_blank">Dutch Embassy website</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">About Angel</span>
<p>Angel has traveled and lived in several European countries. She has completed her MA in Euroculture while living in Germany, Spain and Sweden. Now she is working and living in the Netherlands as editor for Arts Holland in Amsterdam, an organization which promotes Dutch arts and culture abroad. She also DJs regularly and curates “Ice Hotel” &#8211; a music night dedicated to Scandinavian pop music. You can follow her blog at <a href="http://www.angeltrinidad.me/">www.angeltrinidad.me</a></div>
</div>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/3Z9XmRDWriQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-apply-for-a-tourist-schengen-visa-at-the-dutch-embassy-and-get-it-in-2-weeks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-apply-for-a-tourist-schengen-visa-at-the-dutch-embassy-and-get-it-in-2-weeks/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Eat Europe: A Food Pilgrimage</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~3/17r_x0flhw8/</link>
		<comments>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-eat-europe-a-food-pilgrimage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 08:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DJ Yabis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[England]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interesting People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[euro trip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.dreameurotrip.com/?p=2632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I consider myself a gourmand and I oftentimes travel to certain European destinations to pig out on their culinary offerings. This week I interviewed one of the food and travel bloggers I have been following and admire, Sage of Food Pilgrimage. Learn what food pilgrimage is, how to discover Europe through food and different food [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 15px; width:240px;">
		<img src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMG_8376.jpg" width="240" />
		</p><p>I consider myself a gourmand and I oftentimes travel to certain European destinations to pig out on their culinary offerings. This week I interviewed one of the food and travel bloggers I have been following and admire, Sage of <a href="http://foodpilgrimage.com/" target="_blank">Food Pilgrimage</a>.</p>
<p>Learn what food pilgrimage is, how to discover Europe through food and different food stories on the road from Scotland all the way to Bordeaux.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">Meet Sage Russel, food and travel writer</span>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2638" title="Sage" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Sage.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sage Russell is a food and travel writer, Cookery instructor and private chef. In 2010, he left his job as an architect to set sail on a quest to travel the world to learn everything he could about ingredients, techniques and traditions from the great food cultures of the world. He talked his way into restaurant kitchens, hung out with home cooks, and convinced chef’s and street-food vendors to show him their secrets. Follow his food-seeking travel adventures, and you’ll be inspired to eat better, cook more, and live a better life through travel, food, and feeding friends with fabulous feasts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">1. You said that &#8220;I love making food my destination&#8221;. How does your intimate relationship with food shape your travels in Europe?</span>
<div>From my very first trip to Europe, I realized how much more fun people were having with food: The markets of fresh food where real people did real shopping, the 2-hour lunches, the cafe culture, and of course the epic family meals. Now when I travel around Europe, I start my adventure by simply asking a local &#8220;What&#8217;s the quinticential food of the area?&#8221; and then follow up with &#8220;where can I find the best version?&#8221;. The Food Pilgrimage adventure takes off from there.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">2. Have you been a foodie for a long time? If not, how did you end up being one?</span>
<div></div>
<div>I was raised in the kitchen, doing my homework at a big kitchen island, where I was either helping cook, watching cooking, or eating. But it was really my ex-wife Christy (who happens to hail from Spain) that altered my passion for food travel. We were standing in line at yet another &#8220;must see&#8221; tourist site in Italy, and she pointed out how much nicer it would be to simply Gelato hop for the rest of the afternoon. We skipped the tourist bit, spent the day in cafes and gelataria and I&#8217;ve never looked back. Food is now the reason I travel and the end-game of all of my adventures.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2636" title="Sage Russel Food Pilgrimage" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Sage-Russel-Food-Pilgrimage.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 24px; color: #FDEC4E;">3. Explain your idea of a food pilgrimage and how to create a personalized one?</span>
<div></div>
<div>A Food Pilgrimage is simply a travel adventure &#8211; near or far -  where food is the focus. Like any good pilgrimage, it is simply making a fuss of the destination that makes the whole experience special, whether it&#8217;s finally making it to a world-class restaurant or street market, visiting a vineyard or farm, or simply setting out to find the freshest ingredients for a pizza party or catch up with a local food truck. The magic is in the intention. The concept for me was born of wanting to visit the olive farm in Italy where I had adopted an olive tree. Anyone can set out on a food pilgrimage simply by picking a food or meal to track down.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">4. If you are to take us on a food pilgrimage in Europe, where would you take us and what would we be eating?</span>
<div>The sky is the limit. Europe is so diverse, with such an storied food history.The passion that comes from every food culture is staggering.  My recent obsessions would have us hop to the Veneto for Prosecco and fresh Lagoon seafood then to Bordeaux for a good terrine and a bottle of Margaux and finally to Scotland for Shetland Mussels and a pint of Belhaven.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">5. Can you please share us your favorite restaurants or hole-in-the-wall places where we can have some of the best food that you have enjoyed immensely in your European travels?</span>
<div>Where to start and what to divulge? They&#8217;d almost all be street food: Vietnamese at Tre Viet and Caribbean at Granny&#8217;s in Hackney, London, The random crepe window or the falafal joint on Rue Mouffetard in the Latin Quarter of Paris, Robbie&#8217;s restaurant in Estepona, Spain, La Cantina in Venice to name but a recent few.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">6. How do you get in contact with people whose lives revolve around food? Do you even contact them in advance or it&#8217;s more a spontaneous thing wherein you meet them in restaurants or farms as you travel?</span>
<div>I&#8217;ve learned to rely on two very powerful forces: Firstly, putting out the call, telling my fwllow foodies where I&#8217;m going, and asking what to explore. Second is simply asking once I&#8217;m on the ground &#8220;What is the best, and where can I find it?&#8221;</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">7. Personally, I sometimes find it difficult to find good food when I&#8217;m traveling. Do you have any system or secret technique on how to find good food in a new city?</span>
<div></div>
<div>Walk into the nearest cafe and ask the barista, where they would go to lunch if you were going to treat them.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2637" title="Sage Russel" src="http://www.dreameurotrip.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Sage-Russel.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">8. You have been based in London for awhile now, why did you choose London?</span>
<p>London is positively the most cosmopolitan food city in the world. I landed here Primarily because of a girl, but in the end, because it is simply the center of the world, an epic melange of cultures and cuisines and is less than three hours away from anywhere in Europe, not to mention Africa.</p>
<div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<span class="shortcode-typography" style="font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 20px; color: #FDEC4E;">9. What are you future plans with the food pilgrimage website?</span>
<p>Besides hosting my short food-centirc stories and articles about my Food Pilgrimage adventures, it is now the contact point for my cookery classes, private chef bookings and food tours.</p>
<div></div>
</div>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/DreamEuroTrip/~4/17r_x0flhw8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-eat-europe-a-food-pilgrimage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.dreameurotrip.com/how-to-eat-europe-a-food-pilgrimage/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss><!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: www.dreameurotrip.com @ 2013-04-01 19:11:52 by W3 Total Cache -->
