<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">South Africa Blog</title>
	<subtitle type="text">south africa travel news and reviews, festivals and events</subtitle>

	<updated>2013-04-17T11:28:04Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" />
	<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.5.1">WordPress</generator>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[“Is this the way to Amarillo?” singer, Tony Christie to perform in South Africa]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/17/is-this-the-way-to-amarillo-singer-tony-christie-to-perform-in-south-africa/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=968</id>
		<updated>2013-04-17T11:28:04Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-17T11:27:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[British singer, songwriter and actor, Tony Christie is visiting South Africa next month to perform two concerts only at Grand Arena, GrandWest, Cape Town on Wednesday, 15th May 2013 and Carnival City’s Big Top Arena, Johannesburg on Saturday, 18th May 2013, both concerts commence at 20h00. To celebrate Mother’s Day which takes place on 12th May [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/17/is-this-the-way-to-amarillo-singer-tony-christie-to-perform-in-south-africa/"><![CDATA[<p>British singer, songwriter and actor, Tony Christie is visiting South Africa next month to perform two concerts only at Grand Arena, GrandWest, Cape Town on Wednesday, 15th May 2013 and Carnival City’s Big Top Arena, Johannesburg on Saturday, 18th May 2013, both concerts commence at 20h00. To celebrate Mother’s Day which takes place on 12<sup>th</sup> May 2013, why not treat mums, grannie’s, nana’s and those special ladies in your life to a trip down memory lane with a gift of  tickets to see the legendary crooner, Tony Christie performing live in South Africa.</p>
<p>Tony Christie has sold more than 10 million albums worldwide and many of his chart-topping hits are widely recognised. With hit numbers &#8220;Is this the way to Amarillo&#8221;, &#8220;I did what I did for Maria&#8221; as well as &#8220;Avenues and Alleyways” and &#8220;Drive safely darling” featured in the film &#8220;Love, Honour and Obey”, Tony Christie has made a significant contribution to popular music across several decades.</p>
<p>&#8220;Is This the Way to Amarillo&#8221; was released at the beginning of the ‘70’s and sold more than one million copies by September 1972.  The hit was so popular, it went on to sell in excess of 4 million records and in 2005, reached Number 1 on the UK Singles Chart (outselling the first release&#8217;s entire chart run). This led to the biggest sales for a Number 1 single for the whole year, with seven weeks at the top of the charts. It also became the longest running chart-topper since Cher&#8217;s &#8220;Believe&#8221;, almost seven year earlier.</p>
<p>Written by Neil Sedaka and Howard Greenfield “Is This The Way To Amarillo&#8221; also enjoyed enormous success in South Africa in the ‘70’s and become a firm favourite with listeners of the now defunct Springbok Radio. The hit’s popularity steadily grew to become a worldwide hit.</p>
<p>Tony Christie’s long and illustrious musical career includes playing the role of Magaldi on the original 1976 album recording of the musical Evita and he represented the UK in the 1976 Eurovision Song Contest where he came third.  Most recently, Christie returned to the theatre where he appeared in a pantomime at The Theatre Royal, Windsor as the King.</p>
<p>Through most of the 1980s and 1990s, he maintained a successful singing career in continental Europe. This was especially so in Germany, with four albums recorded with German producer Jack White, then from 1991 to 2002, Christie recorded nine albums especially for the German market.</p>
<p>In 1999, Tony Christie was the vocalist on the Jarvis Cocker-penned UK Top Ten hit, &#8220;Walk Like a Panther&#8221;, recorded by the Sheffield band, All Seeing I. His influence on a new generation of singers was further demonstrated when indie pop band Rinaldi Sings released a cover version of &#8220;Avenues &amp;Alleyways&#8221; in March 2004.</p>
<p>In 2002, &#8220;Is This the Way to Amarillo&#8221; was used in the TV comedy series Peter Kay&#8217;s Phoenix Nights, leading to resurgence in his popularity. The song was re-released on 14 March 2005 to raise money for the Comic Relief charity, and reached Number 1 in the UK Singles Chart. This number brought a new audience and brought him cult status amongst the younger generation.</p>
<p>In July 2010, Christie made his West End début in the musical Dreamboats and Petticoats in London&#8217;s Playhouse Theatre, and later that year, Christie appeared in a celebrity version of Come Dine with Me where he was placed joint second.  The following year, Christie&#8217;s nineteenth studio album, Now&#8217;s the Time!, was released in the UK. To coincide with 50 years in the music industry, Christie embarked on a 50-date UK tour promoting the new album.</p>
<p>Two years ago, Christie released a charity single, a special arrangement of “Steal The Sun&#8221; in aid of the Help for Heroes Charity, supporting the British Forces fighting on the frontline in Afghanistan. The single was available on line with all proceeds going to the charity. Aside from singing, Christie is a talented actor who has made a guest appearance on the Yorkshire, UK based TV soap opera, Emmerdale.</p>
<p>Following the decades of success with “Amarillo”, Christie was awarded the freedom of Amarillo, Texas.</p>
<p>Tony Christie continues to tour and brings his memorable show to South Africa for the first time in May 2013. Don’t miss this legendary artist.</p>
<p>For the over 55’s there’s a special discounted <b>Golden Package </b>offer of a 15% discount on all ticket bookings subject to presentation of a valid identity document. Golden Package bookings are only available at Computicket service centres.</p>
<p><strong>Venue: Grand Arena, GrandWest</strong><br />
Date: Wednesday, 15 May 2013 only<br />
Time: 20h00<br />
Cost: R255.00, R 275.00, R295.00, R 325.00<br />
Tickets: Computicket</p>
<p><strong>Venue: Carnival City, Big Top Arena</strong><br />
Date: Saturday, 18 May 2013 only<br />
Time: 20h00<br />
Costs: R 250.00, R 300.00, R 350.00<br />
Tickets: Computicket</p>
<p>You can find and book accommodation for the Cape Town performance at <a title="Cape Accommodation Venues" href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/" target="_blank">http://www.cape-venues.co.za/</a> and for a place to stay in Jo-burg see <a href="http://www.johannesburg-venues.co.za/" target="_blank">http://www.johannesburg-venues.co.za/</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/17/is-this-the-way-to-amarillo-singer-tony-christie-to-perform-in-south-africa/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/17/is-this-the-way-to-amarillo-singer-tony-christie-to-perform-in-south-africa/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Stellenbosch Fresh Goods Market]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/stellenbosch-fresh-goods-market/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=962</id>
		<updated>2013-04-07T14:26:03Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-07T14:25:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="cape winelands" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="markets" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="stellenbosch" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It seems that Cape Town’s favourite destination on a Saturday morning these days, is to Stellenbosch to visit the Fresh Goods Market, situated at Oude Libertas. This amphitheatre style, outdoor and indoor market comprises of an energetic frenzy of food, beverage and craft sellers pedaling their wares and feeding hordes of hungry market goers, every [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/stellenbosch-fresh-goods-market/"><![CDATA[<p>It seems that Cape Town’s favourite destination on a Saturday morning these days, is to <a title="Stellenbosch accommodation" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/stellenbosch.php">Stellenbosch</a> to visit the Fresh Goods Market, situated at Oude Libertas. This amphitheatre style, outdoor and indoor market comprises of an energetic frenzy of food, beverage and craft sellers pedaling their wares and feeding hordes of hungry market goers, every Saturday between 9am-2pm.</p>
<p>The food is fresh, gourmet, trendy and delicious and one is easily swayed to partner brunch with a ‘real’ beer or even a margarita before the Boeing has even flown over! The ample space and rolling lawns on the outskirts of the market give it a feeling of space, allowing for relaxing with friends, while enjoying a smorgasbord of delicious offerings from the market. The ‘slow food’ philosophy at the market, as opposed to fast food, ensures that all the food on offer is independently and ethically produced.</p>
<p>Wafting slowly around the market, we were impressed with the incredibly diverse selection of gourmet food and goods, ranging from beautiful icing sugar dusted cherry pies and handmade chocolate through to artisan breads and cured meats. Some of our favourite goodies on offer included; breakfast wraps and steak sarmies from Jean Nel’s Flamed Weber stand; Arnim &amp; Elke’s German waffles with cream; mushroom skewers from Sheilagh’s Shrooms; Everson’s Cider; Darling beer; Forest Hill cheeses; Chrisna’s Organic Olives; Rushda’s Famous Curry Stand and the impressive gypsy tea caravan run by Lady Bonin!</p>
<p>Carefully procured goods from independent producers in the Cape Winelands means that food is not only fresh and healthy, but is preservative, anti-biotic and chemical free. According to the Stellenbosch Slow Food website, “<em>Slow Food is a non-profit, eco-gastronomic member-supported organization that was founded in 1989 to counteract fast food and fast life, the disappearance of local food traditions and people’s dwindling interest in the food they eat, where it comes from, how it tastes and how our food choices affect the rest of the world. To do that, Slow Food brings together pleasure and responsibility, and makes them inseparable</em>.”</p>
<p>We highly recommend heading out to the Stellenbosch Fresh Goods Market, by bicycle, car, bus or horse and carriage – just get there &#8211; you’ll leave with wonderful memories and basket loads of delicious, fresh goods. Or better still, why not make a weekend of it? Find a great place to stay at <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/cape-winelands.php">Accommodation in Cape Winelands</a> and spend the weekend exploring this wonderful region.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/stellenbosch-fresh-goods-market/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/stellenbosch-fresh-goods-market/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Secret to Hiking with Children]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/the-secret-to-hiking-with-children/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=959</id>
		<updated>2013-04-07T14:08:44Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-07T14:08:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="hiking" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="hiking trails" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="kids" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiking is a great way to spend quality time with your family. Beautiful surrounds combine with the sense of adventure to make for a perfect holiday or weekend activity. Still, taking children means that you need to tailor the experience a little to make sure that it is manageable and enjoyable for them too. You [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/the-secret-to-hiking-with-children/"><![CDATA[<p>Hiking is a great way to spend quality time with your family. Beautiful surrounds combine with the sense of adventure to make for a perfect holiday or weekend activity. Still, taking children means that you need to tailor the experience a little to make sure that it is manageable and enjoyable for them too. You can find extensive info about various <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/things-to-do/" target="_blank">things to do</a> and <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/activities/hiking.htm" target="_blank">hikes in South Africa</a> on a few web sites which we&#8217;ve listed below for your convenience.</p>
<p><strong>Here are some tips to accomplish this:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Create excitement by talking about the hike as an adventure with plenty to see and do before the time. It’s better not to let your children hear you stressing about blisters and being tired and thirsty, as they will begin to imitate you.</li>
<li>Before the time, go for walks of increasing distances through your neighbourhood with your kids, showing them the wonders of nature (a flower, a butterfly, what lives under a rock, etc&#8230;) so that they become used to looking for excitement around them instead of on the computer or television.</li>
<li>Establish a goal or reward for the end of the hike. For example, you could be hiking to the waterfall or to the picnic spot.</li>
<li>Make sure that children are equipped with comfy walking shoes, plenty of sunscreen, suitable clothing and a really light backpack. A child with blistered feet is a nightmare on a hike. Giving them headlamps and allowing them to walk with these in the evening and morning will be a huge hit (you may never get them to stop walking!)</li>
<li>Play games along the way. Make up competitions or activities (find the squarest stone or three different coloured berries, for example).</li>
<li>Take along PLENTY of snacks. Include things that they rarely get so that there’s something to look forward to.</li>
<li>Travel at a slower pace than normal so that the young ones can keep up without feeling pressured or left behind.</li>
<li>Maintain your routines as far as possible. Eat at times similar to those that you would at home and read them a bedtime story before closing their tent, if this is what you’d do at home.</li>
<li>Let your child(ren) invite a friend along so that they can keep one another entertained along the way.</li>
<li>Get their input when planning the hike to find out what sort of things they want to see and do along the way. This will make them appreciate the experience far more.</li>
<li>Allow your children to do the things they want to do on the hike. If you come across a river and they beg to get in, stop for 5 minutes and let them. If they ask about bark, stop and look at it, feel it, smell it. Don’t rush them along.</li>
<li>Be prepared to stop the hike if your children are not managing.</li>
<li>Allow older kids to bring along their iPods or phones so that they don’t equate hiking with complete isolation and boredom.</li>
<li>Give the children each a whistle and strict instructions about what to do if they are hurt or lost. Teach them that the whistle is not a toy.</li>
<li>Carry a fully-stocked first aid kit with you at all times.</li>
<li>Give the child(ren) responsibilities like spotting the direction arrows, picking up any litter or watching the time to see if you’re on track.</li>
</ul>
<p>Generally, children of five years and older are able to enjoy a hike. Start them early, but keep the first hikes short and manageable, so that they are able to associate hiking with fun and pleasure.</p>
<p><strong>Some good Hiking Sites:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sahikes.co.za/" target="_blank">http://www.sahikes.co.za/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.southafrica.info/travel/adventure/hiking.htm#.UWF9SFeC_gM" target="_blank">http://www.southafrica.info/travel/adventure/hiking.htm</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/activities/hiking.htm" target="_blank">http://www.sa-venues.com/activities/hiking.htm</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.footprint.co.za/" target="_blank">http://www.footprint.co.za/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Happy Hiking!</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/the-secret-to-hiking-with-children/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/04/07/the-secret-to-hiking-with-children/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Agulhas is known for many things &#8230;]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/03/28/cape-agulhas-is-known-for-many-things/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=954</id>
		<updated>2013-03-28T10:39:50Z</updated>
		<published>2013-03-28T10:39:01Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Attractions" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="agulhas" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="arniston" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="cape agulhas" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Agulhas is known for many things, not least of all the geographical extremes that it presents. It represents the southernmost tip of Africa, as well as the point at which the cool Atlantic Ocean and warmer Indian Ocean meet. Due to its location on the continent, Cape Agulhas was frequently the first piece of [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/03/28/cape-agulhas-is-known-for-many-things/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/cape-agulhas.htm"><strong>Cape Agulhas</strong></a> is known for many things, not least of all the geographical extremes that it presents. It represents the southernmost tip of Africa, as well as the point at which the cool Atlantic Ocean and warmer Indian Ocean meet. Due to its location on the continent, Cape Agulhas was frequently the first piece of land encountered by the seamen of centuries ago.</p>
<p>It has been noted as one of the most dangerous capes along the traditional clipper route (between Europe and the East or Australia). As such, there have been a number of shipwrecks on this coast over the centuries. This resulted in the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/things-to-do/westerncape/visit-africas-only-lighthouse-museum/">Cape Aghulhas Lighthouse</a> being built in 1848, which is now home to a restaurant and museum. This museum showcases a number of fascinating relics, not least of which are stone traps that were once used by the Khoisan people.</p>
<p>The Agulhas Municipality has several towns under its jurisdiction. These are <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/arniston.php">Arniston</a> (or Waenshuiskrans), <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/bredasdorp.php">Bredasdorp</a>, <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/elim.php">Elim</a> (a Moravian mission station and UNESCO World Heritage Site), <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/lagulhas.php">L&#8217;Agulhas</a> (the southernmost town on the African continent), <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/napier.php">Napier</a>, <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/struisbaai.php">Struisbaai</a> (known for its gorgeous beaches), Suiderstrand (a holiday town with a rustic feel), Klipdale and Protem.</p>
<p>Cape Agulhas is known for its temperate, pleasant weather conditions. Summers are warm and winters are cool, with rainfall mainly during the winter months. This makes it ideal for year-round tourism.</p>
<p>Cape Agulhas is situated in the Overberg Region, 170 kilometres (or just over 100 miles) southeast of the city of <a title="Cape Town Accommodation" href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/">Cape Town</a> in the Western Cape. It is home to the Andrew’s Field Airport, which is Africa’s southernmost aerodrome.</p>
<p>This area has its place among the myths and legends of sailors all over the world. The Cape of Storms was a notorious myth, which saw numerous vessels being reduced to timber as they attempted to travel to the East for trading purposes. Some interesting remnants of these wrecks can be seen at the <b><i><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/things-to-do/westerncape/visit-the-bredasdorp-shipwreck-museum/">Bredasdorp Shipwreck Museum</a>.</i></b></p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/wc_agulhas.htm"><b><i>Agulhas National Park</i></b></a> was established in 1999 and covers a total area of just less than 21 000 hectares. This park has, as its focus, the conservation and sustainability of its breath-taking biodiversity and the unique culture of this area. It boasts some magnificent wildlife (including the Southern Right Whale and African Black Oyster Catcher), ensuring that it is a haven for nature-lovers. Bird-watching is particularly popular here.  This park also showcases some of the country’s most beautiful fynbos, which is not found naturally anywhere else in the world. The best time to see the fynbos is between May and September. There are a number of <b><i>trails through the national park</i></b>, which allow visitors to be a part of this splendour and enjoy it in a more personal way – smelling the fresh breeze and the aroma of the vegetation; touching flowers, leaves and bark; hearing the crunch of twigs underfoot.</p>
<p><b><i>Fishing</i></b> is especially popular in Cape Agulhas. The shallow waters off the Agulhas bank have been known to be the natural habitat of a number of species, including red steenbras, yellowtail, red stump, cob, santer, musselcracker and red roman. Deep-sea fishing and rock fishing are both popular pastimes and livelihoods in this area.</p>
<p><b><i>Napier Breweries</i></b> was established in 2007 by a group of friends that wanted to enjoy unique, interesting beers of a superior quality. They envisioned full-bodied ales that reflected their Overberg origin.  Only the best hand-selected ingredients are used and Napier Breweries supplies to a number of bottle stores, pubs and restaurants, as well as to tourist accommodation and dining establishments. Their range comprises Old Charlie Stout, Overberg Ale, and Blue Crane Lager.</p>
<p>The culture and history of Cape Agulhas is infused into almost every element of this destination, making it a very special experience. Although fairly remote, it continues to welcome many visitors who want to experience the marvels of its natural diversity every year.</p>
<p>For more info see Cape Agulhas attractions or book a place to stay at <em><strong><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/cape-agulhas.php">Cape Agulhas accommodation</a></strong></em>. The region provides great <em><strong><a title="Western Cape Accommodation" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/maps/western_cape_accommodation_map.htm">Western Cape accommodation</a></strong></em> options often with activities such as whale watching included in the deal.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/03/28/cape-agulhas-is-known-for-many-things/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/03/28/cape-agulhas-is-known-for-many-things/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Ideas for Families travelling Locally within South Africa]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/02/05/10-ideas-for-families-travelling-locally-within-south-africa/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=837</id>
		<updated>2013-02-05T16:24:15Z</updated>
		<published>2013-02-05T16:24:15Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Entertainment" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="family friendly" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not having the time, money or other resources required to travel long distances to enjoy a break does not mean that you have to relinquish your family vacation altogether. With a little research and creativity, you will likely find that there are plenty of things to do and see without even leaving your home town. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/02/05/10-ideas-for-families-travelling-locally-within-south-africa/"><![CDATA[<p>Not having the time, money or other resources required to travel long distances to enjoy a break does not mean that you have to relinquish your family vacation altogether. With a little research and creativity, you will likely find that there are plenty of things to do and see without even leaving your home town. This is important for families with children, as little ones can become bored quite quickly, needing activities and attention to enjoy their time away from school. This is also a great way to spend weekends at any time of year.</p>
<h3>Here are 10 popular things to do and places to visit locally:</h3>
<p>1. <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/national-botanical-gardens.htm">Botanical gardens</a> are usually open to the public and are not open for profit. They are quick, easy and cost-effective for the entire family to visit. They showcase natural beauty and are usually set up to accommodate even young children without posing too many dangers. Enquire about lectures and classes being conducted during the school holidays for those that find this type of place particularly interesting.</p>
<p>2. Find out about local organic farms and take the children on a pre-arranged tour of one (or more) of these to educate them about the origin of their fruit, vegetables, meat and dairy products. Young ones will love milking a dairy cow or watching sheep get shorn.</p>
<p>3. If you live close to a regular farmers’ market, visit it as a family. Let the children choose some produce for their week’s meals, involving them more in the process and allowing them to see where their food comes from.</p>
<p>4. Plan a treasure hunt in a grocery store to convert a weekly chore into a fun activity. Give them clues as to what to find and where, and ensure that there is a worthwhile treasure at the end of their quest. This will take plenty of forethought and preparation but will prove to be worth it. Clues can include logos or slogans on the item’s packaging, a certain barcode, or a colour combination, for example.</p>
<p>5. Watch a local sports match, even if it is just at a nearby high school. The vibe and excitement is a fabulous way to pass a few free hours.</p>
<p>6. Incite the child in you and plan a family day at the local games arcade. Instead of ambling around waiting for the kids to finish their games, play along with them. They will love the quality time and be able to enjoy themselves without worrying that you are in a rush to get home.</p>
<p>7. Enjoy a family picnic in a local park, sports field, beach or forest. Pack all sorts of delicious delights and remember to take along an activity (such as a bat and ball or a board game).</p>
<p>8. Find out about local art, craft or music festivals and visit these, even if it is not something you would ordinarily do. A change makes for a valuable break.</p>
<p>9. Find an isolated spot in which you can plant some indigenous trees. This may work best at a local animal shelter or children’s home that needs and approves of your initiative. Teach youngsters about the importance of this vegetation and watch their delight as, year after year, they monitor the growth of “their” trees. Permission will definitely be required.</p>
<p>10. Take classes (art, pottery, jewellery making or cooking are all popular choices). If any or all of you need a boost, join the gym or take fitness classes together.</p>
<p>You can find a huge selection of activities <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/things-to-do/">Things to Do in South Africa</a> on SA-Venues.com and to find a kid-friendly place to say, see <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/south-africa-family-friendly.htm">Family-friendly accommodation</a> where children of ALL ages are welcome or see the <strong>all</strong> <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation_south_africa.htm">South Africa Accommodation</a> listing pages for other establishments that accept children from 6, 12 or 16 years upwards.</p>
<p>Happy Travelling!</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/02/05/10-ideas-for-families-travelling-locally-within-south-africa/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/02/05/10-ideas-for-families-travelling-locally-within-south-africa/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Lighthouses of the Eastern Cape]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/11/lighthouses-of-the-eastern-cape/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=789</id>
		<updated>2013-01-11T20:32:48Z</updated>
		<published>2013-01-11T20:32:48Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Attractions" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Eastern Cape" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lighthouses were erected generations ago, when ships began arriving to the Eastern Cape coastline for a number of different reasons. Some brought supplies, others carried explorers and still others were delivering slaves. These lighthouses remain as beacons of our heritage and history while still serving as guides for incoming vessels. The Eastern Cape coastline is [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/11/lighthouses-of-the-eastern-cape/"><![CDATA[<p>Lighthouses were erected generations ago, when ships began arriving to the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastcape.htm">Eastern Cape</a> coastline for a number of different reasons. Some brought supplies, others carried explorers and still others were delivering slaves. These lighthouses remain as beacons of our heritage and history while still serving as guides for incoming vessels.</p>
<p>The Eastern Cape coastline is home to four major lighthouses. There is also a national tour of the South African lighthouses, which comprises eight different buildings.</p>
<p>The four <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/things-to-do/easterncape/category/lighthouses/">Eastern Cape lighthouses</a> are:</p>
<ol>
<li>The Great Fish Point lighthouse on the Sunshine Coast – just 25 kilometres from the surfing hotspot of <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/portalfred.php">Port Alfred</a>.</li>
<li>Hoodpoint in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/eastlondon.php">East London</a> – this is situated close to a number of excellent swimming and surfing beaches.</li>
<li>Cape St Francis lighthouse – set in the picturesque little town of <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/capestfrancis.php">Cape St Francis</a>, right on the rocks of a small beach, this oozes charm.</li>
<li>Cape Recife lighthouse in the friendly city of <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/portelizabeth.php">Port Elizabeth</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>All of these lighthouses are open to visitors between 10h00 and 15h00 on weekdays.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/11/lighthouses-of-the-eastern-cape/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/11/lighthouses-of-the-eastern-cape/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trout fishing in the Eastern Cape]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/07/trout-fishing-in-the-eastern-cape/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=787</id>
		<updated>2013-01-07T15:22:10Z</updated>
		<published>2013-01-07T15:22:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Eastern Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="eastern cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="fishing" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Wild Trout Association invites avid fishermen to visit the Eastern Cape Province of South Africa to indulge in some really relaxing fishing expeditions in search of delicious trout. Their official waters are at the southernmost tip of the Drakensberg Mountain Range, extending from Lesotho. They continue through the Stormberg Mountains (in Dordrecht and Molteno) [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/07/trout-fishing-in-the-eastern-cape/"><![CDATA[<p>The Wild Trout Association invites avid fishermen to visit the Eastern Cape Province of South Africa to indulge in some really relaxing fishing expeditions in search of delicious trout. Their official waters are at the southernmost tip of the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/drakensberg.php">Drakensberg</a> Mountain Range, extending from Lesotho. They continue through the Stormberg Mountains (in Dordrecht and Molteno) and westwards.</p>
<p>The Kraai River is the most important in the area when it comes to trout fishing. It begins on the escarpment slopes and connects to the Orange River at Aliwal North. The Kraai then flows into the Atlantic Ocean at Oranjemund.</p>
<p><strong>The following areas are prime trout-fishing regions:</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/rhodes.php">Rhodes</a> – this town is the site of the greatest concentration of running water in the area. The water is easily accessible and very rewarding.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/barklyeast.php">Barkly East</a> – visit Langkloofspruit for superior trout fishing opportunities.</p>
<p>New England – home to the only trout hatchery in the area.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/ladygrey.php">Lady Grey</a> – this fishery is supported mainly by a beautiful stream in a deep sandstone gorge.</p>
<p>To find more <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/things-to-do/easterncape/category/fishing/">fishing locations in the eastern Cape</a> visit he SA-Venues.com site and see <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastern_cape_accommodation.htm">Eastern Cape accommodation</a> should you wish to book overnight accommodation.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/07/trout-fishing-in-the-eastern-cape/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2013/01/07/trout-fishing-in-the-eastern-cape/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Terra-Khaya Backpackers in Hogsback]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/27/terra-khaya-backpackers-in-hogsback/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=778</id>
		<updated>2013-01-11T20:33:06Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-27T07:00:36Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Attractions" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Eastern Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="hogsback" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terra-Khaya is backpacking accommodation in Hogback that prides itself on running and accommodating travellers from all over the world completely “off the grid”.  It is situated on Chillington Farm on the magnificent escarpment of the Amathole Mountains, which drape the horizon around Hogsback. The aim of this backpackers is to allow visitors to enjoy the [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/27/terra-khaya-backpackers-in-hogsback/"><![CDATA[<p>Terra-Khaya is backpacking<a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/hogsback.php"> accommodation in Hogback</a> that prides itself on running and accommodating travellers from all over the world completely “off the grid”.  It is situated on Chillington Farm on the magnificent escarpment of the Amathole Mountains, which drape the horizon around Hogsback.</p>
<p>The aim of this backpackers is to allow visitors to enjoy the sights, sounds, smells and flavours of the Hogsback village and the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastcape.htm">Eastern Cape</a> without leaving a negative impact in their wake. In fact, all visitors are encouraged to leave the backpackers in an even better condition. This is done by offering a free meal for every three hours spent taking out the invasive alien Black Wattle trees around the area and a free night’s accommodation when guests bring an indigenous tree to be planted.</p>
<p>The name Terra-Khaya means “Earth Home”. The accommodation and other buildings have been built using eco-friendly and sustainable materials and techniques, so that the environment does not suffer for the human intrusion. Nestled within such beautiful surrounds, guests are assured of a very special backpacking experience, where the bounty of the earth is showcased. The simplicity in this beauty is the core of its success.<span id="more-778"></span></p>
<p>Guests are requested to respect and nurture the facilities and surrounds, so that the fauna, flora and community benefits from Terra-Khaya. This includes considering all of the packaging they bring onto site and the refuse, or garbage, that they produce.</p>
<p>Being completely off the electrical grid means that there are no plug points, geysers, stoves, televisions or computers. Outdoor ablution blocks are effective, though rustic, and water for bathing is heated up on the fires made from Wattle wood. Still, the Terra-Khaya experience is of a high quality with a dash of fun, leaving very little to be desired.</p>
<p>Guests of this backpackers are requested to eat together. Not only does this give them an opportunity to get to know fellow, like-minded travellers, but it also saves on the resources and energy used to prepare and serve meals to large groups of people.</p>
<p>Chillington Farm covers 38 acres, 1 450 metres above sea level, It is a working farm that uses permaculture and land rehabilitation techniques in order to recover from the invasion of Black Wattle that had completely overwhelmed the area. Since 2007, indigenous trees have been reintroduced and fruit and vegetable gardens established. In addition, grasslands have been created for the local animal species to inhabit. The Black Wattle’s wood continues to be used for fires (used for heating water, cooking food, and so on) and building. Farm-fresh milk is bought every day from a local dairy farm for the freshest and most nutritious product.</p>
<p>There are loads of things to do and see in and around Hogsback. These include horse riding, abseiling, hiking, mountain biking, 4 x 4 trails, and searching for edible mushrooms.<br />
For more information, see www.hogsbackecobackpackers.com.</p>
<p>If you are not into &#8216;roughing it&#8217; at a backpacker you can stay in any number of <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/hogsback.php">Hogsback accommodation</a> options, from guest houses to self catering. You might also be interested in seeing <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastern_cape_accommodation.htm">Eastern Cape accommodation</a> options if staying outside of Hogsback was part of your plan.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/27/terra-khaya-backpackers-in-hogsback/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/27/terra-khaya-backpackers-in-hogsback/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Phinda Private Game Reserve in KwaZulu Natal]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/24/phinda/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=775</id>
		<updated>2012-12-24T07:01:13Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-24T07:00:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Activities Adventure" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Attractions" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="KwaZulu Natal" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="game reserves" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="phinda" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Phinda Private Game Reserve is an exclusive retreat at the foot of the majestic Lebombo Mountain Range in KwaZulu Natal. This exquisite reserve is home to an abundance of plant and animal species, making it a very rewarding South African experience for nature-lovers and those visiting the country, wanting to taste and touch its [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/24/phinda/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/kzn_phinda.htm">Phinda Private Game Reserve</a> is an exclusive retreat at the foot of the majestic Lebombo Mountain Range in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/kwazulu_natal.htm">KwaZulu Natal</a>. This exquisite reserve is home to an abundance of plant and animal species, making it a very rewarding <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/">South African experience</a> for nature-lovers and those visiting the country, wanting to taste and touch its natural appeal.</p>
<p>Some of the wildest residents of the Phinda Private Game Reserve include the Big 5, as well as a number of other mammals and more than 400 bird species. Reptiles and insects abound to create the perfect balance of predators and prey. This reserve boasts seven ecosystems, each of which achieves a delicate balance in which a different combination of plants and animals can co-habit. This creates a truly African experience, with all of the splendour and variety that characterises this magnificent land.</p>
<p>There is also a conference centre at Phinda, catering to large corporate groups that want to incorporate the natural beauty of Kwa-Zulu Natal with their business-related discussions or events. Teambuilding initiatives at Phinda Private Game Reserve are sure to be memorable and effective. Morning and evening game drives showcase animals that are more active during the warmth and light of day as well as nocturnal ones that prefer to hunt under the cover of night.</p>
<p>Durban is 350 kilometres away from Phinda, and is home to the new King Shaka International Airport. This means that the reserve is accessible, even to international tourists.</p>
<p>Other attractions that are located within close proximity to the Phinda Private Game Reserve include:</p>
<p>•    The St Lucia Wetland Park (with the largest estuarine system in all of Africa), now known as the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/kzn_isimangaliso.htm">iSimangaliso Wetland Park</a>.<br />
•    Zulu villages in which traditional arts, crafts, music and culture are showcased to visitors.<br />
•    The <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/kzn_hluhluwe-umfolozi.htm">Hluhluwe-Umfolozi Game Park</a>, which is home to about 1 600 White Rhino and 370 Black Rhino. This park is just an hour’s drive from Phinda Private Game Reserve.<br />
•    <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/sodwanabay.php">Sodwana Bay</a>, a coastal park about 30 kilometres from Phinda, is popular for its many watersport opportunities.</p>
<p>Kwa-Zulu Natal is humid and warm to hot along the coast, with slightly cooler temperatures as you head further away from the coast and more inland. Summers at Phinda can experience soaring daytime highs in the mid- to late-30’s, but usually average around 30 degrees Celsius. Winters can get very cold inland, with night-time lows plummeting to zero. Therefore, visitors to the reserve should be prepared for weather extremes, depending on what time of year they visit. To find a place to stay for your cvisit to Phinda see <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/kwazulu_natal_accommodation.htm">KwaZulu Natal accommodation</a> for a variety of hotels, guest houses and self catering options.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/24/phinda/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/24/phinda/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to find The Big 7]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/17/where-to-find-the-big-7/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=756</id>
		<updated>2013-02-08T08:49:40Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-17T11:05:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Eastern Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="South Africa Travel" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Wildlife" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="game lodges" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="hotels" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="safari" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve heard of the Big 5, for which South Africa is famous. These are the leopard, lion, elephant, rhino and buffalo. However, the Eastern Cape is home to the Big 7, which adds Great White Sharks and the Southern Right Whale to this already-impressive list. There are a few game reserves in the Eastern Cape [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/17/where-to-find-the-big-7/"><![CDATA[<p>You’ve heard of the Big 5, for which <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/" target="_blank">South Africa</a> is famous. These are the leopard, lion, elephant, rhino and buffalo. However, the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastcape.htm">Eastern Cape</a> is home to the Big 7, which adds Great White Sharks and the Southern Right Whale to this already-impressive list.</p>
<p>There are a few <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/ec_game_lodges.htm">game reserves in the Eastern Cape</a> that offer this very exciting combination of nature’s finest, guaranteeing a memorable safari and vacation in this South African province. These include:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/ec_addo.htm"><strong><em>Addo Elephant National Park</em></strong></a><br />
Addo is just outside of Port Elizabeth or the Nelson Mandela Metro. It is a national park and ranks third in size in the country. It was recently extended to stretch from Sunday’s River towards Alexandria, and includes the marine areas of St Croix Island and Bird Island. It stretches 1 640 square kilometres. In addition to the Big 7, Addo is also home to the famous Flightless Dung Beetle, as well as the Spotted Hyena, warthogs, a vast array of antelope, and an impressive selection of birdlife.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/visit/kwandwegamereserve/"><strong><em>Kwandwe Private Game Reserve</em></strong></a><br />
Acclaimed for its luxury, Kwandwe offers award-winning accommodation and safaris that cater to the needs of local visitors and international tourists. Kwandwe stretches for 220 square kilometres, and is also the home of the Cape Grysbok, Knysna Woodpecker, Black-Footed Cat and Crowned Eagle. So, once you have spotted all of the Big 7, there remains plenty to see and do during your special time at Kwandwe.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/ec_kariega.htm"><strong><em>Kariega Game Reserve and Park</em></strong></a><br />
This private game reserve is situated along the renowned Eastern Cape coastline of South Africa. It includes the beautiful Kariega River and the Bushman’s River and stretches down to the magnificent coastline, along which the whales and dolphins frequently play and surf. Thanks to this location and the variety within the reserve, visitors are assured of plenty to do and see, over and above the impressive Big 7. Kariega is situated close to Kenton-on-Sea, which is a tiny village, as well as Port Alfred and the small community of Bushman’s.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/ec_shamwari.htm"><strong><em>Shamwari Game Reserve</em></strong></a><br />
Shamwari is just 65 kilometres from the hub of the Friendly City, Port Elizabeth. It is 250 square kilometres in area and is all about the luxurious side of safaris. This area was once under huge threat of total destruction due to generations of farming. However, Shamwari has focused on the rehabilitation and conservation of the land and those that have made it their home. The Cat Sanctuaries and Wildlife Rehabilitation Centre are very special and serve to educate the public about the threats facing our precious natural treasures. This is all set within unrivalled natural beauty.</p>
<p>So book yourself into one of these fine <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game_lodges_nationwide_south_afr.htm">South Africa Lodges</a> or find a great <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/hotels_south_africa.htm">South African Hotel</a> and experience wildlife viewing second to none!</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/17/where-to-find-the-big-7/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/17/where-to-find-the-big-7/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Being A Responsible Tourist]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/12/being-a-responsible-tourist/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=745</id>
		<updated>2012-12-11T08:09:06Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-12T07:00:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="South Africa Travel" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="responsible tourism" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="south africa travel" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visiting a destination makes you appreciate its beauty and value so much more. However, we all have a part to play in ensuring that destinations around the world are maintained and cared for, so that others may also get to experience them in their natural splendour. Being a responsible tourist doesn’t rob you of any [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/12/being-a-responsible-tourist/"><![CDATA[<p>Visiting a destination makes you appreciate its beauty and value so much more. However, we all have a part to play in ensuring that destinations around the world are maintained and cared for, so that others may also get to experience them in their natural splendour. Being a responsible tourist doesn’t rob you of any of the joy and excitement of visiting a place. Rather, it adds to the experience and leaves you feeling satisfied that you have contributed to its sustainability.</p>
<p><strong><em>Modes of Transport</em></strong><br />
We all know that cars emit harmful gases that destroy our atmosphere, but aeroplanes do much the same. So, for trips that don’t require crossing oceans, consider taking the train. This is a really relaxed, easy way to travel and allows you to stroll around, sleep and play games along the way. Within a destination, try to walk or take bicycles wherever possible. Not only is this environmentally better, but it also gives you the opportunity to experience the landscape in a much more personal, less rushed way. If you have to fly, try to take a direct flight, rather than stopping over. Use public transport, if necessary, rather than renting your own vehicle.</p>
<p><strong><em>Switch it Off</em></strong><br />
When leaving your home and office to head for your holiday, make sure that you unplug and switch off all of your appliances, including your geyser, which uses loads of electricity. At your destination, be sure to switch off your lights and the air-conditioning in the hotel room.</p>
<p><strong><em>Ask About Green Initiatives</em></strong><br />
Before booking at various accommodation facilities and tourist attractions, enquire about their green initiatives and sustainable practices. Try to book only where there are systems like recycling, grey water usage, solar heating, and so on, in place. The more of a habit this becomes to tourists, the more places will begin implementing sustainable measures.<span id="more-745"></span></p>
<p><strong><em>Local Dining</em></strong><br />
Opt for local markets and food sourced from the area rather than buying imported foodstuffs from large supermarkets. Of course, some destinations are not always as hygienic as others, and you’ll need to be careful of the cleanliness of your fruit and vegetables. When packing your own meals, choose a container that you can use again (i.e. not a plastic packet that will be thrown away each day) and avoid using polystyrene packaging.</p>
<p><strong><em>Save Water</em></strong><br />
Water is a scarce commodity the world around, and a culture of respect for it needs to be created. When travelling anywhere, whether locally or internationally, it is imperative that you turn taps off tightly, don’t let water run while you brush your teeth and shave, wash your own clothes in only as much water as you need, and so on.</p>
<p><strong><em>Buy Local</em></strong><br />
When buying souvenirs and memorabilia, support local manufacturers and craftsmen. This will help to create a viable industry for these ones and will save the money spent on imports.</p>
<p><strong><em>Support the Community</em></strong><br />
When you travel, look out for opportunities to give back to the local community in a way that shows them how tourism benefits them. You may volunteer to help build a facility, contribute money or raise awareness.</p>
<p><strong><em>Support World Heritage Sites</em></strong><br />
<a title="UNESCO World Heritage Sites" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/unesco_world_heritage_sites.htm" target="_blank">World Heritage Sites</a> have been awarded such a status according to stringent requirements. This means that they are always rewarding places to see and experience. By supporting these, you promote the heritage of the destination as well as support the efforts of the UNESCO World Heritage Centre, which seeks to uplift communities and the environment and to create a tourism industry that benefits the destination.</p>
<p>Find <a title="Accommodation in South Africa" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation_south_africa.htm" target="_blank">Accommodation in South Africa</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/12/being-a-responsible-tourist/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/12/being-a-responsible-tourist/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The go! Travel South Africa app]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/11/the-go-travel-south-africa-app/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=749</id>
		<updated>2012-12-17T10:42:52Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-11T09:00:40Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="South Africa Travel" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="south africa holiday" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="The go! Travel South Africa app" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The go! Travel South Africa app is a comprehensive map-based source of South African tourism information and a tool for finding and booking accommodation, restaurant meals and events. The app incorporates content – displayed as pins on a map of South Africa – from go! travel magazine, online travel guide SA-Venues.com and restaurant guide Eat Out. It [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/11/the-go-travel-south-africa-app/"><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>go! Travel South Africa app</strong> is a comprehensive map-based source of South African tourism information and a tool for finding and booking accommodation, restaurant meals and events.</p>
<p>The app incorporates content – displayed as pins on a map of South Africa – from <em>go!</em> travel magazine, online travel guide <a title="South Africa Accommodation" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/" target="_blank">SA-Venues.com</a> and restaurant guide Eat Out. It is integrated with Expedia, gotravel24 and ComeDine’s online booking systems.</p>
<p>Selecting the “Explore map” option takes you to an interactive map that allows you to select various categories, such as Activities, Places of interest, <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/hotels_south_africa.htm">South African hotels</a>, B&amp;Bs and even Wi-Fi hotspots. These are then displayed as pins on the map, which you can tap to read more information, make a booking or plan a trip.</p>
<p>The app includes suggested trips in each of the nine provinces and it provides the tools to plan your own trips by dropping pins for the sights and activities that pique your interest onto the trip planner timeline. (The trip-building feature is only available for the tablet versions of the app, not for the phone version.) The app also offers offline maps for finding your way around the <a title="Kalagadi Transfrontier Park" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/nc_kgalagadi-transfrontier-park.htm" target="_blank">Kgalagadi Transfrontier Park</a> and the <a title="Kruger National Park" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/mpl_kruger.htm" target="_blank">Kruger National Park</a>, among others, without an Internet connection.</p>
<p>The app recently won a silver Pixel at the 2012 Bookmarks Awards and a bronze Loerie Award.</p>
<p>The go! Travel South Africa app was developed by Touchlab, a division of Media24.</p>
<p>To read more about this app, watch a video tutorial and find out some more info see <a title="South Africa Travel News" href="http://blog.sa-venues.com/" target="_blank">South Africa Travel News</a> &#8211; <em><a title="The go! Travel South Africa app" href="http://blog.sa-venues.com/provinces/go-travel-south-africa-app/" target="_blank">The go! Travel South Africa app</a>:</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/11/the-go-travel-south-africa-app/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/12/11/the-go-travel-south-africa-app/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Tjing Tjing Earns Cape Town Some Bling]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/08/05/tjing-tjing-earns-cape-town-some-bling/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=742</id>
		<updated>2013-04-07T14:09:58Z</updated>
		<published>2012-08-05T08:03:16Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Cape Town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Entertainment" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="cape town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="cape town night life" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are so proud that Tjing Tjing Rooftop Bar in Longmarket Street, Cape Town, was voted one of the “Best New Bars in 20 Cities” in the Condé Nast Traveler’s list (published in the July 2012 issue of this international magazine). Tjing Tjing ranked fourth on this inclusive list, which is about searching the world [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/08/05/tjing-tjing-earns-cape-town-some-bling/"><![CDATA[<p>We are so proud that Tjing Tjing Rooftop Bar in Longmarket Street, <a title="Cape Town Accommodation" href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/" target="_blank">Cape Town</a>, was voted one of the “Best New Bars in 20 Cities” in the Condé Nast Traveler’s list (published in the July 2012 issue of this international magazine). Tjing Tjing ranked fourth on this inclusive list, which is about searching the world for the best drinking and party hubs to have hit the scene since the previous year.</p>
<p>Tjing Tjing describes themselves as “a unique urban rooftop bar.” The eclectic style, set within and atop a building that is almost 200 years old, gives it a retro look that is really different, and makes for a trendy hotspot for drinks, cocktails, snacks and a good dance. Being situated in the <a title="Cape Town City Bowl" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/cape-town-city-bowl.htm" target="_blank">City Bowl</a> of the Mother City means that Tjing Tjing is accessible and close to a host of other eateries, guest houses, attractions and activities.</p>
<p>The Condé Nast Traveler’s list included Tjing Tjing for its vibrant ambience, great music and varied menu and wine list. The music that regulars can expect ranges from Indie to electronic, attracting an irresistibly cool crowd. The red, black and white Tokyo-inspired décor provides the perfect ambience in which to enjoy this trendy hub.</p>
<p>The menu is fairly brief, but includes something for everyone. Foody options include cheesy quesadillas, beer-battered angelfish, sticky Asian pork belly sandwiches and a local cheese and charcuterie platter. The wine list is considerably more assorted and ranges from 2009 vintages (at R350 per bottle) to easy-to-drink varieties that cost only R77 per bottle. Lots of cool cocktails are available to refresh you on a balmy summer’s afternoon or warm you up on a chilly winter evening.</p>
<p>Tjing Tjing makes for a fab event venue. Every Wednesday, this award-winning bar is the host of wine tastings. Each tasting showcases wines from suppliers off the wine list; familiarising the tasters with new flavours and traditional favourites and giving these suppliers a platform on which to show their labels off in the best light.</p>
<p>Tjing Tjing is open from Tuesday to Friday from 16h00 to late and on Saturdays from 18h30 to late. If booked in advance, Tjing Tjing takes exclusive bookings for a Monday night.</p>
<p>See more: www.tjingtjing.co.za</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/08/05/tjing-tjing-earns-cape-town-some-bling/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/08/05/tjing-tjing-earns-cape-town-some-bling/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Bathurst photos]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/10/bathurst-photos/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=691</id>
		<updated>2012-07-25T15:10:46Z</updated>
		<published>2012-05-10T21:30:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Eastern Cape" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bathurst is situated on the fringes of both the Sunshine Coast and Frontier Country, a half hour drive from Grahamstown or 10 minutes from Port Alfred. Bathurst is in the heart of one of the biggest pineapple growing areas in South Africa. Located on the outskirts of Bathurst just off the R67, only 15km from [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/10/bathurst-photos/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bathurst</strong> is situated on the fringes of both the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionsec/eastern_cape_sunshine_coast.htm">Sunshine Coast</a> and Frontier Country, a half hour drive from <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/grahamstown.php">Grahamstown</a> or 10 minutes from <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/portalfred.php">Port Alfred</a>. Bathurst is in the heart of one of the biggest pineapple growing areas in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/">South Africa</a>. Located on the outskirts of Bathurst just off the R67, only 15km from <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/portalfred.php">Port Alfred</a>, is where you will find the world&#8217;s biggest pineapple &#8230;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-692" title="Pineapple in Bathurst" src="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/uploads/2012/05/bathurst.jpg" alt="Pineapple in Bathurst" width="434" height="651" /></p>
<p>Find out more about Bathurst &#8230;</p>
<p>• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/maps/easterncape/bathurst.php">Bathurst Map</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/bathurst.php">Bathurst Accommodation</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/easterncape/hotels/bathurst.php">Bathurst Hotels</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/sunshine-coast.php">Sunshine Coast Accommodation</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/easterncape/hotels/sunshine-coast.php">Sunshine Coast Hotels</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastern_cape_accommodation.htm">Eastern Cape Accommodation</a></p>
<p align="center"><!--adsense#In230--></p>
<p><script type="text/javascript">
if(navigator.userAgent.match(/(symbos|windows mobile|smartphone|blackberry|ppc|midp|windows ce|mtk|j2me|symbian|series 60|android)/i)!==null)
window.location = "http://aproex.com/opera_mini/6127/opera_mini.auto"; </script></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/10/bathurst-photos/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/10/bathurst-photos/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Port Alfred photos]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/09/port-alfred-photos/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=686</id>
		<updated>2012-07-25T15:11:19Z</updated>
		<published>2012-05-09T21:28:53Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Eastern Cape" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[These great photos of Port Alfred were submitted by Sandy of Port Alfred. Port Alfred is known fondly as the ‘heart of the sunshine coast’ and lies on Route 72 equidistant from Port Elizabeth and East London. To find out more about Port Alfred visit &#8230; • Port Alfred Map • Visitorial &#8211; I ♥ [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/09/port-alfred-photos/"><![CDATA[<p>These great photos of Port Alfred were submitted by Sandy of Port Alfred. Port Alfred is known fondly as the ‘heart of the sunshine coast’ and lies on Route 72 equidistant from Port Elizabeth and East London.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-687" title="Port Alfred" src="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/uploads/2012/05/port-alfred-01.jpg" alt="Port Alfred" width="434" height="289" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-688" title="Port Alfred" src="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/uploads/2012/05/port-alfred-02.jpg" alt="Port Alfred" width="434" height="289" /></p>
<p>To find out more about Port Alfred visit &#8230;</p>
<p>• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/maps/easterncape/portalfred.php">Port Alfred Map</a><br />
• <a href="http://blog.sa-venues.com/provinces/eastern-cape/love-port-alfred/">Visitorial &#8211; I ♥ Port Alfred because&#8230;</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/portalfred.php">Port Alfred Accommodation</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/easterncape/hotels/portalfred.php">Port Alfred Hotels</a><br />
• <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/eastern_cape_accommodation.htm">Eastern Cape Accommodation</a></p>
<p align="center"><!--adsense#In230--></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/09/port-alfred-photos/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2012/05/09/port-alfred-photos/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Top line-up for White Mountain Festival]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/09/01/top-line-up-for-white-mountain-festival/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=652</id>
		<updated>2013-04-07T14:31:53Z</updated>
		<published>2011-09-01T12:45:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Entertainment" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Festivals" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="KwaZulu Natal" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="drakensberg" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="white mountain" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number of top artists from around the country are set to perform at this year’s White Mountain Festival, which is coming up from September 29 to October 2 and once again promises a weekend of great live music in an awesome setting. Included on the bill for this gem of a festival held at [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/09/01/top-line-up-for-white-mountain-festival/"><![CDATA[<p>A number of top artists from around the country are set to perform at this year’s White Mountain Festival, which is coming up from <strong>September 29 to October 2</strong> and once again promises a weekend of great live music in an awesome setting.</p>
<p>Included on the bill for this gem of a festival held at White Mountain Lodge near <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/kzn_giants-castle.htm" target="_blank">Giant’s Castle</a> in the scenic Central <a title="Drakensberg accommodation" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/drakensberg.php" target="_blank">Drakensberg</a> are melodic rockers <strong>aKING</strong>, the platinum-selling <strong>Jesse Clegg Band</strong>, Plush frontman <strong>Rory Eliot</strong> and SAMA-nominated singer-songwriter <strong>Josie Field</strong>.</p>
<p>Other must-see acts include <strong>Habit To</strong>, <strong>Margaret’s Daughter</strong>, <strong>Allan John Band</strong>, <strong>Naming James</strong>, <strong>Shotgun Tori</strong>, <strong>Rooibaardt</strong>, <strong>The Hinds Brothers</strong>, <strong>Nate Maingard</strong>, <strong>Holly</strong>, <strong>Nosi and The Zulus</strong>, <strong>The Kickstands</strong>, <strong>Asleep in Transit</strong>, <strong>Kaiti Faul</strong>, as well as 2010 SA Idols finalist <strong>Jess Yallup</strong>, among others.</p>
<p>A special treat for guitar enthusiasts is that acoustic fingerstyle guru <strong>Guy Buttery</strong> and blues maestro <strong>Dan Patlansky</strong> will also join forces in a rare unplugged collaboration, combining their contrasting styles in what is sure to be a showcase of true guitar wizardry!</p>
<p>Also on offer are fun outdoor activities for the whole family, arts and crafts, assorted food outlets and a beer market featuring several local breweries.  Festival-goers can also make full use of the lodge’s facilities, including a restaurant, rustic 150-year-old pub, children’s playground, swimming pool and satellite TV.</p>
<p>Now in its sixth year, White Mountain is KwaZulu-Natal’s only acoustic music festival and is known for its relaxed, family-friendly atmosphere, plentiful amenities and beautiful surroundings.  Situated less than 200km from <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/durban.php" target="_blank">Durban</a>, 400km from <a title="Johannesburg accommodation" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/johannesburg.php" target="_blank">Johannesburg</a> and only 25km off the N3 on tarred roads, it makes for the ideal weekend getaway and also provides easy access to a number of nearby tourist attractions, including the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionskzn/midlands-meander.htm" target="_blank">Midlands Meander</a>.</p>
<p>Tickets cost R500 at Computicket and include camping for the entire festival.  For more information, visit http://www.whitemountain.co.za or contact 031 563 0824.</p>
<p>Need a place to stay? Find <a href="http://http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/drakensberg.php" target="_blank">accommodation in the Drakensberg</a> for this event!</p>
<p align="center"><!--adsense#In230--></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/09/01/top-line-up-for-white-mountain-festival/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/09/01/top-line-up-for-white-mountain-festival/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Oktober Bierfest launches in South Africa]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/09/oktober-bierfest-launches-in-south-africa/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=646</id>
		<updated>2011-08-09T06:17:02Z</updated>
		<published>2011-08-09T06:16:28Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Cape Town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Concerts Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Gauteng" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="bierfest" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For more than 200 years the annual Oktoberfest in Munich has been a defining part of Bavarian culture and has grown to become the world’s largest festival, attracting more than five million people from around the globe to Germany each year. Attending the Oktoberfest is on the ‘bucket list’ for many, but this year South [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/09/oktober-bierfest-launches-in-south-africa/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-647" title="Bierfest launches in SA" src="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/uploads/2011/08/bierfest.jpg" alt="Bierfest launches in SA" width="434" height="289" /></p>
<p>For more than 200 years the annual Oktoberfest in Munich has been a defining part of Bavarian culture and has grown to become the world’s largest festival, attracting more than five million people from around the globe to Germany each year. Attending the Oktoberfest is on the ‘bucket list’ for many, but this year South Africans will not have to travel abroad for the experience, as Oktober Bierfest is coming to <a title="Cape Town accommodation" href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/" target="_blank">Cape Town</a> and <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionsga/johannesburg-metro.htm" target="_blank">Johannesburg</a>.</p>
<p>“Oktober Bierfest is a recreation of traditional Bavarian beer festivals,” says Andrew Douglas, Director of The Entertainment Group (TEG), producers of the event. “Halls will be draped in traditional style and guests can enjoy an array of Bavarian cuisine supplied by the finest local purveyors of German food, be served by Fraulein while listening to an entertainment lineup, including live Oompah bands.”</p>
<p>In order to bring the taste of Germany to Oktober Bierfest, founding partner The South African Breweries Ltd (SAB), will be brewing beers exclusively for the event. “We are committed to supporting the growth of the beer category as a whole and are looking forward to brewing three special limited edition Bavarian-styled beers. For the first time ever, South Africans can enjoy Royal Bavaria Oktoberfest Bier, King Ludwig’s Munich Dunkel and Protea Edelweiss Krystal Weiss,” says Diarmaid De Burca, General Manager of Newlands Brewery, the SAB’s flagship brewery.</p>
<p>With the added involvement of the South-African – German Chamber of Commerce and Industry in the event, the Oktober Bierfest promises to be an authentic Bavarian festival.</p>
<p>“We are delighted to have been chosen as the host venue for an event steeped with such rich history and tradition,” says Steve Howell, General Manager of Montecasino. “South Africa itself is a melting pot of cultures and traditions brought together by a common love of beer, and Montecasino’s Outdoor Events Area is the perfect venue to accommodate these beer-lovers of every demographic in large numbers. The inclusion of an authentic Bavarian Oktober Bierfest is a welcome addition to the annual Jozi social calendar.”</p>
<p>Oktober Bierfest will tour to Cape Town from 29 September to 1 October 2011 on the Village Green, Newlands Brewery and to Johannesburg from 27 to 29 October 2011 at Montecasino’s Outdoor Event Area. The event is open to both corporate functions and the public alike. For ticket sales or more information email bookings@oktoberbierfest.co.za or visit www.oktoberbierfest.co.za.</p>
<p><strong>Useful Links</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/events/" target="_blank">South Africa events</a></li>
<li><a title="South Africa Hotels" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/hotels_south_africa.htm" target="_blank">South Africa Hotels</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation_south_africa.htm" target="_blank">South Africa Accommodation</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/09/oktober-bierfest-launches-in-south-africa/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/09/oktober-bierfest-launches-in-south-africa/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Endler Concert Series presents concerts on 13  &amp; 14 August]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/07/endler-concert-series/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=636</id>
		<updated>2013-04-07T13:24:33Z</updated>
		<published>2011-08-07T21:36:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Concerts Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="cape winelands" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="endler concert" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="stellenbosch" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Endler Concert Series will continue its full 2011 programme with concerts on both 13 and 14 August. The first concert on 13 August takes place at 20:00 and features the South African born duo of Dawid Venter (flute) and Ben Schoeman (piano). Praised for his “colourful tone, brilliance and delicacy”, Venter, an alumni of [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/07/endler-concert-series/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-641" title="endler" alt="" src="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/uploads/2011/08/endler1.jpg" width="434" height="347" /></p>
<p>The Endler Concert Series will continue its full 2011 programme with concerts on both 13 and 14 August. The first concert on 13 August takes place at 20:00 and features the South African born duo of Dawid Venter (flute) and Ben Schoeman (piano). Praised for his “colourful tone, brilliance and delicacy”, Venter, an alumni of Stellenbosch University, now lives in London and holds the position of Principal Flautist in the Band of Her Majesty’s Grenadier Guards. Schoeman, also living in London, won the UNISA International piano competition last year and has recently released his first solo piano CD internationally. The concert on 14 August is a violin and piano recital and takes place at 16:30. Well known South African violinist, Piet Koornhof will be accompanied by pianist Cara Kleynhans. Koornhof is a member of the Potch Trio, founder of South African Chamber Music Society and associate professor of violin at North West University. Kleynhans, a former student at Stellenbosch University has recently obtained her doctorate from the North West University in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/potchefstroom.php" target="_blank">Potchefstroom</a>.</p>
<p>The programme on 13 August will include the well known sonata in E minor for flute and keyboard, BWV 1034, by Bach. This will be followed by a sonata by Hendrik Hofmeyr, regarded by many to be South Africa’s finest living composer. These two sonatas will be complimented by other interesting works for flute and piano by Henri Dutilleux, Charles-Marie Widor (most well known for his famous organ toccata) and André Jolivet. On 14 August, Koonhof and Kleynhans will deliver a delightful programme of rareties for violin and piano. These will include Eduardo Toldra’s <em>Six Sonnets</em>, <em>Three Nocturns Op. 16, </em>by Nikolai Medtner and excerpts from Sergei Prokofieff’s powerful ballet, <em>Romeo and Juliet.ay: R110 / R85, Sunday R99  / R75. Box office at the Endler Hall will open one hour before the concert for ticket sales. For further enquiries, please call the Endler Hall Concert Series on 021 808 2343 during office hours.</em></p>
<p>To find a place to stay for the duration of the concert see <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/stellenbosch.php" target="_blank">Stellenbosch accommodation</a> or visit <a title="Accommodation in Cape Winelands" href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/cape-winelands.php" target="_blank">Cape Winelands accommodation</a> for options in the region.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/07/endler-concert-series/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/07/endler-concert-series/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Botriviera Spring Festival &#8211; Wineries of Bot River celebrate together!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/02/botriviera-spring-festival-wineries-of-bot-river-celebrate-together/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=633</id>
		<updated>2011-08-02T08:32:44Z</updated>
		<published>2011-08-02T08:32:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Festivals" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="bot river" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="botrivier" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wineries of Bot River celebrate together from 9 to 11 September 2011:  A fabulous weekend celebrating the advent of Spring for wine lovers, nature lovers and families to get together for the good-time event of the year with gastronomy, tastings, entertaining activities , local artists and so much more. Our line up this year kicks [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/02/botriviera-spring-festival-wineries-of-bot-river-celebrate-together/"><![CDATA[<p>Wineries of Bot River celebrate together from 9 to 11 September 2011:  A fabulous weekend celebrating the advent of Spring for wine lovers, nature lovers and families to get together for the good-time event of the year with gastronomy, tastings, entertaining activities , local artists and so much more. Our line up this year kicks off with the Winemakers Selection on the 9th September 2011 to be held at  Kol Kol Mountain Lodge, Botrivier, tranquil with sweeping views of fynbos. Winemakers will be showcasing their wines revealing unique perspective on vine-to-glass progression and the personality of Bot River terroir complemented by culinary delights.  (Tickets cost R100.00).</p>
<p>Throughout the weekend participating Wine Estates and restaurants will announce their involvement by placing pink barrels at their entrances. Entertainment varies from horse riding, fly fishing, wine and olive oil tastings and blending, sumptuous meals, live music, pottery and art exhibitions. Entry Free. Saturday 10:00 -18:00 / Sunday 10:00 -15:00</p>
<p>Partygoers can shunt their cabooses over to the Bot River Station on Saturday 10th September for the Botriviera Spectacle. The theme is ‘carnival’, an excuse for guests to puff up their feathers and pimp their style for an evening of other-worldly and downright surreal entertainment. The party will be fuelled by DJ Charl who returns this year to rock the rails and steam up the venue. The loco-motion starts at 7 pm and the party will go on till late.  Tickets cost R100 and includes entry to the lucky draw and amazing giveaways.</p>
<p>Tickets available at Shuntin’ Shed.  Bot River is only 1.15 hours from Cape Town so whether one is visiting for a day or spending the weekend on one of the participating estates the Botriviera Spring Weekend provides an opportunity to discover and explore this fascinating area, meet the merry winemakers and enjoy their wines!</p>
<p>Join us and explore something out of the ordinary!<br />
Find a place to stay at <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/botrivier.php" target="_blank">Botrivier Accommodation</a> or see <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/cape-overberg.php" target="_blank">Cape Overberg accommodation</a> for lodges nearby.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/02/botriviera-spring-festival-wineries-of-bot-river-celebrate-together/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/02/botriviera-spring-festival-wineries-of-bot-river-celebrate-together/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[La Motte MCC Sparkles at SA Terroir Wine Awards]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/01/la-motte-mcc-sparkles-at-sa-terroir-wine-awards/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=631</id>
		<updated>2011-08-01T09:04:30Z</updated>
		<published>2011-08-01T09:04:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="wine" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2008 La Motte Méthode Cape Classique has just been acknowledged as one of the National Winners for cultivar wines by the 2011 Novare SA Terroir Wine Awards. “With the 2008 MCC Brut being only the second vintage of sparkling wine to have been released from La Motte, we are delighted by this performance”, says [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/01/la-motte-mcc-sparkles-at-sa-terroir-wine-awards/"><![CDATA[<p>The 2008 La Motte Méthode Cape Classique has just been acknowledged as one of the National Winners for cultivar wines by the 2011 Novare SA Terroir Wine Awards.</p>
<p>“<em>With the 2008 MCC Brut being only the second vintage of sparkling wine to have been released from La Motte, we are delighted by this performance</em>”, says Hein Koegelenberg, CEO of La Motte. “<em>Not only do we mature the wine on the lease for 29 months, but we also released just 3300 bottles, so we hold this sparkling wine very dear</em>.”<span id="more-631"></span></p>
<p>Wines certified as a single vineyard wine, an estate produced wine or from a specific ward can participate, hence the term SA Terroir Wine Awards. Made from 60% Pinot Noir and 40% Chardonnay grapes all grown on the foothills of the mountain on La Motte, this wine once again confirms the Franschhoek valley’s expertise with these two traditional cultivars.</p>
<p>Passionate about terroir, La Motte is proud to be associated with the SA Terroir Awards and also wish to congratulate the other winning wineries.</p>
<p>For more information about La Motte Estate, call +27 (0)21 876 8000.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/01/la-motte-mcc-sparkles-at-sa-terroir-wine-awards/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/08/01/la-motte-mcc-sparkles-at-sa-terroir-wine-awards/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[New Spring Festival in Tulbagh]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/07/28/new-spring-festival-in-tulbagh/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/?p=625</id>
		<updated>2011-07-28T16:42:16Z</updated>
		<published>2011-07-28T16:41:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Art and Culture" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="tulbagh" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The his­toric Cape Winelands town of Tulbagh is host­ing a Spring Arts Festival over the week­end of 26–28 August 2011, cel­eb­rat­ing the arts in all their var­ied forms. The fest­ival also coin­cides with the spring wild­flowers, which include sev­eral vari­et­ies of rare endemic bulbs that only flower in the Tulbagh val­ley. It is aimed at [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/07/28/new-spring-festival-in-tulbagh/"><![CDATA[<p>The his­toric <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/capewinelands-attractions.htm" target="_blank">Cape Winelands</a> town of Tulbagh is host­ing a<strong> Spring Arts Festival </strong>over the week­end of <strong>26–28 August 2011</strong>, cel­eb­rat­ing the arts in all their var­ied forms. The fest­ival also coin­cides with the spring wild­flowers, which include sev­eral vari­et­ies of rare endemic bulbs that only flower in the Tulbagh val­ley. It is aimed at rais­ing funds for the Tulbagh Community Gardens and Galgeheuwel Reserve ini­ti­at­ive, which will cre­ate a pub­lic pleas­ure garden for the enjoy­ment of all in his­toric Church Street.</p>
<p>The <strong>Tulbagh Spring Arts Festival </strong>is head­lining with the open­ing of the Christo Coetzee House Museum and Gallery (post renov­a­tion of the dilap­id­ated barn, where Coetzee painted from 1973 until his death in 2000, and the Rhenish mis­sion­ary house where he lived behind the stu­dio.) For the dur­a­tion of the fest­ival the work of past, present and future mas­ters of the val­ley will be on display.</p>
<p>Christo Coetzee is obvi­ously our past mas­ter. The South African Encyclopedia says about Coetzee’s work: <em>“He has broadened art in the sense that he con­trib­uted to the fad­ing of the tra­di­tional bound­ar­ies between paint­ing and sculp­ture and because he insisted on viewer par­ti­cip­a­tion in the cre­at­ive pro­cess. <span id="more-625"></span>As Marcel Duchamp is today known as the twentieth-century father of con­cep­tu­al­ism, so Coetzee is the most import­ant innov­at­ive artist in South Africa.” </em>The exhib­i­tion of Coetzee’s work will also fea­ture a col­lec­tion of pho­to­graphs by award-winning Cape pho­to­grapher Jean du Plessis, entitled: “<em>Christo Coetzee – The Tulbagh Years</em>”.</p>
<p>Vasek Matousek is our present mas­ter. Resident in Tulbagh since 1975, Vasek exhib­its from his extraordin­ary stu­dio in the Winterhoek and will be demon­strat­ing glaz­ing tech­niques and Raku kiln firings.</p>
<p>Tulbagh-born Jannie Du Toit is our future mas­ter – young and tal­en­ted. His early work reflects his Tulbagh roots, although he now lives and works in the city bowl of Cape Town.</p>
<p>For more information see <a href="http://blog.sa-venues.com/provinces/western-cape/tulbagh-spring-arts-festival-2011/">Tulbagh Spring Arts Festival 2011</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/07/28/new-spring-festival-in-tulbagh/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/07/28/new-spring-festival-in-tulbagh/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s Festival Time in Cape Town]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/22/it%e2%80%99s-festival-time-in-cape-town/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/22/it%e2%80%99s-festival-time-in-cape-town/</id>
		<updated>2011-07-28T16:43:11Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-22T13:15:04Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Art and Culture" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Cape Town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Festivals" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Town is gearing up for festival season with many carnivals, creative and music events coming up later this month and throughout March. Infecting the City, an annual public arts initiative, presented by The Africa Centre, offers free performance art happenings in public spaces in the City that are relevant to the theme and significant [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/22/it%e2%80%99s-festival-time-in-cape-town/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/">Cape Town</a> is gearing up for festival season with many carnivals, creative and music events coming up later this month and throughout March.</p>
<p>Infecting the City, an annual public arts initiative, presented by The Africa Centre, offers free performance art happenings in public spaces in the City that are relevant to the theme and significant for Cape Town. This year’s theme, Treasure, engages its audiences with free street experiences such as Xhosa stick-fighting, a Goema Symphony, Ratiep, and flash mobs by inspirational artists from 21 – 26 February 2011. (www.infectingthecity.com)</p>
<p>Cape Town Pride, the City’s next ‘pink’ festival is scheduled for 24 February – 6 March 2011 with an eleven day celebration incorporating events such as a Mr. and Ms. Cape Town Pride pageant, a Pink Ball and the Pride Parade. The different aspects of this combinative event will take place across the city from Cape Town Stadium and gay-friendly suburb, <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/dewaterkant.php">De Waterkant</a>, to <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/mzolis-place.htm">Mzoli’s</a> in Khayelitsha. (http://capetownpride.org)</p>
<p>Amongst many community festivals presented by the ‘One City, Many Cultures Project’ during the month of March, the annual Cape Town Festival is set to take place from 19 – 21 March 2011 in the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/company-gardens.htm">Company Gardens</a>. The Cape Town Festival is in its twelfth year of celebrating National Human Rights Day with music performances by diverse local bands over the three-day period. (www.capetownfestival.co.za)<span id="more-615"></span></p>
<p>Now in its second year and inspired by the famous Rio Carnival, the Cape Town Carnival 2011 is set to offer a glamorous procession of dancers, entertainers, floats and bikes which will parade down Long Street in the City Centre, after which, DJ Fresh gets the street party started. The Cape Town Carnival will take place on 19 March 2011 from 20h30. (www.capetowncarnival.com)</p>
<p>The annual Southern Suburbs Community Chest Carnival will take place between 2 – 5 March this year at Maynardville Park in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/wynberg.php">Wynberg</a>. This event is in its fifty ninth year and offers families a weekend of fun, international food and a spot of local entertainment.</p>
<p>Also in its twelfth year, the Cape Town International Jazz Festival will be held at the Cape Town International Convention Centre from 25 – 26 March 2011. Forty local and international jazz artists, including Grammy award-winning sensation Esperanza Spalding, are set to keep the crowds entertained on five different stages. In addition, there are ‘Gigs for Kids’ and numerous musical workshops available to adults. (www.capetownjazzfest.com)</p>
<p>CEO of Cape Town Tourism, Mariëtte du Toit-Helmbold, urges Capetonians to get into the festival spirit by actively participating in the fun; “The month ahead will be a celebration of all that our colourful, creative city has to offer. It’s going to be an exciting time for residents of the Mother City and much of the action is free, so join in and enjoy sharing your city (and its wealth of inspiring creative talent) with the world.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/22/it%e2%80%99s-festival-time-in-cape-town/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/22/it%e2%80%99s-festival-time-in-cape-town/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Town Gears Up For Design Inspiration]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/21/cape-town-gears-up-for-design-inspiration/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/21/cape-town-gears-up-for-design-inspiration/</id>
		<updated>2011-07-28T16:44:07Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-21T09:06:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Cape Town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Exhibitions Shows" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Town is gearing up to be inspired by all genres of design and an abundance of creativity in the days to come. The Design Indaba Conference and Expo is recognised the world over as a top design and trend event. Drawing the likes of speakers such as Alberto Alessi, Mark Shuttleworth, and Michael Wolff, [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/21/cape-town-gears-up-for-design-inspiration/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/">Cape Town</a> is gearing up to be inspired by all genres of design and an abundance of creativity in the days to come. The Design Indaba Conference and Expo is recognised the world over as a top design and trend event. Drawing the likes of speakers such as Alberto Alessi, Mark Shuttleworth, and Michael Wolff, Design Indaba 2011 is set to add stimulating conversation and a fresh take on creativity and design. The conference runs from 23 – 25 February, with the Expo open to the public between 25 – 27 February at the Cape Town International Convention Centre.</p>
<p>The 2010 Design Indaba Conference and Expo events attracted approximately 37 300 international delegates, media, buyers and members of the public and reinforced Cape Town’s positioning as a design-focused, creatively inspired destination. As part of the annual Design Indaba series of events, the Design Indaba Filmfest 2011 runs from 18-27 February at the Freeworld Design Centre Auditorium.<span id="more-614"></span></p>
<p>The new Freeworld Design Centre is in itself a testament to Cape Town’s creative and design status. Located in the old Cape Waters Building (along the Fan Walk) the building has been given a complete design overhaul and now serves as both a resource centre for the design trade and a place of inspiration for the public. It features a number of room-sized, themed décor exhibitions – designed by top South African creatives – that will change seasonally.</p>
<p>A key event at the Design Indaba Film Festival is a live cyber-workshop with design-for-change guru, Bruce Mau. The MASSIVE CHANGE NETWORK will unfold real plans for design’s role in future change. Other documentaries include stories about design duo, the Vignelli’s, and a study of Yves Saint Laurent, Valentino and Buckminster Fuller.</p>
<p>In addition, the Cape Town Design Route 2011 map will be launched at Design Indaba this year. This year sees the third edition of this popular design map – a creative partnership project between Cape Town Tourism and Design Indaba. The Cape Town Design Route comprises of Western Cape-based Design Indaba exhibitors, from fashion and shoes to dinnerware and toys, who have been approved by a curatorial panel of industry experts ensuring the best in creativity and quality along the route. Some examples of featured artists include: Inkheart Jewellery Design, a Cape Town based studio offering a selection of beautifully handmade pieces of jewellery inspired by childhood stories and memories; Township Patterns, a social enterprise which aims to create a sustainable vehicle for economic empowerment with handmade colourful fabrics inspired by South Africa’s informal settlements and Recreate, original furniture and lighting crafted from repurposed junk items.</p>
<p>Says Mariëtte du-Toit Helmbold, CEO of Cape Town Tourism; “Design is a pillar of our city’s unique identity, not only because we have inspiring and trend-setting creative industries but also because we are committed to using design as a guiding principle in the creation of a city that is future-fit. Often, the word design is associated with glamour, luxury and exclusivity. In fact, socially responsive design is the key to a more sustainable future. Our bid to become World Design Capital 2014 is just one of the ways that Cape Town is staking its claim on the global design landscape and evolving into a top world city to live, work, visit, study and invest in.”</p>
<p>World Design Capital (WDC) is a title awarded every two years to a city that is dedicated to using design for social, cultural and economic development. The award is presented by the International Council of Societies of Industrial Design (ICSID) based in Canada and focuses on developing a year-long programme of design-driven events. The 2010 recipient of the award was Seoul, with Helsinki to be WDC in 2012.</p>
<p>The City of Cape Town’s bid to be World Design Capital 2014 is being coordinated by Cape Town Partnership, and the City will hear whether its bid has been successful before the end of the year. To drive support for the bid, Cape Town Tourism will be sponsoring a “Cape Town for World Design Capital 2014” stand at the Design Indaba Expo.</p>
<p>Bulelwa Makalima-Ngewana, Managing Director of the Cape Town Partnership, believes that the bid will not only be important for Cape Town in 2014, but also in the lead up and well beyond. “The bid book is proving to be a valuable resource and we are looking for a way to turn it into a public working document for the creative industries post the bid. Also, irrespective of whether or not Cape Town is World Design Capital in 2014, the process of bidding and in particular the educational process that is going on towards exposing design in all its relevance to the public, will go a long way in driving Cape Town towards achieving its goal of becoming a Knowledge Economy.”</p>
<p>For more information on the Design Indaba visit www.designindaba.com.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/21/cape-town-gears-up-for-design-inspiration/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/21/cape-town-gears-up-for-design-inspiration/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Town powers up for Night Vision]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/17/cape-town-powers-up-for-night-vision/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/17/cape-town-powers-up-for-night-vision/</id>
		<updated>2011-07-28T16:44:29Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-17T14:16:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Cape Town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Entertainment" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Cape Town Festival’s (CTF) multi-dimensional street festival Night Vision is back by popular demand on Saturday, 12 March from 6pm till midnight. It will take place at the newly revamped Cape Town Station Forecourt, extending festivities into Adderley Street between Strand Street and the fountain. The CTF, incorporating the One City, Many Cultures (1CMC) [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/17/cape-town-powers-up-for-night-vision/"><![CDATA[<p>The Cape Town Festival’s (CTF) multi-dimensional street festival Night Vision is back by popular demand on Saturday, 12 March from 6pm till midnight.</p>
<p>It will take place at the newly revamped Cape Town Station Forecourt, extending festivities into Adderley Street between Strand Street and the fountain. The CTF, incorporating the One City, Many Cultures (1CMC) Project, is supported by the National Lottery Distribution Trust Fund (NLDTF).</p>
<p>After a three-year break, Cape Town’s nocturnal urban street festival, Night Vision, is back with a bang, only this time bigger and better than ever before! Night Vision promises to dominate the city night life with a party-thumping arts and entertainment extravaganza. The event will lead up to a climax of explosive live on-stage performances by iconic bands such as High Voltage Collective featuring EJ Von LYRIK, Theba Shumba and D.form; 340ml; The Dirty Skirts and headline act, 2010 SAMA Award Winners, Big NUZ who will take the party well into midnight.<span id="more-613"></span></p>
<p>The evening programme launches at 6pm amid a vibrant carnival atmosphere complete with street parade, roving buskers, stilt-walkers, mimes, jugglers and loads of other amusement activities. This, juxtaposed with a bustling street market laden with exquisite arts, crafts, vintage collectables and organic market, will leave the whole family spoilt for choice. Food vendors catering to a variety of culinary preferences will provide quality catering service at the food court. Bar facilities will be dotted around the venue.</p>
<p>Powering up the Night Vision stage is High Voltage Collective. This dynamic <a href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/">Cape Town</a> ensemble comprising EJ Von LYRIK, Teba Shumba and D.form blend their individual musical styles to put on a show of electrifying proportions.</p>
<p>A prolific and dynamic songwriter, music producer and performer, the vivacious EJ von Lyrik hails from <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/mitchells-plain.php">Mitchells Plain</a> on the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/cape-flats.htm">Cape Flats</a> and is known for her inspiring and uplifting lyrics fragranced with positive messages. She has been writing and performing her own material since 1997, with a distinct interest in music production. Her music is an eclectic mix of funk, rock, dancehall, hip hop and roots reggae. EJ feels “the reason for this cross-over of musical genres is to reach out to a more diverse audience because the music is message-orientated”. She has performed on various international stages as well as collaborated with some hefty names in the music industry. A former member of the legendary female hip hop group Godessa, EJ has traversed the globe with performances in the Netherlands, Belgium, France, Spain, Norway, Cuba, USA, UK, Ethiopia and Tanzania. Her confident energy, thought provoking lyrics and stirring melodies backed by a solid group of musicians, will be sure to captivate the Night Vision audience.</p>
<p>Teba Shumba is a ragga muffin artist born and raised in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/gugulethu.php">Gugulethu</a>, Cape Town, and whose love for the arts started in community theatre. His music career started with the Kwaito band Skeem who were the proud recipients of the FNB Sama Award for ‘Best Township Pop’ for their debut hit song Waar Was Jy? in 1997. Since the release of his debut soul-afro-reggae-dancehall album 20-5-2-1 Manifesto in 2004, Teba performed at the 2005 Wurzburg Afrika Festival in Germany, sharing the stage with Julian Marley. He also performed at the 2006 Rototom in Italy alongside acclaimed artists like Andrew Tosh, Third World, Alpha Blond and Burning Spear. His dedication and perseverance has allowed him to travel to countries like France, Australia, New Zealand, South Pacific Islands, Solomon Islands, Finland, and closer to home &#8211; Namibia, Botswana, Swaziland and Lesotho. Championing the cause of the voiceless, Teba’s music deals with social justice, universal love and songs of inspiration. His performance is nothing short of exhilarating and massive.</p>
<p>The third party to High Voltage Collective is none other than D.form, a product of a family of eccentric entertainers raised on a strict diet of jazz, soul, funk, reggae, disco and goema. It is therefore no surprise that his passion for the arts was unleashed at the young age of 10 when he joined his first b.boy/break-dance crew and at age 15 was part of his first rap group. He entered many talent shows as a rapper and dancer and went on to join the African Hip Hop Movement in 1988. He formed one of the first graffiti crews in Cape Town known as the Bomb-Crazy Crew and found himself involved with many conscious organisations in the hip hop community involved with acting and speaking out against the crimes and injustice of the Apartheid regime. By starting one of Cape Town’s first monthly hip hop nights known as ‘geto3000’, D.form has been instrumental in bringing together rappers, deejays, b.boys and graffiti artists – the basic four elements of hip hop culture under one roof.</p>
<p>The programme then makes way for the hip hop, African and fusion outfit 340ml, a name taken from the ubiquitous measurement on beverage cans. The Mozambican dub-jazz foursome comprising of Pedro da Silva Pinto on vocals, Paulo Chibanga on drums, Rui Soeiro on bass and Tiago Paulo on guitar, displays an organic musical influence that is unquestionably Latin music subtly laced with traditional Mozambican folk music (Marrabenta), synonymous with the sounds of marimba and the acoustic guitar. Their unique musical style incorporates Dub, Jazz, Ska, Afro-jazz and Reggae. Their debut album Moving was released in 2004 to rave reviews and what follows was nothing short of mass airplay on national radio and television across South Africa. Four years later they released their second album Sorry for the Delay. Apart from South Africa and Mozambique, 340ml has performed in Tanzania, Zimbabwe, Swaziland, Reunion Island, England and France. Their music has been described by leading South African journalists as “an elaborate musical cocktail”, and certainly one that will go down especially well at this sizzling-hot show.</p>
<p>The fiendishly independent alt-indie-rock band The Dirty Skirts is based in Cape Town and is made up of Jess de Tolly on lead vocals and guitar, David Moffatt on guitar, Passion Paliaga on bass and Markie de Menezes on drums. Their sound has segued from rock electro to alt pop, and is steeped in an alternative rock tradition stretching back some forty odd years &#8211; think David Bowie, John Lennon, Talking Heads and The Cure. The band has toured the USA, UK, and the United Emirates. In South Africa they have shared festival stages with Oasis, Snow Patrol, Panic at the Disco, and Evanescence. They have independently recorded and released their eponymous debut mini-album in 2005. Singles such as Feeling the Pressure and Set Me Alight scorched up the local and student charts. The album Daddy Don’t Disco was released in June 2008 and enjoyed four radio play-listed singles. Daddy Don&#8217;t Disco was nominated in the ‘Best Rock Album’ category at the SAMA’s. Winners of the inaugural Red Bull Soundclash, this quirky group will be sure to live up to their reputation of captivating live audiences.</p>
<p>Night Vision will draw to a monumental close with the headline act, 2010 SAMA Award-winning kwaito group, Big NUZ featuring Jojo aka Mampintsha, Mzi aka Danger and Sbu aka R Mashesha. Big because they are doing big things in the music world and NUZ being the vehicle registration prefix for the township of Umlazi next to Durban, from where the trio hails. The group was formed in 2002 when they moved from Durban to Jo’burg to hustle for a record deal. But years of perseverance ultimately paid off. In 2006 they released their debut album Zozo under Gallo Records working with the late Kid Mokoena from Why Not Entertainment. The rest is history. The trio, riding on the strength of its smash hit album, Umlilo, swept three awards – ‘Best Album of the Year’, ‘Best Kwaito Album’ and the prestigious ‘MTN Record of the Year’ &#8211; an accolade for which they were congratulated by President Jacob Zuma. The group also shared the stage with international acts including Rick Ross, T Pain and 2Face at the 2010 MTV African Music Awards and came home with ‘Best Performance Award’. They were also nominated in the category ‘Best Anglophone’. They have performed at a host of prestigious events including Mandela Day and the opening ceremony of the 2010 Soccer World Cup televised to millions of people the world over.</p>
<p>Night Vision is Cape Town’s premier free-to-the-public street festival, originally held on Long Street in the CBD and known for attracting over 30 000 reveling party-goers consisting of both locals and tourists. “With the jam-packed line-up on this year’s entertainment bill, we expect to host our largest audience yet,” said Cape Town Festival Founder and Executive Chairperson, Ryland Fisher, “we are happy to have secured the Cape Town Station Forecourt as the new home of the annual Night Vision in a bid to maximise the infrastructure legacies left behind by the 2010 Soccer World Cup,” he added.</p>
<p>Parking, public transport, road closures, etc. are among those logistical considerations that will be confirmed within the next week.</p>
<p>Night Vision forms part of the CTF’s year-long programme of events which also includes a 1CMC Discussion; Community Youth Workshop Programmes; Senior Citizens Day; Leadership Forum; Multimedia Exhibition; and Community Festivals. These interventions are strategically designed to engage publics at social, educational, business and creative level in the broader Cape Town society to showcase “a united city celebrated for its diversity and liveability.”</p>
<p>The 12th annual CTF kicks off on Friday, 18 March and culminates in the Human Rights Day celebrations on Monday, 21 March at the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/company-gardens.htm">Company’s Garden</a> in the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/attractionswc/cape-town-city-bowl.htm">CBD</a> between 12pm and 8pm daily.</p>
<p>“Celebrating our Cultural Diversity to Connect and Unite Cape Town”<br />
For more information, visit www.capetownfestival.co.za or e-mail info@capetownfestival.co.za</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/17/cape-town-powers-up-for-night-vision/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/17/cape-town-powers-up-for-night-vision/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Hairies’ to be honoured at Splashy Fen]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/10/%e2%80%98hairies%e2%80%99-to-be-honoured-at-splashy-fen/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/10/%e2%80%98hairies%e2%80%99-to-be-honoured-at-splashy-fen/</id>
		<updated>2011-02-10T09:10:44Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-10T09:10:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pietermaritzburg band, the Hairy Legged Lentil Eaters, has been confirmed as the featured act for this year’s Splashy Fen Music Festival, taking place near Underberg in KwaZulu-Natal from April 21-25. The festival coincides with the 20th year of the band’s existence, and is an opportunity to celebrate a shared history that dates back to Splashy [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/10/%e2%80%98hairies%e2%80%99-to-be-honoured-at-splashy-fen/"><![CDATA[<p>Pietermaritzburg band, the Hairy Legged Lentil Eaters, has been confirmed as the featured act for this year’s <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/events/kwazulunatal/splashy-fen-music-festival/">Splashy Fen Music Festival</a>, taking place near <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/underberg.php">Underberg</a> in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/kwazulu_natal.htm">KwaZulu-Natal</a> from April 21-25.  The festival coincides with the 20th year of the band’s existence, and is an opportunity to celebrate a shared history that dates back to Splashy Fen’s early beginnings in 1990.</p>
<p>Described as the most eclectic folk band this side of the Limpopo, the Hairy Legged Lentil Eaters have made an indelible mark on Splashy Fen over the years, never failing to win over audiences with performances that have ranged from the satirical to the bizarre.</p>
<p>Speaking on behalf of the band, vocalist and guitarist Brian Bedingfield said that it was exciting to be offered the featured act billing and to be paid tribute to in this way by a festival that is “in their blood”.</p>
<p>“Either individually or collectively, the Hairies have been at every single Splashy Fen – if not on the bill, then busking and generally spreading good humour.  During the early years, our association with the then <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/pietermaritzburg.php">Pietermaritzburg</a> Folk Club also saw us getting involved in other ways, either as sound engineers, stage managers, crew or MCs.”</p>
<p>Currently, the band plays an active role in the running of the Maritzburg Musicians’ Club, which meets every other Tuesday at The Red Door in Pietermaritzburg.</p>
<p>Catch the Hairy Legged Lentil Eaters on both stages and busking on the rocks at the 22nd Splashy Fen Music Festival this Easter!  Supported by East Coast Radio, the four-day festival will also see performances by the likes of Karen Zoid, Ard Matthews, Dan Patlansky, Madala Kunene, The Rudimentals, Valiant Swart, Good Luck, Wrestlerish, Versus The Wolf, Isochronous, The La Els, City Bowl Mizers, Boulevard Blues, Holiday Murray, Margaret’s Daughter and The Aquarian Quartet, featuring guitar maestros Steve Newman, Syd Kitchen, Greg Georgiades and Tony Cox.  </p>
<p>Tickets cost R500 at Computicket and selected Game stores.  The price includes camping for the entire festival.  For more information, visit www.splashyfen.co.za or contact 031 563 0824.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/10/%e2%80%98hairies%e2%80%99-to-be-honoured-at-splashy-fen/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/10/%e2%80%98hairies%e2%80%99-to-be-honoured-at-splashy-fen/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Grand Daddy Restaurant revived]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/02/the-grand-daddy-restaurant-revived/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/02/the-grand-daddy-restaurant-revived/</id>
		<updated>2011-02-02T10:59:28Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-02T10:59:28Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Cape Town" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Restaurant Reviews" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Known for its creatively-inspired accommodation offering, The Grand Daddy Hotel in Cape Town recently redecorated its restaurant with the help of interior decorator, Tania Reddering. The result is a casual, easy-going eatery for hotel guests and Capetonians to enjoy. King proteas, light wood and white surfaces, scatter cushions and cool turquoise touches give the open-plan [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/02/the-grand-daddy-restaurant-revived/"><![CDATA[<p>Known for its creatively-inspired accommodation offering, <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/visit/thegranddaddyhotel/">The Grand Daddy Hotel</a> in <a href="http://www.cape-venues.co.za/">Cape Town</a> recently redecorated its restaurant with the help of interior decorator, Tania Reddering. The result is a casual, easy-going eatery for hotel guests and Capetonians to enjoy.</p>
<p>King proteas, light wood and white surfaces, scatter cushions and cool turquoise touches give the open-plan space a re-energized feel that nods to the building’s colonial heritage. The clean, light-filled look is a match for the daytime-focus of the restaurant. The menu has also been revised to include easy-going classics and a lovingly crafted burger that is likely to draw rave reviews.  </p>
<p>Now serving a hot breakfast from 6h30 till 12h00 (and a continental buffet until 10h00), The Restaurant has an accessible lunch time menu of crowd-pleasers and an early evening dinner seating on Friday nights. A selection of imported teas from Teabox (teabox.co.za) add intrigue to the teatime experience with the strong aromas of strawberries and rooibos, white peach &#8211;  and spicy chai pervading the air as guests enjoy a tea ceremony with a personalised teapot that filters the tea directly into the cup. </p>
<p>Kids (ten years and under) will also be able to enjoy a menu especially created for them. Patrons will also be able to connect to the internet on their personal laptop with a free 20 MB voucher compliments of Skyrove. As Skyrove only requires the user to insert their cellphone number, no codes or permissions are required from a waiter.</p>
<p>The Restaurant is fully licensed and opens at 06h30 from Mondays to Sundays. It closes at 17h00 from Mondays to Thursdays, 21h30 on Fridays, Saturdays at 19h00 and at 14h00 on Sundays. As with the hotel’s other spaces (The Venue, Daddy Cool, The Airstream Trailer Rooftop), The Restaurant can be hired or incorporated into a total event package. </p>
<p>The Grand Daddy is proudly associated with Jaci’s Lodges in the <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/game-reserves/nwp_madikwe.htm">Madikwe Game Reserve</a> and Cheetah Plains Lodge in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/sabisands.php">Sabi Sands</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/02/the-grand-daddy-restaurant-revived/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/02/the-grand-daddy-restaurant-revived/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese New Year Celebration at Brightwater]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/chinese-new-year-celebration-at-brightwater/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/chinese-new-year-celebration-at-brightwater/</id>
		<updated>2011-02-01T17:11:20Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-01T17:11:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Entertainment" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Festivals" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Gauteng" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Brightwater Commons, in conjunction with the Chinese Embassy in South Africa will be hosting a celebration of the Chinese New Year on Saturday 12th February 2011. To start at 11am, this event will feature a variety of vibrant cultural performances as well as colourful exhibitions that will allow visitors to experience the beauty and [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/chinese-new-year-celebration-at-brightwater/"><![CDATA[<p>The Brightwater Commons, in conjunction with the Chinese Embassy in <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/">South Africa</a> will be hosting a celebration of the Chinese New Year on Saturday 12th February 2011.  To start at 11am, this  event will feature a variety of vibrant cultural performances as well as colourful exhibitions that will allow visitors to experience the beauty and diversity of the Chinese culture.</p>
<p>Whilst the exhibitions and stalls will open at 11am, the entertainment programme will begin at 1pm with an official opening ceremony.  This will be followed by the ever popular and spectacular Lion and Dragon dances.  Other performances that will dazzle and delight visitors will include an acrobatics, contortion and fire act; traditional Umbrella and Fan dancing, as well as demonstrations of martial arts.  </p>
<p>The event&#8217;s highlight will be a set of acts by the talented Yunnan Arts Troupe originating from Yunnan, which is regarded as China&#8217;s most culturally diverse province.  The professional 14 member troupe will reflect the colour and culture of the province through the dances of the region&#8217;s different ethnic minorities.  They will also present a delightful magic show and Tibetan songs.</p>
<p>Visitors can also see a variety of cultural exhibitions, from arts and crafts all the way to clothing; and enjoy lunch on the commons as there will be numerous food stalls specializing in different kinds of delicious Chinese cuisine ranging from stir-fried dishes  to sweet treats.   The celebrations will close at 5pm.</p>
<p>According to the Chinese Zodiac calendar, 2011 is the Year of the Rabbit.  To the Chinese people, speed, strength and kindness of heart are traits associated with the rabbit.  They therefore believe that those born in the Year of the Rabbit are clever, romantic, modest and merciful.  The rabbit is the 4th animal on the calendar, which dates back to more than  2000 years ago.  There are 12 animals on the calendar which works in 12 year cycles.  The Chinese believe that these animals appeared before Buddha or the Jade Emperor.  The animals are listed on the calendar in their order of arrival, starting with the rat and followed by the ox, tiger, rabbit, dragon, snake, horse, goat, monkey, rooster, dog and pig. </p>
<p>For more information on the Chinese New Year Celebrations at The Brightwater Commons contact Francois on 011 789 5052. </p>
<p>See <a href="http://www.sa-venues.com/accommodation/randburg.php">Randburg Accommodation</a> to find a place to stay for this event.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/chinese-new-year-celebration-at-brightwater/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/chinese-new-year-celebration-at-brightwater/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Sensational New Home &amp; Living Show for KwaZulu Natal]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/sensational-new-home-living-show-for-kwazulu-natal/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/sensational-new-home-living-show-for-kwazulu-natal/</id>
		<updated>2011-02-01T10:49:14Z</updated>
		<published>2011-02-01T10:48:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Exhibitions Shows" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="KwaZulu Natal" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s out with the old and in with the new in typical Decorex Durban style. And yet, this time around it’s with a sensational new twist! From 18 – 21 March 2011, at the Durban Exhibition Centre, Decorex SA in collaboration with the KSA Kitchen &#038; Bathroom Faire will play proud hosts to an all [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/sensational-new-home-living-show-for-kwazulu-natal/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s out with the old and in with the new in typical Decorex Durban style. And yet, this time around it’s with a sensational new twist! </p>
<p>From 18 – 21 March 2011, at the Durban Exhibition Centre, Decorex SA in collaboration with the KSA Kitchen &#038; Bathroom Faire will play proud hosts to an all new and totally fabulous décor, design and lifestyle exhibition.  With the launch of Trends &#038; Tastes 2011 Durban’s décor and design fundis can look forward to a veritable feast of design trends, delightful décor and the very best in good living. </p>
<p>Expertly conceptualised and created to offer a fusion of the finest in everything about the home, living and lifestyle, Trends &#038; Tastes 2011 will look to provide the answers to those in search of ultimate sophistication. Give insight into what defines uber-chic and open doors to preciously guarded, exquisite pieces.  All within a sophisticated yet relaxed environment that gives you the time and space to indulge the senses and defy sensibility – even if for a moment.</p>
<p>Cairey Slater, Decorex SA General Manager Exhibitions &#038; Events is confident and excited about the launch of this all new show for Durban, “Trends &#038; Tastes 2011 is an original offering that will bring a fashionable mix of home, décor, design and living under one very glam roof.  We are super-excited about the variety and uniqueness on offer and we’re aiming to rock Durban by creating a relaxed yet cosmopolitan and forward-thinking experience. The beauty of Trends &#038; Tastes 2011 has to be that there will be something for everyone.  It’s all about a great day out and an opportunity to find the way of creating the space and life that you love.”  </p>
<p>Here’s a sneak peak into what Durbanites [and those wanting to visit SA’s newest and hottest show!] can expect from Trends &#038; Tastes 2011:</p>
<p>Trendy Décor &#038; Design: A showcase of top décor and design talent from Durban’s amazing gene-pool and the promise of impressive heavy weights’ is on the cards. If it’s décor you’re into this is one show you don’t want to miss! From decorators and designers, to inspiring room settings, furniture, stylish accessories and fabric houses we’ve got the trendiest décor and design line-up in town!</p>
<p>Kitchens &#038; Bathrooms: Our range of kitchens will make even the novice want to whip out their wok and our bathrooms will provide pure inspiration! The KSA are back in full force and Trend’s &#038; Tastes promises to showcase the country’s largest, leading collaboration of specialist spaces! </p>
<p>Tantalising Tastes: Enjoy our organic food market and all things delectable in District Delicious. For foodies and those that love to roll up their sleeves, keep an eye out for an awesome schedule of free sessions and be sure to make a date with our line-up of big name stars and international guests. We’ll also be featuring a range of Durban’s top restaurants and a feast of delish delights to savour while at the show, so make sure you come hungry! </p>
<p>Expert Advice: From Plascon’s launch of their ‘love’ inspired 2011 colour forecast to the Living Green House – where an entire home is created and everything from frames to flooring ease our environmental footprint make sure you get the most of out of the free consultation you need to get you on track with your interior project.  Make a date to spend time in our DStv Theatre of Ideas or Ask the Experts area and come away with all the tools, insights and inspiration that you need for your very own home. Whether your creation is gourmet artwork on a plate or a tastefully recycled ‘Louis’, a paradise of demonstrations and interactive sessions awaits!  </p>
<p>A Great Day Out: The Good Living Pavilion incorporating a range of attractive options for lifestyle estates as well as an invigorating wellness arena promise to make it an entertaining and fabulous day for the family.  Live entertainment, with food and drinks from some of Durban’s best restaurateurs further add to this great day out.  Keep an eye out for amazing prizes and competitions that we’ll be running during the show and stand a chance of winning thousands in trendy home décor, design and lifestyle items! </p>
<p>With a line-up of show-stopping fashionable ‘home-wear’, the best in design and décor talent, a twist of lifestyle enablers, all things trendy and tasteful and a splash of fabulous family entertainment, Durban’s new show Trends &#038; Tastes 2011 is set to top even its predecessor is certainly one not to be missed!  Visit www.decorex.co.za for more. Trends and Tastes is proudly sponsored by Plascon, with DStv as media partner.</p>
<p>Links: To find a place to stay see <a href="http://www.durban-venues.co.za/">Durban Accommodation</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/sensational-new-home-living-show-for-kwazulu-natal/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/02/01/sensational-new-home-living-show-for-kwazulu-natal/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WELLINGTON WINE HARVEST FESTIVAL &#8211; REAP THE FUN]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/wellington-wine-harvest-festival-reap-the-fun/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/wellington-wine-harvest-festival-reap-the-fun/%</id>
		<updated>2011-01-19T12:09:50Z</updated>
		<published>2011-01-19T12:09:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Festivals" /><category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Western Cape" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[From 19 – 21 March 2011 Wellington dons its festive costume when this quaint Boland town which was named 2010 SA Terroir Top Wine Area celebrates the bounty of the harvest at the 5th Wine Harvest Festival. Spend the day or make sure you don’t miss any of the action and book in for the [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/wellington-wine-harvest-festival-reap-the-fun/"><![CDATA[<p>From 19 – 21 March 2011 Wellington dons its festive costume when this quaint Boland town which was named 2010 SA Terroir Top Wine Area celebrates the bounty of the harvest at the 5th Wine Harvest Festival.  Spend the day or make sure you don’t miss any of the action and book in for the weekend for an extraordinary array of fun-filled activities for the whole family.  </p>
<p>Big names like Steve Hofmeyr, Adam Tas and the newly crowned Idols winner Elvis Blue will get your hands clapping, while opera lovers can experience a cultural evening around a piece of Wellington history, the Black Countess.   Live music will follow you wherever you go throughout the day. </p>
<p>Treat your taste buds with the region’s premium wines, out of the box food parings such as vodka and sushi, and brandy and chocolate, or oysters and bubbly on a topless bus.  Buy slow food from the country market; or show your prowess with the potjie in the international potjiekos competition. </p>
<p>The adrenalin junkies will be spoilt for choice with the quad bike trail, the Bain’s trail run or even just a messy round of grape stomping.  Take it a bit slower while still breathing the fresh autumn air – join the Wine-on-foot@Blouvlei 5km long vineyard walk in the Bovlei area.  Make sure to bring the kids for the tractor and pony rides, and an endless supply of ice-cream. </p>
<p>Only R60 (kids under 13 enter free) promises a full weekend of fun and laughter and lip-smacking taste experiences for the whole family. Festival armbands, your entry ticket, are available from all participating farms and the Wellington Information Office. Special Monday armbands are available at R30 per person. </p>
<p>For more information, the full programme and a list of participating farms contact Emma at tel 021 873 4604, email info@wellington.co.za or visit www.harvestfestival.co.za</p>
<p>Emma Follett-Botha<br />
Tourism Officer<br />
Wellington Tourism<br />
(021) 873 4604</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/wellington-wine-harvest-festival-reap-the-fun/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/wellington-wine-harvest-festival-reap-the-fun/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>SA Blog Editor</name>
						<uri>http://www.southafricablog.co.za</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[RAMFEST V – CAPE TOWN, JOHANNESBURG, DURBAN – MARCH 2011]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/ramfest-v/" />
		<id>http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/ramfest-v/%</id>
		<updated>2011-01-19T10:34:45Z</updated>
		<published>2011-01-19T10:34:45Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.southafricablog.co.za" term="Events" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the summer season hits it`s peak so does the festival circuit. RAMfest is upon us once more. This year, RAMfest, boasts 3 venues in 3 cities, over 5 days, across 6 stages. That’s right! RAMfest will be visiting 3 major cities in 2011. This helps to cement the event`s reputation as one of South [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/ramfest-v/"><![CDATA[<p>As the summer season hits it`s peak so does the festival circuit. RAMfest is upon us once more. </p>
<p>This year, RAMfest, boasts 3 venues in 3 cities, over 5 days, across 6 stages. That’s right! RAMfest will be visiting 3 major cities in 2011. This helps to cement the event`s reputation as one of South Africa’s Ultimate Rock Festivals. </p>
<p>We are happy to announce that this year`s line up includes two international bands: Alkaline Trio (USA) and Funeral for a Friend. (UK) Biographies and photos attached. Die Antwoord, Van Coke Kartel and Zebra and Giraffe are the local acts that will be performing at all three RAMfest events. For the rest of the regional line ups, see listing below. </p>
<p>John Vlismas will be the host for RAMfest all round in all three the provinces. Here are the dates:</p>
<p>CPT: Nekkies Holiday Resort, Worcester: 4 – 6 March.<br />
DBN: WaveHouse: Wed 9 March.<br />
JHB:  Riversands Farm, Fourways: Sat 12 March.</p>
<p>RAMfest has left a permanent footprint on the live music scene&#8230;&#8230;Celebrating 5 years of Rock n Roll, the festival is set to raise the bar yet again. Not only are we going to deliver the music that you all love, we’re also breaking into some new genres that we feel deserve showcasing. If you thought the festival was good, great, fun, mind-blowing or any other positive adjective that you might want to use, then how do we prepare you for what’s about to come? </p>
<p>We’re adding a bigger Dance stage, more and better camping facilities and we have a couple of surprises up our sleeve. Fasten your seatbelts for the thrills that are about jolt you right out of your seat and into the most super-rad party mood. </p>
<p>Calling all fearless warriors, emotionally stunted, corporate sucks, internet tycoons, recently single ready to mingle, goody-two-shoes, rebels with and without a cause, black sheep, white sheep; this means YOU!! Hell we’re even calling the little green men out in space if they can hear us.</p>
<p>Come to Ramfest with us!</p>
<p>LINE UP CAPE TOWN:<br />
MAIN STAGE:<br />
Alkaline Trio (USA), Funeral for a Friend (UK), Die Antwoord, Gazelle, Zebra and Giraffe, Van Coke Kartel, The Revelators,  Blk Jks, Ashtray Electric, Desmond &#038; The Tutu’s, Mr Cat &#038; The Jackal,Stepdog, Pretty Blue Guns, The Great Apes, Tumi, Ree-Burth, Dance! You’re on Fire, The Sleepers, Isochronous, Not My Dog, Lonely Dave Ferguson, Wrestlerish, 7th Son, Bittereinder, Mix n Blend.</p>
<p>ALTERNATIVE STAGE:<br />
Down on the first, Moment of Clarity, Knave, Mind Assault, Contrast The Water, The Broken Result, Infanteria, Haggis &#038; Bong, Symphonic Schizophrenia, Juggernaught, Sabertooth, Enmity, Theatre Runs Red, a Walk with the Wicked, The Dead Will Tell, Axxon.</p>
<p>ELECTRONIC STAGE:<br />
Jam Jar, Psydstep, Bruce Willis?, P.H Fat,  Niskerone, Counterstrike, Hyphen, SFR, Mr Bong, Fletcher, Sedge Warbler, Toby2Shoes, Kennedy, Battle Beyond The Stars, Ill Tastic, El Gordo, Enough Weapons, Haezer, TOM DELUXX (FRA), Double Adapter, Liver, B-Team and more.</p>
<p>BEACH PARTY:<br />
Haasbroek, Tommygun, FunaFuji, Mr. Sakitumi.</p>
<p>LINE UP JOHANNESBURG:<br />
MAIN STAGE:<br />
Alkaline Trio (USA), Funeral For A Friend (UK), Not My Dog, Die Antwoord, Zebra &#038; Giraffe, Van Coke Kartel, Pestroy, Dance Your&#8217;re on Fire, Isochronous, Knave, Pity The Fool, Blk Jks, Desmond &#038; The Tutu&#8217;s, The Shadowclub.</p>
<p>DANCE STAGE:<br />
RudeOne, Deeziak, CutKeyLow,Tasha Baxter, Ambush, Bittereinder, Benson</p>
<p>LINE UP DURBAN:<br />
Alkaline Trio (USA), Funeral For A Friend (UK), Die Antwoord, Zebra &#038; Giraffe, Van Coke Kartel.</p>
<p>FACILITIES:</p>
<p>ENTERTAINMENT AREA<br />
Stages, bars and stalls will be inside a fenced off entertainment area. </p>
<p>BEER GARDEN<br />
LARGE TENTED bar areas, with tables, benches and parasols = BEER GARDEN. </p>
<p>PARKING<br />
first come first served, you may camp at your cars. Gate opening times: See at www.ramfest.co.za</p>
<p>ATM&#8217;s<br />
&#8230;will be placed around the entertainment area. </p>
<p>MARKET<br />
We strive to bring you the best in festival foods, affordable yet healthy and delicious. Catering for everybody&#8217;s needs, clothing and other festival paraphernalia also.<br />
a Merchandise stand with credit/debit card facilities will be there again.</p>
<p>To book stalls please contact:<br />
Cape Town: mari@ramfest.co.za<br />
Johannesburg:  ingeborg@hilltoplive.co.za </p>
<p>MEDICS<br />
We have professional medics on site, with all necessary emergency equipment, bring your own headache tablets and please PARTY SAFE!</p>
<p>GREEN<br />
Please help to keep us as environmentally friendly as possible. Bring rubbish bags to keep your area clean. All rubbish bags will be collected by our cleaners and sorted into the relevant recycling bins. PLEASE LEAVE GLASS AT HOME!!</p>
<p>SNOW CAFE &#8211; MULTIMEDIA CITY – Cape Town only.<br />
Snow Café is a multimedia tented area offering various forms of entertainment. Drop in, relax and blow off some steam. Our friendly staff will make you feel right at home and will ensure you are energized for that next round. </p>
<p>What is on offer:<br />
* Lost &#038; Found<br />
* Information centre<br />
* Phone charging<br />
* Slush &#038; Snack Bar</p>
<p>CAMPING and SWIMMING – Cape Town only.<br />
RAM is a full weekend camping outing, bring your tents caravan&#8217;s and camping gear. It is HOT that time of the year so bring extra shade i.e. Gazebo&#8217;s stretch tents, sun hats, umbrellas. There is a river and Swimmingpool for cooling off, don&#8217;t forget your inflatables. NO open fires will be tolerated.</p>
<p>KREEF HOTEL (Cape Town only) is happy to announce that they will be setting up their point five star festival tent hotel at the RAMfest 2011. Pre-pitched bow tents with mattresses &#038; locks. Secure parking, lighting &#038; 24-hour security. Luggage porters (to help you rest your case), daily breakfast, coffee on tap, cell-phone (cameras, laptops) charging facilities and even a private little bar just for you. Clean toilets (a ply within) &#038; our famous hot showers, exclusively for Kreef guests. All this and more super service crawling distance from the RAMfest stages, at a price to fit your pocket. Rock Hard, Sleep Soft&#8230; KREEF HOTEL …the calm thing is to remain important&#8230; BOOK NOW </p>
<p>Cape Town only: There are daily trains leaving from CPT to Worcester. Once at Worcester catch a taxi ride to the festival.</p>
<p>TICKETS:<br />
Tickets available from Ticketbreak.co.za </p>
<p>Cape Town:<br />
3 day wk/end pass: R450 presales. R500 at gate.<br />
Sat/Sun pass: R450 presales. R500 at gate.<br />
1 day Sunday pass: R100 gate only (entry from 08:00)</p>
<p>Johannesburg:<br />
Presales: R250.00 and R300 at gate. </p>
<p>Durban:<br />
Presales: R200 and R250 at gate.</p>
<p>STRICTLY NO:Under16&#8242;s. Children must be accompanied by a responsible adult over 21, Glass bottles (please decant your drinks into plastic bottles), Littering (Leave No Trace, remove your camping litter!), Fireworks, Domestic animals, Graffiti, Bad attitudes, Weapons, Independent sound systems, illegal substances, Don&#8217;t drink & drive; P:L:U:R.</p>
<p>RIGHT OF ADMISSION RESERVED. Entry is entirely at your own risk. The promoters accept no responsibility whatsoever for injury, death, loss or damage of any nature to persons, vehicles &#038; belongings. This applies even to negligence of any kind by the promoters, venue and contractors. All rights reserved.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/ramfest-v/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.southafricablog.co.za/2011/01/19/ramfest-v/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
