<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>living4Impactliving4Impact</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.living4impact.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.living4impact.com</link>
	<description>The Challenge: Running from Montreal to New York City for charity. The Result: Unknown. Follow me over the next few months as I prepare, both physically and emotionally, for my journey. I will share my insights and struggles in the hope of inspiring and motivating you to set goals for yourself and push your own limits.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 20:06:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Climbing the Steps One at a Time</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/17/climbing-the-steps-one-at-a-time/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/17/climbing-the-steps-one-at-a-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 20:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenging Yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goal Setting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenging yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goal setting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no excuses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushing the limits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surpassing yourself]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=415</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week was our dreaded Mount-Royal step climbing workout&#8230;we had heard nightmare stories about it. People wanting to quit or barely being able to complete climbing them. Most of us were anticipating what was to come. Would we be able to get through it? I know I was stressed out. I<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/17/climbing-the-steps-one-at-a-time/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week was our dreaded Mount-Royal step climbing workout&#8230;we had heard nightmare stories about it. People wanting to quit or barely being able to complete climbing them. Most of us were anticipating what was to come. Would we be able to get through it? I know I was stressed out. I had been feeling sick for the last 2 days, I had had tough days at work, but worst of all I didn&#8217;t want a repeat of the <a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/08/moment-of-discouragement-moment-of-realization/">previous week&#8217;s workout.</a> I had struggled and hit my wall last week. I wasn&#8217;t prepared to do that again this week. Would the infamous steps get the best of me?</p>
<p>For those who are not familiar with the Mount-Royal steps there are approximately 260 of them. Our task was to climb them over and over again&#8230;until we&#8217;ve completed 10 rounds of 260 steps. If an average flight of stairs is approximately 12 steps, we climbed almost 10 flights of stairs&#8230;10 times!!!</p>
<p>We did the first climb at a slow pace. Even at a slow pace by the time I got to the last 10 steps I could really feel the burn. But, overall I felt good. One down, nine more to go. Of course we weren&#8217;t going to be climbing each time at a slow pace. This is a physical challenge after all! The next three climbs had to be done at a faster speed with a quicker completion time then our slow climb. As a group we now had to complete the climb up the 260 steps in about 15 seconds faster than the first climb. This was a challenge. But we now had 4 climbs done.  Climb 5 was a recuperation climb &#8211; as much as anyone can recuperate climbing up 260 steps!!</p>
<p>Climb 6 through 8 entailed having at least one person of our team being carried up the steps at all times during the climb. For most in the group these climbs were easier than the individual climb up because the focus was about making sure we didn&#8217;t drop our team member. I didn&#8217;t really feel the same &#8211; all the climbs were tough!! Climb 9 was supposedly our last climb up so we had to go as fast as possible. After a few weeks of training with the coaches of Montreal-New York I know very well that this wasn&#8217;t going to be the case. Of course, 9 climbs was not enough, 10 was a much better number! Again we went up as fast as possible.</p>
<p>Wow 260 steps 10 times! What an accomplishment! Especially after all the stress of the days before seeing the posts on Facebook from the other participants about the toughness of the week&#8217;s challenge. I had gotten wrapped up in all the hype and let it get to my head. I had doubts that I would be able to get through it. The hamster in my head (as one of my fellow participants, Marie-Lou, likes to refer to the negative self-talk we create for ourselves) was running wild! Funny how that hamster never tells us we&#8217;ll be able to get through the challenge in front of us. Well after accomplishing this physical challenge I can say I shut that damn hamster up!</p>
<p>Going down those 260 steps for the last time after having officially completing the climbs left me feeling so satisfied and proud of myself and everyone else who had completed the challenge. We did it! We did it as a team! I could barely see the steps as I was going down that last time as tears were overflowing. I had proved to myself that I can. Last week was a blimp in the road; a challenge that pushed me to have more faith in my abilities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/17/climbing-the-steps-one-at-a-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working on my Running Technique</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/11/working-on-my-running-technique/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/11/working-on-my-running-technique/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Running Technique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Working Out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running outside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workout]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=390</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the last few weeks I&#8217;ve been working on my running technique. With the coaches of the Montreal-New York Challenge we were able to record on video ourselves running on a treadmill and analyse what we saw as a group. The video allowed us to see for ourselves how we<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/11/working-on-my-running-technique/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few weeks I&#8217;ve been working on my running technique. With the coaches of the Montreal-New York Challenge we were able to record on video ourselves running on a treadmill and analyse what we saw as a group.</p>
<p>The video allowed us to see for ourselves how we run. I had suspected that my running technique was not optimal, but seeing it on tape was proof that I had elements to work on. For one, I was surprised to see that my center of gravity when landing was pretty much under my body. This is good. Ideally, you want your foot to fall down in line with your upper body. This will allow a lessening of pressure on your lower back that may be caused if you lean too far forward.</p>
<p>Before even watching myself on tape I expected to see my heel hitting the ground before my forefoot. I know this is not good, and this is exactly what I saw. Your foot should be hitting the ground near the middle foot area and not the heel. A good image to keep in mind when trying to correct this error in technique is to think about being barefoot in your bathroom and suddenly the phone rings and you rush off to answer. Does your heel land first or does your mid-fore foot? Naturally you will start that dash for the phone with your forefoot. By landing this way you are able to achieve maximum power while you push-off. You also save valuable energy.</p>
<p>One last pointer that stuck with me is that running should be a fluid movement that does not generate too much noise. You shouldn&#8217;t be pounding the pavement. Running should be a fairly silent process. Your movement should be springy and light.</p>
<p>In my last few runs I&#8217;ve paid particular attention to these elements of my running. I can see and hear the difference. My body is thanking me for the small corrections I am making with each run.</p>
<p>For more info on running technique you can check out the following:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.runnersworld.com/running-tips/perfect-form">http://www.runnersworld.com/running-tips/perfect-form</a></p>
<p>And here&#8217;s a quick video with the key points to remember:</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='584' height='359' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Tx6x2cD6Y8Q?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/11/working-on-my-running-technique/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moment of Discouragement, Moment of Realization</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/08/moment-of-discouragement-moment-of-realization/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/08/moment-of-discouragement-moment-of-realization/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 13:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenging Yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenging yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushing the limits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[runner empathy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running teamwork]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=400</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sometimes you need to take two steps back to be able to move forward. Last night I probably took 10 steps back. There is what happened.   I hit a physical and mental wall last night. It was our weekly group training and boy was I not ready for what<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/08/moment-of-discouragement-moment-of-realization/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Sometimes you need to take two steps back to be able to move forward. Last night I probably took 10 steps back. There is what happened.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I hit a physical and mental wall last night. It was our weekly group training and boy was I not ready for what was to come. We had to run and cover a certain distance in 15 seconds, 15 seconds rest and repeat and repeat and repeat&#8230;all of this in about 8 inches of snow. I found the first sprint hard. By the 4 or 5th one I could barely catch my breath before starting the next sprint. After about 6 repetitions I thought my torture was over. The mental wall really came when we were told we would be doing it all over again.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>No. I can&#8217;t. How? Please make it stop. Those were the only things going through my head. Those 15 seconds seemed like huge mountains. I know it&#8217;s all a question of perspective and if you put your mind to it you can achieve anything. But I just couldn&#8217;t get there.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The worst was the pressure I created for myself seeing all the other participants pushing through their own pain and doing it. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Then I really cracked. With two sprints left I stopped. I couldn&#8217;t do it anymore. The group went ahead and did their two last sprints. I could hear them. I wanted to turn around and encourage them to keep going, but I couldn&#8217;t. I felt like such a traitor. They were struggling. They were hurting. But, they were doing it. It killed me to think that I let them down and didn&#8217;t push through. Emotional breakdown.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I disappointed myself. I let the doubts take over. I disappointed my team.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>If I can&#8217;t manage to run a few 15 second sprints how will I ever get to New York?</div>
<div> </div>
<blockquote>
<div>Develop success from failures. Discouragement and failure are two of the surest stepping stones to success. Dale Carnegie</div>
</blockquote>
<div>What amazed me is how supportive everyone was. They comforted me. They reassured me that I wasn&#8217;t a disappointment. Their words and gentil touch made all the difference. This is why we push each other physically during the challenge. We get to see that despite the pain, despite the struggles and the mental breakdowns we survive. We survive hopefully to be stronger. Stronger together.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I always put lots of pressure on myself to keep up with the group. I don&#8217;t want to break the pace. But in the back of my head I always have that perception of myself as a non-athlete. I can&#8217;t keep up because I&#8217;m not as strong as the others. I don&#8217;t have the natural ability or the cardio. I always put myself at the bottom of the pack.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>On the way home in my car after the workout last night I realized something&#8230;I was out there. I was running with everyone. I wasn&#8217;t at home on my couch listening to tv. I was moving. I was participating in a sport. I wasn&#8217;t being lazy. I&#8217;ve run 5km races. 10km races. A half-marathon for God&#8217;s sake. Fuck that, I AM AN ATHLETE!</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Last night made me realize that I need to be nicer to myself. Just like my team was with me. I am part of the team. I can measure up. I am not a non-athlete as I often refer to myself. I can compete. I can push my limits. <strong><em>I am an athlete. It&#8217;s as simple as that.</em></strong></div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/08/moment-of-discouragement-moment-of-realization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Running Injuries: Big Scare, Big Realizations</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/06/running-injuries-big-scare-big-realizations/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/06/running-injuries-big-scare-big-realizations/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 01:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenging Yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Working Out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[injury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working out]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=382</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last weekend I was working out at the gym; after a few leg exercises I decided to do squats. I go in position, squatted down and pushed back up until&#8230;a sharp pain in my left knee. I managed to get back up in a standing position and figured it was<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/06/running-injuries-big-scare-big-realizations/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend I was working out at the gym; after a few leg exercises I decided to do squats. I go in position, squatted down and pushed back up until&#8230;a sharp pain in my left knee. I managed to get back up in a standing position and figured it was just a false movement. I got in position again and squatted down. Again a sharp pain in my left knee on the way back up. After 5-6 tries I decided squats were definitely not a good idea for me at the moment.</p>
<p>I was able to walk without too much pain, but the idea of squatting down again and injuring myself more freaked me out too much. That was pretty much the end of my workout for the day. Back home my boyfriend convinced me to ice my knee. Then I made the mistake many people make&#8230;I got on the internet and started researching sharp knee pain. The scare of a torn meniscus was just too much. I have a big running challenge coming up. I&#8217;ve invested countless hours of training and lots of energy trying to raise money for the cause. Doing all of this and not being able to participate in the challenge would be horrible.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been very lucky in the last year since I&#8217;ve started running more seriously. Aside from some sheen pain for a few weeks last year I&#8217;ve been injury free. Last year before the Montreal half marathon a friend suffered an injury that stopped him from participating in the marathon. Reading his updates online on whether he would be able to run or not was heartbreaking. I know what kind of training a long distance race takes, and getting to a few days before the big race day and realizing you will not be able to race after all is a horrible feeling.</p>
<p>It made me think of the olympic athletes and all the years of training and sacrifice they go through to get to the games&#8230;and the disastrous news that an injury will not allow them to participate. I can&#8217;t imagine. It takes great courage to manage through that.</p>
<p>If you want to see real courage and determination through injury watch this video. It will surely inspire you (it inspires me every time I watch it):</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='584' height='359' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/rCAwXb9n7EY?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>Thankfully, in the end, after some ice and rest my knee is thankfully doing much better.  <img src='http://www.living4impact.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/06/running-injuries-big-scare-big-realizations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working Out Together with 250 People&#8230;Wow!</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/04/working-out-together-with-250-people-wow/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/04/working-out-together-with-250-people-wow/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Working Out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pushing the limits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[team]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workout]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=375</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few Sundays ago was our first full group training. We usually train weekly with 2 other teams (we are teams of 8 so typically our weekly workouts are with 24 other participants), but this workout was with all of the 250 participants in the Montreal-New York City challenge. I typically<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/04/working-out-together-with-250-people-wow/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few Sundays ago was our first full group training. We usually train weekly with 2 other teams (we are teams of 8 so typically our weekly workouts are with 24 other participants), but this workout was with all of the 250 participants in the Montreal-New York City challenge.</p>
<p>I typically workout on my own, so every week it&#8217;s an adaptation for me to workout with 24 other people&#8230;250 other people is a whole different ballgame!</p>
<p>It was great! It was like being back in grade school at recess time! We were all running around trying to catch each other, rolling on the ground, and just having a great time. It was great to see all the different types of people participating in this challenge. Athletes, non-athletes, young, older&#8230;this is a challenge for ALL.</p>
<p>Before all this play and fun we were given a conference on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biofeedback">biofeedback</a> and nutrition. All great information. I especially liked the biofeedback part, more specifically the cardiac coherence part. In layman&#8217;s terms, cardiac coherence is about getting your breathing in line with your heart rate. Cardiac coherence will release chemicals in your body and allow you to more effectively face the physical challenge ahead. It is amazing everything the human body does when faced with different stressful situations. The example that stuck out for me was in front of a hill you can either choose to breath and take it one step at a time or be unfocused and struggle all the way up. The hill is the same &#8211; it doesn&#8217;t suddenly become steeper. The physical condition of the person running it is the same. The mindset is different. </p>
<p>A lot about running, and physical exercise in general, is about mental strength. You can have the best conditions lined up for a great workout and it turns out to be disastrous and vice versa. Last week for example, I had had bad news on the family front, I was tired and I decided to go for a run in the evening after supper. I never run in the evening, much less on a full stomach. But I knew I needed that run. I knew that it would do me a world of good. I knew I would be happy I did it. I decided to try some cardiac coherence and I adopted the right mindset. In the end it served me well because it was a great run.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m learning a lot of valuable information with this challenge and I&#8217;m excited to apply it more regularly in my individual training.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/03/04/working-out-together-with-250-people-wow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominated for a Bloggie Award!!!</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/28/nominated-for-a-bloggie-award/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/28/nominated-for-a-bloggie-award/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 21:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Goal Setting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog Awards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=370</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was so happy to find out this weekend that Blogging4Impact was nominated for a Bloggie 2013 Award!!! I am nominated in the Best-Kept Secret category. I took a look at the other nominees and I do have to say it&#8217;s quite an honor. &#8221;It&#8217;s an honor just to be nominated&#8221; is definitely not<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/28/nominated-for-a-bloggie-award/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was so happy to find out this weekend that Blogging4Impact was nominated for a Bloggie 2013 Award!!! I am nominated in the Best-Kept Secret category. I took a look at the other nominees and I do have to say it&#8217;s quite an honor. &#8221;It&#8217;s an honor just to be nominated&#8221; is definitely not an understatement!</p>
<p>For those not familiar, the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/" target="_blank">Bloggies</a> (or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Weblog_Awards_(Bloggies)" target="_blank">Weblog Awards</a>) are the longest running (since 2001) and one of the largest blog awards, with winners determined through internet voting by the public. This is Big my friends!!!</p>
<p>Who would have thought that a crazy decision one day to run for charity from Montreal to New York City and write a blog about it would mean I would be recognized by my peers?!</p>
<p> <a href="http://www.living4impact.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/running-race-winner.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-371 alignleft" alt="race" src="http://www.living4impact.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/running-race-winner.png" width="260" height="260" /></a></p>
<p>I started writing this blog as a way to reach out to people and share my thoughts. Having an impact with what I write is always on my mind. If I can make one person think differently about their lifestyle and the choices they make it&#8217;s all worth it. Since I started writing Blogging4Impact I&#8217;ve started to see life differently. I&#8217;m constantly thinking about what can I write about next? Where do I want to take this whole adventure? What can I write about that will interest people and make them think differently?</p>
<p>I am doing my blog out of my own time (limited time, I have to say because of work and of course training to <a href="http://espritdecorps.biz/en/foundation/montreal-new-york" target="_blank">run from Montreal to New York City</a>!), but I love doing it. And I want to do more of it!</p>
<p>If you like my work and would like to encourage me don&#8217;t hesitate to vote for me by choosing Blogging4Impact in the Best-Kept Secret category: <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/">http://2013.bloggi.es/</a> Voting ends March 17.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/28/nominated-for-a-bloggie-award/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Doing, Start Performing, Continue Achieving</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/25/stop-start-continue-framework/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/25/stop-start-continue-framework/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 17:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenging Yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goal Setting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Strategies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenging yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goal setting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=358</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week during a workshop at work we used the Stop, Start, Continue Framework. The purpose of the exercise was to identify the behaviours our management team wanted to stop doing, start and continue doing. The model inherently means that there are things that you are currently doing that are bad, good and<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/25/stop-start-continue-framework/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week during a workshop at work we used the Stop, Start, Continue Framework. The purpose of the exercise was to identify the behaviours our management team wanted to stop doing, start and continue doing. The model inherently means that there are things that you are currently doing that are bad, good and that you should begin doing.</p>
<p>Although the model was used in a work context, it was very clear to me how it could also very easily apply to everyday life.</p>
<p>If I take the goal of eating healthier, for example. I can STOP choosing unhealthy snacks at night, STOP buying unhealthy snacks with my groceries. I can START preparing vegetables in advance so when I want to eat something it&#8217;s an easy choice. I can START a food journal for a week to see my eating habits and spot opportunities to improve them. I can CONTINUE having healthy lunches of home cooked meals versus frozen pre-packaged lunches.</p>
<p>This is a simple example, but it illustrates well a behavior modification strategy. These are all simple behavior modifications that can be easily achieved by anyone &#8211; we are not talking major life changing modifications. I think the success of any sustainable behavior change is the capacity to incorporate the change into everyday life and make little changes that are manageable. Once a little change is made you can piggyback on that change and move towards the next modification you want to make.</p>
<p>The STOP, START, CONTINUE is one tool to help get you to the change you want to achieve. It can be applied to any sphere of your life, whether it is personal or professional. </p>
<p>There&#8217;s recap:</p>
<p>- <strong><em>Identify a Goal</em> </strong>for Behavior Change</p>
<p>- Think about the behaviors you want to <em>Stop, Start, and Continue</em></p>
<p>- <strong><em>STOP</em></strong>: What am I doing that isn&#8217;t working? What are the things that are not adding value?</p>
<p>- <strong><em>START</em></strong>: What should I put in place to improve? What are the things that I am not doing that would help to improve the situation?</p>
<p>- <strong><em>CONTINUE</em></strong>: What is working well? What are the things that are working to some extent, but could be improved with some changes?</p>
<p><strong>What behavioral modification strategies have you used in the past? What has worked best for you?</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/25/stop-start-continue-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ottawa Relay Winter Marathon Results</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/18/ottawa-relay-winter-marathon-results/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/18/ottawa-relay-winter-marathon-results/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenging Yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[race]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relay marathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running outside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running race]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I wrote a few weeks ago that I would be participating in the Somersault Winter Relay Marathon&#8230;well the big race was this weekend. Let me just say that it was an interesting experience. We were a team of 3 for the marathon. After some discussion we decided that my boyfriend would<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/18/ottawa-relay-winter-marathon-results/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a few weeks ago that I would be participating in the <a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/01/11/me-run-a-relay-marathon-really/" target="_blank">Somersault Winter Relay Marathon</a>&#8230;well the big race was this weekend.</p>
<p>Let me just say that it was an interesting experience. We were a team of 3 for the marathon. After some discussion we decided that my boyfriend would run a 10.55km, our friend a 21.1 km and depending on how I was feeling I would run either a 5.28km or 10.55km and my boyfriend would do my remaining 5.28 km if needed.</p>
<p>Weather conditions were tough to say the least. At the 8:30am start we were facing at least -18C weather and with wind chill it was at least -25C. It was freezing cold! I&#8217;ve been fairly lucky this winter because most of my outdoor runs (unfortunately there haven&#8217;t been too many) have been in good winter conditions. Let me just say -25C with wind is cold!</p>
<p>The course was essentially a 5km lap. Depending on how many kilometers you were running you could do this lap 1 to 8 times. I felt bad for those who had to do the course more than once simply because of the sheer monotony of it all. Also, depending on how you decided to split the distances you could wait between 30 minutes to a few hours before you got to do your distance. Luckily the <a href="http://www.warmuseum.ca/home/">Ottawa War Museum</a> was nice enough to let us stay in their lobby while we waited.  Regardless, it made for a long morning!</p>
<p>With the temperature and associated difficulty breathing in cold weather, my lack of training and mental sabotage I ended up doing a 5km. 5km is fair enough, but it is far from being a triumph. I ate my share of humble pie during those 5kms. I can usually run a 5km without much problem, but yesterday I let my mind win and walked twice during my distance. &#8220;It&#8217;s cold, I&#8217;m out of shape and out of breath, I need to stop if I want to get through it.&#8221; That was the conversation that was going on in my mind.</p>
<p>Running is sometimes much more a mental exercise than a physical one. I suspect that if I had run a 10km I would have started that negative self talk only 5kms in rather than at 2.5km like yesterday. I&#8217;ve been able to train and run for a 21kms why couldn&#8217;t I complete a simple 5km?</p>
<p>I think I&#8217;ve got some mental work to do in the upcoming weeks if I want my <a href="http://espritdecorps.biz/fondation/montreal-new-york" target="_blank">Montreal-New York City Challenge</a> to be a success. If I want any chance of being able to complete the 84kms in 3 days to get to New York City I need to get my mind muscles as strong, if not stronger, than the rest of my body.</p>
<p><strong><em>What do you tell yourself to keep going in the middle of a race or workout when you think you can&#8217;t go any further? </em></strong></p>
<p>Overall, the cold weather, the monotony of the race course, and the waiting between relays would not necessarily entice me to do this event again. However, I will be reliving the relay experience once more with the Montreal-New York City challenge but on a much larger scale and with an end destination in mind versus doing lap after lap.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t end this post without showing one of the highlights - the beautiful view that Ottawa gave us during the race. Here is a snapshot I took near the end of the race.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.living4impact.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Ottawa-winter-marathon.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-353" alt="relay marathon" src="http://www.living4impact.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Ottawa-winter-marathon.jpg" width="1024" height="768" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/18/ottawa-relay-winter-marathon-results/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Running: What Do You Really Need?</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/13/running-what-do-you-really-need/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/13/running-what-do-you-really-need/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 22:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life Strategies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running and music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working out]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=346</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was reading Kevin Lu&#8217;s post today on iRunner&#8217;s Blog about running without technology. Although Kevin is a big fan of anything running technology he talks about not needing all the latest technology to run. He couldn&#8217;t be more right! I often hear people say that they can&#8217;t run without<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/13/running-what-do-you-really-need/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was reading <a href="http://www.irunnerblog.com/runners-technology/runners-tech-running-unplugged/comment-page-1/#comment-15117" target="_blank">Kevin Lu&#8217;s post</a> today on <a href="http://www.irunnerblog.com/" target="_blank">iRunner&#8217;s Blog </a>about running without technology. Although Kevin is a big fan of anything running technology he talks about not needing all the latest technology to run. He couldn&#8217;t be more right! I often hear people say that they can&#8217;t run without their ipod and music. I once also thought that was true, but I now run more often without music than with music.</p>
<p>I remember being completely stressed about having my ipod during my first 10km race last year…of course when I got to the start line my ipod wasn’t working and I ran the whole 10km without my precious music. Guess what? It was the best thing that could happen…I was able to enjoy the race and take in  the sights and sounds of my first race! I was both in my head talking to myself while being with thousands of other people who were racing with me. I would not have had the same experience if I had been concentrated on my music.</p>
<p>Why was I so hung up on making sure I ran with music? For me it was a way to get through the race. I knew that by listening to my music I could concentrate on other things aside from the race. I could be distracted. But, why did I want to be distracted? I think I told myself I wasn&#8217;t strong enough to complete my race. I was using music not only as a distraction but also as a crutch to hide my fear of not being able to do it. Music was a distraction from my negative self-talk.</p>
<p>When I run without my music now instead of negative self-talk I simply count to ten. It&#8217;s still a distraction from what is going on with my body and how much I am suffering, but it&#8217;s not negatively impacting my confidence. With each count of 1, 2, 3 I am closer to the finish line. I now try to look around me, see people&#8217;s expression as I pass them instead of singing along to some random song. Don&#8217;t get me wrong I enjoy a good run with my ipod blasting in my ears, but running with the thoughts in my head no longer scares me.</p>
<p>In my case I was forced by a glitch in technology to step outside of my comfort zone, but I would encourage anyone to try it a few times before saying that you cannot run without your music. </p>
<p><em><strong>How do you change your running habits to step outside your zone of comfort?</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/13/running-what-do-you-really-need/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Effective Teamwork: Together We Can Accomplish Amazing Things</title>
		<link>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/11/340/</link>
		<comments>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/11/340/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 14:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nancy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenging Yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenging yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surpassing yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teamwork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workout]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.living4impact.com/?p=340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Coming together is a beginning; keeping together is progress; working together is success. Henry Ford Last week was our first team training workout. What an energizing event!! Our team met up with our coach and 2 other teams and we headed outside in -25C weather to warm-up (ironic I know!),<a href="http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/11/340/" class="read-more">Read the Rest...</a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<blockquote>
<div>Coming together is a beginning; keeping together is progress; working together is success. Henry Ford</div>
</blockquote>
<div>Last week was our first team training workout. What an energizing event!! Our team met up with our coach and 2 other teams and we headed outside in -25C weather to warm-up (ironic I know!), jog a little and play a few games together. After the fun outside we headed back inside for a fit test to evaluate everyone&#8217;s fitness level.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The sense of partnership and teamwork amazing! The games we played stimulated a sense of togetherness that I have rarely experienced. I have never really participated in a team sport before, and it struck me how everyone was pulling together with a common goal. From my previous experiences I always thought that people operated with only themselves in mind. That couldn&#8217;t be further than the truth last week. We encouraged each other to push through the pain. It didn&#8217;t matter what your fitness level was as long as you did your best that&#8217;s all that counted.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Some of the key elements for an <a title="Effective team characteristics" href="http://effective-training-development.co.uk/top-10-characteristics-of-an-effective-team/" target="_blank">effective team</a> include: shared values, common goal, vision and purpose, and is celebratory. Only from my experience last week I have no doubt that we will be an effective team and I&#8217;m looking forward to every minute of it! </div>
<div> </div>
<div>
<div>The high that teamwork and collaboration combined with physical exercise was amazing. It was energizing and revitalizing. Seeing people achieve things they didn&#8217;t think possible and reaching a goal is so inspiring for me. Now I know I need to push myself not only for me, but for my team members who need me.</div>
</div>
<div> </div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.living4impact.com/2013/02/11/340/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
