<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Invading Holland</title>
	
	<link>http://www.invadingholland.com</link>
	<description>The story of an accident prone Englishman in Holland</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 08:56:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/invader-stu/slpz" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="invader-stu/slpz" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item>
		<title>Stuart For King Badges</title>
		<link>http://www.invadingholland.com/stuart-for-king-badges/</link>
		<comments>http://www.invadingholland.com/stuart-for-king-badges/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 08:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Invader Stu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Web Shop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Badges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[king stu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koninginnedag]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queens Day]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.invadingholland.com/?p=4537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last year I declared myself the new king of Holland. A few months ago the Queen announced her abdication. Now you can show your support for King Stu this Queen’s Day with the ‘Stuart for King Badge’. Details: The “Stuart for King” badge is a multi-functional badge that can be worn on coats, jackets, jumpers, [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="justify">Last year I declared myself the new king of Holland. A few months ago the Queen announced her abdication. Now you can show your support for King Stu this Queen’s Day with the ‘Stuart for King Badge’.</p>
<p><center><br />
<img src="http://www.invadingholland.com/media/inv_badge_price.jpg"><br />
</center></p>
<p align="justify"><b><font size=4>Details:</font></b><br />
The “Stuart for King” badge is a multi-functional badge that can be worn on coats, jackets, jumpers, shirts, t-shirts, bag straps, bags, back packs, back pack straps and a wide variety of items that badges can usually be pinned to. It’s 35mm in diameter and comes with the extra bonus that if King Stuart sees you wearing it he will say hello.</p>
<p align="justify"><b><font size=4>Prices &#038; Discounts:</font></b><br />
Badges cost 1.40 each. The cost of delivery is included in the price which means you don’t have to pay anything extra. And as an bonus; if you order ten badges you get an extra one for free!</p>
<p align="justify"><b><font size=4>Ordering:</font></b><br />
If you would like to have your very own ‘Stuart for King’ Badge you can do so by sending an email to the following address:</p>
<p><center><font size=4><a href="mailto:shop@invadingholland.com">shop@invadingholland.com</a></font></center></p>
<p align="justify">Be sure to include how many badges you would like and which address you want them sent to. I (King Stuart) can then send you an official invoice along with information on how you can pay for your order (by direct bank transfer or PayPal). Invading Holland T-Shirts are also still available <a href="http://www.invadingholland.com/invading-holland-t-shirts/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p align="justify">I am still hard at work on the official webshop which is part of a new redesign for the whole site. I hope to have it ready soon but it’s amazing how much longer things take when you become a father.</p>
<p align="justify"><b><font size=4>Future Badges:</font></b><br />
If these badges sell well I plan to get more made using some of the other Invader Stu cartoons. Maybe you have one in mind that you would like to see in badge form. Mention it in the comments and I will put it into a future post where you guys get to vote on what the next Invading Holland badge will be.</p>
<p><center><br />
<img src="http://www.invadingholland.com/media/inv_badges.jpg"><br />
</center><br />
<center><font color="#cccccc"><b>Legal Stuff</b><br />
Invading Holland Designs / KvK Number: 55885551 / Postbus 91248 3007ME Rotterdam</font></center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.invadingholland.com/stuart-for-king-badges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Greatest Mystery of All</title>
		<link>http://www.invadingholland.com/the-greatest-mystery-of-all/</link>
		<comments>http://www.invadingholland.com/the-greatest-mystery-of-all/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 10:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Invader Stu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.invadingholland.com/?p=4526</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Life is full of mysteries. Who are we? Why are we here? Did I leave the oven on? Great big mysteries that are difficult to solve and keep a lot of very intelligent people busy. However, there is a mystery that is bigger than any mystery ever pondered! Larger than any question ever asked! More [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="cartoon"><img src="http://www.invadingholland.com/cartoons/inv_mystery.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p align="justify">Life is full of mysteries. Who are we? Why are we here? Did I leave the oven on? Great big mysteries that are difficult to solve and keep a lot of very intelligent people busy.</p>
<p align="justify">However, there is a mystery that is bigger than any mystery ever pondered! Larger than any question ever asked! More infinite than any puzzle ever puzzled! Many people have attempted to solve this mystery and been driven insane by it. It is simply cannot and will not be solved&#8230; What is the correct usage of de and het in the Dutch language?</p>
<p align="justify">The true meaning of life will be solved long before anyone even comes close to solving this unsolvable mystery.</p>
<p align="justify">Please! Do not try to answer this question yourself. Even if you believe that you know the answer. Simply pondering this question for even a moment can put your mental health at serious risk. Thinking about if for just one second puts your sanity in danger. If you are an expat trying to learn the language it is far safer to just get it wrong and refer to things as de huis or het man (for example). It simply is not worth risking trying to get it right. I cannot stress this enough.</p>
<p align="justify">Dutch people especially might think they can answer this mystery. They are Dutch after all and being Dutch is a pretty good qualification to have on the subject of being and speaking Dutch. However, no matter how much they think they know the answer the truth is that they do not. This becomes very evident the moment they make the mistake of trying to explain the answer.</p>
<p align="justify">At first it is all very simple. ‘De’ is used for masculine and feminine words, where as ‘Het’ is used for neutral words. That’s it. How hard can it be?&#8230; But then they remember that one occasion where the rule does not work&#8230; and then that other one where it does not apply&#8230; and another where it is invalid&#8230; and that strange one where the rule is flipped&#8230; and sometimes reversed&#8230; or occasionally upside down&#8230; or when a entirely different rule is used based on the position of the moon!</p>
<p align="justify">Suddenly they realize they cannot explain the mysteries of De and Het. It was foolish of them even to attempt to do so, and it is probably best that they stop before the headache (that they don’t remember having a few moments ago) gets any worse.</p>
<p align="justify">It is at this point that there is only one explanation that they can give, wise words that have been handed down from generation to generation of Dutchman when dealing with outsiders trying to learn the language; “You just have to know it.”</p>
<p align="justify">It is a mystery that can never be solved without being born Dutch. And even then, trying to truly understand or explain it ends in madness.</p>
<p><center>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</center><br />
<font color="#fff">Still don’t believe me that it is dangerous to attempt solving this mystery? While writing this post I had a migraine.</font></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.invadingholland.com/the-greatest-mystery-of-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Born to Party</title>
		<link>http://www.invadingholland.com/born-to-party/</link>
		<comments>http://www.invadingholland.com/born-to-party/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 09:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Invader Stu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cartoons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.invadingholland.com/?p=4516</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This cartoon appeared in the March/April edition of DUTCH:The Magazine, a bi-monthly magazine for Dutch descendants and expats living in Canada.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center><img src="http://www.invadingholland.com/comics/inv_strip_01.jpg"></center></p>
<p>This cartoon appeared in the March/April edition of <a href="http://www.dutchthemag.com/" target="_blank">DUTCH:The Magazine</a>, a bi-monthly magazine for Dutch descendants and expats living in Canada. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.invadingholland.com/born-to-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best European Blog 2013</title>
		<link>http://www.invadingholland.com/best-european-blog-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://www.invadingholland.com/best-european-blog-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 08:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Invader Stu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.invadingholland.com/?p=4505</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have some very exciting news. So exciting in fact that it is taking all my focus and concentration to write coherent sentences instead of simply resorting to loud cheering noises while fist pumping the air (which I would still do if it was not for the fact that that would look very weird written [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="cartoon"><img src="http://www.invadingholland.com/cartoons/inv_award_win.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p align="justify">I have some very exciting news. So exciting in fact that it is taking all my focus and concentration to write coherent sentences instead of simply resorting to loud cheering noises while fist pumping the air (which I would still do if it was not for the fact that that would look very weird written down).</p>
<p align="justify">Basically the exciting news is this; Invading Holland has won. Thanks to your amazing help and support Invading Holland has won the <a href="http://2013.bloggi.es/#european" target="_blank">Best European Blog</a> category of the 2013 Bloggies. I owe each and every one of you a huge thank you.</p>
<p align="justify">If it was not for the fact that I am already married and a father I would say this is the happiest day of my life but I cannot say such things without getting into a lot of trouble. So instead lets agree that this achievement ranks somewhere below my wedding day and the birth of my daughter but much higher than the time I broke my ankle&#8230; And that I am extremely happy and honoured.</p>
<p align="justify">I was not the only Holland based expat blog to make it to the finals this year either. Also nominated were <a href="http://www.likeasponge.nl/" target="_blank">Like a Sponge</a> and <a href="http://nomadmomdiary.com/" target="_blank">Nomad Mum</a>. Proof that we are not just taking over Holland but the rest of Europe too.</p>
<p align="justify">In closing; if you are a long term reader, a short term reader or even a medium term reader; Thank You.</p>
<p align="justify">And if you are finding this blog for the first time&#8230; Hello. My name is Stuart, accident prone Englishman and self proclaimed <a href="http://www.invadingholland.com/new-leadership/" target="_blank">King of Holland</a>. Nice to meet you. Welcome to my strange little corner of the internet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.invadingholland.com/best-european-blog-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Time in Holland</title>
		<link>http://www.invadingholland.com/spring-time-in-holland/</link>
		<comments>http://www.invadingholland.com/spring-time-in-holland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 08:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Invader Stu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cartoons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.invadingholland.com/?p=4499</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The first snowflake of spring has fallen. The Easter bunny has wrapped up in his warmest scarf and woolliest jumper. The tulips have frozen and cute baby animals everywhere are huddling together for warmth. Spring has truly arrived in Holland.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><center><img src="http://www.invadingholland.com/cartoons/inv_postcard_spring.jpg"></center><br />
The first snowflake of spring has fallen. The Easter bunny has wrapped up in his warmest scarf and woolliest jumper. The tulips have frozen and cute baby animals everywhere are huddling together for warmth.  Spring has truly arrived in Holland.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.invadingholland.com/spring-time-in-holland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
